<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 18:05:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>MetroMile says a website bug let a hacker obtain driver&#8217;s license numbers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/metromile-website-bug-hacker/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/metromile-website-bug-hacker/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 17:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law enforcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MetroMile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ryan graves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Car insurance startup MetroMile said it has fixed a security flaw on its website that allowed a hacker to obtain driver&#8217;s license numbers. The San Francisco-based insurance startup disclosed the security breach in its latest 8-K filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. MetroMile said a bug in the quote form and application process [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Car insurance startup MetroMile said it has fixed a security flaw on its website that allowed a hacker to obtain driver&#8217;s license numbers.</p>
<p>The San Francisco-based insurance startup disclosed the security breach in <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1819035/000121390021005784/ea134248-8k_insuacquis2.htm?=1819035-01022021">its latest 8-K filing</a> with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
<p>MetroMile said a bug in the quote form and application process on the company&#8217;s website allowed the hacker to &#8220;obtain personal information of certain individuals, including individuals&#8217; driver&#8217;s license numbers.&#8221; It&#8217;s not clear exactly how the form allowed the hacker to obtain driver&#8217;s license numbers or how many individuals had their driver&#8217;s license numbers obtained.</p>
<p>The disclosure added: &#8220;Metromile immediately took steps to contain and remediate the issue, including by releasing software fixes, notified its insurance carrier, and has continued its ongoing operations. Metromile is working diligently with security experts and legal counsel to ascertain how the incident occurred, identify additional containment and remediation measures, and notify affected individuals, law enforcement, and regulatory bodies, as appropriate.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rick Chen, a spokesperson for MetroMile, said that the company has so far confirmed that driver&#8217;s license numbers were accessed, but that the &#8220;investigation is still ongoing.&#8221;</p>
<p>MetroMile has not disclosed the security incident on its website or its social channels. Chen said the company plans to notify affected individuals of the incident.</p>
<p>News of the security incident landed as the company <a href="https://www.metromile.com/blog/ryan-graves-saltwater-investment-metromile/">confirmed</a> a $50 million investment from former Uber executive Ryan Graves, who will also join the company&#8217;s board. It comes just weeks after the auto insurance startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/pay-per-mile-auto-insurer-metromile-is-heading-to-public-markets-via-spac/">announced</a> it was planning to go public via <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/almost-everything-you-need-to-know-about-spacs/">a special-purpose acquisition company</a> — or SPAC — in a $1.3 billion deal.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="D92oa8mt3k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/decoding-data-breach-notice/">How to decode a data breach notice</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to decode a data breach notice&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/decoding-data-breach-notice/embed/#?secret=D92oa8mt3k" data-secret="D92oa8mt3k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/metromile-website-bug-hacker/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107271</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcome Tage Kene-Okafor, Mary Ann Azevedo, Sophie Burkholder and a guy named Drew</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/welcome-tage-kene-okafor-mary-ann-azevedo-sophie-burkholder-and-a-guy-named-drew/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/welcome-tage-kene-okafor-mary-ann-azevedo-sophie-burkholder-and-a-guy-named-drew/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Panzarino]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 17:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drew olanoff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106895</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are some additions to the TechCrunch team that I&#8217;m happy to announce. First, Kirsten Korosec, who has been with us for more than two years, was promoted to Transportation Editor. Kirsten has done amazing work, helping to elevate our foothold in the transportation space and making our Mobility events some of the most successful [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There are some additions to the TechCrunch team that I&#8217;m happy to announce.</p>
<p>First, <a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec">Kirsten Korosec</a>, who has been with us for more than two years, was promoted to Transportation Editor. Kirsten has done amazing work, helping to elevate our foothold in the transportation space and making our Mobility events some of the most successful we’ve produced. This means that not only will she continue to hunt for scoops, but she’ll also be bringing on some fresh voices in transportation. Look for them on TechCrunch and Extra Crunch soon.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re also happy to say that <a href="https://twitter.com/jshieber?">Jon Shieber</a> will become our new Climate Editor, focused on the startups and funding being put behind renewables, environmental technology and green businesses. More on this soon.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Next, we’d like to welcome some new contract writers who will be joining our small but mighty team of reporters covering the startup ecosystem:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/ulonnaya">Tage Kene-Okafor</a>, who is based in Lagos, will be covering Western Africa for us. He comes to us from <a href="https://techpoint.africa/author/tagekeneokafor/">TechPoint Africa</a> where he covered startups and venture capital.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/bayareawriter">Mary Ann Azevedo</a> will be covering startups and investing. She is coming to us from <a href="https://finledger.com/author/mazevedo/">FinLedger</a>, where she was charged with getting the fintech-focused site launched. Before that, she worked for our very own Alex Wilhelm at <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/author/maryannazevedo/">Crunchbase News</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/sophieburkhold">Sophie Burkholder</a> will be covering startups from health and biotech to enterprise.</li>
</ul>
<p>Rounding out our fresh lineup of writers are some other contributors. Mark Harris, who has already <a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/mark-harris/">broken several great scoops</a> for us, <a href="https://twitter.com/la__cuen?lang=en">Leigh Cuen</a> who will be covering crypto and <a href="https://twitter.com/marcemccarthy">Marcella McCarthy</a>, who will be all over the startup scene in Miami, as well as contribute to Extra Crunch.</p>
<p>Finally, we are welcoming back <a href="https://twitter.com/yoda">Drew Olanoff</a> who has taken on our community-building project, something we’re extremely excited about. Drew will help us to identify the global TechCrunch community and will serve as the connective tissue between Extra Crunch and TechCrunch, as well as our events, like Disrupt, where all of our content comes alive.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s going to be a big year at TechCrunch and we&#8217;re excited to have them all a part of the team. Welcome them aboard if you get a chance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/welcome-tage-kene-okafor-mary-ann-azevedo-sophie-burkholder-and-a-guy-named-drew/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106895</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Anonymous&#8217; fintech startup Millions raises $3 million, gives away cash on Twitter</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/anonymous-fintech-startup-millions-raises-3-million-gives-away-cash-on-twitter/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/anonymous-fintech-startup-millions-raises-3-million-gives-away-cash-on-twitter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 16:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107203</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An &#8220;anonymously&#8221;-led startup called Millions has raised a $3 million seed round for its fintech company that&#8217;s currently giving away free money through its Twitter account. The concept, inspired by the likes of YouTuber David Dobrik, is partly aimed at attracting attention for the new company but is also setting the stage for a forthcoming [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">An &#8220;anonymously&#8221;-led startup called <a href="https://millions.app/">Millions</a> has raised a $3 million seed round for its fintech company that&#8217;s currently giving away free money through its Twitter account. The concept, inspired by the likes of YouTuber <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Dobrik">David Dobrik</a>, is partly aimed at attracting attention for the new company but is also setting the stage for a forthcoming business model of sorts, where brands could participate in giveaways more directly.</p>
<p>The idea of brand and cash giveaways is not a new one, of course. Outside of social media personalities and traditional sweepstakes like Publishers Clearing House, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/14/hq-trivia-shuts-down/">mobile game HQ Trivia</a> more recently had tried to <a href="https://digiday.com/future-of-tv/inside-hqs-attempt-grow-ad-business/">integrate brand giveaways</a> in an attempt to draw players to its live trivia games. But HQ Trivia couldn&#8217;t maintain an audience after the novelty wore off and eventually shut down, after also dealing with internal <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/14/trivia-game-of-thrones/">strife</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/16/hq-trivia-and-vine-co-founder-colin-kroll-found-dead-of-suspected-overdose/">tragedy</a>.</p>
<p>Millions has a different idea. Instead of weekly live games, users follow the Twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/millions">@millions</a>, which either does a drop of some sort or gives away money to its followers every month. This month, for example, the account is launching its &#8220;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5aSE-bawQ8Y&amp;feature=youtu.be">million dollar sweepstakes</a>.&#8221; Users follow @millions on Twitter, visit <a href="https://millions.app/">Millions.app</a>, the enter 6 numbers. If all 6 match, they win $1 million*. <em>(See details below). </em></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Next month, the startup will launch a game called &#8220;are you my number neighbor?&#8221; where users will enter their phone number on a website, and if it&#8217;s just a digit off from the phone number on the site, the user wins $100,000.</p>
<p>These stunts &#8212; apparently just giving away investor cash &#8212; are meant to raise brand awareness and acquire customers.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107279" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107279" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2107279" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-02-at-11.37.08-AM-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="394" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-02-at-11.37.08-AM-1.jpg 3046w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-02-at-11.37.08-AM-1.jpg?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-02-at-11.37.08-AM-1.jpg?resize=300,174 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-02-at-11.37.08-AM-1.jpg?resize=768,445 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-02-at-11.37.08-AM-1.jpg?resize=680,394 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-02-at-11.37.08-AM-1.jpg?resize=1536,891 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-02-at-11.37.08-AM-1.jpg?resize=2048,1187 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-02-at-11.37.08-AM-1.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107279" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Millions/MyCard, Inc.</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;If you think about customer acquisition costs &#8212; and this is a little bit controversial &#8212; people just give money to Facebook or Instagram, or Apple or Google. The money goes straight to a social network and not the people,&#8221; explained a Millions co-founder, who asked to remain anonymous. &#8220;They&#8217;re trying to get the people, but they&#8217;re not giving the people the money. The Millions way is really giving the people the money. We don&#8217;t need to run advertisements. We&#8217;re giving the money directly to the people, and hopefully, they follow our ecosystem, subscribe for updates, and they&#8217;ll see the future launch,&#8221; they said.</p>
<p>Ultimately, the larger plan for Millions is to transfer the customers it acquires through the games to the fintech play, which will also have something to do with winning money.</p>
<p>TechCrunch agreed to not reveal the co-founders&#8217; name during a discussion to learn what the startup was up to, as they said they wanted to keep the game playful and anonymous for the time being. But we&#8217;re not breaking any agreements by pointing to what&#8217;s easy-to-access, publicly available data. We found the company, Mycard Inc. is referenced on the Millions website&#8217;s <a href="https://millions.app/">Terms</a> as the legal entity behind this endeavour. That same company is on <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1837649/000183764920000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml">this SEC filing</a> for a $3 million fundraise in December 2020. The filing lists two names: Kieran and Rory O&#8217;Reilly. These are the same names as the brothers <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/skipping-school-to-become-tech-giants/">behind gifs.com</a>.</p>
<p>Investors in the startup&#8217;s seed round included Giant Ventures, 8VC, Supernode, Supernode, Twitter co-founder Biz Stone, Italic CEO Jeremy Cai, Allbirds co-founder and CEO Joey Zwillinger, Casper co-founders Neil Parikh and Luke Sherwin, MSCHF head of strategy and growth Daniel Greenberg, CEO of Deel Alex Bouaziz, CEO of Hellosaurus James Ruben, CEO of Beek Pamela Valdes, PM at Facebook (for the Payments Gateway team) Luis Vargas, co-founder of Block Renovations Koda Want, CEO of Nebula Genomics Kamal Obbad, plus some of the co-founders from Warby Parker and Harry&#8217;s, and other fintech angels.</p>
<p>A few investors also agreed to vouch for Millions on the record, and hinted at the MyCard product to come.</p>
<p>&#8220;This company is creating delight from what would otherwise be the mundane, everyday necessity of swiping a credit card. We invested in Millions because they will spark joy in people&#8217;s lives, and think the traditional points model of accumulating hard-to-use airline and hotel points is tired, and ripe for reinvention,&#8221; said <a href="https://www.allbirds.com/">Allbirds</a> co-founder and CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jzwillinger/">Joey Zwillinger</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Millions is building an incredibly loyal audience through an unparalleled, engaging customer experience and the $1M giveaway is only the tip of the iceberg of what&#8217;s to come. These are some of the strongest founders I know and have truly captured lightning in a bottle,&#8221; said <a href="http://italic.com/">Italic</a> CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremyhcai">Jeremy Cai.</a></p>
<p>&#8220;I invested in Millions because the trend is clear &#8211; people love winning money.It’s clear that there’s something going on here. Millions is dedicated to giving away money in crazy ways and I’m happy to be involved,&#8221; said <a href="https://mschf.xyz/">MSCHF</a> head of strategy and growth, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-greenberg-4aab97115/">Daniel Greenberg</a>.</p>
<p>Millions&#8217; arrival, however, comes at a time when people are desperate for money due to the economic downturn driven by the COVID-19 pandemic and lack of government assistance. The pandemic has exacerbated the class divide, leading people (<a href="https://apnews.com/article/virus-outbreak-pope-francis-archive-capitalism-bcde0053314e65612add0709fada5519">including</a> the Pope) to question whether capitalism has failed. It has fueled the &#8220;<a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/photos/2005082-gamestop-stock-surge">eat the rich</a>&#8221; ethos behind the GameStop frenzy. And this situation has added a darker layer to otherwise do-gooder activities, like Dobrick&#8217;s <a href="https://www.elitedaily.com/p/these-tweets-about-david-dobriks-coronavirus-giveaway-will-make-you-emotional-22846125">stunts</a> or <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@lexylately?lang=en">Lexy Kadey&#8217;s TikTok &#8220;Venmo Challenges</a>,&#8221; where she tips waitstaff and fast food workers hundreds or even a thousand dollars and films them breaking down in relief.</p>
<p>Millions&#8217; co-founder acknowledges we&#8217;re in a time of need, but also argues that&#8217;s why the product makes sense.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you think about what&#8217;s going on in the world right now &#8212; with the pandemic and the 99% versus the 1% &#8212; people are looking for a) hope and b) money,&#8221; they said. &#8220;If you can combine a product that has two of those things, you&#8217;re giving people fun, excitement, and something to look forward to&#8230;I think that&#8217;s really inspiring.&#8221;</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/5aSE-bawQ8Y?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p><em>*Note: Like many sweepstakes, you&#8217;re playing for a &#8220;chance&#8221; to win. But in this case, $10,000 is a guaranteed Grand Prize win for one person. The Millions website lists the digital promotions company <a href="https://www.rtm.com/">Realtime Media</a> as being involved in helping manage the game. However, the insurance provider that insures the program is actually HCC.  </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/anonymous-fintech-startup-millions-raises-3-million-gives-away-cash-on-twitter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107203</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Valon closes on $50M a16z-led Series A to grow mobile-first mortgage servicing platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/valon-closes-on-50m-a16z-led-series-a-to-grow-mobile-first-mortgage-servicing-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/valon-closes-on-50m-a16z-led-series-a-to-grow-mobile-first-mortgage-servicing-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 16:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angela Strange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mortgage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’ve ever applied for a mortgage, you know it’s one of the most painful processes out there. Keeping up with payments and dealing with customer service over the course of the loan is no picnic either. So it’s no surprise that big bucks are being poured into the space with the goal of making [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’ve ever applied for a mortgage, you know it’s one of the most painful processes out there. Keeping up with payments and dealing with customer service over the course of the loan is no picnic either.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So it’s no surprise that big bucks are being poured into the space with the goal of making the process easier, more digital and more transparent.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To that end, <a href="https://valon.com/">Valon</a>, a tech-enabled mortgage servicer, announced this morning it has raised $50 million in a Series A round of funding &#8212; which is large for its stage even by today’s standards.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Andreessen Horowitz (a16z) led the round for the New York-based company formerly known as Peach Street. Returning backers Jefferies Financial Group, New Residential Investment Corporation – an affiliate of Fortress Investment Group LLC – and 166 2nd LLC (<a href="https://massinvestordatabase.com/publicfirm.php?name=166+2nd+Financial+Services">the family office of WeWork</a> co-founder Adam Neumann) also participated in the financing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Valon previously raised $3.2 million from seed investors such as serial entrepreneur Kevin Ryan’s Alley Corp, Soros, Kairos, and Zigg Capital. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Andrew Wang, Eric Chiang and Jon Hsu founded Valon in June 2019 with the mission of breaking up what it sees as “a monopoly in the market,” with “the largest mortgage servicing software company” (software giant Black Knight) controlling more than half of all U.S. residential loans.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re on the cusp of a mortgage foreclosure crisis comparable to 2008, and the majority of homeowners struggling to make their loan payments are unaware of their options,” Valon CEO Wang said. “This stranglehold has driven servicing costs up nearly 250% in the past decade, and the fees are passed on directly to the borrower.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Concurrent with the raise, Valon recently got the green light from Fannie Mae to service its government sponsored home loans. (For the unacquainted, servicing loans means doing things like collecting payments on behalf of a lender). The approval will only continue to fuel Valon&#8217;s rapid growth, according to Wang.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We went from no contracts committed to $10 billion in mortgages committed to be serviced in one year,” he told TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Valon operates in 49 states, and expects to add New York this year. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a former investor in mortgage servicing space, Wang was frustrated by “the lack of service” provided by other servicers. So he teamed up with Chiang and Hsu, who had prior product and engineering experience at Google and Twilio, to launch Valon.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s cloud-native platform aims to deliver what it describes as a borrower-oriented experience. Lenders also can request access to real-time API data feeds to view performance of their borrowers and reconcile transaction data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike mortgage originators, which lend money to the borrower, a mortgage servicer interfaces with the borrower for the duration of their loan – and that can be anywhere from 15 to 30 years. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This includes things like collecting payments on behalf of the lender and providing assistance and guidance to the borrower in moments of stress,” Wang said. “Traditional mortgage servicers use antiquated technology and provide poor service to borrowers. Valon looks to change that dynamic by providing transparency and full self-service capabilities to homeowner</span>s.<b>”</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company also claims that its technology has the potential to reduce mortgage servicing costs by up to 50% by vertically integrating the entire process. Its platform is built on Google Cloud with security as a “first-principle” with features such as default encryption and intrusion detection, the company said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Millions of Americans<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/04/06/coronavirus-bailout-there-is-going-to-be-complete-chaos-mortgage-ceo.html"> stopped paying their mortgages</a> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in 2020 due to the economic strain of the coronavirus pandemic. This led to requests for forbearance (postponement of payments) and foreclosure moratoriums.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The pandemic highlighted the stress in the market and greatly accelerated the need for a new age mortgage servicer,” Wang said. “Homeowners faced a great deal of financial stress and had difficulty getting the right option and assistance from existing servicers due to their antiquated technology and inability to process requests&#8230; In 2021 we will see forbearance and foreclosure leniency come to an end and this need will be even more acute.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://twitter.com/astrange">Angela Strange</a>, a general partner at Andreessen Horowitz who joined Valon’s board in mid-2020, says Valon has built a mobile-first mortgage servicer from the ground up.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Homeowners are faced with clumsy websites, call centers, and often misinformation,” she said in a written statement. “In Valon, they have a trusted software driven advisor who can provide clear, transparent, regulatory compliant information in good times and bad &#8211; without needing to pick up the phone.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Fannie Mae approval only serves as further validation of the platform the team has created, she added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Valon plans to use its new capital to triple headcount to about 100 by year’s end as well as to acquire more mortgage servicing rights (MSR) contracts to service.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/valon-closes-on-50m-a16z-led-series-a-to-grow-mobile-first-mortgage-servicing-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107234</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atlassian stops selling on-prem server licenses, adds new enteprise pricing tier</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/atlassian-stops-selling-on-prem-licenses-adds-new-enteprise-pricing-tier/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/atlassian-stops-selling-on-prem-licenses-adds-new-enteprise-pricing-tier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlassian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Atlassian has made it clear for some time that it&#8217;s all in on the cloud, but now it&#8217;s official. The company stopped selling new on-prem server licenses as of yesterday. Perhaps to take away the sting of that move for large organizations, today it announced a new all-inclusive enterprise pricing tier. Atlassian chief revenue officer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://atlassian.com">Atlassian</a> has made it clear for some time that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/02/atlassians-two-year-cloud-journey/">it&#8217;s all in on the cloud</a>, but now it&#8217;s official. The company stopped selling new on-prem server licenses as of yesterday. Perhaps to take away the sting of that move for large organizations, today it announced a new all-inclusive enterprise pricing tier.</p>
<p>Atlassian chief revenue officer Cameron Deatsch says that previously the company had offered a free tier and then standard and premium level paid tiers. &#8220;And now this cloud Enterprise Edition will be our highest tier, and what this will allow is for the most complex deployments, the largest customers who need unlimited scale, the customers that have all the security and regulatory requirements, data residency, you name it, &#8212; that is what we&#8217;re launching starting [today],&#8221; Deatsch told me.</p>
<p>What the enterprise tier delivers is unlimited instances across the Atlassian product line for each enterprise customer. That means a big company with multiple divisions could, for instance, have 20 instances of Jira and Confluence deployed with one for each division and a central management console.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="L4Se83th1L"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/02/atlassians-two-year-cloud-journey/">Atlassian&#8217;s two-year cloud journey</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Atlassian&#8217;s two-year cloud journey&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/02/atlassians-two-year-cloud-journey/embed/#?secret=L4Se83th1L" data-secret="L4Se83th1L" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While the company is supporting existing on-prem server customers until 2024, the idea is to now move them to the cloud and this offering should help. One thing we have clearly seen is that the pandemic has accelerated the move to the cloud by companies of every size, and this should encourage the company&#8217;s largest customers to make the move.</p>
<p>&#8220;The reality is, the demand was there, which was great to see, but we actually had this huge pipeline of our largest customers, basically trying to build their plan over the next couple of years to get to our cloud. The general availability of our Enterprise Edition is going to accelerate that even more,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a move the company has been working towards for some time, but it really began to take shape when they shifted their operations to AWS and<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/02/atlassians-two-year-cloud-journey/"> rebuilt the entire stack as a set of microservices</a> beginning in 2016. This was the first step towards being able to handle the increased kinds of workloads an enterprise tier would require.</p>
<p>The company reported earnings at the end of last month with revenue of $501.4 million up 23% YoY with over 11,000 net new subscribers, a record for the company. The new enterprise tier won&#8217;t help with new customer volume, but it should help with overall revenue as more customers look for cloud solutions and pricing that meets their needs.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qdQOnOcTtQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/a-pandemic-and-recession-wont-stop-atlassians-saas-push/">A pandemic and recession won&#8217;t stop Atlassian&#8217;s SaaS push</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A pandemic and recession won&#8217;t stop Atlassian&#8217;s SaaS push&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/a-pandemic-and-recession-wont-stop-atlassians-saas-push/embed/#?secret=qdQOnOcTtQ" data-secret="qdQOnOcTtQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/atlassian-stops-selling-on-prem-licenses-adds-new-enteprise-pricing-tier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107205</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bumble IPO could raise more than $1B for dating service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/bumble-ipo-could-raise-more-than-1b-for-dating-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/bumble-ipo-could-raise-more-than-1b-for-dating-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 15:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bumble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Match Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Could this IPO prove that there is lucrative space in the market for more dating products?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">On the heels of private companies Robinhood and Databricks <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/robinhoods-long-weekend-brings-a-total-of-3-4-billion-to-its-balance-sheet/">each</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/databricks-raises-1b-at-28b-valuation-as-it-reaches-425m-arr/">raising $1 billion or more yesterday</a>, Bumble is out with a new IPO filing this morning indicating that it wants to raise 10 figures as well.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">The relationship-finding service where women reach out first will go public on the heels of strong public debuts in December by companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/">like Airbnb</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">DoorDash </a>and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/how-doordash-and-c3-ai-can-defend-their-red-hot-ipo-valuatons/">C3.ai</a> with<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/after-soaring-above-23b-qualtrics-founder-and-ceo-reflect-on-a-stellar-debut/"> Qualtrics</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/poshmark-prices-ipo-above-range-as-public-markets-continue-to-yolo-startups/">and Poshmark</a> lighting the way in January.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>But at a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1830043/000119312521025246/d20761ds1a.htm">range of $28 to $30 per share</a>, is Bumble aiming high or low in its valuation and resulting multiples? (For more, check out our first-look at Bumble&#8217;s results <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/bumble-files-to-go-public/">here</a>.)</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995210 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Annoyingly, it&#8217;s a little tricky to figure out, as the company&#8217;s ownership structure and results are messy thanks to a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/08/badoos-andrey-andreev-sells-his-stake-in-bumble-to-blackstone-valuing-the-dating-app-at-3b/">majority-sale to Blackstone back in 2019</a>. So this won&#8217;t be entirely clean or simple.</p>
<p>But we&#8217;ll get through it. Here&#8217;s what we want to know:</p>
<ul>
<li>Simple and diluted valuations for Bumble at its current IPO price range.</li>
<li>What sort of multiples Bumble expects public investors to pay for its shares.</li>
<li>How those stack up compared to Match Group&#8217;s own numbers.</li>
<li>And, finally, what the Bumble IPO could mean for dating and relationship-focused startups; could this IPO prove that there is lucrative space in the market for more dating products?</li>
</ul>
<p>So let&#8217;s get to work, starting with Bumble&#8217;s valuation.</p>
<h2>It&#8217;s a bird! It&#8217;s a plane! It&#8217;s a very valuable bee?</h2>
<p>Bumble&#8217;s simple valuation is just that to calculate, a doddle. At $28 to $30 per share, and Bumble noting that it expects to have 108,384,634 shares outstanding after its IPO, including its full underwriters&#8217; option, the company would be worth $3.03 billion up to $3.25 billion.</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s a bit too simple. Bumble&#8217;s share count is actually quite a lot higher. For example, if we assume the &#8220;exchange of all Common Units held by the Pre-IPO Common Unitholders,&#8221; then the company&#8217;s share count rises to 189,548,952. At that share count, Bumble is worth $5.31 billion to $5.69 billion. That&#8217;s a lot more!</p>
<p>Now things get actually tricky. Our last share count did not take into its confines &#8220;any shares of Class A common stock issuable in exchange for as-converted Incentive Units or upon settlement of certain other interests.&#8221; So, what are those?<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/bumble-ipo-could-raise-more-than-1b-for-dating-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107179</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla recalls 135,000 vehicles over touchscreen failures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/tesla-recalls-135000-vehicles-over-touchscreen-failures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/tesla-recalls-135000-vehicles-over-touchscreen-failures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 14:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107196</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Own a Tesla Model S or Model X? It might have a recall, and it&#8217;s serious. Tesla today issued one of its largest recalls to date, covering roughly 135,000 Model S and Model X. The touchscreen is the concern. According to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA), the touchscreen in these vehicles can fail [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Own a Tesla Model S or Model X? It might have a recall, and it&#8217;s serious.</p>
<p>Tesla today issued one of its largest recalls to date, covering roughly 135,000 Model S and Model X. The touchscreen is the concern.</p>
<p>According to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA), the touchscreen in these vehicles can fail when a memory chips runs out of storage capacity, which can cause a host of failures, including affecting turn signals and defrosters, and the rearview camera. This failure can also affect Tesla&#8217;s self-driving Autopilot functionality.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The <a href="https://static.nhtsa.gov/odi/inv/2020/INRM-EA20003-11321.pdf">NHTSA explained the department&#8217;s findings</a> to Tesla in a mid-January letter. According to NHTSA&#8217;s Office of Defects Investigation (ODI), the affected vehicle&#8217;s memory chips are to blame. The 8GB chip eventually wears out, and the only remedy is a replacement, the letter says.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/tesla-recalls-roughly-135-000-vehicles-over-touch-screen-failures-11612270332">According to the WSJ</a>, Tesla disagrees that the issue is a failure, though the automaker is recalling a select amount of vehicles to investigate the issue.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is economically, if not technologically, infeasible to expect that such components can or should be designed to last the vehicle&#8217;s entire useful life,&#8221; Tesla said in the letter.</p>
<p>The vehicles covered by the recall include Model S sedans built between 2012 and 2018 and Model X vehicles made between 2016 and 2018. The affected vehicles are equipped with NVIDIA Tegra 3 computing platforms and an 8GB eMMC NAND flash memory device.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/tesla-recalls-135000-vehicles-over-touchscreen-failures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107196</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uber is buying alcohol delivery service Drizly for $1.1B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/uber-is-buying-alcohol-delivery-service-drizly-for-1-1b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/uber-is-buying-alcohol-delivery-service-drizly-for-1-1b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 14:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drizly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Uber today announced plans to acquire alcohol delivery service Drizly. The approximately $1.1 billion deal includes stock and cash and is expected to close in the first half of the year. The plan will build Drizly’s marketplace directly into the Uber Eats app, though the company notes that it will maintain Drizly as a standalone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Uber <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210202005693/en/Uber-to-Acquire-Drizly">today announced plans</a> to acquire alcohol delivery service Drizly. The approximately $1.1 billion deal includes stock and cash and is expected to close in the first half of the year. The plan will build Drizly’s marketplace directly into the Uber Eats app, though the company notes that it will maintain Drizly as a standalone app offering as well, for the time being.</p>
<p>Certainly there&#8217;s a marketplace fit here. Uber provides the underlying ride hailing and delivery technologies, while Drizly can help the company expand Uber Eats into an even more potentially lucrative service.</p>
<p>&#8220;[CEO Cory Rellas] and his amazing team have built Drizly into an incredible success story, profitably growing gross bookings more than 300 percent year-over-year,&#8221; Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi said in a release. &#8220;By bringing Drizly into the Uber family, we can accelerate that trajectory by exposing Drizly to the Uber audience and expanding its geographic presence into our global footprint in the years ahead.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The service has experienced a steady roll out in markets across the U.S. Though local liquor laws have offered something of a hurdle for expansion. Last month,<a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/drizly-brings-on-demand-adult-beverage-delivery-to-atlanta-following-recent-statewide-legalization-of-alcohol-e-commerce-301200960.html#:~:text=All%20Products-,Drizly%20Brings%20On%2DDemand%20Adult%20Beverage%20Delivery%20To%20Atlanta%20Following,Legalization%20Of%20Alcohol%20E%2DCommerce&amp;text=BOSTON%2C%20Jan.%205%2C%202021,is%20now%20available%20in%20Atlanta."> it added Atlanta</a> to the list, teaming up with a dozen or so local markets and liquor stores to expand delivery. Like Uber Eats, Drizly teams with local merchants in the markets it services. The company says its services reach more than 1,400 cities in North America at last count. No doubt pandemic-related shutdowns have also gone a ways toward expanding the appeal of alcohol delivery.</p>
<p>Founded in 2012, Boston-based Drizly has raised just under $120 million to date, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/drizly">per Crunchbase</a>. That includes<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/11/online-liquor-store-drizly-just-landed-34-5-million-in-fresh-funding/"> a $34.5 million Series C</a> back in late-2018. More recently, the service was hit <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/28/drizly-data-breach/">with a data breach</a>. The breach, which was disclosed last July, was believed to have impacted up to 2.5 million accounts.</p>
<p>Uber says it expects around 90% of the payment to Drizly stockholders to be made in Uber stock, with the remainder coming via cash. The deal will be is pending standard regulatory approval.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/uber-is-buying-alcohol-delivery-service-drizly-for-1-1b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107183</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Divvy Homes secures $110M Series C to help renters become homeowners</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/divvy-homes-secures-110m-series-c-to-help-renters-become-homeowners/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/divvy-homes-secures-110m-series-c-to-help-renters-become-homeowners/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite all the headaches that come with it, homeownership is still the American dream for many. Divvy Homes &#8211; a startup that is out to help more people realize that dream by buying a house and renting it back to them while they build equity &#8211; has just closed on $110 million in Series C [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Despite all the headaches that come with it, homeownership is still the American dream for many.</p>
<p>Divvy Homes &#8211; a startup that is out to help more people realize that dream by buying a house and renting it back to them while they build equity &#8211; has just closed on $110 million in Series C funding. Tiger Global Management led the round, which also saw participation from a slew of other investors including GGV Capital, Moore Specialty Credit, JAWS Ventures, and existing backers such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/09/divvy-an-interesting-new-fractional-home-ownership-startup-just-raised-a-series-a-round-led-by-andreessen-horowitz/">a16z</a>. The latest financing brings Divvy’s total debt and equity raised since its 2017 inception to over $500 million with about one-third of that raised in equity and two-thirds in debt.</p>
<p>The startup last raised $43 million<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/25/fractional-home-ownership-startup-divvy-raises-43m-series-b-to-build-a-path-from-rent-to-purchase/"> in Series B funding</a> from the likes of Affirm CEO Max Levchin and homebuilder Lennar (via its venture arm), among others. In fact, Divvy – which was co-founded by Adena Hefets, Nick Clark and Alex Klarfeld.  – was incubated in Levchin&#8217;s startup studio HVF.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Mortgage rates dropped to historic laws in 2020, driven by the COVID-19 pandemic. Instead of making it easier to buy a home, many banks actually tightened underwriting requirements for approvals, said Divvy CEO Hefets. So while lenders were busier than ever, much of that volume was driven by people who already owned homes refinancing with the lower rates.</p>
<p>Like most companies, Divvy was initially unsure as to how the pandemic would impact its business. But as the year went on – and the whole world spent more time at home than ever, the company only saw increased demand.</p>
<p>“We actually paused home buying for March and April and just kind of stood still waiting to see what would happen to the world,” Hefets said. “And when it felt like the world became stable again, we said, ‘Okay, let’s get back out there.’ ”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107024" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107024" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2107024" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Adena_Hefets_7893-1.jpg?w=225" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Adena_Hefets_7893-1.jpg 1875w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Adena_Hefets_7893-1.jpg?resize=113,150 113w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Adena_Hefets_7893-1.jpg?resize=225,300 225w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Adena_Hefets_7893-1.jpg?resize=768,1024 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Adena_Hefets_7893-1.jpg?resize=510,680 510w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Adena_Hefets_7893-1.jpg?resize=1152,1536 1152w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Adena_Hefets_7893-1.jpg?resize=1536,2048 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Adena_Hefets_7893-1.jpg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107024" class="wp-caption-text">Divvy Homes CEO and co-founder Adena Hefets</p></div></p>
<p>Ultimately, over the course of 2020, Divvy expanded operations from 8 to 16 total markets and financed five times as many homes as it had in pre-pandemic times. It also worked with its existing customers by offering flexibility and rent relief in  the way of waived late fees and flexible payment scheduling, for example.</p>
<p>“Mortgages were harder to get yet we were seeing this mad rush of people who wanted to move out of multifamily and downtown areas,” Hefets recalls. “So while traditional financing dried up, we saw a really good tailwind for our business.”</p>
<p>Divvy declined to disclose the valuation at which this round was raised but Hefets said it was “very highly oversubscribed.”</p>
<h2>Rent to own</h2>
<p>So how does Divvy work?</p>
<p>Divvy claims to be different from other real estate tech companies in that it aims to digitize “the archaic, data-heavy processes buyers encounter along the way.” It works with renters who want to become homeowners by buying the home they want and renting it back to them for three years “while [they build] the savings needed to own it themselves.”</p>
<p>Rather than buy homes and look for renters, the company does the opposite. Customers pick out a home and Divvy purchases it on their behalf with the renter contributing an initial 1-2 percent of the home value. They move in at closing, and pay one monthly amount. Part of that money is a “market-rate” rent and about 25 percent goes toward building up their savings in the house so they can put a down payment (estimated at 10 percent value of the home) on to purchase from Divvy later. The renters can choose to cash out their equity or purchase the home before the three years are up, if they choose. They also have the option to re-up their contract if needed, to take a bit longer to save up for a larger down payment.</p>
<p>Divvy  started buying homes in the first half of 2018 and so far, the company is seeing nearly half of those renters buying back the homes.</p>
<p>“Even the most experienced players in the space, maybe have low single-digit buyback rates so it’s definitely quite a bit higher than what the rest of the industry is seeing,” Hefets told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>When it first started out, the prices of the homes it bought averaged around $140,000 to $150,000. Now the average home prices are more like just over $200,000, she said.</p>
<p>While Divvy’s mission involves wanting to make homeownership more accessible, Hefets points out that it’s a lucrative business model as well.</p>
<p>“The number of people who fall outside of the traditional mortgage box is growing,” she added, with more people struggling to be able to purchase a home.</p>
<h2>Investor POV</h2>
<p>Andreessen Horowitz General Partner Alex Rampell led the first investment in Divvy. He recognizes that from the consumer perspective, it’s difficult to be able to save for a down payment “when you’re throwing away money on rent every month.”</p>
<p>“A huge number of people want to become homeowners but just can’t,” he said.</p>
<p>Rampell also appreciates that its model is not as speculative as the typical investor approach of first buying a home and then renting it out.</p>
<p>“So they’re not spending the first nine months after purchasing a home looking for a tenant,” he said. “They’re not speculating on an empty house and worrying what happens if they buy a home and can’t rent it out.”</p>
<p>For Tiger Global Partner Scott Shleifer, what Divvy has accomplished is “phenomenal.”</p>
<p>“Over the next ten years we believe they could help over one hundred thousand families become financially responsible homeowners,” he said in a written statement.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Divvy plans to use its fresh capital in part to expand to more markets with the lofty goal of serving more than 70 million Americans in over 20 markets by year’s end beyond cities such as Atlanta, Denver, Dallas and Tampa. The 80-person company also plans to take its offering a step further by launching ancillary product offerings to take buyers throughout the home buying journey. It already helps customers through title &amp; escrow, inspections, negotiating and repairs. But ultimately, Divvy wants to “create a complete end-to-end experience” from providing realtors to serving as a lender, according to Hefets.</p>
<p>“That’s our bigger vision,” she said. “We’re not there yet.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/divvy-homes-secures-110m-series-c-to-help-renters-become-homeowners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107000</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adobe expands Acrobat Web, adds PDF text and image editing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/adobe-expands-acrobat-web-adds-pdf-text-and-image-editing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/adobe-expands-acrobat-web-adds-pdf-text-and-image-editing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 14:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acrobat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe Creative Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer graphics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PDF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106906</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For the longest time, Acrobat was Adobe&#8217;s flagship desktop app for working with &#8212; and especially editing &#8212; PDFs. In recent years, the company launched Acrobat on the web, but it was never quite as fully featured as the desktop version, and one capability a lot of users were looking for, editing text and images [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For the longest time, Acrobat was Adobe&#8217;s flagship desktop app for working with &#8212; and especially editing &#8212; PDFs. In recent years, the company launched Acrobat on the web, but it was never quite as fully featured as the desktop version, and one capability a lot of users were looking for, editing text and images in PDFs, remained a desktop-only feature. That&#8217;s changing. With its latest update to Acrobat on the web, Adobe is bringing exactly this ability to its online service.</p>
<p>&#8220;[Acrobat Web] is strategically important to us because we have more and more people working in the browser,&#8221; Todd Gerber, Adobe&#8217;s VP for Document Cloud, told me. &#8220;Their day begins by logging into whether it&#8217;s G Suite or Microsoft Office 365. And so we want to be in all the surfaces where people are doing their work.&#8221; The team first launched the ability to create and convert PDFs, but as Gerber noted, it took a while to get to the point where being able to edit PDFs in a performant and real-time way was possible. &#8220;We could have done it earlier, but it wouldn&#8217;t have been up to the standards of being fast, nimble and quality.&#8221; He specifically noted that working with fonts was one of the more difficult problems the team faced in bringing this capability online.</p>
<p>He also noted that even though we tend to think of PDF as an Adobe format, it is an open standard and lots of third-party tools can create PDFs. That large ecosystem, with the potential for variations between implementations, also makes it more difficult to offer editing capabilities for Adobe.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/cJcaS3-ejb0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>With today&#8217;s launch, Adobe is also introducing a couple of additional browser-based features: protecting PDFs, splitting them into two and merging multiple PDFs. In addition, after working with Google last year to offer a handful of Acrobat shortcuts using the .new domain, Adobe is now launching a set of new shortcuts like <a href="http://EditPDF.new">EditPDF.new</a>. The company plans to roll out more of these over the course of the next year.</p>
<p>In total, Adobe says, the company saw about 10 million clicks on its existing shortcuts, which just goes to show how many people try to convert or sign PDFs every day.</p>
<p>As Gerber noted, a lot of potential users don&#8217;t necessarily think of Acrobat first. Instead, what they want to do is compress a PDF or convert it. Acrobat Web and the .new domains help the company bring a new audience to the platform, he believes. &#8220;It&#8217;s unlocking a new audience for us that didn&#8217;t initially think of Adobe. They think about PDFs, they think about what they need to do with them,&#8221; he said. &#8220;So it&#8217;s allowing us to expand our customer base by being relevant in the way that they&#8217;re looking to discover and ultimately transact. Our journey with Acrobat web actually started with that notion: let&#8217;s go after the non-branded searches.&#8221;</p>
<p>Adobe, of course, funnels to the Acrobat desktop app all branded searches where users are explicitly looking for Acrobat, but for the more casual user, it brings them to Acrobat Web where they can easily perform whatever action they came for without even signing up for the service.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/adobe-expands-acrobat-web-adds-pdf-text-and-image-editing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106906</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Omnispace raises $60M to fuse satellites and 5G into one ubiquitous network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/omnispace-raises-60m-to-fuse-satellites-and-5g-into-one-ubiquitous-network/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/omnispace-raises-60m-to-fuse-satellites-and-5g-into-one-ubiquitous-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 14:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fortress investment group]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[5G has been on a tear the last few years as wireless operators and smartphone manufacturers have made a marketing push touting higher bandwidth and lower latency for users. Yet, for all the attention that 5G gets from consumers, some of the most important new applications for the next-generation wireless technology are actually on the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">5G has been on a tear the last few years as wireless operators and smartphone manufacturers have made a marketing push touting higher bandwidth and lower latency for users. Yet, for all the attention that 5G gets from consumers, some of the most important new applications for the next-generation wireless technology are actually on the enterprise side. The canonical example is self-driving cars, which will presumably rely on a combination of edge computing, low latency and high bandwidth in order to work.</p>
<p>Yet, there are far more applications that are perhaps even more interesting and more readily deployable today than AVs. On farms, connectivity can help with managing equipment, monitoring livestock, and analyzing water usage to optimize plant growth. Logistics companies need to monitor global supply chains, tracking shipping containers as they wend their way around the world from port to port.</p>
<p>There’s just one problem: 5G wireless is hard to implement in rural areas where base stations are unprofitable to deploy and therefore few and far between. On the oceans of course, there are no wireless base stations at all.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>DC-based <a href="https://omnispace.com">Omnispace</a> wants to offer ubiquitous 5G-compliant connectivity for enterprise users using a hybrid of wireless ground technology and satellites. The idea is that by integrating these two different modes — terrestrial and space — into one cohesive package, end users like agriculture and logistics companies wouldn’t have to transition their IoT connectivity between different types of technologies in order to secure the promise of 5G.</p>
<p>Today, the company announced a $60 million equity investment led by Joshua Pack of Fortress Investment Group, who serves as the burgeoning firm’s head of credit investing and also <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/fortress-investment-group-spac-fortress-value-files-for-a-%24300-million-ipo-2020-03-06">co-leads one of the firm’s SPACs</a>, Fortress Value Acquisition. Existing investors Columbia Capital, Greenspring Associates, TDF Ventures and Telcom Ventures also participated in the round.</p>
<p>Omnispace started in 2012 as a holding company for wireless spectrum assets, particularly around the 2Ghz “S band” spectrum, which were purchased from the remnants of ICO Global, a satellite-based provider that had previously gone into bankruptcy. CEO Ram Viswanathan, who joined Omnispace in early 2016, said that the company started looking at how to use a technology layer to integrate its various assets together, eventually identifying an opportunity around global 5G connectivity with specific applications in IoT.</p>
<p>“The 5G rollout is going to be gated by the scope and rollout of mobile operators,” Viswanathan said. “Neither all of the landmass or customers are going to be covered” using traditional ground-based wireless technology. “Satellite’s main utility is really extending the reach of the network into more remote and rural areas.”</p>
<p>Viswanathan has spent decades in the satellite and wireless market, most recently as the co-founder of Devas Multimedia, an India-focused connectivity startup that has been embroiled in <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/nclt-admits-antrix-petition-to-wind-up-devas-multimedia-7156600/">a long-running legal spat with the government there over the cancelation of the firm’s satellite launch</a>, with U.S. courts recently ordering a government-affiliated commercialization business to <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/us-court-asks-isros-commerical-arm-to-pay-12-billion-compensation-to-bengaluru-start-up/article32979594.ece">pay Devas $1.2 billion in compensation</a>.</p>
<p>While there is perhaps an easy comparable with SpaceX’s <a href="https://www.starlink.com">Starlink</a> project, Omnispace is not focused on the consumer broadband market, but rather enterprise and IoT use cases. Furthermore, Omnispace is a hybrid network using a mix of different technologies, whereas Starlink is focused only on space deployment.</p>
<p>Omnispace is using its new capital from Fortress to flesh out its services and finish up pilot trials with some mobile operators and prepare the network for commercial usage starting in 2023, with the network ready in 2022. Viswanathan said that “our aim is to provide the service globally” with “a footprint that covers everywhere.”</p>
<p>Omnispace has contracted with Thales Alenia, part of the French space and defense conglomerate Thales Group, to execute on its space strategy. On the terrestrial side, it is tying together its spectrum assets and piloting with several mobile operators to bring out a cohesive solution, with early strength in Asia-Pacific and Latin America.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/omnispace-raises-60m-to-fuse-satellites-and-5g-into-one-ubiquitous-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106946</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Folx Health raises $25 million for virtual clinical offerings and care for the LGBTQIA+ community</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/folx-health-raises-25-million-for-virtual-clinical-offerings-and-care-for-the-lgbtqia-community/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/folx-health-raises-25-million-for-virtual-clinical-offerings-and-care-for-the-lgbtqia-community/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connecticut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Define Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delaware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Erectile Dysfunction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[massachusetts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north carolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polaris venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spora health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virginia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Folx Health is leveraging the explosion of virtual care services to offer greater access to healthcare focused on the needs of the LGBTQIA+ community, and has raised $25 million in new funding to help it grow. It&#8217;s part of a revolution in care that&#8217;s targeting the needs of specific communities with access to physicians that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://folxhealth.com/">Folx Health</a> is leveraging the explosion of virtual care services to offer greater access to healthcare focused on the needs of the LGBTQIA+ community, and has raised $25 million in new funding to help it grow.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s part of a revolution in care that&#8217;s targeting the needs of specific communities with access to physicians that understand those needs. And it&#8217;s all made possible by virtual interactions.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We have a good sense of the nature of the need and the depth of the pain in the community,&#8221; said A.G. Breitenstein, the founder and chief executive of Folx Health. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;As a non-binary lesbian and healthcare industry veteran, I have seen and experienced firsthand just how broken the current system is for the queer and trans community,” </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Breitenstein said Folx would be using the cash to try and expand to all fifty states and increase the available products and services the healthcare company would look to make available to the queer and trans community.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Whether it’s HRT, PrEP, sexual health or family creation, health care is essential for us to be who we are. It’s about time we build a platform for ourselves, so Queer and Trans people feel seen, heard, and celebrated,” she said in a statement. </span></p>
<p>That was one reason why Bessemer Venture Partners leapt at the chance to lead the new financing round for Folx, according to Morgan Cheatham, an investor out of Bessemer&#8217;s New York office. The other was the size of the market.</p>
<p>&#8220;At a high level, 2% of the population identify as transgender,&#8221; said Cheatham. &#8220;At that math, when we looked at that, we were able to see a multibillion dollar market opportunity not just to provide [hormone replacement therapy], but to provide a healthcare destination for this community.&#8221;</p>
<p>Telescoping out to the opportunity to provide care to the LGBTQ community broadly, when that population represents about 10% to 20% of the population is a &#8220;deca-billion opportunity,&#8221; said Cheatham.</p>
<p>Breitenstein envisions offering family planning services, broad primary care, and sexual health and wellness care in addition to the hormone therapies that the company currently offers.</p>
<p>Folx joins a cohort of companies tackling health issues specifically for the LGBTQIA+ community which include the mental healthcare service, <a href="https://www.joinviolet.com/">Violet</a>; <a href="https://www.includedhealth.com/">Included Health</a>, an employee benefit service; and<a href="https://getplume.co/"> Plume</a>, which focuses on care for the transgender community.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We believed in the vision and the approach that she’s taking. She&#8217;s building a healthcare experience that is celebratory and dignified rather than one that pathologizing healthcare,&#8221; said Cheatham. </span></p>
<p>For Bessemer and Cheatham, the investment speaks to broader opportunities to identify specific populations that need care tailored to their specific experience. That includes companies like <a href="https://www.sporahealth.com/">Spora Health</a> and <a href="https://www.livechair.co/">Live Chair Health</a>, which focus on providing healthcare specifically to people of color.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Our individual identities whether it be socioeconomic status, race, gender… All of these things inform how we interface with the medical industrial complex,&#8221; Cheatham said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Previous investors </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Define Ventures and Polaris Venture Partners will also participate in the round, which follows quickly on the heels of Folx&#8217;s launch from stealth in December 2020. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For its patients, Folx Health is offering Hormone Replacement Therapy (HRT: testosterone or estrogen) with monthly plans starting at $59 a month. Folx Health will also begin releasing its sexual health and wellness offerings starting with Erectile Dysfunction (ED) treatment, soon to be followed by at-home STI Testing and Treatment, all customized for the specifics of Queer and Trans bodies, the company said.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">T</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">he services will include unlimited on-demand clinical support with at-home lab testing (for most plans) and home-delivered medications (costs may vary based on medication). The company&#8217;s services are now available in California, Connecticut, Delaware, Florida, Illinois, Massachusetts, North Carolina, New York, Texas, Virginia, and Washington.</span></p>
<p>The company is also launching a Folx Library, which will serve as a content hub and resource for Queer and Trans health, written by Folx clinicians and its broader community.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our partnership with Folx is a historical moment. It’s challenging to articulate how transformative Folx is for our community. We do so mindful of the brilliant and brave Queer and Trans people who fought for this moment to happen,” said Cheatham in a statement.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/folx-health-raises-25-million-for-virtual-clinical-offerings-and-care-for-the-lgbtqia-community/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107172</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buy now, pay later to be regulated in the UK</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/buy-now-pay-later-to-be-regulated-in-the-uk/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/buy-now-pay-later-to-be-regulated-in-the-uk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 13:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit score]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial Conduct Authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sebastian Siemiatkowski]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following a government review, the U.K.&#8217;s financial services regulator will instructed to regulate the buy now, pay later industry made popular by companies such as Klarna, and AfterPay (known as Clearpay in the U.K.). A further consultation with the industry is underway and then, when parliamentary time allows, new laws regulating buy now, pay later [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Following a government review, the U.K.&#8217;s financial services regulator will instructed to regulate the buy now, pay later industry made popular by companies such as Klarna, and AfterPay (known as Clearpay in the U.K.).</p>
<p>A further consultation with the industry is underway and then, when parliamentary time allows, new laws regulating buy now, pay later will be passed.</p>
<p>This will see the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) asked to bring in stricter controls for interest-free buy now, pay later agreements, including firms being asked to undertake more comprehensive affordability checks before lending, and ensuring customers are treated fairly, &#8220;particularly those who are vulnerable or struggling with repayments&#8221;. Until now, because the industry has been unregulated since it falls outside of other interest-bearing credit products, such as credit cards, consumers have been left with little formal recourse when things go wrong.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Many consumers do not view interest-free buy-now-pay-later as a form of credit, so do not apply the same level of scrutiny, and checks undertaken by providers tend to focus on the risk for the firm rather than how affordable it is for the customer,&#8221; says the U.K. Treasury.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.fca.org.uk/publications/corporate-documents/woolard-review-unsecured-credit">review</a>, undertaken by the FCA’s Christopher Woolar, also rightfully highlights the issue of credit checks and the lack of visibility between lenders. &#8220;Although the average transaction tends to be relatively low, shoppers can take out multiple agreements with different providers – and the Review finds it would be relatively easy to accrue around £1,000 of debt that credit reference agencies and mainstream lenders cannot see,&#8221; notes the Treasury.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6j111ZuaqV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/making-sense-of-klarna/">Making sense of Klarna</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Making sense of Klarna&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/making-sense-of-klarna/embed/#?secret=6j111ZuaqV" data-secret="6j111ZuaqV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The review also estimates that buy now, pay later in the U.K. is worth £2.7 billion ($3.7 billion), with 5 million people USING buy now, pay later since the pandemic-induced boom in online shopping, with many already in arrears from other forms of credit.</p>
<p>Up until now, interest-free buy now, pay later offered by retailers has fallen outside of U.K. regulation designed to protect consumers from credit-based financial products, something Alice Tapper, a financial campaigner in the U.K. who last June started the #regulateBuyNowPayLater campaign, previously told me is &#8220;a classic case of regulation not keeping up with tech giants&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;The consumer credit act, written back in the 1970s was not drafted with algorithms and split-second lending decisions in mind,&#8221; she explained. “What this means in practice is zero consumer protection. Consumers are given no information about risk at the point of purchase or in ads. No mention of debt collection or responsible spending. This is particularly concerning for young and vulnerable consumers, who may have no prior experience of using credit products.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Klarna, for example, has always maintained it isn&#8217;t against further regulation per se. The devil, of course, will be in the detail, which is still being worked out. “I think good regulation that’s written in a meaningful way could make sense,” Klarna CEO and co-founder Sebastian Siemiatkowski <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/making-sense-of-klarna/">told me late last year</a>. “We’re not against it at any point, as long as it makes sense, as long as it’s equal for all players in the market.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/buy-now-pay-later-to-be-regulated-in-the-uk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107168</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holded, an &#8216;ERP for small businesses&#8217;, raised €15M from Elaia, Lakestar, Nauta and Seedrocket</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/holded-an-erp-for-small-businesses-raised-e15m-from-elaia-lakestar-nauta-and-seedrocket/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/holded-an-erp-for-small-businesses-raised-e15m-from-elaia-lakestar-nauta-and-seedrocket/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 13:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107162</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Holded, a platform billing itself as an ERP aimed at small businesses, has raised a €15M Series B funding round led by VC firm Elaia, together with Lakestar, Nauta Capital and Seedrocket. Holded says it gives small business access to ERP-style planning across invoicing, accounting, sales, project management, inventory management and HR, in one dashboard. It’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.holded.com/">Holded</a>, a platform billing itself as an ERP aimed at small businesses, has raised a €15M Series B funding round led by VC firm Elaia, together with Lakestar, Nauta Capital and Seedrocket.</p>
<p>Holded says it gives small business access to ERP-style planning across invoicing, accounting, sales, project management, inventory management and HR, in one dashboard. It’s attracted 80,000 customers to date. The money will be used to grow its technology and business teams. Its product is also used by accounting firms to digitalize their businesses and become value-added resellers. It will now open an office in Paris.</p>
<p>In a statement co-founder, Javi Fondevil said: “We knew the idea of centralizing all your business in one place was very powerful and the only reason why nobody did it before was that it’s extremely hard to design an intuitive self-serve ERP for Small Businesses.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Pauline Roux, Partner at Elaia, said: “We strongly believe that the opportunity ahead to build solutions for small businesses is massive. In the case of ERPs, solutions tend to be very complex modular products and, as Small Businesses don’t have independent departments, they need an integrated and very intuitive solution. Most of the new ERPs are just doing the same as the incumbents but in the cloud. Holded developed the first ERP we have seen without modules, long implementation times or consultants needed, they’ve really changed the whole experience.” </p>
<p>The ERP startup space is hotting-up. In January Xentral, a German startup that develops enterprise resource planning software covering a variety of back-office functions for the average online small business, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/germanys-xentral-nabs-20m-led-by-sequoia-to-help-online-facing-smbs-run-back-offices-better/">picked up</a> a Series A of $20 million.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/holded-an-erp-for-small-businesses-raised-e15m-from-elaia-lakestar-nauta-and-seedrocket/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107162</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Soon Boston Dynamics’ Spot will be remotely opening doors anywhere</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/soon-boston-dynamics-spot-will-be-remotely-opening-doors-anywhere/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/soon-boston-dynamics-spot-will-be-remotely-opening-doors-anywhere/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 13:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPOT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s something difficult to reconcile watching Spot walk up a flight of stairs in some industrial setting. After years of watching viral videos of Boston Dynamics robots perform aesthetically impressive feats, there’s a banality in the quadruped performing those dull, dirty and dangerous tasks that roboticist love to talk about. But six and half months [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There’s something difficult to reconcile watching Spot walk up a flight of stairs in some industrial setting. After years of watching viral videos of Boston Dynamics robots perform aesthetically impressive feats, there’s a banality in the quadruped performing those dull, dirty and dangerous tasks that roboticist love to talk about.</p>
<p>But six and half months after the company opened Spot up for sale (and more than 400 sold, per BD), companies have been deploying the advanced piece of machinery in some downright dreary settings. Yesterday morning, I had the opportunity to pilot the robot around one of them, from the comfort of my own desk.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="x3FzdWtCJW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/following-hyundai-acquisition-boston-dynamics-ceo-discussing-the-robotics-pioneers-future/">Following Hyundai acquisition, Boston Dynamics’ CEO discusses the robotics pioneer’s future</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Following Hyundai acquisition, Boston Dynamics’ CEO discusses the robotics pioneer’s future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/following-hyundai-acquisition-boston-dynamics-ceo-discussing-the-robotics-pioneers-future/embed/#?secret=x3FzdWtCJW" data-secret="x3FzdWtCJW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This week the Hyundai-owned robotics pioneer is introducing Scout, a browser-based interface for remotely controlling the robot. The arrival will also be joined by a self-charging “Enterprise” edition of the robot and the already announced Spot Arm. All of the new hardware is available starting today through Boston Dynamics’ site (it’s one of those “call for a quote” pricing deals), though Scout will also be compatible with any version of the robot.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2106972" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2106972" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2106972" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Enterprise_Industrial_Inspection_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Enterprise_Industrial_Inspection_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg 8256w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Enterprise_Industrial_Inspection_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Enterprise_Industrial_Inspection_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Enterprise_Industrial_Inspection_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Enterprise_Industrial_Inspection_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Enterprise_Industrial_Inspection_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Enterprise_Industrial_Inspection_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Enterprise_Industrial_Inspection_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2106972" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Boston Dynamics</p></div></p>
<p>That said, the company is recommending it be paired with the self-docking Enterprise version. After all, the robot runs about 90 minutes on a charge, so if you’re intending to use it to monitor a situation without people present, that’s probably the way to go.</p>
<p>I’ve driven Spot around a few times in person &#8212; and like those, there’s a bit of a learning curve here. Boston Dynamics estimates it will take around 15 minutes to get you fully up to speed, but after a minute or two, I was able to send the robot up and down a flight of stairs at BD HQ. There are, thankfully, a whole bunch of cameras and other sensors built into the $75,000 robot to help you avoid doing something really stupid.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2106975" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2106975" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2106975" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Scout-workfromhome_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.png" alt="" width="1024" height="579" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Scout-workfromhome_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.png 1909w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Scout-workfromhome_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.png?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Scout-workfromhome_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.png?resize=300,170 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Scout-workfromhome_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.png?resize=768,434 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Scout-workfromhome_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.png?resize=680,384 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Scout-workfromhome_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.png?resize=1536,868 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Scout-workfromhome_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2106975" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Boston Dynamics</p></div></p>
<p>The system will work with Bluetooth gaming controllers, but for my demo, I was stuck with the keyboard. There’s a basic WASD control scheme that should be familiar if you’ve done any PC gaming. The arrow keys, meanwhile, can be used to switch between four cameras, giving you a view from all sides. There are a number of additional views, including a terrain mode that gives you a kind of top-down rendered view of the robot. That’s probably the best way to view all of the immediate obstacles &#8212; or better still, you can do a picture in picture to get views at once.</p>
<p>I found myself using “click to go” a lot, as well. It essentially works the way it sounds: You click on a point on the ground and Spot walks toward it. The feature is designed primarily for those with connection issues &#8212; imagine, say, you’ve got poor Spot deployed on some oil rig somewhere.</p>
<p>“[W]e have a power plant customer who had a possible equipment failure. They were able to use the robot to repeatedly inspect something that, if it failed could have been dangerous to a human inspector,” Spot’s Chief Engineer Zack Jackowski told TechCrunch. “So they logged in, checked on this pipe repeatedly and were able to avoid an expensive shut down.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2106974" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2106974" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2106974 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Arm_Industrial_Gripper_Cam_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Arm_Industrial_Gripper_Cam_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg 8256w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Arm_Industrial_Gripper_Cam_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Arm_Industrial_Gripper_Cam_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Arm_Industrial_Gripper_Cam_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Arm_Industrial_Gripper_Cam_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Arm_Industrial_Gripper_Cam_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Arm_Industrial_Gripper_Cam_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Arm_Industrial_Gripper_Cam_Credit-to-Boston-Dynamics.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2106974" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Boston Dynamics</p></div></p>
<p>There’s also a “stair mode” that positions the robot for walking up and down stairs. The feature needs to be manually toggled on and off, though the robot should be able to walk up a flight of stairs in normal mode (I did this in my demo, and didn’t appear to give anyone on staff a heart attack). For the time being, the functionality is limited to line of sight. Jackowski adds, “We have all sorts of crazy plans to extend that to building scale, but the first thing we want to get out there is line of vision.”</p>
<p>In addition to a new docking connector on the Robot’s bum, the Enterprise version will also sport an enhanced CPU and improved wireless connectivity. It will ship either as a bundle with the dock or solo.</p>
<p>Sadly, we weren’t able to take the new arm out for a spin, but Jackowski did offer some detail on that functionality, noting, “you issue the arm commands, like ‘move your hand here’ or ‘pick up this object’ or ‘turn this valve,’ and the robot’s actually smart enough to figure out, ‘hey, if I’m going to turn that valve, I need to stand over here, I need to shift my weight like this, I need to figure out how to keep the right part of my wrist limp to accommodate how that valve moves.’ ”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IYQqZeF5OM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/16/now-any-us-business-can-buy-boston-dynamics-spot-robot-for-74500/">Now any US business can buy Boston Dynamics&#8217; Spot robot for $74,500</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Now any US business can buy Boston Dynamics&#8217; Spot robot for $74,500&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/16/now-any-us-business-can-buy-boston-dynamics-spot-robot-for-74500/embed/#?secret=IYQqZeF5OM" data-secret="IYQqZeF5OM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/soon-boston-dynamics-spot-will-be-remotely-opening-doors-anywhere/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106964</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rocket startup Astra is going public via SPAC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/rocket-startup-astra-is-going-public-vis-spac/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/rocket-startup-astra-is-going-public-vis-spac/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 12:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alaska]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackRock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chris kemp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holicity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kodiak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASDAQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special-purpose acquisition company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rocket launch company Astra, which just reached space this past December with a test launch from Alaska, will be going public on the Nasdaq via a merger with a special purpose acquisition company (SPAC) called Holicity. The recent SPAC craze has already extended to the New Space sector, and Virgin Galactic was among those in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rocket launch company Astra, which just reached space this past December with a test launch from Alaska, will be going public on the Nasdaq via a merger with a special purpose acquisition company (SPAC) called Holicity. The recent SPAC craze has already extended to the New Space sector, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/08/richard-bransons-virgin-galactic-will-be-the-first-publicly-traded-company-for-human-spaceflight/">Virgin Galactic</a> was among those in this wave of a new path to public listing, so there is precedent for space launch in particular, but Astra will be the first to list on the Nasdaq.</p>
<p>The terms of the deal will result in an anticipated $500 million in cash for Astra, from a combined $200 million held by Holicity in trust and a $300 million injection via a PIPE (private investment in public equity) from funds under management by BlackRock. The arrangement sets a pro forma enterprise valuation of Astra at around $2.1 billion &#8212; the valuation of the company minus the $500 million in cash the SPAC merger brings in. Astra expects it to complete by the second quarter of this year, after which the company will trade under the ticker &#8220;ASTR.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nQdIa6koOS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/launch-startup-astras-rocket-reaches-space-for-the-first-time/">Launch startup Astra&#8217;s rocket reaches space</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Launch startup Astra&#8217;s rocket reaches space&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/launch-startup-astras-rocket-reaches-space-for-the-first-time/embed/#?secret=nQdIa6koOS" data-secret="nQdIa6koOS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Astra manufactures its own rockets, which are designed to carry small orbital payloads, at a facility in Alameda, California. Thus far, it has then shipped its launch vehicles to Kodiak, Alaska for flight – requiring just a handful of people on the ground at the actual spaceport to mount and launch the rocket, with the majority of the team overseeing the flight operating remotely out of a mission control facility back in California. The company&#8217;s model focuses on high output production of relatively inexpensive rockets, which can be responsively shipped and launched virtually anywhere depending on needs.</p>
<p>With its successful test in December, Astra achieved a pay-off of years of quiet work building and iterating its launch model. The startup was originally pursuing a DARPA-funded competition to achieve rapid response launch capabilities, but that contest expired with the prize unclaimed. The successful test in December still proved out the viability of Astra&#8217;s model – though it fell slightly short of achieving orbital velocity for actual payload delivery. The company said that this was a relatively easy remaining issue to fix, wholly manageable via software tweaks, and it intends to deliver its first commercial satellites beginning this summer.</p>
<p>Ultimately, Astra aims to be launching payloads on a daily cadency by 2025, and in a blog post accompanying the SPAC news, Astra founder and CEO Chris Kemp said that it&#8217;s also intent on &#8220;building a platform of space services&#8221; that implies ambitions beyond its work today on rockets.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Vd8RWAXwdk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/06/why-astra-built-a-space-startup-and-rocket-factory-in-silicon-valley/">Why Astra built a space startup and rocket factory in Silicon Valley</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Astra built a space startup and rocket factory in Silicon Valley&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/06/why-astra-built-a-space-startup-and-rocket-factory-in-silicon-valley/embed/#?secret=Vd8RWAXwdk" data-secret="Vd8RWAXwdk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/rocket-startup-astra-is-going-public-vis-spac/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107160</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China launched its national carbon trading market yesterday</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/china-launched-its-national-carbon-trading-market-yesterday/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/china-launched-its-national-carbon-trading-market-yesterday/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 12:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chemicals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chinese Communist Party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oil and gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shanghai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shenzhen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, China flipped the switch on a nationwide carbon trading market, in what could be one of the most significant steps taken to reduce greenhouse gas emissions in 2021 &#8212; if the markets can work effectively. China is the world&#8217;s largest emitter of greenhouse gases and its share of the world&#8217;s emissions output continues to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Yesterday, <a href="http://mee.gov.cn/xxgk2018/xxgk/xxgk02/202101/t20210105_816131.html">China flipped the switch on a nationwide carbon trading market</a>, in what could be one of the most significant steps taken to reduce greenhouse gas emissions in 2021 &#8212; if the markets can work effectively.</p>
<p>China is the <a href="https://www.ucsusa.org/resources/each-countrys-share-co2-emissions">world&#8217;s largest emitter of greenhouse gases</a> and its share of the world&#8217;s emissions output continues to climb.</p>
<p>As the Chinese government works to curb its environmental impact, policies like a carbon trading system could spur the adoption of new technologies, increasing demand for goods and services from domestic startups and tech companies around the world.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Carbon markets, implemented in some parts of the U.S. and widely across Europe, put a price on industrial emissions and force companies to offset those emissions by investing in projects that would remove an equivalent portion of greenhouse gases from the atmosphere.</p>
<p>They&#8217;re <a href="https://time.com/5748374/carbon-markets-paris-agreement/">a key component of the 2015 Paris Agreement, but they&#8217;re also a controversial one</a>. That&#8217;s because if they&#8217;re not implemented properly and managed effectively they can be a “massive loophole” for emitters, as Gilles Dufrasne, policy officer at Carbon Markets Watch, told Time last year.</p>
<p>This is especially true of China. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3010679/chinas-green-efforts-hit-fake-data-and-corruption-among-grass">Corruption in China is endemic</a> and the country has <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/07/27/chinese-communist-party-environment-co2/">long sacrificed environmental policy and stewardship at the altar of economic growth</a>. China&#8217;s not alone in making that calculus, but the decisions have happened at a scale orders of magnitude larger than almost any other nation (with the exception of the U.S.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="B5suaMrgqY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/forsaking-funding-at-a-1-billion-valuation-solugen-preps-a-new-green-chemical-product-and-a-big-2021/">Forsaking funding at a $1 billion valuation, Solugen preps a new green chemical product and a big 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Forsaking funding at a $1 billion valuation, Solugen preps a new green chemical product and a big 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/forsaking-funding-at-a-1-billion-valuation-solugen-preps-a-new-green-chemical-product-and-a-big-2021/embed/#?secret=B5suaMrgqY" data-secret="B5suaMrgqY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The efficacy of the policy is also affected by the hierarchies that exist within the bureaucracy of the Chinese Communist Party. As <a href="https://chinadialogue.net/en/climate/chinas-national-carbon-market-is-about-to-launch/">ChinaDialogue noted</a>, the measures were issued by the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, which carry lower legal authority than if they came from the NDRC, the leading governing body for macroeconomic policy across China and the overseer of the nation&#8217;s major economic initiatives.</p>
<p>That said, no country as large as China, which accounts for 28% of the world&#8217;s greenhouse gas emissions, has ever implemented a national carbon emissions trading market.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1622990" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1622990" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-1622990" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-934775218.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-934775218.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-934775218.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-934775218.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-934775218.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-934775218.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-934775218.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-934775218.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-934775218.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1622990" class="wp-caption-text">BEIJING, CHINA &#8211; MARCH 20: Chinese President Xi Jinping delivers a speech during the closing session of the National People&#8217;s Congress (NPC) at the Great Hall of the People on March 20, 2018 in Beijing, China. (Photo by Lintao Zhang/Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<p>China first started testing regional emissions trading systems back in 2011 in Shenzhen, Shanghai, Beijing, Guangdong, Tianjin, Hubei, Chongqing and Fujian. Using a system that instituted caps on emissions based on carbon intensity (emissions per unit of GDP) rather than an absolute emissions cap, the Chinese government began rolling out these pilots across its power sector and to other industries.</p>
<p>After a restructuring in 2018, the plan, which was initially drafted under the auspices of the National Development and Reform Commission, was kicked down to the Ministry of Ecology and the Environment. The devolution of China&#8217;s cap and trade emissions program came as the United States was withdrawing from the Paris Agreement amid an abdication of climate regulation or initiatives under the presidency of Donald Trump.</p>
<div class="wp-block-cd-story-image block--story-image">
<div class="block--story-image__column">
<div class="block--story-image__content">
<div class="block--story-image__caption">Initially intended to begin with trading simulations in 2020, China&#8217;s emissions schemes were derailed by the COVID-19 pandemic and pushed back to the back half of the year with an implementation of actual trading starting yesterday.</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>For now, the emissions trading system covers China&#8217;s power industry and roughly 2,000 energy generation facilities. That alone represents 30% of the nation&#8217;s total emissions and over time the trading system will encompass heavy industry like cement, steel, aluminum, chemicals and oil and gas, <a href="https://chinadialogue.net/en/climate/chinas-national-carbon-market-is-about-to-launch/">according to ChinaDialogue</a>.</p>
<p>Initially, the government is allocating emissions allowances for free and will begin auctioning allowances &#8220;at the appropriate time according to the situation.&#8221;</p>
<p>That kind of language, and concerns raised by state-owned enterprises and financial services firms flagging the effect carbon pricing could have on profitability and lending risk, shows that the government in Beijing is still putting more weight on the economic benefits rather than environmental costs of much of its industrial growth.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E4nNnczhQb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/the-biggest-step-the-biden-administration-took-on-climate-yesterday-wasnt-rejoining-the-paris-agreement/">The biggest step the Biden administration took on climate yesterday wasn&#8217;t rejoining the Paris Agreement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The biggest step the Biden administration took on climate yesterday wasn&#8217;t rejoining the Paris Agreement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/the-biggest-step-the-biden-administration-took-on-climate-yesterday-wasnt-rejoining-the-paris-agreement/embed/#?secret=E4nNnczhQb" data-secret="E4nNnczhQb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That said, a survey of market participants cited by ChinaDialogue indicated that prices are expected to start at 41 yuan (US$6.3) per ton of CO2 and rise to 66 yuan per ton in 2025. The price of carbon in China is expected to hit 77 yuan by 2030.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a commission on carbon prices formed in 2017 and helmed by the economists Joseph Stiglitz and Nicholas Stern indicated that carbon needed to be priced at somewhere between $40 and $80 by 2020 and somewhere in the $50 to $100 range by 2030 if the markets and prices were to have any impact on behavior.</p>
<p>No nation has actually hit those price targets, although the European Union has come the closest &#8212; and seen the most reduction in greenhouse gas emissions as a result.</p>
<p>Still, the plan from the Chinese government does include public reporting requirements for verified company-level emissions. And the existence of a market, if the government decides to put real prices in place, and consequences for flouting the system, could be a huge boon for the monitoring and management equipment startups that are developing tech to track emissions.</p>
<p>As the analysts at ChinaDialogue note:</p>
<blockquote><p>The hardest part of carbon pricing is often getting it started. The moment that the Chinese government decides to increase ambition with the national ETS, it can. The mechanism is now in place, and it can be ramped up if the momentum and political will provided by President Xi’s climate ambition continues. In the coming years, this could see an absolute and decreasing cap, more sectors covered, more transparent data provision and more effective cross-government coordination. This is especially so with energy and industrial regulators who will need to see the ETS not as a threat to their turf, but as a measure with significant co-benefits for their own policy objectives.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/china-launched-its-national-carbon-trading-market-yesterday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107123</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oyster snaps up $20M for its HR platform aimed at distributed workforces</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/oyster-snaps-up-20m-for-its-hr-platform-aimed-at-distributed-workforces/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/oyster-snaps-up-20m-for-its-hr-platform-aimed-at-distributed-workforces/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 11:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contractors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distributed workforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emergence Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oyster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote working]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The growth of remote working and managing workforces that are distributed well beyond the confines of a centralized physical office &#8212; or even a single country &#8212; have put a spotlight on the human resources technology that organizations use to help manage those people. Today, one of the HR startups that&#8217;s been seeing a surge [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">The growth of remote working and managing workforces that are distributed well beyond the confines of a centralized physical office &#8212; or even a single country &#8212; have put a spotlight on the human resources technology that organizations use to help manage those people. Today, one of the HR startups that&#8217;s been seeing a surge of growth is announcing a round of funding to double down on its business.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.oysterhr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oyster</a>, a startup and platform that helps companies through the process of hiring, onboarding and then providing contractors and full-time employees in the area  of &#8220;knowledge work&#8221; with HR services like payroll, benefits and salary management, has closed a Series A round of $20 million.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The company is already working in 100 countries, and CEO and Tony Jamous (who co-founded the company with Jack Mardack) said in an interview that the plan is to expand that list of markets, and also bring in new services, particularly to address the opportunity in emerging markets to hire more people.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">Currently, Oyster does not cover candidate sourcing or any of the interviewing and evaluation process: those could be areas where it might build its own tech or partner to provide them as part of its one-stop shop. It has dabbled in virtual job fairs, as a pointer to one potential product that it might explore.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;There are 1.5 billion knowledge workers coming into the workforce in the next 10 years, mostly from emerging economies, while in developed economies there are some 90 million jobs unfilled,&#8221; Jamous said. &#8220;There are super powers you can gain from being globally distributed, but it poses a major challenge around HR and payroll.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Emergence Capital, the B2B VC that has backed the likes of Zoom, Salesforce, Bill.com and our former sister site Crunchbase, is leading the funding. The Slack Fund (Slack&#8217;s strategic investment vehicle) and London firm Connect Ventures (which has previously backed the company at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/connect-ventures-three/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">seed stage</a>) are also participating. The investment will accelerate <span class="il">Oyster</span>’s rapid growth, and support its mission of enabling people to work from anywhere.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vaIch6UrvC"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/connect-ventures-three/">Connect Ventures outs $80M third fund to back &#8216;product-led&#8217; seed-stage founders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Connect Ventures outs $80M third fund to back &#8216;product-led&#8217; seed-stage founders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/connect-ventures-three/embed/#?secret=vaIch6UrvC" data-secret="vaIch6UrvC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p dir="ltr">Oyster&#8217;s valuation is not being disclosed. The startup has raised about $24 million to date.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">One of the great ironies of the global health pandemic is that while our worlds have become much smaller &#8212; travel and even local activities have been drastically curtailed, and many of us spend day in, day out at home &#8212; the employment opportunity and scope of how organizations are expected to operate has become significantly bigger. </span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Public health-enforced remote working has led to companies de-coupling workers from offices, and that has opened the door to seeking out and working with the best talent, regardless of location.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">This predicament may have become more acute in the last year, but it&#8217;s been one that has been gradually coming into focus for years, helped by trends in cloud computing and globalization. Jamous said that the idea for Oyster that came to him was something he&#8217;s been thinking about for years, but became more apparent when he was still at his previous startup, Nexmo &#8212; the cloud communications provider that was <a href="https://www.prnewswire.co.uk/news-releases/vonage-holdings-corp-to-acquire-nexmo-inc-second-largest-cpaas-company-globally-578242471.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">acquired by Vonage for $230 million</a> in in 2016. </span></p>
<p dir="ltr">At Nexmo we wanted to be a great local employer. We were headquartered in two countries but wanted to have people everywhere,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We spent millions building employment infrastructure to do that, becoming knowledgeable about local laws in France, Korea and more countries.&#8221; He realized quickly that this was a highly inefficient way to work. &#8220;We weren’t ready for the complexity and diversity of issues that would come up.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr">After he moved on from Nexmo and did some angel investing (he backs other distributed work juggernauts like Hopin, among others), he decided that he would try to tackle the workforce challenge as the focus of his next venture.</p>
<p dir="ltr">That was in mid-2019, pre-pandemic. It turned out that the timing was spot on, with every organization looking in the next year at ways to address their own distributed workforce challenges.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The emerging market focus, meanwhile, also has a direct link to Jamous himself: He left his home country of Lebanon to study in France when he was 17, and has essentially lived abroad since then. But as with many people who move from developed into emerging markets, he knew that the base of technical talent in his home country was something that was worth tapping and nurturing to help residents and the countries themselves improve their lots in life; and he thought he could use tech to help there, too.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span class="il">Related to that wider social mission, Oyster</span> has a pending application to become a B-Corporation.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Jamous is not the only one that has founded an HR company based on his personal experience: Turing&#8217;s founders have cited their own backgrounds growing up in India and working with people remotely from there as part of their own impetus for building Turing; and Remote&#8217;s founder hails from Europe but built GitLab (where he had been head of product) based on a similar premise of tapping into the talent he knew existed all around the world.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And indeed, Oyster is not alone in tackling this opportunity. The list of HR startups looking to be the ADPs of the world of distributed work include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/deel-nabs-30m-more-for-payroll-compliance-and-other-tools-to-run-global-workforces/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Deel</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/remote-raises-35m-to-help-orgs-with-global-workforce-payroll-benefits-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Remote</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/hibob-raises-70m-on-a-500m-valuation-for-its-new-take-on-hr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hibob</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/papaya-global-raises-40m-for-a-payroll-and-hr-platform-aimed-at-global-workforces/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Papaya Global</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/personio-raises-125m-on-a-1-7b-valuation-for-an-hr-platform-targeting-smes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Personio</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/factorial-raises-16m-to-take-on-the-hr-world-with-a-platform-for-smbs/">Factorial</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/lattice-a-people-management-platform-picks-up-45m-at-a-400m-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lattice</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/turing-nabs-32m-more-for-an-ai-based-platform-to-source-and-manage-engineers-remotely/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Turing</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/rippling-nabs-145m-at-a-1-35b-valuation-to-build-out-its-all-in-one-platform-for-employee-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rippling</a>. And these are just some of the HR startups that have raised money in the last year; there are many, many more.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xZzM0D6PNX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/rippling-nabs-145m-at-a-1-35b-valuation-to-build-out-its-all-in-one-platform-for-employee-data/">Rippling nabs $145M at a $1.35B valuation to build out its all-in-one platform for employee data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rippling nabs $145M at a $1.35B valuation to build out its all-in-one platform for employee data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/rippling-nabs-145m-at-a-1-35b-valuation-to-build-out-its-all-in-one-platform-for-employee-data/embed/#?secret=xZzM0D6PNX" data-secret="xZzM0D6PNX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p dir="ltr">The attraction of Oyster seems to come in the simplicity of how the services are provided &#8212; you have options for contractors and full-timers, and full, larger staff deployments in other countries. You have options to add benefits for employees if you choose. And you have some tools to work out how hires fit into your bigger budgets, and also to guide you on remuneration in each local market. Pricing ranges from $29 per person, per month for contractors, to $399 for working with full employees, to other packages for larger deployments.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Oyster works with local partners to provide some aspects of these services, but it has built the technology to make the process seamless for the customer. As with other services, it essentially handles the employment and payroll as a local provider on behalf of its customers, but can do so under contract terms that reconcile both a company&#8217;s own policies and those of the local jurisdictions (which can differ widely between each other in areas like vacation time, redundancy terms, maternity leave and more).</p>
<p>&#8220;It has a few well-funded competitors, but that’s usually a good signal,&#8221; said Jason Green, the Emergence partner who led its investment. &#8220;But you want to bet on the horse that will lead the race, and that comes down to execution. Here, we are b<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">etting on a team that’s done it before, an entrepreneur experienced in building a company and selling it. Tony&#8217;s made money and knows how to build a business. But more than that, he&#8217;s </span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">mission driven and that will matter in the space, and to employees.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/oyster-snaps-up-20m-for-its-hr-platform-aimed-at-distributed-workforces/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107124</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter quietly rolls out Revue newsletters shortcut on web</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/twitter-quietly-rolls-out-revue-newsletters-integration-on-web/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/twitter-quietly-rolls-out-revue-newsletters-integration-on-web/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 10:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[publishing tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you were itching to launch an email newsletter via Twitter following its acquisition of the Dutch newsletter platform Revue last month, you&#8217;ll have to wait a bit longer for a fully featured integration. But Twitter has quietly added a newsletter link to its web app &#8212; pointing users of its social network to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you were itching to launch an email newsletter via Twitter following its acquisition of the Dutch newsletter platform Revue <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">last month</a>, you&#8217;ll have to wait a bit longer for a fully featured integration. But Twitter has quietly added a newsletter link to its web app &#8212; pointing users of its social network to the publishing platform.</p>
<p>The company told us the two platforms remain separate for now &#8212; meaning those wanting to sign up for a Twitter-owned Revue newsletter can still create a separate (Revue) account to do so (albeit, Revue does also offer a sign-in via Twitter option). So it&#8217;s the first baby step on the path toward any future, deeper integration.</p>
<p>New sign-ups for Revue&#8217;s Publisher-tier paid newsletters also remain on pause for now.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>T<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">witter confirmed it&#8217;s reverted Revue&#8217;s Publisher offer back to private beta for the moment </span>while it concentrates on investing in platform infrastructure to pave the way for expected future demand.</p>
<p>The paid tier will offer more advanced features such as the ability to manage multiple newsletters and customize themes.</p>
<p>Twitter was unable to provide a timeline for when that tier of newsletters will be open for new sign-ups again. But<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> it said it&#8217;s still possible to create a paid newsletter under the free newsletter tier via Revue&#8217;s platform. </span></p>
<p>One change it has made already is to lower the fee Revue takes for paid newsletters &#8212; to 5%.</p>
<p>It also told us it&#8217;s merged the original Free and Pro tiers that Revue had been offering prior to the acquisition &#8212; meaning the free Revue tier is now a little more fully featured.</p>
<p>The addition of a link to &#8220;Newsletters&#8221; in the &#8220;More&#8221; tab of Twitter&#8217;s web app was spotted earlier by a few eagle-eyed users &#8212; including our very own editor-in-chief, Matthew Panzarino.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">setting up my twtrevue <a href="https://t.co/VTAZPFSCTY">pic.twitter.com/VTAZPFSCTY</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Matthew Panzarino (@panzer) <a href="https://twitter.com/panzer/status/1356367183425667072?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 1, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>If you click on the Newsletter link it leads to a pop-up encouraging Twitter users to set up a free newsletter to reach their audience, flagging features such as the ability to embed tweets, import email lists, analyze engagement and earn money from subscribers.</p>
<p>A big &#8220;Find out more&#8221; button links through directly to Revue&#8217;s platform.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107127" style="width: 1510px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107127" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2107127 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/revue-twitter-2.jpg" alt="" width="1500" height="934" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/revue-twitter-2.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/revue-twitter-2.jpg?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/revue-twitter-2.jpg?resize=300,187 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/revue-twitter-2.jpg?resize=768,478 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/revue-twitter-2.jpg?resize=680,423 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/revue-twitter-2.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107127" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Unless you&#8217;ve been on a very long digital detox you&#8217;ll have noticed that newsletters have been having quite the moment of late. The rise of platforms that help writers monetize their content via an email-delivery format presents a clear risk/opportunity to Twitter, a company that relies on an army of users freely and publicly contributing short-form content.</p>
<p>But with Twitter launching its own in-house newsletter, tweets can potentially inflate in value &#8212; becoming the top of the funnel for Twitter users to build a community of followers who they made be able to convert to paying subscribers for longer-form content, delivered in a newsletter format.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HiwNWoHQEn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">Twitter acquires newsletter platform Revue</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter acquires newsletter platform Revue&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/embed/#?secret=HiwNWoHQEn" data-secret="HiwNWoHQEn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Twitter told us it has put on ice new sign-ups to the paid Revue tier so it can focus on improving infrastructure to effectively meet the demand of new customers and make Revue an even more powerful tool for publishers.</p>
<p>It added that it&#8217;s <span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">working quickly to roll out a new version of the paid Publisher tier of the newsletter tool that&#8217;s open to new customers, pointing to a mailing list for interested parties to sign up to get the latest updates (<a href="https://www.getrevue.co/publisher" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.getrevue.co/publisher&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1612345241390000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFaQtBNNX_JiUCkksom8APbhnhz7w">here</a>).</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iXxeztrShb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/twitter-is-already-working-on-integrating-newsletters-on-its-site-following-revue-acquisition/">Twitter is already working on integrating newsletters on its site, following Revue acquisition</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter is already working on integrating newsletters on its site, following Revue acquisition&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/twitter-is-already-working-on-integrating-newsletters-on-its-site-following-revue-acquisition/embed/#?secret=iXxeztrShb" data-secret="iXxeztrShb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/twitter-is-already-working-on-integrating-newsletters-on-its-site-following-revue-acquisition/">Last month </a>we reported Twitter had been spotted working to integrate the newsletter into its platform, so it appears to be moving at a clip to get Revue plugged in and capitalize on the hype and momentum around paid newsletters. Albeit, it&#8217;s prioritising infrastructure investment over any deeper integration for now &#8212; and told us it&#8217;s still brainstorming how that might work in practice. So it sounds like there&#8217;s a way to go.</p>
<p>Preventing Twitter users from finding a home for their longer-form thoughts elsewhere is likely front of mind for Twitter &#8212; as competition for attention in the social sphere heats up, such as from the likes of (rival) newsletter platform <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/16/substack-series-a/">Substack</a> (which has been building momentum since <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/16/substack-sinocism-launch/">2017</a>); and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/clubhouse-announces-plans-for-creator-payments-and-raises-new-funding-led-by-andreessen-horowitz/">buzzy live-voice chat app Clubhouse</a> (which has recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/31/elon-musk-goes-live-on-clubhouse-but-with-the-room-full-fans-stream-audio-on-youtube/">captivated the clique-loving technorati</a>).</p>
<p>The current integration on Twitter&#8217;s web app can be found under the three-dot “More” menu option in the sidebar &#8212; which brings up a prompt to &#8220;Find out more&#8221;.</p>
<p>Twitter noted that features it flags up there &#8212; such as the ability to drag and drop tweets to embed them &#8212; were already offered by Revue.</p>
<p>The Revue newsletter platform, which competes with, among others <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/16/substack-series-a/">Andreessen Horowitz-backed Substack</a>, maintains integration support for a number of third-party services, including Facebook, Instagram, Pocket, Product Hunt, Instapaper and even RSS feeds. Once users have integrated these services, they can drag and drop stories from those feeds to the newsletter.</p>
<p>In the current avatar, users can manually add email addresses of subscribers, or import a list from Mailchimp or a CSV file. On the welcome screen, which noted reverse engineer <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/twitter-is-already-working-on-integrating-newsletters-on-its-site-following-revue-acquisition/">Jane Manchun Wong first spotted last week</a>, Twitter also advertises that its newsletter can help writers and publishers earn money from paid subscribers.</p>
<p>Revue&#8217;s platform also lets users schedule their newsletters.</p>
<p>It remains to be seen what additional features Twitter will be bringing to the platform.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We imagine a number of integrations on Twitter that will help readers more easily discover and connect with writers &#8212; from easy ways to subscribe to a newsletter to new settings for writers to host conversations with subscribers.</p>
<p>&mdash; Mike Park (@mep) <a href="https://twitter.com/mep/status/1354036614809464832?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><em>This report was updated with a number of corrections after we received additional information from Twitter to clarify that the web app integration only extends to displaying a shortcut in the tab at this point. The two platforms remain separate &#8212; so any deeper integration is yet to come. </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nzOufdwaYB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/will-this-time-be-any-different-for-twitter/">Will this time be any different for Twitter?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will this time be any different for Twitter?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/will-this-time-be-any-different-for-twitter/embed/#?secret=nzOufdwaYB" data-secret="nzOufdwaYB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/twitter-quietly-rolls-out-revue-newsletters-integration-on-web/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107115</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seyna is building an insurance-as-a-service startup for the French market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/seyna-is-building-an-insurance-as-a-service-startup-for-the-french-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/seyna-is-building-an-insurance-as-a-service-startup-for-the-french-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 09:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seyna]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Seyna is getting a new CEO. Stephen Leguillon is joining the company as chief executive while Philippe Mangematin is stepping back from day-to-day activities for personal reasons — he’ll become honorary chairman. If you’re not familiar with the company, Seyna is an insurtech startup that has obtained an insurance license focused on property [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.seyna.eu">Seyna</a> is getting a new CEO. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephen-leguillon-67001937/">Stephen Leguillon</a> is joining the company as chief executive while Philippe Mangematin is stepping back from day-to-day activities for personal reasons — he’ll become honorary chairman.</p>
<p>If you’re not familiar with the company, Seyna is an insurtech startup that has obtained an insurance license focused on property and casualty. This is a significant move as the French regulator (ACPR) hasn’t handed out a new license in this category since 1983.</p>
<p>The company’s go-to-market strategy is also interesting as it doesn’t sell insurance products to consumers directly. Instead, the company is building out insurance-as-a-service products. It partners with other companies that offer Seyna’s insurance products under their own brands.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Behind the scenes, Seyna offers an API to generate insurance contracts on demand — an API is a programming interface that lets two services interact with each other. You can also connect directly to Seyna’s interface to manage contracts.</p>
<p>Seyna has created its own core insurance system, which is an important differentiating factor compared to legacy players. The startup can generate many different variants that cover around 20 different insurance products — pet insurance, ticket cancelation, rent guarantee, etc. Clients include Garantme and Decathlon.</p>
<p>The company’s new CEO Stephen Leguillon previous co-founded La Belle Assiette, a company that lets you hire a chef for a dinner at home and that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/la-belle-assiette/">I covered</a> on TechCrunch. He added a second product called GoCater, a corporate catering service — GoCater was letter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/18/gocater-spins-out-from-la-belle-assiette-to-build-a-corporate-catering-marketplace/">spun out</a> from La Belle Assiette and acquired by ezCater.</p>
<p>Seyna has raised a €14 million seed round ($17 million at today’s rate) from Global Founders Capital, Allianz France, Financière Saint James and several business angels. Insurance companies require a ton of capital to operate, that’s why the seed round seems quite big for the French market.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9Od4eQNxTN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/leocare-raises-18-1-million-for-its-insurance-products-designed-to-fit-in-a-mobile-app/">LeoCare raises $18.1 million for its insurance products designed to fit in a mobile app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;LeoCare raises $18.1 million for its insurance products designed to fit in a mobile app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/leocare-raises-18-1-million-for-its-insurance-products-designed-to-fit-in-a-mobile-app/embed/#?secret=9Od4eQNxTN" data-secret="9Od4eQNxTN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/seyna-is-building-an-insurance-as-a-service-startup-for-the-french-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106845</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
