<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 17:14:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>AWS brings ECS, EKS services to the data center, open sources EKS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/aws-brings-ecs-eks-services-to-the-data-center-open-sources-eks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/aws-brings-ecs-eks-services-to-the-data-center-open-sources-eks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 17:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andy Jassy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS re:Invent 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[containers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today at AWS re:Invent, Andy Jassy talked a lot about how companies are making a big push to the cloud, but today&#8217;s container-focussed announcements gave a big nod to the data center as the company announced ECS Anywhere and EKS Anywhere, both designed to let you run these services on-premises, as well as in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today at AWS re:Invent, Andy Jassy talked a lot about how companies are making a big push to the cloud, but today&#8217;s container-focussed announcements gave a big nod to the data center as the company announced ECS Anywhere and EKS Anywhere, both designed to let you run these services on-premises, as well as in the cloud.</p>
<p>These two services, ECS for generalized container orchestration and EKS for that&#8217;s focused on <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/kubernetes" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="kubernetes">Kubernetes <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> will let customers use these popular AWS services on premises. Jassy said that some customers still want the same tools they use in the cloud on prem and this is designed to give it to them.</p>
<p>Speaking of ECS he said,  &#8220;I still have a lot of my containers that I need to run on premises as I&#8217;m making this transition to the cloud, and [these] people really want it to have the same management and deployment mechanisms that they have in AWS also on premises and customers have asked us to work on this. And so I&#8217;m excited to announce two new things to you. The first is the launch, or the announcement of Amazon ECS anywhere, which lets you run ECS and your own data center,&#8221; he told the re:Invent audience.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2081026" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081026" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2081026" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-01-at-11.48.24-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="345" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-01-at-11.48.24-AM.jpg 2016w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-01-at-11.48.24-AM.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-01-at-11.48.24-AM.jpg?resize=300,152 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-01-at-11.48.24-AM.jpg?resize=768,390 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-01-at-11.48.24-AM.jpg?resize=680,345 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-01-at-11.48.24-AM.jpg?resize=1536,780 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-01-at-11.48.24-AM.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2081026" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> AWS</p></div></p>
<p>He said it gives you the same AWS API&#8217;s and cluster configuration management pieces. This will work the same for EKS, allowing this single management methodology regardless of where you are using the service.</p>
<p>While it was at it, the company also announced it was open sourcing EKS, its own managed Kubernetes service. The idea behind these moves is to give customers as much flexibility as possible, and recognizing what Microsoft, IBM and Google have been saying, that we live in a multi-cloud and hybrid world and people aren&#8217;t moving everything to the cloud right away.</p>
<p>In fact, in his opening Jassy stated that right now in 2020, just 4% of worldwide IT spend is on the cloud. That means there&#8217;s money to be made selling services on premises, and that&#8217;s what these services will do.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/aws-reinvent-2020"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/aws-reinvent-2020-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/aws-brings-ecs-eks-services-to-the-data-center-open-sources-eks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081006</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Find out how we&#8217;re working toward living and working in space at TC Sessions: Space 2020</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/find-out-how-were-working-toward-living-and-working-in-space-at-tc-sessions-space-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/find-out-how-were-working-toward-living-and-working-in-space-at-tc-sessions-space-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 17:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2020]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The idea of people going to live and work in space, outside of the extremely unique case of the International Space Station, has long been the strict domain of science fiction. That&#8217;s changing fast, however, with public space agencies, private companies and the scientific community all looking at ways of making it safe for people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The idea of people going to live and work in space, outside of the extremely unique case of the International <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-ecb7" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-ecb7">Space <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Station, has long been the strict domain of science fiction. That&#8217;s changing fast, however, with public space agencies, private companies and the scientific community all looking at ways of making it safe for people to live and work in space for longer periods – and broadening accessibility of space to people who don&#8217;t necessarily have the training and discipline of dedicated astronauts.</p>
<p>At <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=livingspace&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=livingspacepost&amp;display=">TC Sessions: Space on December 16 &amp; 17</a>, we&#8217;ll be talking to some of the people who want to make living and working in space a reality, and who are paving the way for the future of both commercial and scientific human space activity. Those efforts range from designing the systems people will need for staying safe and comfortable on long spaceflights, to ideating and developing the technologies needed for long-term stays on the surface of worlds that are far less hospitable to life than Earth, like the Moon and Mars.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re thrilled to have Janet Kavandi from Sierra Nevada Corporation, Melodie Yashar from SEArch+, Nujoud Mercy from <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/nasa" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="nasa">NASA <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Axiom&#8217;s Amir Blachman joining us at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=livingspace&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=livingspacepost&amp;display=">TC Sessions: Space</a> on December 16 &amp;17 to chat about the future of human space exploration and commercial activity.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Janet Kavandi is Executive Vice President of Space Systems at the Sierra Nevada Corporation. She was selected as a NASA astronaut in 1994 as a member of the fifteenth class of U.S. astronauts. She completed three space flights in which she supported space station payload integration, capsule communications and robotics. She went on to serve as director of flight crew operations at NASA&#8217;s Johnson Space Center and then as director of NASA&#8217;s Glenn Research Center, where she directed cutting-edge research on aerospace and aeronautical propulsion, power and communication technologies. She retired from NASA in 2019 after 25 years of service.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--callout block--right" >
		<h4 class="block--callout__title">More panels from TC Sessions: Space</h4>
		
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/after-historic-osiris-rex-asteroid-sample-collection-lockheed-martin-vp-lisa-callahan-will-join-us-at-tc-sessions-space/">Lockheed Martin VP Lisa Callahan</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/rocket-labs-peter-beck-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-space-2020/">Rocket Lab’s Peter Beck</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/26/u-s-space-force-lt-general-john-f-thompson-will-join-us-at-tc-sessions-space-in-december/">US Space Force Lt. General John F. Thompson</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/how-is-the-air-force-looking-to-spend-its-60-billion-rd-budget/">Will Roper, Assistant Secretary, Air Force</a></li>
<li>Read the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/announcing-the-agenda-for-tc-sessions-space-2020/">agenda</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/13/nasas-head-of-human-spaceflight-kathy-lueders-will-join-us-at-tc-sessions-space/">NASA’s head of human spaceflight, Kathryn Lueders</a></li>
</ul>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Melodie Yashar is a design architect, technologist, and researcher. She is co-founder of Space Exploration Architecture (SEArch+), a group developing human-supporting concepts for space exploration. SEArch+ won top prize in both of NASA’s design solicitations for a Mars habitat within the 3D-Printed Habitat Challenge. The success of the team’s work in NASA’s Centennial Challenge led to consultancy roles and collaborations with UTAS/Collins Aerospace, NASA Langley, ICON, NASA Marshall, and others.</p>
<p>Nujoud Merancy is a systems engineer with extensive background in human spaceflight and spacecraft at NASA Johnson Space Center. She is currently the Chief of the Exploration Mission Planning Office responsible for the team of engineers and analysts designing, developing, and integrating NASA’s human spaceflight portfolio beyond low earth orbit. These missions include planning for the Orion Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle, Space Launch System, Exploration Ground Systems, Gateway, and Human Landing System.</p>
<p>Amir Blachman is Chief Business Officer at Axiom, a pioneering company in the realm of commercializing space and building the first generation of private commercial space stations. He spent most of his career investing in and leading early stage companies. Before joining Axiom as the company’s first employee, he managed a syndicate of 120 space investors in 11 countries. Through this syndicate, he funded lunar landers, communication networks, Earth imaging satellites, antennae and exploration technologies.</p>
<p>In order to hear from these experts, you’ll need to pick up your ticket to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=livingspace&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=livingspacepost&amp;display=true">TC Sessions: Space</a>, which will also include video on demand for all sessions, which means you won’t have to miss a minute of expert insight, tips and trend spotting from the top founders, investors, technologists, government officials and military minds across public, private and defense sectors. There are even <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=livingspace&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=livingspacepost&amp;display=true">discounts for groups, students and military/government officials</a></strong>.</p>
<p>You’ll find panel discussions, interviews, fireside chats and interactive Q&amp;As on a range of topics: mineral exploration, global mapping of the Earth from space, deep tech software, defense capabilities, 3D-printed rockets and the future of agriculture and food technology. Don’t miss the breakout sessions dedicated to accessing grant money. Explore <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=livingspace&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=livingspacepost&amp;display=/#2f65e915-5963-4a04-be6a-667c01da1e6d">the event agenda</a> now and get a jump on organizing your schedule.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-63a70c19e197308b71b19a195112a25c"
			width="99%"
			height="1200"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/63a70c19e197308b71b19a195112a25c"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-63a70c19e197308b71b19a195112a25c')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-63a70c19e197308b71b19a195112a25c'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/find-out-how-were-working-toward-living-and-working-in-space-at-tc-sessions-space-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079252</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Softbank, Volvo back Flock Freight with $113.5M to help shippers share the load</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/softbank-volvo-back-flock-freight-with-113-5m-to-help-shippers-share-the-load/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/softbank-volvo-back-flock-freight-with-113-5m-to-help-shippers-share-the-load/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Everyday thousands of trucks carry freight along U.S. highways, propelling the economy forward as consumer goods, electronics, cars and agriculture make their way to distribution centers, stores and eventually households. It&#8217;s inside these trucks — many of which sit half empty — where Flock Freight, a five-year-old startup out of San Diego believes it can [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Everyday thousands of trucks carry freight along U.S. highways, propelling the economy forward as consumer goods, electronics, cars and agriculture make their way to distribution centers, stores and eventually households. It&#8217;s inside these trucks — many of which sit half empty — where Flock Freight, a five-year-old startup out of San Diego believes it can transform the industry.</p>
<p>Now, it has the funds to try and do it.</p>
<p>Flock Freight said Tuesday it has raised $113.5 million in a Series C round led by Softbank Vision Fund 2. Existing investors SignalFire, GLP Capital Partners and Google Ventures also participated in the round, in addition to a new minority investment by strategic partner Volvo Group Venture Capital. Ervin Tu, managing partner at SoftBank Investment Advisers, will join Flock Freight&#8217;s board. The company, which has raised $184 million to date, has post-funding valuation of $500 million, according to a source familiar with the deal who confirmed an earlier report by Bloomberg.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A slew of startups have popped up in the past several years all aiming to use technology to transform trucking — the backbone of the U.S. economy that moves more than 70% of all U.S. freight — into a more efficient machine. Most have focused on building digital freight networks that connect truckers with shippers.</p>
<p>Flock Freight has focused instead on the shipments themselves. The company created a software platform that helps pool shipments into a single shared truckload to make carrying freight more efficient. Flock Freight says its software avoids the traditional hub-and-spoke system, which is dominated by trucks with less than a full load, known in the industry as LTL. Flock Freight says that by pooling shipments that are going the same direction onto one truck, freight-related carbon emissions can be reduced by 40%.</p>
<p>The funds will be used to hire more employees; it has 129 employees to date.</p>
<p>&#8220;Unlike the digital freight-matching category that uses technology to simply improve efficiency as workflow automation, Flock Freight uses technology to power a new shipping mode (shared truckload) that makes freight transportation more efficient. The impact of Flock Freight&#8217;s algorithms is that shippers no longer need to adhere to LTL constraints for freight that measures up to 44 linear feet; instead, they can classify it as &#8216;shared truckload,'&#8221; Oren Zaslansky, founder and CEO of Flock Freight said in a statement. &#8220;Shippers can use Flock Freight&#8217;s efficient shared truckload solution to accommodate high demand and increased urgency.&#8221;</p>
<p>Their pitch has been compelling enough to attract a diverse mix of venture firms and corporate investors such as Volvo and Softbank.</p>
<p>&#8220;Flock Freight is improving supply chain efficiency for hundreds of thousands of shippers. Our investment is intended to accelerate the company&#8217;s ability to scale its business and capture a greater share of the market,&#8221; said Tu, Managing Partner at SoftBank Investment Advisers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/softbank-volvo-back-flock-freight-with-113-5m-to-help-shippers-share-the-load/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080977</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AWS launches Trainium, its new custom ML training chip</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/aws-launches-trainium-its-new-custom-ml-training-chip/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/aws-launches-trainium-its-new-custom-ml-training-chip/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 16:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon SageMaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS re:Invent 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tensorflow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its annual re:Invent developer conference, AWS today announced the launch of AWS Trainium, the company&#8217;s next-gen custom chip dedicated to training machine learning models. The company promises that it can offer higher performance than any of its competitors in the cloud, with support for TensorFlow, PyTorch and MXNet. It will be available as EC2 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its annual re:Invent developer conference, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/aws" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="aws">AWS <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> today announced the launch of <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/machine-learning/trainium/">AWS Trainium</a>, the company&#8217;s next-gen custom chip dedicated to training machine learning models. The company promises that it can offer higher performance than any of its competitors in the cloud, with support for TensorFlow, PyTorch and MXNet.</p>
<p>It will be available as EC2 instances and inside <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/amazon" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="amazon">Amazon <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> SageMaker, the company&#8217;s machine learning platform.</p>
<p>New instances based on these custom chips will launch next year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The main arguments for these custom chips are speed and cost. AWS promises 30% higher throughput and 45% lower cost-per-inference compared to the standard AWS GPU instances.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-01-084212.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2081001" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-01-084212.png" alt="" width="976" height="459" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-01-084212.png 976w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-01-084212.png?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-01-084212.png?resize=300,141 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-01-084212.png?resize=768,361 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-01-084212.png?resize=680,320 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-01-084212.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 976px) 100vw, 976px" /></a></p>
<p>In addition, AWS is partnering with <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/intel" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="intel">Intel <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> to launch Habana Gaudi-based EC2 instances for machine learning training. Coming next year, these instances promise to offer up to 40% better price/performance compared to the current set of GPU-based EC2 instances for machine learning. These chips will support <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tensorflow" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tensorflow">TensorFlow <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and PyTorch.</p>
<p>These new chips will make their debut in the AWS cloud in the first half of 2021.</p>
<p>Both of these new offerings complement <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/machine-learning/inferentia/">AWS Inferentia</a>, which the company launched at last year&#8217;s re:Invent. Inferentia is the inferencing counterpart to these machine learning pieces, which also uses a custom chip.</p>
<p>Trainium, it&#8217;s worth noting, will use the same SDK as Inferentia.</p>
<p>&#8220;While Inferentia addressed the cost of inference, which constitutes up to 90% of ML infrastructure costs, many development teams are also limited by fixed ML training budgets,&#8221; the AWS team writes. &#8220;This puts a cap on the scope and frequency of training needed to improve their models and applications. AWS Trainium addresses this challenge by providing the highest performance and lowest cost for ML training in the cloud. With both Trainium and Inferentia, customers will have an end-to-end flow of ML compute from scaling training workloads to deploying accelerated inference.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/aws-reinvent-2020"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/aws-reinvent-2020-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/aws-launches-trainium-its-new-custom-ml-training-chip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080802</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lucid Motors completes $700M factory to produce its first electric vehicles</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/lucid-motors-completes-700m-factory-to-produce-its-first-electric-vehicles/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/lucid-motors-completes-700m-factory-to-produce-its-first-electric-vehicles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080906</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Electric automaker Lucid Motors has completed the initial phase of its $700 million factory, a milestone required to begin production of its first luxury all-electric Air sedan this spring. The factory, which is located about halfway between Tucson and Phoenix off Interstate 10, has the capacity to produce 30,000 vehicles a year. If Lucid, led [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Electric automaker Lucid Motors has completed the initial phase of its $700 million factory, a milestone required to begin production of its first luxury all-electric Air sedan this spring.</p>
<p>The factory, which is located about halfway between Tucson and Phoenix off Interstate 10, has the capacity to produce 30,000 vehicles a year. If Lucid, led by CEO Peter Rawlinson, is successful in its bid to attract buyers, that factory will expand from its current 999,000 square feet to more than 5 million square feet. Once fully built out, the factory will have the capacity to build 400,000 vehicles a year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2080941" style="width: 3850px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-factory.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2080941" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2080941 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-factory.jpg" alt="lucid motors factory" width="3840" height="2160" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-factory.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-factory.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-factory.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-factory.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-factory.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-factory.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-factory.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-factory.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3840px) 100vw, 3840px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2080941" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Lucid Motors</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s an ambitious plan for a company that has yet to deliver a single vehicle. Yet, Rawlinson has remained bullish of EVs and Lucid&#8217;s future. Lucid is already getting ready to resume construction on the next phase of the factory early next year that will be used to produce its next vehicle, an all-electric SUV in 2023.</p>
<p>The company plans to build out the factory, which sits on 590 acres, over four phases through 2028.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2080944" style="width: 3850px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-Paint-shop_01.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2080944" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2080944 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-Paint-shop_01.jpg" alt="lucid motors-Paint shop" width="3840" height="2160" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-Paint-shop_01.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-Paint-shop_01.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-Paint-shop_01.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-Paint-shop_01.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-Paint-shop_01.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-Paint-shop_01.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-Paint-shop_01.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lucid-motors-Paint-shop_01.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3840px) 100vw, 3840px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2080944" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Lucid Motors</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The completion of the first phase comes about four years since Lucid Motors first announced its intentions to produce electric vehicles. It&#8217;s a milestone that almost didn&#8217;t happen. As the company burned through capital, it struggled to find new investors. Saudi Arabia’s sovereign wealth fund finally stepped up in September 2018 and committed to invest $1 billion into the company.</p>
<p>The all-electric luxury Air sedan, which was revealed in September, has a range of up to 517 miles, depending on the variant, and a design that puts technology and understated luxury front and center.</p>
<p>Two of the four variants — the $169,000 flagship Dream edition and a $139,000 Grand Touring model — will go into production first at its new factory this year. Deliveries of these variants are slated to begin in spring 2021. Two other variants, a Touring model priced at $95,000 and a base model that’s a smidge below $80,000, are expected at the end of 2021 and into 2022, respectively. (All prices are before the $7,500 federal tax credit is accounted for.)</p>
<p>The Air is meant to be the electric alternative to the Mercedes Benz S Class. That means performance matters as much the design. and it does come with some eye popping performance specs. For instance, the Dream edition boasts 1,080 horsepower and can travel from zero to 60 mph acceleration in 2.5 seconds. As a result of the power, the Dream edition has 465 miles of range. Meanwhile, the Grand Touring has 800 horsepower and can hit that same acceleration in 3 seconds, but has the highest range of 517 miles.</p>
<p>The Air will also be loaded with 32 sensors, a driver-monitoring system and an Ethernet-based architecture all for its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/28/lucid-motors-all-electric-air-will-have-32-sensors-including-lidar-to-support-hands-free-highway-driving/">advanced driver assistance system</a>, which is designed to support hands-free driving on highways. Inside, a 34-inch curved glass 5K display sits in front of the driver, and appears to float above the dashboard. Another center touchscreen is retractable, revealing more storage. Meanwhile, a few physical controls remain on the steering wheel and just above the center screen to control volume and activate the ADAS and Amazon Alexa, which is integrated into the vehicle. Below that center touchscreen and moving to the console is a spot for inductive charging, cup holders and USB-C ports, along with additional storage.</p>
<p>To accomplish all of this, Lucid as touted its approach to design as well as its advanced manufacturing process. Lucid says is uses riveted and bonded monocoque body structure instead of spot welds. Most modern vehicles today have a unibody design, which means the frame, floor and chassis are made of a single structure. A monocoque design is typically seen in motorsports with the frame acting as a skin that gets its strength by distributing tension and compression.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/lucid-motors-completes-700m-factory-to-produce-its-first-electric-vehicles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080906</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China&#8217;s Chang&#8217;e-5 lunar lander successfully lands on the Moon</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/chinas-change-5-lunar-lander-successfully-lands-on-the-moon/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/chinas-change-5-lunar-lander-successfully-lands-on-the-moon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chinese Lunar Exploration Program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080954</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chinese state news agencies are reporting a successful landing of the Chang&#8217;e-5 lunar robotic lander, which will seek to return lunar rock samples back to Earth. The launch took off on November 23, and attained lunar orbit on November 28. It launched the lander vehicle on November 30, and the reports today from the China [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chinese state news agencies are reporting a successful landing of the Chang&#8217;e-5 lunar robotic lander, which will seek to return lunar rock samples back to Earth. The launch took off on November 23, and attained lunar orbit on November 28. It launched the lander vehicle on November 30, and the reports today from the China National <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-ecb7" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-ecb7">Space <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Administration (CNSA) says that at shortly after 10 AM EST it achieved its goal of touching down on the Moon&#8217;s surface intact.</p>
<p>China&#8217;s Chang&#8217;e-5 mission will be the third ever to bring back soil or rock samples from the Moon – only the U.S. and the former Soviet Union have accomplished that so far. The mission landed on the side of the Moon closest to the Earth (which is always the same side, since the Moon is locked in its orientation during its orbit around our planet).</p>
<p>This landing starts a clock that has a pretty fixed duration in terms of the next steps for the mission – the lander doesn&#8217;t actually have a heater unit on board, so it can&#8217;t withstand the lunar night. That means it will have to collect the samples it hopes to return within a period spanning the next 14 Earth days, with a potential landing planned for around December 16 or 17 (which means, coincidentally, that if everything goes to plan, China will have its Moon rocks back to study just in time for our debut <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/">TC Sessions: Space event</a>).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This isn&#8217;t the only extraterrestrial sample return mission going on right now – a Lockheed Martin-designed probe successfully retrieved samples from near-Earth asteroid Bennu just last month, and will seek to return those with a trip beginning next March. NASA has also launched its Mars sample-return mission, using the Perseverance rover it launched in July.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YiUuo0cLBr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/nasa-successfully-launches-its-mars-2020-perseverance-rover-using-an-atlas-v-rocket/">NASA successfully launches its Mars 2020 Perseverance rover using an Atlas V rocket</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NASA successfully launches its Mars 2020 Perseverance rover using an Atlas V rocket&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/nasa-successfully-launches-its-mars-2020-perseverance-rover-using-an-atlas-v-rocket/embed/#?secret=YiUuo0cLBr" data-secret="YiUuo0cLBr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/chinas-change-5-lunar-lander-successfully-lands-on-the-moon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080954</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join us for a live Q&#038;A with Sapphire’s Jai Das today at 2 pm EST/11 am PST</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/join-us-for-a-live-qa-with-sapphires-jai-das-today-at-2-pm-est-11-am-pst/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/join-us-for-a-live-qa-with-sapphires-jai-das-today-at-2-pm-est-11-am-pst/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jai Das]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulesoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sapphire Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080929</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The conversation is part of the second season of our Extra Crunch Live series that has seen all sorts of investors and founders join TechCrunch for a dig into their work.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today&#8217;s the day! In just a few hours I am chatting with with <a href="https://twitter.com/jai_das?lang=en">Jai Das</a>, a managing director at <a href="https://sapphireventures.com/">Sapphire Ventures</a>.</p>
<p>The conversation is part of the second season of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/announcing-the-extra-crunch-live-event-series/">Extra Crunch Live</a> series that has seen all sorts of investors and founders join TechCrunch for a dig into their work.</p>
<p>Das&#8217; participation comes at the perfect moment: he invested early in MuleSoft, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/20/salesforce-is-buying-mulesoft-at-enterprise-value-of-6-5-billion/">sold to Salesforce for $6.5 billion</a> back in 2018. Salesforce is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/slacks-stock-climbs-on-possible-salesforce-acquisition/">expected to announce its purchase of Slack later today</a>, perhaps before our chat. Either way, we&#8217;ll ask Das about selling companies, selling them to Salesforce in particular and what we should take away concerning the enterprise software M&amp;A market from the deal.</p>
<p><em>Here <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/why-bessemers-byron-deeter-thinks-saas-companies-could-grow-even-faster-in-2021/">are notes</a> from the last episode of Extra Crunch Live with Bessemer’s Byron Deeter.</em></p>
<p>And as we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/join-us-for-a-live-qa-with-sapphires-jai-das-on-tuesday-at-2-pm-et-11-am-pt/">noted last week</a>, we will also dig into the role of corporate venture capital in 2020 and beyond, the state of early-to-growth stage investing as Sapphire leads rounds from Series A to Series C, API-led startups, along with the importance of geographic location in the pandemic for founding teams, and more.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s going to be fun! And it&#8217;s in just a few hours. So make sure that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=jaidaspost">your Extra Crunch login works</a>, hit the jump, save the time to your calendar and submit a question ahead of time if you want me to see your notes before we start. In the meantime, I&#8217;m going to find my most Zoom-friendly shirt and run through my intro a few times.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re live in mere hours! See you soon.</p>
<h2>Details</h2>
<p>Below are links to add the event to your calendar and to save the Zoom link. We’ll share the YouTube link shortly before the discussion:<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/join-us-for-a-live-qa-with-sapphires-jai-das-today-at-2-pm-est-11-am-pst/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080929</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US shopping app downloads on Black Friday reached a record 2.8M installs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/u-s-shopping-app-downloads-on-black-friday-reached-a-record-2-8m-installs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/u-s-shopping-app-downloads-on-black-friday-reached-a-record-2-8m-installs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App Annie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Best-Buy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black friday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyber monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sams club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensor tower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many U.S. consumers spent this year&#8217;s Black Friday sales event shopping from home on mobile devices. That led to first-time installs of mobile shopping apps in the U.S. to break a new record for single-day installs on Black Friday 2020, according to a report from Sensor Tower. The firm estimates that U.S. consumers downloaded approximately [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Many U.S. consumers spent this year&#8217;s Black Friday sales event <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/28/black-friday-online-sales-numbers/">shopping from home</a> on mobile devices. That led to first-time installs of mobile shopping apps in the U.S. to break a new record for single-day installs on Black Friday 2020, according <a href="https://sensortower.com/blog//shopping-app-downloads-black-friday-2020">to a report from Sensor Tower</a>. The firm estimates that U.S. consumers downloaded approximately 2.8 million shopping apps on November 27th &#8212; a figure that&#8217;s up by nearly 8% over last year.</p>
<p>However, this number doesn&#8217;t necessarily represent faster growth than in 2019, which also saw about an 8% year-over-year increase in Black Friday shopping app installs, the report noted. This could be because mobile shopping and the related app installs are now taking place throughout the month of November, though, as retailers adjusted to the pandemic and other online shopping trends by hosting earlier sales or even month-long sales events.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2080940" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2080940" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2080940" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-installs.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="444" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-installs.png 1494w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-installs.png?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-installs.png?resize=300,196 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-installs.png?resize=768,502 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-installs.png?resize=680,444 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-installs.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2080940" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sensor Tower</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The data seems to indicate this is true. Between Nov. 1 and Nov. 29, U.S. consumers downloaded approximately 59.2 million shopping apps from across the App Store and Google Play &#8212; an increase of roughly 15% from the 51.7 million they downloaded in Nov. 2019. That&#8217;s a much higher figure than the 2% year-over-year growth seen during this same period in 2019.</p>
<p>Another shift taking place in mobile shopping is the growing adoption of app from brick-and-mortar retailers. During the first three quarters of 2020, apps from brick-and-mortar retailers grew installs 27%. This trend continued on Black Friday, when 5 out of the top 10 mobile shopping apps were those from brick-and-mortar retailers, led by Walmart.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2080938" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2080938" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2080938" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-top-apps.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="405" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-top-apps.png 2900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-top-apps.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-top-apps.png?resize=300,179 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-top-apps.png?resize=768,458 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-top-apps.png?resize=680,405 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-top-apps.png?resize=1536,915 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-top-apps.png?resize=2048,1220 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/black-friday-2020-top-apps.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2080938" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sensor Tower</p></div></p>
<p>Walmart saw the highest adoption this year, with around 131,000 Black Friday installs, followed by Amazon at 106,000, then Shopify&#8217;s Shop at 81,000. Combined, the top 10 apps saw 763,000 total new installs, or 27% of the first-time downloads in the Shopping category.</p>
<p>Because the firms are only looking at new app installs, they aren&#8217;t giving a full picture of the U.S. mobile shopping market, as many consumers already have these apps installed on their devices. And many more simply shop online via a desktop or laptop computer.</p>
<p>To give these figures some context, Shopify reported on Saturday it had seen record Black Friday sales of $2.4 billion, with 68% on mobile. And today, Amazon <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/supporting-small-saving-big-and-shopping-early">announced</a> its small business sales alone topped $4.8 billion from Black Friday to Cyber Monday, a 60% year-over-year increase, but it didn&#8217;t break out the percentage that came from mobile.</p>
<p>Sensor Tower and rival app store analytics firm <a href="https://www.appannie.com/en/">App Annie</a> largely agreed on the top 5 shopping apps downloaded this Black Friday. They both saw Walmart again beating Amazon to become the most-downloaded U.S. shopping app on Black Friday &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/walmart-tops-amazon-as-most-downloaded-u-s-shopping-app-on-black-friday/">as it did in 2019</a>. The two firms reported that Amazon remained No. 2 by downloads, followed by Shopify&#8217;s Shop app, then Target. However, Sensor Tower put Best Buy in 5th place, followed by Nike, while App Annie saw those positions swapped.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2080933" style="width: 540px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2080933" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2080933" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image002-4.png?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image002-4.png 603w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image002-4.png?resize=117,150 117w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image002-4.png?resize=234,300 234w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image002-4.png?resize=530,680 530w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image002-4.png?resize=39,50 39w" sizes="(max-width: 530px) 100vw, 530px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2080933" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>The rest of Sensor Tower&#8217;s top 10 included SHEIN, Sam&#8217;s Club, Klarna, then Offer Up, while App Annie&#8217;s list was rounded out by SHEIN, Sam&#8217;s Club, Wish, then Offer Up.</p>
<p>The pandemic&#8217;s impact may not have been obvious given the growth in online shopping this year, but the recession it triggered has played a role in how U.S. consumers are paying for their purchases. &#8220;Buy Now, Pay Later&#8221; apps like Klarna were up this year, even breaking into the top 10 per Sensor Tower&#8217;s data. The firm also noted that many new shopping apps launched this year focused on discounts and deals and retailers ran longer sales this year, as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/u-s-shopping-app-downloads-on-black-friday-reached-a-record-2-8m-installs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080910</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook&#8217;s self-styled &#8216;oversight&#8217; board selects first cases, most dealing with hate speech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/facebooks-self-styled-oversight-board-selects-first-cases-most-dealing-with-hate-speech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/facebooks-self-styled-oversight-board-selects-first-cases-most-dealing-with-hate-speech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content moderation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook Oversight Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platform regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080874</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A Facebook -funded body that the tech giant set up to distance itself from tricky and potentially reputation-damaging content moderation decisions has announced the first bundle of cases it will consider. In a press release on its website the Facebook Oversight Board (FOB) says it sifted through more than 20,000 submissions before settling on six [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>-funded body that the tech giant set up to distance itself from tricky and potentially reputation-damaging content moderation decisions has announced the first bundle of cases it will consider.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.oversightboard.com/news/719406882003532-announcing-the-oversight-board-s-first-cases-and-appointment-of-trustees/">press release</a> on its website the Facebook Oversight Board (FOB) says it sifted through more than 20,000 submissions before settling on six cases &#8212; one of which was referred to it directly by Facebook.</p>
<p>The six cases it&#8217;s chosen to start with are:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Facebook submission: <b>2020-006-FB-FBR</b></strong></p>
<p>A case from France where a user posted a video and accompanying text to a COVID-19 Facebook group &#8212; which relates to claims about the French agency that regulates health products &#8220;purportedly refusing authorisation for use of hydroxychloroquine and azithromycin against COVID-19, but authorising promotional mail for remdesivir&#8221;; with the user criticizing the lack of a health strategy in France and stating &#8220;[Didier] Raoult&#8217;s cure&#8221; is being used elsewhere to save lives&#8221;. Facebook says it removed the content for violating its policy on <a class="_8js5 _8gv4 _912q _8jjf" href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/credible_violence" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" aria-hidden="">violence and incitement</a>. The video in questioned garnered at least 50,000 views and 1,000 shares.</p>
<p>The FOB says Facebook indicated in its referral that this case &#8220;presents an example of the challenges faced when addressing the risk of offline harm that can be caused by misinformation about the COVID-19 pandemic&#8221;.</p>
<p><strong>User submissions:</strong></p>
<p>Out of the five user submissions that the FOB selected, the majority (three cases) are related to hate speech takedowns.</p>
<p>One case apiece is related to Facebook&#8217;s nudity and adult content policy; and to its policy around dangerous individuals and organizations.</p>
<p>See below for the Board&#8217;s descriptions of the five user submitted cases:</p>
<ul>
<li class="_8gu_ _8-v2"><span class="_8gv4 _8gv1 _OBTypography__text _8gv7"><b>2020-001-FB-UA: </b></span><span class="_8gv4 _8gv1 _OBTypography__text _8gv7"><i>A user posted a screenshot of two tweets by former Malaysian Prime Minister, Dr Mahathir Mohamad, in which the former Prime Minister stated that &#8220;Muslims have a right to be angry and kill millions of French people for the massacres of the past&#8221; and &#8220;[b]ut by and large the Muslims have not applied the &#8216;eye for an eye&#8217; law. Muslims don&#8217;t. The French shouldn&#8217;t. Instead the French should teach their people to respect other people&#8217;s feelings.&#8221; The user did not add a caption alongside the screenshots. Facebook removed the post for violating its policy on </i><a class="_8js5 _8gv4 _912q _8jjf" href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/hate_speech" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" aria-hidden=""><i>hate speech</i></a><i>. The user indicated in their appeal to the Oversight Board that they wanted to raise awareness of the former Prime Minister&#8217;s &#8220;horrible words&#8221;.</i></span></li>
<li>
<p class="_8gu_ _8-v2"><span class="_8gv4 _8gv1 _OBTypography__text _8gv7"><b>2020-002-FB-UA: </b></span><span class="_8gv4 _8gv1 _OBTypography__text _8gv7"><i>A user posted two well-known photos of a deceased child lying fully clothed on a beach at the water&#8217;s edge. The accompanying text (in Burmese) asks why there is no retaliation against China for its treatment of Uyghur Muslims, in contrast to the recent killings in France relating to cartoons. The post also refers to the Syrian refugee crisis. Facebook removed the content for violating its </i><a class="_8js5 _8gv4 _912q _8jjf" href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/hate_speech" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" aria-hidden=""><i>hate speech</i></a><i> policy. The user indicated in their appeal to the Oversight Board that the post was meant to disagree with people who think that the killer is right and to emphasise that human lives matter more than religious ideologies.</i></span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="_8gu_ _8-v2"><i></i><b style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">2020-003-FB-UA: </b><i style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">A user posted alleged historical photos showing churches in Baku, Azerbaijan, with accompanying text stating that Baku was built by Armenians and asking where the churches have gone. The user stated that Armenians are restoring mosques on their land because it is part of their history. The user said that the &#8220;т.а.з.и.к.и&#8221; are destroying churches and have no history. The user stated that they are against &#8220;Azerbaijani aggression&#8221; and &#8220;vandalism&#8221;. The content was removed for violating Facebook&#8217;s </i><a class="_8js5 _8gv4 _912q _8jjf" style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/hate_speech" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" aria-hidden=""><i>hate speech</i></a><i style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> policy. The user indicated in their appeal to the Oversight Board that their intention was to demonstrate the destruction of cultural and religious monuments.</i></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="_8gu_ _8-v2"><span class="_8gv4 _8gv1 _OBTypography__text _8gv7"><b>2020-004-IG-UA: </b></span><span class="_8gv4 _8gv1 _OBTypography__text _8gv7"><i>A user in Brazil posted a picture on Instagram with a title in Portuguese indicating that it was to raise awareness of signs of breast cancer. Eight photographs within the picture showed breast cancer symptoms with corresponding explanations of the symptoms underneath. Five of the photographs included visible and uncovered female nipples. The remaining three photographs included female breasts, with the nipples either out of shot or covered by a hand. Facebook removed the post for violating its policy on </i><a class="_8js5 _8gv4 _912q _8jjf" href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/adult_nudity_sexual_activity" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" aria-hidden=""><i>adult nudity and sexual activity</i></a><i>. The post has a pink background, and the user indicated in a statement to the Oversight Board that it was shared as part of the national &#8220;Pink October&#8221; campaign for the prevention of breast cancer.</i></span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="_8gu_ _8-v2"><span class="_8gv4 _8gv1 _OBTypography__text _8gv7"><b>2020-005-FB-UA: </b></span><span class="_8gv4 _8gv1 _OBTypography__text _8gv7"><i>A user in the US was prompted by Facebook&#8217;s &#8220;On This Day&#8221; function to reshare a &#8220;memory&#8221; in the form of a post that the user made two years ago. The user reshared the content. The post (in English) is an alleged quote from Joseph Goebbels, the Reich Minister of Propaganda in Nazi Germany, on the need to appeal to emotions and instincts, instead of intellect, and on the unimportance of truth. Facebook removed the content for violating its policy on </i><a class="_8js5 _8gv4 _912q _8jjf" href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/dangerous_individuals_organizations" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" aria-hidden=""><i>dangerous individuals and organisations</i></a><i>. The user indicated in their appeal to the Oversight Board that the quote is important as the user considers the current US presidency to be following a fascist model</i></span></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Public comments on the cases can be submitted via the <a href="https://www.oversightboard.com/news/719406882003532-announcing-the-oversight-board-s-first-cases-and-appointment-of-trustees/">FOB&#8217;s website</a> &#8212; but only for seven days (closing at 8:00 Eastern Standard Time on Tuesday, December 8, 2020).</p>
<p>The FOB says it &#8220;expects&#8221; to decide on each case &#8212; and &#8220;for Facebook to have acted on this decision&#8221; &#8212; within 90 days. So the first &#8216;results&#8217; from the FOB, which only began reviewing cases in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/facebook-oversight-board-controversy/">October</a>, are almost certainly not going to land before 2021.</p>
<p>Panels comprised of five FOB members &#8212; including at least one from the region &#8220;implicated in the content&#8221; &#8212; will be responsible for deciding whether the specific pieces of content in question should stay down or be put back up.</p>
<p>Facebook&#8217;s outsourcing of a fantastically tiny subset of content moderation considerations to a subset of its so-called &#8216;Oversight Board&#8217; has attracted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/28/under-consideration/">plenty of criticism</a> (including inspiring a mirrored unofficial entity that dubs itself the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/the-real-facebook-oversight-board-launches-to-counter-facebooks-oversight-board/">Real Oversight Board</a>) &#8212; and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/21/meet-facebooks-latest-fake/">no little cynicism</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="86J89hHWpV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/the-real-facebook-oversight-board-launches-to-counter-facebooks-oversight-board/">&#8216;The Real Facebook Oversight Board&#8217; launches to counter Facebook&#8217;s &#8216;Oversight Board&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;The Real Facebook Oversight Board&#8217; launches to counter Facebook&#8217;s &#8216;Oversight Board&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/the-real-facebook-oversight-board-launches-to-counter-facebooks-oversight-board/embed/#?secret=86J89hHWpV" data-secret="86J89hHWpV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Not least because it&#8217;s entirely funded by Facebook; structured as Facebook intended it to be structured; and with members chosen via a system devised by Facebook.</p>
<p>If it&#8217;s radical change you&#8217;re looking for, the FOB is not it.</p>
<p>Nor does the entity have any power to change Facebook policy &#8212; it can only issue recommendations (which Facebook can choose to entirely ignore).</p>
<p>Its remit does not extend to being able to investigate how Facebook&#8217;s attention-seeking business model influences the types of content being amplified or depressed by its algorithms, either.</p>
<p>And the narrow focus on content taken downs &#8212; rather than content that&#8217;s already allowed on the social network &#8212; skews its purview, as we&#8217;ve<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/facebook-oversight-board-controversy/"> pointed out before</a>.</p>
<p>So you won&#8217;t find the board asking tough questions about why hate groups continue to flourish and recruit on Facebook, for example, or robustly interrogating how much succour its algorithmic amplification has gifted to the antivaxx movement.  By design, the FOB is focused on symptoms, not the nation-sized platform ill of Facebook itself. <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Outsourcing a fantastically tiny subset of content moderations decisions can&#8217;t signify anything else.  </span></p>
<p>With this <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Facebook-commissioned pantomime of accountability the tech giant will be hoping to generate a helpful pipeline of distracting publicity &#8212; focused around specific and &#8216;nuanced&#8217; content decisions &#8212; deflecting plainer but harder-hitting questions about the exploitative and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/06/facebook-still-isnt-taking-myanmar-seriously/">abusive</a> nature of Facebook&#8217;s business itself, and the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/22/first-major-gdpr-decisions-looming-on-twitter-and-facebook/">lawfulness</a> of its mass surveillance of Internet users, as lawmakers around the world <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/uk-to-set-up-pro-competition-regulator-to-put-limits-on-big-tech/">grapple with how to rein in tech giants</a>.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The company wants the FOB to reframe discussion about the culture wars (<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/dec/01/facebook-youtube-google-accused-complicity-vietnam-repression">and worse</a>) that Facebook&#8217;s business model fuels as a societal problem &#8212; pushing a self-serving &#8216;fix&#8217; for algorithmically fuelled societal division in the form of a few hand-picked professionals opining on individual pieces of content, leaving it free to continue defining the shape of the attention economy on a global scale. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eqZ2RZWdVP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/france-and-the-netherlands-signal-support-for-eu-body-to-clip-the-wings-of-big-tech/">France and the Netherlands signal support for EU body to clip the wings of big tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;France and the Netherlands signal support for EU body to clip the wings of big tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/france-and-the-netherlands-signal-support-for-eu-body-to-clip-the-wings-of-big-tech/embed/#?secret=eqZ2RZWdVP" data-secret="eqZ2RZWdVP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/facebooks-self-styled-oversight-board-selects-first-cases-most-dealing-with-hate-speech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080874</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlackBerry shares rocket upwards on AWS deal to integrate sensor data in vehicles</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/blackberry-shares-rocket-upwards-aws-deal-to-integrate-sensor-data-in-vehicles/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/blackberry-shares-rocket-upwards-aws-deal-to-integrate-sensor-data-in-vehicles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BlackBerry shares shot up in early trading on news that the company will partner with Amazon Web Services to jointly develop and market its vehicle data integration and monitoring platform, IVY. BlackBerry stock was up 35% or $2.11 at the opening bell on the New York Stock Exchange. It&#8217;s a sign of both the potential market [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.blackberry.com/us/en">BlackBerry</a> shares shot up in early trading on news that the company will partner with <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/">Amazon Web Services</a> to jointly develop and market its<a href="https://blackberry.qnx.com/en/aws"> vehicle data integration and monitoring platform, IVY</a>.</p>
<p>BlackBerry stock was up 35% or $2.11 at the opening bell on the New York Stock Exchange. It&#8217;s a sign of both the potential market for smart vehicle services and the ability of Amazon businesses to turn boost the fortunes of businesses with its attention.</p>
<p>The former undisputed heavyweight of the smartphone market, BlackBerry has transformed itself into a provider of business security and information integration services and it&#8217;s through this transformation that the company attracted the attention of Amazon&#8217;s web services business.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The companies first announced a collaboration in the pre-pandemic January of 2020 when BlackBerry<a href="https://www.blackberry.com/us/en/company/newsroom/press-releases/2020/blackberry-collaborating-with-amazon-web-services-to-demonstrate-safe-secure-and-intelligent-connected-vehicle-software-platform-for-in-vehicle-applications"> said it would collaborate with AWS</a> on connected vehicle safety and security services for in-vehicle applications.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.blackberry.com/us/en/company/newsroom/press-releases/2020/blackberry-qnx-software-now-embedded-in-more-than-175-million-vehicles">Around 175 million vehicles are already using BlackBerry and AWS-enabled QNX service</a>, which was first launched five years ago.</p>
<p>“In the past five years we’ve gone from BlackBerry QNX technology helping to power 60 million cars to today’s announcement of more than 175 million – a nearly threefold increase and a testament to the fact that today’s leading automakers and their tier one suppliers continue to put their trust in BlackBerry and our ability to provide them with safe and secure software upon which the next generation of vehicles is being built,” said John Chen, Executive Chairman and CEO, BlackBerry.</p>
<p>The newest iteration of connected car services from the Waterloo, Canada-based company allows automakers to read vehicle sensor data coming off of equipment from multiple vendors, normalize that data and provide insights around the data for use either remotely or in vehicles.</p>
<p>The IVY software system can run inside a vehicle&#8217;s embedded systems, but configured from the cloud to let automakers providers drivers with features that can include indications about road conditions, driver performance, or battery use for electric vehicles.</p>
<p>The BlackBerry toolkit can also make it easier for automakers to collaborate with a wider pool of developers to create new services around vehicle performance optimization, reduce maintenance costs and perform remote software updates on vehicles. Call it the potential for the Tesla-fication of a broad class of vehicles that use the service.</p>
<p>“Data and connectivity are opening new avenues for innovation in the automotive industry, and BlackBerry and AWS share a common vision to provide automakers and developers with better insights so that they can deliver new services to consumers,” said John Chen, Executive Chairman and CEO, BlackBerry, in a statement. “This software platform promises to bring an era of invention to the in-vehicle experience and help create new applications, services, and opportunities without compromising safety, security, or customer privacy. We are pleased to expand our relationship with AWS to execute this vision and deliver BlackBerry IVY.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile&#8230; The Internet has jokes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Markets so hot that BlackBerry is surgin’ <a href="https://t.co/W6SKVFuPX6">https://t.co/W6SKVFuPX6</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Tero Kuittinen (@teroterotero) <a href="https://twitter.com/teroterotero/status/1333774372222406658?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/blackberry-shares-rocket-upwards-aws-deal-to-integrate-sensor-data-in-vehicles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080893</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Novakid&#8217;s ESL app for children raises $4.25M Series A led by PortfoLio and LearnStart investors</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/novakids-esl-app-for-children-raises-4-25m-series-a-led-by-portfolio-and-learnstart-investors/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/novakids-esl-app-for-children-raises-4-25m-series-a-led-by-portfolio-and-learnstart-investors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BonAngels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brilliant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eastern europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LETA Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TMT Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080919</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the pandemic playing havoc with children’s education EdTech startups have been on a roll. A new fundraising seems to come almost every week at this point. Today it’s Novakid’s turn. This EdTech startup is yet another &#8216;learning English as a second language for children&#8217; startup. But it at least has a chance among the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With the pandemic playing havoc with children’s education  EdTech startups have been on a roll. A new fundraising seems to come almost every week at this point.</p>
<p>Today it’s <a href="https://www.novakidschool.com/">Novakid’s</a> turn. This EdTech startup is yet another &#8216;learning English as a second language for children&#8217; startup. But it at least has a chance among the plethora of solutions out there, having raised a $4.25 million Series A financing led by Hungary-based PortfoLion (part of OTP, a leading banking group in Eastern Europe), alongside a prominent EdTech-focused US fund LearnStart. LearnStart is part of the LearnCapital VC  which has previously backed VIPKID and Brilliant.org. TMT Investments and Xploration Capital also joined the round. Both seed investors &#8211; South Korea-based BonAngels, as well as LETA Capital, took part in this financing round in January this year, of $1.5M.</p>
<p>Novakid’s teaching method is based around the ideas of language acquisition by Asher, Thornbury, Krashen and Chomsky, and it is specifically suited for children aged 4-12. It is incorporated in the US with development and customer support around Europe.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dchcxjl9PN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/allright-an-english-learning-app-for-children-raises-5m-to-scale-up-from-genesis-investments/">AllRight, an English language learning app for children, raises $5M from Genesis Investments</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AllRight, an English language learning app for children, raises $5M from Genesis Investments&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/allright-an-english-learning-app-for-children-raises-5m-to-scale-up-from-genesis-investments/embed/#?secret=dchcxjl9PN" data-secret="dchcxjl9PN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Max Azarow, Co-founder and CEO said: “Novakid is reinventing English learning for kids in countries where English is not a primary spoken language. There, English would usually be taught as an abstract subject, with focus on grammar and with little live practice offered. Novakid on the other hand, implements a unique format that combines a highly-interactive digital curriculum and with individual live tutor sessions where students &amp; tutor only speak English for a 100% language immersion.”</p>
<p>Aurél Påsztor, Partner at PortfoLion, commented: &#8220;Novakid attracted investor attention due to its excellent traction, which resulted in over 500% growth year-on-year both in terms of number of students and in terms of revenue. Other attractive points were strong customer retention, international business footprint and a solid monetization via paid subscriptions.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pGCatJqHB3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/tutor-marketplace-gostudent-takes-its-series-a-to-e13-3m-with-left-lane-capital-and-dn-capital/">Tutor marketplace GoStudent takes its Series A to €13.3M with Left Lane Capital and DN Capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tutor marketplace GoStudent takes its Series A to €13.3M with Left Lane Capital and DN Capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/tutor-marketplace-gostudent-takes-its-series-a-to-e13-3m-with-left-lane-capital-and-dn-capital/embed/#?secret=pGCatJqHB3" data-secret="pGCatJqHB3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/novakids-esl-app-for-children-raises-4-25m-series-a-led-by-portfolio-and-learnstart-investors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080919</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fundr, launching its first portfolio, uses an algorithm to remove bias from investing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/fundr-launching-its-first-portfolio-uses-an-algorithm-to-remove-bias-from-investing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/fundr-launching-its-first-portfolio-uses-an-algorithm-to-remove-bias-from-investing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For all the ways that the Silicon Valley scene excels, diversity and inclusion is not one of them. But a new startup called Fundr is looking to do the heavy lifting to help investors diversify their portfolio. Fundr is an investment marketplace founded by Lauren Washington, Boris Moyston, and Jean-Philippe Desmontils. The platform is aimed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For all the ways that the Silicon Valley scene excels, diversity and inclusion is not one of them. But a new startup called Fundr is looking to do the heavy lifting to help investors diversify their portfolio.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.fundr.ai/">Fundr</a> is an investment marketplace founded by Lauren Washington, Boris Moyston, and Jean-Philippe Desmontils. The platform is aimed at angel investors, but available to institutional VCs as well, to do the vetting and due diligence across the startup ecosystem that angels don&#8217;t always have the resources to pull off on their own.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s how it works:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Startups apply to the platform and share in-depth quantitative data about their market, team, traction, and background, which ultimately results in a Fundr score assigned to each company. This score determines how much that company is able to raise, or if they&#8217;re even eligible to be on the platform to begin with.</p>
<p>Fundr then uses that information to put these companies in a diversified portfolio. In fact, today Fundr is announcing its first portfolio of 15 startups out of more than 450 global applications.</p>
<p>Investors can then write a check to invest into that portfolio, with the ability to opt out of investing in certain companies or allocate more of their funds to their top picks. The goal is to raise $1.5 million and invest $100k into all 15 companies, with plans to close fundraising for this portfolio on December 11.</p>
<p>According to Fundr, there are more than <a href="https://dqydj.com/accredited-investors-in-america/#:~:text=We%20estimate%20in%202020%20there,trillion%20in%20wealth%20in%202020">13.6 million accredited investors</a> out there, only three percent are actively angel investing. Washington explained that the major barriers to angel investing are time, resources, and access to high-quality startups. Moreover, broad indexing at the seed stage usually outperforms individual investor selection by upwards of 90 percent over ten years, according to the company.</p>
<p>Within Fundr&#8217;s first portfolio, ten industries are represented (including clean energy, AI, blockchain and fintech). Fifty-six percent of founders in the portfolio identify as underrepresented people of color, and 44 percent identify as female, with 75 percent of founders hailing from outside traditional tech hubs like Silicon Valley and New York.</p>
<p>Washington said that the company tested its algorithm at the Black Women Talk Tech international pitch competition this year, and correctly predicted the winner. It took a seasoned team of investors six hours to come to the same conclusion.</p>
<p>Fundr is bootstrapped save for $100,000 that it raised through an Austin-based accelerator, and plans to first raise for its new portfolio before it raises more funding for itself.</p>
<p>You can check out the full list of startups in Fundr&#8217;s portfolio right <a href="https://www.fundr.ai/post/it-s-here-fundr-s-first-portfolio-launches-with-15-companies">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/fundr-launching-its-first-portfolio-uses-an-algorithm-to-remove-bias-from-investing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080856</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thousands of U.S. lab results and medical records spilled online after a security lapse</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/ntreatment-lab-results-medical-records-exposed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/ntreatment-lab-results-medical-records-exposed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronic health records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical imaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NTreatment, a technology company that manages electronic health and patient records for doctors and psychiatrists, left thousands of sensitive health records exposed to the internet because one of its cloud servers wasn&#8217;t protected with a password. The cloud storage server server was hosted on Microsoft Azure and contained 109,000 files, a large portion of which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">NTreatment, a technology company that manages electronic health and patient records for doctors and psychiatrists, left thousands of sensitive health records exposed to the internet because one of its cloud servers wasn&#8217;t protected with a password.</p>
<p>The cloud storage server server was hosted on Microsoft Azure and contained 109,000 files, a large portion of which contained lab test results from third-party providers like LabCorp, medical records, doctor&#8217;s notes, insurance claims, and other sensitive health data for patients across the U.S., a class of data considered protected health information under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA). Running afoul of HIPAA can result in steep fines.</p>
<p>None of the data was encrypted, and nearly all of the sensitive files were viewable in the browser. Some of the medical records belonged to children.</p>
<p>TechCrunch found the exposed data as part of a separate investigation. It wasn&#8217;t initially clear who owned the storage server, but many of the electronic health records that TechCrunch reviewed in an effort to trace the source of the data spillage were tied to doctors and psychiatrists and healthcare workers working at hospitals or networks known to use nTreatment. The storage server also contained some internal company documents, including a non-disclosure agreement with a major prescriptions provider.</p>
<p>The data was secured on Monday after TechCrunch contacted the company. In an email, NTreatment co-founder Gregory Katz said the server was &#8220;used as a general purpose storage,&#8221; but did not say how long the server was exposed.</p>
<p>Katz said the company would notify affected providers and regulators of the incident.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the latest in a series of incidents involving the exposure of medical data. Earlier this year we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/28/labcorp-website-bug-medical-data-exposed/">found a bug in LabCorp&#8217;s website</a> that exposed thousands of lab results, and reported on the vast amounts of medical imaging <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/10/medical-images-exposed-pacs/">floating around the web</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DNb2SQJzuZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/10/medical-images-exposed-pacs/">A billion medical images are exposed online, as doctors ignore warnings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A billion medical images are exposed online, as doctors ignore warnings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/10/medical-images-exposed-pacs/embed/#?secret=DNb2SQJzuZ" data-secret="DNb2SQJzuZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/ntreatment-lab-results-medical-records-exposed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080576</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Qualcomm announces the new Snapdragon 888 chip</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/qualcomm-announces-the-new-snapdragon-888-chip/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/qualcomm-announces-the-new-snapdragon-888-chip/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snapdragon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Qualcomm kicked off an all-virtual version of its annual summit this morning by announcing the launch of the the Snapdragon 888 platform. The chipmaker is clearly saving some key information for later in the virtual event, because it has yet to reveal a ton about its next SoC. We do, however, have an extremely modest [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/qualcomm" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="qualcomm">Qualcomm <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> kicked off an all-virtual version of its annual summit this morning by announcing the launch of the the Snapdragon 888 platform. The chipmaker is clearly saving some key information for later in the virtual event, because it has yet to reveal a ton about its next SoC.</p>
<p>We do, however, have an extremely modest quote from Qualcomm president Cristiano Amon to go on: “Creating premium experiences takes a relentless focus on innovation. It takes long-term commitment, even in the face of immense uncertainty. It takes an organization that’s focused on tomorrow, to continue to deliver the technologies that redefine premium experiences.”</p>
<p>Granted, that’s more self-congratulatory than legitimately helpful. We do know that some key device makers have signed up to include the chip on future handsets, including ASUS, Black Shark, LG, MEIZU, Motorola, Nubia, realme, OnePlus, OPPO, Sharp, vivo, Xiaomi and ZTE.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Also, Qualcomm when ahead and blew past the expected 875. The company tells TechCrunch,</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">8 has always been a special number for Snapdragon. For over a decade, the number 8 has stood for premium. The Snapdragon 8-series is comprised of our premium tier mobile platforms, which is where we debut our latest technology innovations that will power the next generation mobile experiences. Year after year, these advancements are not only firsts for Snapdragon, but also for the mobile industry. Especially this year, 5G is rapidly expanding globally and creating new experiences and new opportunities, which are far beyond the industry’s expectation. Snapdragon is the platform of choice to deliver those 5G experiences to more consumers worldwide.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The number 8 is also a lucky number around the world. For some, it signifies infinity, success or inner wisdom, while for others it symbolizes luck. For example, in India the number 8 is known as Ashtha, Asta, or Ashta in Sanskrit and is the number of wealth and abundance. While in Chinese numerology 888 is a representation of triple luck.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So, not dissimilar from moves we&#8217;ve seen from handset makers like OnePlus. Naturally, 5G is on board. The chip will sport the company’s third-gen X60 5G modem, which sports both sub-6 and mmWave 5G bands. There’s also a 6th-gen AI Engine, capable of performing 26 tera operations per second (TOPS) with improved power efficiency.</p>
<p>Imaging is, naturally, a big piece of the puzzle, as well. The 888 features an up to 35% faster ISP, with support for up to 2.7 gigapixels per second (~120 12-megapixel photos). Gaming performance has also been improved, courtesy of an update to its Elite Gaming platform. More info &#8212; including the first few smartphones to sport the new SoC &#8212; soon, no doubt.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Tbm6EnYPNJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/qualcomm-unveils-snapdragon-865-and-765-platforms/">Qualcomm unveils Snapdragon 865 and 765 platforms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Qualcomm unveils Snapdragon 865 and 765 platforms&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/qualcomm-unveils-snapdragon-865-and-765-platforms/embed/#?secret=Tbm6EnYPNJ" data-secret="Tbm6EnYPNJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/qualcomm-announces-the-new-snapdragon-888-chip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078653</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In first IPO price range, Airbnb&#8217;s valuation recovers to pre-pandemic levels</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/in-first-ipo-price-range-airbnbs-valuation-recovers-to-pre-pandemic-levels/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/in-first-ipo-price-range-airbnbs-valuation-recovers-to-pre-pandemic-levels/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 14:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[booking holdings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silver lake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is Airbnb expensive or not?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/airbnb" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="airbnb">Airbnb <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> released <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1559720/000119312520306257/d81668ds1a.htm">an S-1/A filing</a> that details its initial IPO price range. The home-sharing unicorn intends to price its shares between $44 and $50 in its debut.</p>
<p>Per the company&#8217;s own accounting, it will have 596,399,007 or 601,399,007 shares outstanding, depending on whether its underwriters exercise their option. That gives the company a valuation range of $26.2 billion to $30.1 billion at the extremes.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s simple share count does not include a host of other shares that have vested but not yet been exercised. Including those shares, the company&#8217;s fully diluted valuation stretches to $35 billion, by <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/01/airbnb-ipo-seeks-valuation-of-up-to-35-billion.html">CNBC&#8217;s arithmetic</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>The top-end of Airbnb&#8217;s simple valuation places it near its Series F valuation <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/09/airbnb-closes-1b-round-at-31b-valuation-profitable-as-of-2h-2016-no-plans-for-ipo/">set in 2017</a>. Its fully-diluted valuation exceeds <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/funding_round/airbnb-series-f--e7075227">that $30.5 billion valuation</a> and is far superior to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/airbnb-ups-its-debt-by-1bn-amid-the-coronavirus-travel-crunch/">$18 billion, post-money valuation</a> that it raised at during its troubled period early in the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995210 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>For those investors, Silver Lake and Sixth Street, the company&#8217;s initial IPO price range is a win. For the company&#8217;s preceding investors, to see the company appear ready to at least match its preceding private valuation is a win as well, given <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/5-questions-from-airbnbs-ipo-filing/">how much damage Airbnb&#8217;s business sustained</a> early in the pandemic.</p>
<p>But how do those Airbnb valuation numbers match up against its revenues, and will public market investors value the company based on its current results, or expectations for a return-to-form once a vaccine comes to market? And if so, is Airbnb expensive or not?</p>
<h2>Expectations, hopes and hype</h2>
<p>Shares of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/the-priceline-group" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="the-priceline-group">Booking Holdings, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> which owns travel services like Kayak, Priceline, OpenTable and others, have almost doubled in value since its pandemic lows and is within spitting distance of its all-time highs. This despite its revenues <a href="https://ir.bookingholdings.com/static-files/3dfd6475-5e72-44bd-a0e3-889194a24285">falling 48%</a> in its most recent quarter. There&#8217;s optimism in the market that travel companies are on the cusp of a return to form, buoyed &#8212; we presume &#8212; by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/positive-vaccine-news-punishes-pandemic-boosted-companies-like-zoom-peloton-etsy/">good news</a> regarding effective coronavirus vaccines.</p>
<p>My expectation is that Airbnb is enjoying a similar bump, as investors intend to buy its shares not to bask in awe of its Q4 2020 results, but instead to enjoy what happens in the back half of 2021 as vaccines roll out and the travel industry recovers.</p>
<p>But what happens if we stack Airbnb&#8217;s revenues against its valuation today?<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/in-first-ipo-price-range-airbnbs-valuation-recovers-to-pre-pandemic-levels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080857</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook-backed Libra Association rebrands as Diem</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/libra-association-rebrands-as-diem/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/libra-association-rebrands-as-diem/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 14:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Libra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Libra Association]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Libra Association, a consortium created by Facebook to support its Libra cryptocurrency efforts, announced this morning that it has a new name — the Diem Association — and made some key hires ahead of its launch. This is just the latest course correction since the Libra project was announced last year. In an attempt [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/libra-association" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="libra-association">Libra Association, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> a consortium created by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> to support its Libra cryptocurrency efforts, <a href="https://www.diem.com/en-us/updates/diem-association/">announced</a> this morning that it has a new name — <a href="https://www.diem.com/">the Diem Association</a> — and made some key hires ahead of its launch.</p>
<p>This is just the latest course correction since the Libra project was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/18/facebook-libra/">announced last year</a>. In an attempt to appease financial regulators around the world, the association <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/facebook-backed-association-revamps-libra-following-regulatory-concerns/">shifted its strategy</a> away from creating a global stablecoin and will instead launch multiple stablecoins, each tied to a different fiat currency (such as the U.S. dollar and the euro).</p>
<p>The project has also seen some <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/12/leave-the-association/">high-profile departures</a>, with announced partners like Visa and Stripe leaving the project. And Facebook has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/facebook-rebrands-libra-wallet-service-calibra-to-novi/">rebranded its cryptocurrency wallet, changing the name from Calibra to Novi</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In a statement, Diem Association CEO Stuart Levey more-or-less acknowledged that the new name is an attempt to distance the group from Facebook, and from its earlier controversies.</p>
<p>“The Diem project will provide a simple platform for fintech innovation to thrive and enable consumers and businesses to conduct instantaneous, low-cost, highly secure transactions,” Levey said. “We are committed to doing so in a way that promotes financial inclusion – expanding access to those who need it most, and simultaneously protecting the integrity of the financial system by deterring and detecting illicit conduct. We are excited to introduce Diem – a new name that signals the project’s growing maturity and independence.”</p>
<p>As for the new hires, they include Chief Technology Officer Dahlia Malkhi, Chief of Staff Christy Clark, Chief Legal Officer Steve Bunnel and Executive Vice President for Growth and Innovation/Deputy General Counsel Kiran Raj. Diem Networks, the subsidiary that will actually operate the Diem payment system, has also hired James Emmett as managing director, Sterling Daines as chief compliance officer, Ian Jenkins as chief financial and risk officer and Saumya Bhavsar as general counsel.</p>
<p>While today&#8217;s announcement doesn&#8217;t include any specifics about timing, it suggests the association is positioning itself for an imminent launch — albeit one that will &#8220;proceed only upon receiving regulatory approval, including a payment systems license for the operational subsidiary of the Association from FINMA.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MXTDf3FSYu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/facebooks-libra-could-launch-in-january/">Facebook’s Libra could launch in January</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook’s Libra could launch in January&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/facebooks-libra-could-launch-in-january/embed/#?secret=MXTDf3FSYu" data-secret="MXTDf3FSYu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/libra-association-rebrands-as-diem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080896</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uber officially completes Postmates acquisition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/uber-officially-completes-postmates-acquisition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/uber-officially-completes-postmates-acquisition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 14:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postmates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080890</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Uber today announced the official completion of its Postmates acquisition deal, which it announced originally back in July. The all-stock deal, valued at around $2.65 billion at the time of its disclosure, sees Postmates join Uber, while continuing to operate as a separate service with its own branding and front-end – while some backend operations, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/uber" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="uber">Uber <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> today announced the official completion of its <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/postmates" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="postmates">Postmates <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> acquisition deal, which it announced originally back in July. The all-stock deal, valued at around $2.65 billion at the time of its disclosure, sees Postmates join Uber, while continuing to operate as a separate service with its own branding and front-end – while some backend operations, including a shared pool of drivers, will merge.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Lf86DLojKX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/06/uber-takes-out-postmates/">Uber confirms it is acquiring Postmates in an all-stock, $2.65B deal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uber confirms it is acquiring Postmates in an all-stock, $2.65B deal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/06/uber-takes-out-postmates/embed/#?secret=Lf86DLojKX" data-secret="Lf86DLojKX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Uber <a href="https://www.uber.com/newsroom/stronger-together-uber-eats-postmates-partner-to-benefit-merchants/">detailed some of its further thinking</a> around the newly combined companies and what that will mean for the businesses they work with in a new blog post. The company posited the move as of benefit to the merchant population they work with, and alongside the official closure announced a new initiative to encourage <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">and gather customer feedback on the merchant side.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>They&#8217;re calling it a &#8220;regional listening exercise&#8221; to be run beginning next year, wherein they&#8217;ll work with local restaurant associations and chambers of commerce to hear concerns from local business owners in their own communities. This sounds similar in design to Uber&#8217;s prior efforts to focus on driver feedback from a couple of years ago in order to improve the way it works with that side of its double-sided marketplace.</p>
<p>Focusing on the needs of its merchant population is doubly important given the current global pandemic, which has seen Uber Eats emerge as even more of a key infrastructure component in the food service and grocery industries as people seek more delivery options in order to better comply with stay-at-home orders and other public safety recommendations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/uber-officially-completes-postmates-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080890</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Loop Team wants to give remote workers an in-office feel</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/loop-team-wants-to-give-remote-workers-an-in-office-feel/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/loop-team-wants-to-give-remote-workers-an-in-office-feel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 14:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise communications tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loop Team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080870</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we&#8217;ve moved to work from home during the pandemic, it&#8217;s been challenging for remote workers to feel connected. Loop Team, a new entrant into the enterprise communications space, thinks the way we are communicating needs improvement. That&#8217;s why the startup is releasing Loop Team today, a tool that is trying to use software to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As we&#8217;ve moved to work from home during the pandemic, it&#8217;s been challenging for remote workers to feel connected. <a href="https://loopteam.co/">Loop Team</a>, a new entrant into the enterprise communications space, thinks the way we are communicating needs improvement. That&#8217;s why the startup is releasing <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/loop-team" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="loop-team">Loop Team <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> today, a tool that is trying to use software to reproduce the in-office experience.</p>
<p>Company founder and CEO Raj Singh says that he learned about the problems of feeling disconnected first-hand at a previous remote-first company, but in spite of his best attempts to use technology to produce that in-office feel, he said he continued to feel out of the loop (so to speak). That&#8217;s when he decided to build the solution he wanted.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve looked at a lot of the interactions that happen when you&#8217;re physically in an office &#8212; the visual communication, the background conversations, the hallway chatter, the serendipitous bumping, things like that. And we built an experience that effectively is a virtual office. And so it tries to represent the best parts of what a physical office experience might be like, but in a virtual form,&#8221; Singh explained to me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cWs6k2PGjy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/wall-street-needs-to-relax-because-remote-work-is-here-to-stay/">Wall Street needs to relax, as startups show remote work is here to stay</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wall Street needs to relax, as startups show remote work is here to stay&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/wall-street-needs-to-relax-because-remote-work-is-here-to-stay/embed/#?secret=cWs6k2PGjy" data-secret="cWs6k2PGjy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While he created this company prior to COVID, the pandemic has highlighted the need for a tool like this. Before he created the software, he interviewed hundreds of people who worked from home to understand their issues working outside of the office and he heard a lot of common complaints.</p>
<p>&#8220;There was an office and they didn&#8217;t necessarily know what was going on. They didn&#8217;t know who was available. They didn&#8217;t know who was around. It was difficult to connect. Everything was scheduled through calendar. They were missing some of that presence &#8212; and they were feeling lonely or out of touch or out of the loop,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>His company&#8217;s solution tries to reproduce the office experience using AI, good, old-fashioned presence awareness and other tech to let team members know what you&#8217;re doing and if you&#8217;re available to chat. So just as you would wander down the hall and see your colleague on the phone or deeply involved with work on the laptop, and know to leave them be, you could get that same feel with Loop.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2080883" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2080883" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2080883" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Loop-Team-Highlights.png?w=680" alt="Loop Team Highlights" width="680" height="534" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Loop-Team-Highlights.png 1981w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Loop-Team-Highlights.png?resize=150,118 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Loop-Team-Highlights.png?resize=300,236 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Loop-Team-Highlights.png?resize=768,604 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Loop-Team-Highlights.png?resize=680,534 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Loop-Team-Highlights.png?resize=1536,1207 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Loop-Team-Highlights.png?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2080883" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Loop Team</p></div></p>
<p>It gives the current status of the person, and you can know from looking at the list of people on your team, who&#8217;s available to talk and who&#8217;s busy. As you go into virtual discussions, the team can see who&#8217;s having meetings and individuals can pop in too, just as you might do in the office.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, you can set up rooms (like in Slack), but these are designed to give you a more personal connection using video and audio for actual discussion. You can work on projects via screen share and people who miss these meetings because of other obligations or time zone differences, can always review what they missed.</p>
<p>While you can do all of these things in Slack and Zoom, or in some combination of similar tools, Loop&#8217;s layout and presentation is designed to help you see the conversations in a clear way and expose what you want to see, while hiding parts of the day that don&#8217;t interest you.</p>
<p>The product is available for free starting today, but Singh wants to introduce a pricing model sometime next year based on team size. He expects there will always be a freemium version for teams under 10 people.</p>
<p>The company was founded in 2018 and nurtured at the Stanford Research Institute (SRI). It has raised $4.75 million so far. Today it starts on its journey as a startup with its first product, and it&#8217;s one that comes with good timing as more teams find themselves working remotely than every before.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d5uYrvXgdC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/08/what-weve-learned-about-working-from-home-7-months-into-the-pandemic/">What we&#8217;ve learned about working from home 7 months into the pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What we&#8217;ve learned about working from home 7 months into the pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/08/what-weve-learned-about-working-from-home-7-months-into-the-pandemic/embed/#?secret=d5uYrvXgdC" data-secret="d5uYrvXgdC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/loop-team-wants-to-give-remote-workers-an-in-office-feel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080870</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SoftBank takes a $690M stake in cloud-based Swedish customer engagement company Sinch</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/softbank-takes-a-690m-stake-in-cloud-based-swedish-crm-company-sinch/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/softbank-takes-a-690m-stake-in-cloud-based-swedish-crm-company-sinch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 13:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the heels of Facebook taking a big step into customer service with the acquisition of Kustomer for $1 billion, another big move is afoot in the world of customer relationship management and engagement. Sinch, a Swedish company that provides cloud-based &#8220;omnichannel&#8221; voice, video and messaging services to help enterprises communicate with customers, has announced [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On the heels of Facebook taking a big step into customer service with the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/facebook-confirms-it-has-acquired-kustomer-sources-say-for-1b/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">acquisition of Kustomer for $1 billion</a>, another big move is afoot in the world of customer relationship management and engagement. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/facebook-confirms-it-has-acquired-kustomer-sources-say-for-1b/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sinch</a>, a Swedish company that provides cloud-based &#8220;omnichannel&#8221; voice, video and messaging services to help enterprises communicate with customers, has <a href="https://investors.sinch.com/news-releases/news-release-details/sinch-ab-publ-sinch-announces-completion-directed-new-share" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announced</a> that SoftBank is taking a $690 million stake in the company. Sinch said that it plans to use the proceeds of the share sale for M&amp;A of its own.</p>
<p>&#8220;We see clearly how our cloud-based platform helps businesses leverage mobile technology to reinvent their customer experience,&#8221; said Oscar Werner, Sinch CEO, to TechCrunch. &#8220;Whereas people throughout the world have embraced mobile messaging to interact with friends and family, most businesses have yet to seize this opportunity. We are establishing Sinch as a leader in a global growth market that is still very fragmented, and we&#8217;re excited that SoftBank is now helping us realize that vision.&#8221;</p>
<p>Specifically, Sinch has issued and sold 3,187,736 shares worth SEK 3.3 billion, and large shareholders have sold a further 5,200,000 shares &#8212; with SoftBank the sole buyer.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The move underscores the growing opportunity that those in the world of customer engagement and CRM &#8212; which include not just Sinch and Kustomer but Salesforce and many others &#8212; are seeing to double down on their services at the moment. With people working and doing everything else remotely, and with the general upheaval we&#8217;ve had in the global economy due to Covid-19, there has been an increased demand and strain put on the digital channels that people use to communicate with organizations when they have questions or problems.</p>
<p>The catch is that customer relations and engaging users has grown to be more than just 1-800 numbers and being on hold for endless hours: it includes social media, email, websites with interactive chats, chatbots, messaging apps, and yes those phone calls.</p>
<p>Organizations like Sinch and Kustomer &#8212; which build platforms to help businesses manage all of those fragmented options in what are described as omnichannel offerings, have been capitalising on the demand and are now investing and looking for the next step in their strategies to grow.</p>
<p>For Kustomer that has been leaping into the arms of Facebook, which itself has spotted an opportunity to build out a CRM business to complement its other services for businesses. Recall that it&#8217;s also been experimenting and working on its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/facebook-is-working-on-neighborhoods-a-nextdoor-clone-based-on-local-groups/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">latest Nextdoor competitor</a> to promote local businesses; and it has added a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/facebook-adds-hosting-shopping-features-and-pricing-tiers-to-whatsapp-business/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ton of business tools</a> to its messaging apps too.</p>
<p>It will be interesting to see what Salesforce does next. While acquiring Slack gives the company an obvious channel into workplace communications, don&#8217;t forget that Slack is also a very popular tool for engaging with people outside of your employee network, too. It will be worth watching how and if Salesforce looks to develop that aspect of the business, too.</p>
<p>For Sinch, its strategy has been around making acquisitions of its own, including paying $250 million to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/sinch-acquires-saps-digital-interconnect-messaging-business-for-250m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pick up a business unit of SAP, Digital Interconect</a>, which has 1,500 enterprise customers mostly in the US using it to run &#8220;omnichannel&#8221; communications. Now the plan will be to do more, since there are still huge swathes of the market that have yet to upgrade and update their approaches.</p>
<p>Sinch, notably, is traded publicly on Sweden&#8217;s stock exchange and it currently has a market cap of SEK70 billion ($8.2 billion at current rates). It is profitable and generating cash so has &#8220;no need to raise funding for our ongoing business,&#8221; Thomas Heath, Sinch&#8217;s chief strategy officer and head of investor relations, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>For SoftBank, the investment marks another step in the company taking sizable stakes in fast-growing public or semi-public tech companies in Europe.</p>
<p>In October, it put <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/kahoot-picks-up-215m-from-softbank-for-its-user-generated-gamified-e-learning-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$215 million into Kahoot</a>, the online education platform aimed both at students and enterprises, built around the concept of users themselves creating &#8220;learning games&#8221; that can then be shared with others. Kahoot trades a proportion of its shares publicly on the stock exchange in Norway and like Sinch, the plan is to use a good part of the money for acquisitions.</p>
<p>Not all of SoftBank&#8217;s investments in scaled-up European businesses have panned out. Having put around $1 billion into German payments company Wirecard, the company turned out to be one of the biggest scandals in the history of European fintech, facing accounting scandals before <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/house-of-wirecard-insolvency/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">collapsing into insolvency earlier this year</a>.</p>
<p>Sinch, as a profitable and a steady business with predictable lines of recurring revenue, looks like a safer bet for now. Even with Salesforce, Facebook and others raising their game, there as Sinch&#8217;s CEO says, there is enough of an untapped market that playing well might be enough to do well.</p>
<p><em>Updated to clarify that Sinch considers its work &#8220;customer experience&#8221; more than CRM.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/softbank-takes-a-690m-stake-in-cloud-based-swedish-crm-company-sinch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080853</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Despite everything, Oyo still has $1 billion in cash</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/despite-everything-oyo-still-has-1-billion-in-cash/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/despite-everything-oyo-still-has-1-billion-in-cash/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 13:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ritesh agarwal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080854</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India’s Oyo has been one of the worst impacted startups with the coronavirus, but it has enough cash to steer through the pandemic and then look at funding further scale, a top executive says. In a townhall with employees last week, Oyo founder Ritesh Agarwal said the budget lodging firm “continued to hold on to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India’s Oyo has been one of the worst impacted startups with the coronavirus, but it has enough cash to steer through the pandemic and then look at funding further scale, a top executive says.</p>
<p>In a townhall with employees last week, Oyo founder <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/ritesh-agarwal" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="ritesh-agarwal">Ritesh Agarwal <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said the budget lodging firm “continued to hold on to close to a billion dollars of cash” across its group companies and joint venture firms and has “tracked to runway very closely.”</p>
<p>“At the same time, we&#8217;ve been very disciplined in making sure that we can respond to the crisis in a good way to try and ensure that we can come out of it at the right time,” he said in a fireside chat with Rohit Kapoor, chief executive of Oyo India and SA, and Troy Alstead, a board member who previously served as the chief executive officer of Startbucks.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The revelation will deliver a huge reassurance to employees and hotel partners of Oyo, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/04/softbank-backed-indian-startup-oyo-to-cut-5000-jobs-globally/">eliminated or furloughed over 5,000 jobs earlier this year</a> and reported in April that the pandemic had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/08/indias-oyo-furloughs-thousands-of-employees-as-revenue-drops-by-over-50/">cut its revenue and demand by more than 50%</a>.</p>
<p>Oyo also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/16/oyos-revenue-surged-in-fy19-but-loss-widened-too/">reported a loss of $335 million on $951 million revenue globally</a> for the financial year ending March 31, 2019, and earlier this year pledged to cut down on its spending.</p>
<p>Agarwal said the startup is recovering from the pandemic as nations relax their lockdowns, and with recent progress with vaccine trials, he is hopeful that the travel and hospitality industries will bounce back strongly.</p>
<p>&#8220;Together globally, we were able to get to around 85% of the gross margin dollars of our pre COVID levels. This I can tell you was extremely hard. But in my view was probably only possible because of the efforts of our teams in each one of the geographies,&#8221; he said, adding that Oyo Vacation has proven critical to the business in recent months delivering &#8220;packed&#8221; hotels and holiday homes.</p>
<p>During the conversation, a transcript of which was shared with employees and obtained by TechCrunch, Agarwal was heard talking about making Oyo &#8212; which was privately <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/07/india-oyo-ritesh-agarwal-investment/">valued at $10 billion last year when it was in the process of raising $1.5 billion</a> last year &#8212; ready for IPO. He, however, did not share a timeline on when the SoftBank-backed startup plans to go public and hinted that it’s perhaps not in the immediate future.</p>
<p>“And last but not the least, for me, it is very critical. I want the groups to know that I, our board and our broader management are fully committed to making sure that long-term wealth creation for our OYOpreneurs &#8212; beyond that of just the compensation, but the wealth creation by means of your stocks can be substantially grown.”</p>
<p>“At the end of the day, what is the right time to go out is frankly a decision of the board to make and from the management side, we&#8217;ll be ready to make sure that we build a company that is ready to go public. And we will look at various things like that of the market situation, opportunities outside and so on, that the board will consider and then potentially help advise on the timeline,” he said.</p>
<p>Alstead echoed Agarwal’s optimism, adding, “I think that <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/oyo-rooms" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="oyo-rooms">OYO <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is made up of a combination of assets, its hotels, its homes, its vacation homes. That&#8217;s unique, I think in the industry in the category, I think it makes it probably a little more challenging sometimes for people externally to measure and compare and benchmark a unique portfolio company like this. But I&#8217;d also tell you, I think that makes OYO resilient. It makes OYO balanced for the future. It gives OYO several sorts of vertical opportunities to address both customer needs at any time, whether it be a hotel or a small hotel or a vacation home.”</p>
<p>“And it also gives opportunities and expands that interaction in a good healthy way with the property owners, with the partners, who have an opportunity depending on what asset type they have partnered with OYO in different ways, and also to have the access to a technology platform and a continued investment in that innovative platform for customers. So all those things, I think a balanced portfolio, a technology platform, a heavy focus on putting the customer first, putting the business partner first &#8212; all those things, in my view, are what positioned OYO for the future.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/despite-everything-oyo-still-has-1-billion-in-cash/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080854</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
