<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:42:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Hone, a human-powered platform for leadership training, nabs $16 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/hone-a-human-powered-platform-for-leadership-training-nabs-16-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/hone-a-human-powered-platform-for-leadership-training-nabs-16-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cowboy ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the Great Resignation builds, corporations and organizations are looking for bigger and better ways to retain talent. One of the most popular ways to do that, right now, is to offer better tools around personal development and career growth to employees. Hone, a startup backed by Cowboy Ventures, is looking to do just that. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/01/great-resignation-may-be-altering-workforce-dynamic-for-good.html">the Great Resignation builds</a>, corporations and organizations are looking for bigger and better ways to retain talent. One of the most popular ways to do that, right now, is to offer better tools around personal development and career growth to employees.</p>
<p><a href="https://honehq.com/">Hone</a>, a startup backed by Cowboy Ventures, is looking to do just that.</p>
<p>The company is today announcing the close of a $16 million Series A funding round led by F-Prime Capital, with participation from Cowboy Ventures, NextGen Venture partners, Slack Fund, Gaingels, and SemperVirens.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227640" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Specifically, Hone focuses on leadership training within organizations with live, intimate online classes led by a coach. New students will enter into a four-week bootcamp, with topics selected by the company. From there, they have unlimited access to Hone classes throughout the year.</p>
<p>There are plenty of corporate training topics that don&#8217;t necessarily require live sessions, such as security and data protection. But when it comes to having tough conversations with employees, coaching them through a challenge, or leading discussions on diversity and inclusion, strong communication and interpersonal skills are absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>Hone provides a platform that gives managers the tools they need, and lets them practice those skills, without bringing them to an in-person two-day conference that has no real lasting effect.</p>
<p>Moreover, Hone&#8217;s software makes it really easy to schedule across different geographies and timezones with our now-commonplace distributed workforces, letting senior leaders at the company focus on the important stuff.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Personal development and leadership training has become an incredibly hot space in the past couple of years. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/21/chief-the-leadership-network-for-women-raises-15-million-in-funding/">Chief</a> has raised $40 million, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/medley-the-coaching-platform-for-personal-and-professional-development-gets-3-7m-led-by-a16z/">Medley</a> has come on to the scene with a fresh take around group learning, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/30/how-one-founder-turned-painful-personal-experience-into-the-solution-for-a-huge-gap-in-healthcare/">Inclusivv</a> is another player getting in on this sector.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the biggest challenges is meeting the demand we&#8217;re seeing right now,&#8221; said cofounder Savina Perez. &#8220;Global organizations are coming to us, so being able to deliver for them, thinking about localization and translation, is something that keeps me up.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cofounder Tom Griffiths added that it&#8217;s tougher to scale a business like Hone, which has so much human input, rather than a standard SaaS product.</p>
<p>Thus far, the company has attracted over 100 customers (organizations), which represents 400 percent YoY growth. Hone does 300 classes per month and has a team of 30 people, with 50 percent of the team being female and 43 percent being people of color.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/hone-a-human-powered-platform-for-leadership-training-nabs-16-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227640</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Today! Join NASA, US Space Force fireside chat on the new space age</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/today-join-nasa-us-space-force-fireside-chat-on-the-new-space-age/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/today-join-nasa-us-space-force-fireside-chat-on-the-new-space-age/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emily Calandrelli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emmy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steve isakowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thompson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning at 8:30 am PT we are hosting a live, 30-minute FREE webinar called, Full Speed Ahead: Accelerating Government and Commercial Collaboration in the New Space Age. Join experienced space leaders for this candid discussion and learn how government demands for mission success intersect with new capabilities from commercial companies. This event is free, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning at 8:30 am PT we are hosting a live, 30-minute FREE webinar called, <a href="https://hopin.com/events/full-speed-ahead-accelerating-government-and-commercial-collaboration-in-the-new-space-age" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Full Speed Ahead: Accelerating Government and Commercial Collaboration in the New Space Age.</strong></a></p>
<p>Join experienced space leaders for this candid discussion and learn how government demands for mission success intersect with new capabilities from commercial companies. This event is free, but you must <a href="https://hopin.com/events/full-speed-ahead-accelerating-government-and-commercial-collaboration-in-the-new-space-age" target="_blank" rel="noopener">register to attend.</a></p>
<p>The conversation, moderated by Emily Calandrelli, an MIT-trained engineer and Emmy-nominated science TV host, features Steve Isakowitz, president and CEO of The Aerospace Corporation; Gen. David D. “DT” Thompson, the vice chief of space operations, United States Space Force; Mandy Vaughn, the CEO and founder of GXO, Inc.; and Alex MacDonald, chief economist at NASA.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227568" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The booming space industry is evolving and expanding at an unprecedented rate. It’s the most complex, costly sector, and the traditional boundaries between national security, civil and commercial space are changing rapidly to create new opportunities.</p>
<p>Topics on the table include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Challenges to “evolving space at speed,” including key trends and drivers of change that are impacting missions and shaping this moment in space.</li>
<li>Current capability gaps surrounding specific applications, mission integration challenges and a robust workforce.</li>
<li>How to best leverage commercial capabilities at the national level to support enterprise mission success.</li>
<li>Opportunities for new space companies to partner and do business with government space programs.</li>
</ul>
<p>Don’t miss this rare chance to gain a deeper understanding of partnering opportunities to unlock new era of human achievement in space.</p>
<p>Full Speed Ahead: Accelerating Government and Commercial Collaboration in the New Space Age takes place today from 8:30 am – 9:00 am (PT) / 11:30 am – 12:00 pm (ET). <a href="https://hopin.com/events/full-speed-ahead-accelerating-government-and-commercial-collaboration-in-the-new-space-age" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Register to attend today for 100% free</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/today-join-nasa-us-space-force-fireside-chat-on-the-new-space-age/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227568</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Independent worker network Contra goes commission-free as it secures new NEA-led capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/independent-worker-network-contra-goes-commission-free-as-it-secures-new-nea-led-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/independent-worker-network-contra-goes-commission-free-as-it-secures-new-nea-led-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ann Bordetsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cowboy ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unusual Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wikis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Contra provides tools for independent workers to build a professional identity and manage their work from inquiry to project scope discussion to signing a contract to getting paid.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.contra.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Contra</a>, a professional network for independent workers, unveiled a new payment model Tuesday that lets users accept payments for their services on Contra without paying any commission fees.</p>
<p>The new feature comes as the company brings in $30 million in Series B funding, led by NEA, with participation from Unusual Ventures and Cowboy Ventures, both of which invested in Contra’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/contra-series-a/">$14.5 million Series A</a> earlier this year. The latest funding round gives the company just under $45 million in total funding, Ben Huffman, Contra founder and CEO told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Contra provides tools for independent workers to build a professional identity and manage their work from inquiry to project scope discussion to signing a contract to getting paid, all without having to pay upwards of 20% of fees that other independent work websites may charge, Huffman said.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227147" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2227149" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227149" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2227149" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg" alt="Contra" width="1024" height="408" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg 3860w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=150,60 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=300,119 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=768,306 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=680,271 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=1536,612 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=2048,815 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=50,20 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227149" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Contra</p></div></p>
<p>Securing the new funding is giving Contra an opportunity to not only work with Ann Bordetsky, partner at NEA, but capitalize on “the crazy amount of user growth post-pandemic,” as more people turned to independent work, Huffman said. He cited figures that said over 50% of people stated working independently at the start of the pandemic and more than 1 million people joined Contra to find work or hire talent.</p>
<p>“We have always wanted to roll this out, but wanted to be able to ensure the client pays and there is trust on the network,” he added. “We have users in 139 countries, and while many workers complete successful projects, they don’t get stocks or other benefits, so we want to help them collect on that stored value and make it easier to get paid.”</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the company surveyed over 10,000 independent workers for its first <a href="https://contra.com/freelance-industry-report-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">State of Independence</a> report and found that independent workers value the freedom, autonomy and financial benefits of freelance work: In fact, 86% surveyed said they work less than 40 hours per week. In addition, by having a fluid revenue stream through Contra, they are charging for per-project versus hourly, which enables them to earn the same amount of money with fewer projects, Huffman said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Meanwhile, the new funding will be funneled into hiring and continued product innovation with new products on tap to be released early next year.</p>
<p>With many people opting for the flexibility of independent work, NEA’s Bordetsky said she was intrigued by the trend and spoke with people who all had shared pain points of wanting to work in this way, yet not being satisfied by the existing marketplaces for building careers.</p>
<p>She saw that Contra was becoming a resource that “the Gen Z digital worker is excited to use” and how the company leveraged TikTok and other tools to build an audience.</p>
<p>“Ben knows those pain points,” Bordetsky added. “What was impressive was his creative vision for what the platform could do and also his practical understanding. Ben is the visionary to build this in the space, and NEA supports that Contra is following that trend.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N69kKfPuqq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/31/freelancers-rights-come-of-age-as-gig-economy-booms/">Freelancers rights come of age as gig economy booms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Freelancers rights come of age as gig economy booms&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/31/freelancers-rights-come-of-age-as-gig-economy-booms/embed/#?secret=N69kKfPuqq" data-secret="N69kKfPuqq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/independent-worker-network-contra-goes-commission-free-as-it-secures-new-nea-led-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227147</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Activeloop snags $5M seed to build streaming database for AI applications</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/activeloop-snags-5m-seed-to-build-database-for-ai-applications/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/activeloop-snags-5m-seed-to-build-database-for-ai-applications/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activeloop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer Vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[databases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Activeloop, a member of the Y Combinator summer 2018 cohort, is building a database specifically designed for media-focused  artificial intelligence applications. Today the company announced a $5 million seed investment led by 468 Capital and CM Ventures with participation from Tribe Capital, Shasta Ventures and various tech industry angels. Davit Buniatyan, founder and CEO at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.activeloop.ai/">Activeloop</a>, a member of the Y Combinator <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/activeloop">summer 2018 cohort</a>, is building a database specifically designed for media-focused  artificial intelligence applications. Today the company announced a $5 million seed investment led by 468 Capital and CM Ventures with participation from Tribe Capital, Shasta Ventures and various tech industry angels.</p>
<p>Davit Buniatyan, founder and CEO at the company says the company developed out of research he was doing at Princeton where saw the need for a streaming database of unstructured data like images and video specifically designed for AI use cases. The company is also launching an alpha version of a commercial product today.</p>
<p>&#8220;[We are] introducing a database for AI, specifically a storage layer that helps to very efficiently store the data and then stream this to machine learning applications or training models to do computer vision, audio processing, NLP (natural language processing) and so on,&#8221; Buniatyan explained.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227331" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In practical terms, this takes the form of an open source API that enables users to convert the data (video, audio, etc) into a mathematical representation that machines can understand. In addition, the API lets you track different versions of the data and finally lets you store that in a repository like Amazon S3.</p>
<p>By streaming the data, the data scientist or developer no longer has to download all of this data to a local laptop, but sends it through for use by the model in the same way that Netflix streams a movie to you, so you aren&#8217;t downloading the whole thing to your local machine.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227343" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227343" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2227343" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/visualization-activeloop-gif.gif?w=680" alt="Gif of Activeloop streaming database in action showing hundreds of images." width="680" height="383" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227343" class="wp-caption-text">Activeloop image database.<strong> Image Credits:</strong> Activeloop</p></div></p>
<p>He says that there are 55 contributors to the open source project and 700 community members overall. The program has been downloaded 300,000 times so far.</p>
<p>He came up with the idea for streaming the data while working on large amounts of data at the neuroscience lab at Princeton. He found the files were so huge, it wasn&#8217;t practical to download them, so he came up with this way of streaming them that would become the basis for Activeloop.</p>
<p>The company has 15 employees so far and is looking to hire around half a dozen high-end engineers. He says as he builds the company he is looking at diverse talent wherever it may be. He points out that his VP of Engineering is a woman. Recently the company offered a job to an Ethiopian engineer who ended up turning it down, but he says it&#8217;s an example of looking for talent wherever it happens to be.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not about where a person is originally from, or what kind of biases in terms of where in the world he or she was born. What matters is that we are on this mission. We are building this [company] to have an impact, and we do care about people on our team who are building this,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The API is open source, but the company&#8217;s commercial product, which is being released in alpha today, will be adding features on top of this such as being able to run SQL queries on the streaming data, which aren&#8217;t available in the open source product. The company is pre-revenue at the moment, but is hoping to release the commercial version in Q1 next year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/activeloop-snags-5m-seed-to-build-database-for-ai-applications/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227331</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla recalls 11,704 vehicles after identifying Full Self-Driving Beta software error</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tesla-recalls-11704-vehicles-after-identifying-full-self-driving-beta-software-error/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tesla-recalls-11704-vehicles-after-identifying-full-self-driving-beta-software-error/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autopilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[full self driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national highway transportation and safety administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nhtsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tesla voluntarily recalled nearly 11,704 vehicles after identifying a software error that could cause a false forward-collision warning or unexpected activation of the automatic emergency brake system, the National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration said. All of the affected vehicles had early access to the automaker’s “Full Self-Driving Beta,” it’s advanced driver assistance system. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tesla voluntarily recalled nearly 11,704 vehicles after identifying a software error that could cause a false forward-collision warning or unexpected activation of the automatic emergency brake system, the National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration said.</p>
<p>All of the affected vehicles had early access to the automaker’s “Full Self-Driving Beta,” it’s advanced driver assistance system. The system, which is still in beta mode and requires the driver to be attentive at all times, has been released to thousands of customers in recent weeks. Tesla said it was not aware of any crashes or injuries as a result of the software error.</p>
<p>The over-the-air firmware update, which was released on October 23, introduced what the regulator called “a software communication disconnect” between two on-board chips. The following day, Tesla said it started receiving reports from customers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227651" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“This communication disconnect can result in the video neural networks that operate on that chip to run less consistently than expected,” <a href="https://static.nhtsa.gov/odi/rcl/2021/RCLRPT-21V846-7836.PDF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the safety recall report</a> said. “The inconsistency can produce negative object velocity detections when other vehicles are present, which in turn can lead to false [forward-collision warnings] and [automatic emergency braking] events.”</p>
<p>Affected vehicles include certain Model S, Model X, Model 3 cars that were manufactured between 2017-2021, and certain Model Y models that were manufactured between 2020-2021. Tesla has released a separate over-the-air software update to address the issue and owners will be sent letters notifying them of the issue and resolution.</p>
<p>&#8220;In a matter of hours, we investigated the reports and took actions to mitigate any potential safety risk,&#8221; Tesla said.</p>
<p>The formal recall is a marked departure from the California automaker’s recent interactions with the country&#8217;s top automotive safety agency, which includes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/us-regulator-targets-tesla-on-ndas-over-the-air-software-updates/">releasing a software update for a separate bug identified in its Autopilot system</a> last month, for which Tesla did not issue a recall. NHTSA sent a letter to the automaker on October 12 asking why it did not issue a recall.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“As Tesla is aware, the Safety Act imposes an obligation on manufacturers of motor vehicles and motor vehicle equipment to initiate a recall by notifying NHTSA when they determine vehicles or equipment they produced contain defects related to motor vehicle safety or do not comply with an applicable motor vehicle safety standard,” the agency wrote.</p>
<p>The regulator has opened a separate investigation into Autopilot in August after identifying 12 separate incidents in which a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/u-s-safety-regulator-opens-investigation-into-tesla-autopilot-following-crashes-with-parked-emergency-vehicles/">Tesla crashed into parked emergency vehicles</a>.</p>
<p>Regarding this recall, NHTSA said it would “continue its conversations with Tesla to ensure that any safety defect is promptly acknowledged and addressed.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tesla-recalls-11704-vehicles-after-identifying-full-self-driving-beta-software-error/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227651</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tempo launches a $395 home fitness system the size of a minifridge</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tempo-launches-a-400-home-fitness-system-the-size-of-a-minifridge/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tempo-launches-a-400-home-fitness-system-the-size-of-a-minifridge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connected fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tempo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic drove explosive growth for the connected fitness industry, as gyms shut down and people struggled to find ways to work out without leaving their homes. Along with the likes of Peloton and Mirror, Tempo is one of the companies that has benefitted from the trend. The San Francisco-based company specializes in cardio and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The pandemic drove <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/the-peloton-effect/">explosive growth</a> for the connected fitness industry, as gyms shut down and people struggled to find ways to work out without leaving their homes. Along with the likes of Peloton and Mirror, <a href="https://tempo.fit/">Tempo</a> is one of the companies that has benefitted from the trend. The San Francisco-based company specializes in cardio and strength training through guided workouts using a system of barbells and dumbbells.</p>
<p>For many, however, there have been two primary barriers to entry: price and size. The company&#8217;s Tempo Studio product is a perfect example of those blockers, standing six feet tall and running $2,500 for the starter pack. That’s a lot of space and money to get your foot in the door.</p>
<p>Today, however, the company is introducing a much lower barrier of entry in the form of the Tempo Move.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225401" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2225412" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225412" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2225412" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="751" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg 2680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=150,110 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=300,220 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=768,563 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=680,499 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1127 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1502 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2225412" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tempo</p></div></p>
<p>The $395 system is roughly the size of a side table or minifridge, if you will. It serves as storage for 50 pounds of weight plates and dumbbells &#8212; no barbells here, for what should be obvious reasons. Up top is a “core” docking system for an iPhone. The core is effectively the brain of the system, with a processor and 1GB of RAM.</p>
<p>Once plugged in, the handset’s True Depth camera system (with lidar use at some point in the future) serves as a rough approximation for the Studio’s on-board tracking, while an HDMI cable runs the data into a connected TV. The system taps into Tempo’s existing selection of live and on-demand classes, letting users filter by those that only require dumbbells. That system runs another $39 a month.</p>
<p>The Tempo Move is available for preorder now and is set to start shipping in early December.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Tempo&#8217;s expansion of its product line comes as Peloton sees its growth decelerate as its pandemic-fueled bump to sales ebbs. It will be interesting to see if the Move&#8217;s lower price point will open Tempo&#8217;s market to include more casual exercisers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tempo-launches-a-400-home-fitness-system-the-size-of-a-minifridge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225401</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cities have a new planning tool to fold ride-sharing into public transit systems</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/vias-remix-launches-tool-for-cities-to-plan-on-demand-and-fixed-route-transit-together/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/vias-remix-launches-tool-for-cities-to-plan-on-demand-and-fixed-route-transit-together/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on demand transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Remix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ride-sharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rideco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[via]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Remix, the mapping software startup acquired by Via in March, is launching a new product designed to help cities plan how on-demand rides and fixed route transit, like buses and subways, can work together. Usually, Remix uses data to help cities plan out things like public transportation services or where to build a new bike [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__right" role="presentation" data-qa="message_content">
<div class="c-message_kit__blocks c-message_kit__blocks--rich_text">
<div class="c-message__message_blocks c-message__message_blocks--rich_text">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer" data-qa="block-kit-renderer">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper--first">
<div class="p-rich_text_block" dir="auto">
<p class="p-rich_text_section">Remix, the mapping software startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/via-buys-mapping-startup-remix-for-100-million/">acquired by Via in March</a>, is launching a new product designed to help cities plan how on-demand rides and fixed route transit, like buses and subways, can work together.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">Usually, Remix uses data to help cities plan out things like public transportation services or where to build a new bike lane. Adding this tool to the mix allows cities to model<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> which routes can be replaced with flexible ride-sharing services and which ones would benefit from increased bus or light rail service. The new software is already being beta tested in nearly a dozen cities, where planners are able to evaluate a city&#8217;s metro or bus network based on ridership, demographics and service quality while simultaneously determining potential zones for ridesharing services.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">This is the first time t</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">hat Remix and Via are offering a joint product, and it&#8217;s one that truly helps cities visualize how on-demand services, such as those offered by companies like Via, RideCo, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/plentywaka-founder-onyeka-akumah-on-african-startups-and-global-expansion/">Treepz</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/15/meet-the-startups-changing-mobility-for-emerging-middle-classes/">Swvl</a>, can become part of the public transit system. </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">While Remix&#8217;s new tool is currently focused on ways to implement shared rides, it&#8217;s easy to imagine expanding the services to include things like micromobility zone planning.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226783" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>&#8220;Previously, on-demand was kind of in its own world, siloed into special projects, and then fixed route was the purview of typical strategic planning teams,&#8221; founder and CEO of Remix Tiffany Chu told TechCrunch. &#8220;Now, we&#8217;re going to be combining those two worlds together to more holistically help cities understand the allocation of resources before implementation.&#8221;</p>
<p>Over the years, Remix has received hundreds product requests for this type of tool, particularly from rural agencies or second tier cities that don&#8217;t have a public transit system that&#8217;s robust enough to handle the city&#8217;s mobility needs, according to Chu. As cities try to reach their carbon emissions goals, they are on the lookout for ways to get communities with high car ownership to mode shift.</p>
<p>The on-demand planning tool&#8217;s smart algorithm relies on data like demographics, population density, job makeup, car ownership status, geography and land use to help cities evaluate where it makes the most sense to deploy a flexible system in the context of what public transit they already have. The goal is by no means to cannibalize public transit, but rather to enhance it, according to Chu.</p>
<p>An agency&#8217;s interaction with the tool is fairly simple. A city planner draws a zone on a map, which immediately populates relevant statistics based on data from existing flexible and on-demand services around the world, including Via&#8217;s over 500 global partnerships and nearly 100 million rides with Remix&#8217;s intelligent transport planning software.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;And you can say, &#8216;If we have the budget for 10 vehicles, what would the waiting time be?&#8217; Or if you want to say, &#8216;I want to ensure a five minute wait time for an on-demand service, maybe that tells me I&#8217;m going to need 15 vehicles instead of 10,'&#8221; said Chu. &#8220;It helps you be very logical about your resources as opposed to this hand-wavy planning which was previously how a lot of these on-demand zones were planned.&#8221;</p>
<p>In Seattle, Remix and Via have been working with the King County Metro to plan transit that links commuters with the fairly new light rail service that runs north to south, and soon, east to west. The county wants to help people get to the train service without necessarily constructing huge parking structures next to the stations, so it&#8217;s been partnering with Via to determine the best way to deploy on-demand zones around all of the new light rail station openings.</p>
<p>“Overall, on-demand planning was super helpful as a starting point for understanding where to draw our service areas and how much service we can provide with our current budget,&#8221; said innovative mobility senior planner <span style="font-weight: 400;"> Casey Gifford in a statement.</span> &#8220;As a non-service planner, I was able to draft proposals and have data-driven, educated conversations with my service planning colleagues.”</p>
<p>Miami-Dade County has been working with Remix for the past two years to redesign its whole transit network, which means there will be cuts to lower performing fixed routes that were only servicing a handful of people.</p>
<p>“I sat down next to the director and drew an on-demand zone to substitute a low-performing fixed route,&#8221; said Carlos Cruz-Casas, assistant director of <span style="font-weight: 400;">Miami-Dade County’s Department of Transportation, in a statement</span>. &#8220;I was able to show that with the same number of vehicles, we can offer better service and save resources that could be reallocated into increasing fixed-route frequency on higher demand routes.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/vias-remix-launches-tool-for-cities-to-plan-on-demand-and-fixed-route-transit-together/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226783</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Martie launches with $3M to divert shelf-stable food items from landfills</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/martie-launches-with-3m-to-divert-shelf-stable-food-items-from-landfills/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/martie-launches-with-3m-to-divert-shelf-stable-food-items-from-landfills/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food sharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kari Morris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kobie Fuller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Louise Fritjofsson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Martie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supermarkets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upfront ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Martie aims to stop food from going into landfills that are thrown away due to package changes, being a seasonal product or reaching their expiration date before purchase.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Companies are attacking food waste in different ways, from developing a better food supply chain to “skins” for produce to food sharing.</p>
<p>And today, <a href="https://martie.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Martie</a> officially enters the market with its approach to stop from going into landfills food that is thrown away due to package changes, being a seasonal product or reaching its expiration date before purchase.</p>
<p>Louise Fritjofsson and Kari Morris started the company in January to “rescue” pantry staples and offer them, initially in California, for between 40% and 70% off retail prices. The pair met two years ago. Both previous entrepreneurs, Fritjofsson from the tech side and Morris on the food side, they bonded over wanting to make better-for-you food more accessible and affordable.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227285" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Fritjofsson says there are 13 million Americans who are food insecure and have to make the decision everyday on what to eat, and are often swayed by food that is not as healthy because it is cheaper.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227288" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227288" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2227288" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Martie-Website.gif" alt="Martie" width="1024" height="511" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227288" class="wp-caption-text">Martie website. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Martie</p></div></p>
<p>They tested a few different things, including launching five food brands, but kept having a surplus of items they didn’t know what to do with.</p>
<p>“If you don’t have a sustainable approach you shouldn’t do it,” Fritjofsson told TechCrunch. “We thought we were doing the right things, but we still had a surplus. We started talking to food brands about their surplus, and they usually sell it for pennies on the dollar.”</p>
<p>Ironically, they learned that donating surplus food to places like food banks was difficult, cumbersome and the tax credit only went so far. Though brands are usually careful with positioning their inventory in normal retail channels, some 40% of shelf-stable food — around 146 tons — goes to the landfill each year, she added.</p>
<p>Taking a nod from brands that paved the way by providing imperfect or “ugly” fruits and vegetables, Fritjofsson and Morris decided to do the same, but with pantry staples like cookies, coffee, baking ingredients and snacks. Products come in 10 categories, like breakfast, bakeshop, condiments and pastas.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Since the global pandemic started over 18 months ago, consumer behavior toward <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/content/2021-online-grocery-sales-will-surpass-100-billion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">purchasing groceries online</a> became more regular and is expected to grow to $190 billion by 2024. Not only that, but with food prices increasing since September, experts say <a href="https://theweek.com/culture/1006438/this-years-thanksgiving-dinner-could-be-the-most-expensive-meal-in-the-history-of" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this year’s Thanksgiving dinner could be the most expensive meal</a> in the holiday’s history.</p>
<p>Martie comes online with over 400 SKUs and $3 million in funding from Upfront Ventures. The new funding enables the company to make new hires to build efficiencies on the website, form additional buyer relationships and develop marketing.</p>
<p>There is no subscription or membership for Martie. Consumers can go to the website, pick the items they want and check out.</p>
<p>“Our goal is to keep barriers low, so there are no constraints,” Fritjofsson said. “We even have a call-in number in Spanish and English for people who are not comfortable placing an online order.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="StFwiU2ZNj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apeel-bites-into-another-250m-funding-round-at-a-2b-valuation-to-accelerate-fresh-food-supply-chains/">Apeel bites into another $250M funding round, at a $2B valuation, to accelerate fresh food supply chains</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apeel bites into another $250M funding round, at a $2B valuation, to accelerate fresh food supply chains&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apeel-bites-into-another-250m-funding-round-at-a-2b-valuation-to-accelerate-fresh-food-supply-chains/embed/#?secret=StFwiU2ZNj" data-secret="StFwiU2ZNj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Kobie Fuller, partner at Upfront Ventures, says his firm has a history of investing in retail and consumer, with a big emphasis on startups that have an impact on the planet, including Apeel Sciences, which recently brought in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apeel-bites-into-another-250m-funding-round-at-a-2b-valuation-to-accelerate-fresh-food-supply-chains/">$250 million in new funding</a> to continue developing its plant-based layer for the surface of fruits and vegetables that is tasteless and odorless and that keeps moisture in while letting oxygen out.</p>
<p>Fuller heard about what Fritjofsson and Morris were doing and their sustainability approach checked off a lot of boxes for him. The future of food waste will require “a village of companies” and the new wave of investments into this space are necessary to elevate those successes into household names that will be the model for sustainability, he added.</p>
<p>Fuller knew Fritjofsson from a previous company and while he didn’t invest in that one at the time, he thought the concept of Martie was a hit.</p>
<p>“Here is a budding product that rescues foods while offering discounts and does it in a way that the brand is elevated,” he said. “For me, this is brilliant. I am super impressed with Louise and her team and think this is going to be gigantic.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6gb9d9HN9h"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/4-sustainable-industries-where-founders-and-vcs-can-see-green-by-going-green/">4 sustainable industries where founders and VCs can see green by going green</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 sustainable industries where founders and VCs can see green by going green&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/4-sustainable-industries-where-founders-and-vcs-can-see-green-by-going-green/embed/#?secret=6gb9d9HN9h" data-secret="6gb9d9HN9h" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/martie-launches-with-3m-to-divert-shelf-stable-food-items-from-landfills/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227285</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Autonomous delivery startup Nuro lands investment from Google, Tiger Global in new $600 million round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/nuro-lands-investment-from-google-tiger-global-in-new-600-million-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/nuro-lands-investment-from-google-tiger-global-in-new-600-million-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fidelity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nuro has raised $600 million in a fundraising round led by new investor Tiger Global Management, capital that the autonomous delivery startup will use to ramp up commercial operations. The funding has pushed Nuro&#8217;s valuation to about $8.6 billion — or some 72% higher than a year ago — according to people familiar with the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nuro has raised $600 million in a fundraising round led by new investor Tiger Global Management, capital that the autonomous delivery startup will use to ramp up commercial operations.</p>
<p>The funding has pushed Nuro&#8217;s valuation to about $8.6 billion — or some 72% higher <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/autonomous-delivery-startup-nuro-hits-5-billion-valuation-on-fresh-funding-of-500-million/">than a year ago</a> — according to people familiar with the round who requested to anonymity because they are not authorized to speak for the company. A group of mostly existing investors joined the Series D round, including Baillie Gifford, Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company, China-based venture firm Gaorong Capital, grocery retailer Kroger, SoftBank Vision Fund 1, funds and accounts advised by T. Rowe Price Associates, Inc. and Woven Capital, a venture arm of Toyota subsidiary Woven Planet. Google, a new investor, also joined the round.</p>
<p>&#8220;With the boost of this new funding, we&#8217;re turning our focus to commercializing and scaling the production of our third-generation vehicle at our new facility in Southern Nevada,&#8221; Dave Ferguson, Nuro co-founder and president said in an email to TechCrunch. He added that construction on its manufacturing facility will begin in December and is expected to be completed in 2022.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227341" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6xjH6EOttQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec-1/">The Nuro EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Nuro EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec-1/embed/#?secret=6xjH6EOttQ" data-secret="6xjH6EOttQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As part of Tuesday&#8217;s funding news, Nuro also announced a five-year partnership with Google Cloud. Securing a cloud computing platform partnership is on the to-do list of any autonomous vehicle company hoping to commercialize. Self-driving vehicles — on the road or in a computer simulation to test the technology— generates vast amounts of data, making cloud services one of the bigger costs for an AV company.</p>
<p>Under this particular deal, Nuro and Google said they will also &#8220;explore opportunities together to strengthen and transform local commerce.&#8221; What&#8217;s unclear is how this partnership and investment in Nuro fits in with Waymo, the former Google self-driving project that spun out to become a standalone business under parent company Alphabet.</p>
<p>Nuro is developing autonomous vehicle technology. Unlike others in the burgeoning segment, Nuro has focused its capital on designing and deploying a low-speed electric self-driving vehicle that transports packages, not people.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Nuro has found a steady and ready stream of investors since former Google engineers Ferguson and Jiajun Zhu founded the company in June 2016. Nuro’s Series A funding round of $92 million, which officially closed in June 2017, included Greylock, Banyan and gave NetEase founder Ding Lei (aka William Ding) a seat on Nuro’s board. Less than two years later, a $940 million investment made by the SoftBank Vision Fund helped push Nuro ahead of numerous other startups attempting to commercialize autonomous vehicle technology.</p>
<p>Nuro has also landed several<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-partnerships/"> high-profile partners</a>. The company has completed or is currently piloting its technology with a number of companies, including fast casual restaurant chain Chipotle, CVS pharmacies, FedEx, Kroger grocery stores and Walmart.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/nuro-lands-investment-from-google-tiger-global-in-new-600-million-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Magnify raises $6M for its post-sales orchestration platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/magnify-raises-6m-for-its-post-sales-orchestration-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/magnify-raises-6m-for-its-post-sales-orchestration-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brightedge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decibel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decibel Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrona venture group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oregon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Singh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In many companies, post-sales can be a bit of a haphazard process, with customer success, marketing and product teams all trying to figure out how to provide the best service to new and existing customers. With limited resources, that often means focusing on a few customers. Magnify aims to automate more of this process so [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In many companies, post-sales can be a bit of a haphazard process, with customer success, marketing and product teams all trying to figure out how to provide the best service to new and existing customers. With limited resources, that often means focusing on a few customers. <a href="https://www.magnify.io/">Magnify</a> aims to automate more of this process so that companies can reach more of their customers to drive product usage, adoption and retention. The Seattle, Washington- and Bend, Oregon-based platform today announced that it has raised a $6 million seed round from Madrona Venture Group, Decibel Partners and a number of Pacific Northwest-based SaaS executives.</p>
<p>Magnify was incubated at Madrona Venture Labs. Madrona managing director (and former Concur CEO) Steve Singh was instrumental in getting the company off the ground and will join it as Chairman of the Board.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227495" style="width: 240px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Joshua_Crossman-small.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227495" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2227495" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Joshua_Crossman-small.jpeg?w=230" alt="Magnify CEO Joshua_Crossman" width="230" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Joshua_Crossman-small.jpeg 588w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Joshua_Crossman-small.jpeg?resize=115,150 115w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Joshua_Crossman-small.jpeg?resize=230,300 230w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Joshua_Crossman-small.jpeg?resize=521,680 521w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Joshua_Crossman-small.jpeg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 230px) 100vw, 230px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2227495" class="wp-caption-text">Magnify CEO Joshua_Crossman</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227493" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company was founded by Joshua Crossman, whose experience in executive-level post-sales roles at BrightEdge, QuinStreet and, most recently, Chef taught him a thing or two about how the industry works.</p>
<p>&#8220;The amazing thing about customer success is you have this remarkable set of people that are doing heroic work to try and drive product and adoption &#8212; and they&#8217;re talking to a tenth of the users &#8212; or two or three percent of the users. And you&#8217;ve got the marketing teams off doing their great work, you&#8217;ve got the product teams doing their great work. And the [customer success] and sales organizations are acting as that integration layer. They&#8217;re stitching it all together,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The idea behind Magnify then, he explained, is to help companies to reach the large majority of customers who don&#8217;t get customer success interactions under the current system. &#8220;With product led growth and everything else, we give a set of tools to the product and success team to create a unified customer experience,&#8221; Crossman said.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s still early days for Magnify&#8217;s product and the team spent the last few months building out the initial feature set and launching a few initial pilots. But at the core of Magnify is a no-code experience that integrates customer touchpoints (think email, webinars, support tickets etc.) to automate more of the customer lifecycle.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“<span class="il">Magnify</span> solves a massive problem in the software industry, and I’m deeply excited about its potential to transform the customer lifecycle,&#8221; said Singh. &#8220;Growth and value creation for software companies is directly tied to reducing churn and increasing product adoption, and the teams running those efforts need the benefits of the modern tech stack.&#8221;<u></u></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/magnify-raises-6m-for-its-post-sales-orchestration-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227493</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fiverr acquires Stoke Talent for $95M, adding freelance management tools for employers to its platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/fiverr-acquires-stoke-talent-for-95m-adding-freelance-management-tools-for-employers-to-its-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/fiverr-acquires-stoke-talent-for-95m-adding-freelance-management-tools-for-employers-to-its-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 12:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativeLIVE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiverr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelancers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micha kaufman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[service marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stoke talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tel Aviv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommuting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TLV Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upwork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227620</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the heels of LinkedIn last week launching Service Marketplace, a competitor to freelance platforms like Fiverr and Upwork, today Fiverr announced an acquisition that speaks to how it plans to stay in the game by building in more features for its users. Fiverr is acquiring Stoke Talent, which lets companies manage their freelance teams, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On the heels of LinkedIn last week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/linkedin-rolls-out-its-freelance-services-marketplace-globally-after-picking-up-2m-users-in-smaller-us-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launching Service Marketplace</a>, a competitor to freelance platforms like Fiverr and Upwork, today Fiverr announced an acquisition that speaks to how it plans to stay in the game by building in more features for its users. Fiverr is <a href="https://investors.fiverr.com/press-releases/press-releases-details/2021/Fiverr-Acquires-Freelance-Management-Platform-Stoke-Talent/default.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquiring</a> Stoke Talent, which lets companies manage their freelance teams, for $95 million.</p>
<p>Stoke&#8217;s toolset includes features to onboard new freelancers; employers can also pay them through the platform, and accordingly track their overall freelance budgets. The idea here is to build tools that both tie in those employers more tightly into Fiverr&#8217;s freelance marketplace &#8212; Stoke will remain independently operated, but the products also will be integrated, so that freelancers hired via Fiverr can be onboarded and paid through Stoke &#8212; and also tie Fiverr more deeply into how those companies work with freelancers overall, even if they are not sourced via Fiverr itself.</p>
<p>Fiverr is now headquartered in New York &#8212; it&#8217;s publicly traded on the NYSE and is valued at $6.3 billion &#8212; but it was was founded Tel Aviv, and that makes it a neighbor to Stoke, which was also founded in the city, by Shahar Erez and Hilik Paz, and it has 30 employees. Stoke had raised just under $20 million, with investors including Battery Ventures and TLV Partners. Its last valuation, according to PitchBook, was around $44 million, representing a small but decent return for investors.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227620" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“We share Fiverr’s vision that freelance talent can help propel companies to new heights, both from a productivity and agility standpoint,” said Erez, who is also CEO at Stoke Talent, in a statement. “This is an amazing opportunity to continue doing what we love to do, but on a much larger and broader scale. Together with Fiverr, we have the ability to build an ecosystem where businesses can implement a multi-channel freelancer strategy, and provide tools for them to efficiently manage not only freelancer engagement on Fiverr&#8217;s marketplace, but those off Fiverr&#8217;s marketplace as well. There are meaningful synergies between the two companies and we’re excited for what the future holds.”</p>
<p>The deal speaks to how big players in recruitment &#8212; namely Microsoft-owned LinkedIn &#8212; are working on ways of expanding their business by moving into new and adjacent areas of the employment market. This is in turn driving some consolidation, with larger and established players in freelance services snapping up smaller companies to expand their own platforms, creating more utility and monetizable features in the process.</p>
<p>Fiverr is still well ahead of LinkedIn in the freelancer landscape: its marketplace covers freelancers from some 160 countries with specialties in more than 500 categories and nine verticals such as graphic design, digital marketing, programming, video and animation; and some 4 million customers have used Fiverr to engage those freelancers. LinkedIn by contrast covers half as many categories (with plans to expand soon to 500), with some 2 million freelancers registered; it&#8217;s not disclosing how many customers have engaged their services just yet, and it is only now opening up globally outside of a limited, closed beta that it ran in the U.S. But LinkedIn, with nearly 800 million users and a very strong presence in the wider professional networking and job-hunting markets, will be a formidable competitor in any adjacent space that it decides to tackle.</p>
<p>That is something not lost on Fiverr. Indeed, it was less than a month ago that Fiverr <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/fiverr-is-acquiring-online-learning-company-creativelive/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired</a> the online learning company CreativeLive, bringing a platform for freelancers to pick up and train on new skills to expand their employability. This was an especially poignant acquisition in light of LinkedIn launching a Fiverr competitor: LinkedIn has spent years building bridges between its online learning and professional development content and how that ties in with its recruitment and job-hunting tools. If LinkedIn is finding some traction in that area, it&#8217;s essential for Fiverr to offer professional development tools, too, to remain a compelling platform for candidates to use.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Stoke acquisition is serving the same purpose for the employer side of the Fiverr marketplace. Workflow and providing more efficient, one-stop-shop offerings is the name of the game these days in enterprise productivity, so having an option not just to source freelancers but begin the process of working with them from one place makes sense, even in cases where a company might already be using other budgeting and talent management tools already. Managing freelancers has its own complex set of requirements, which differ by country, where employing a freelancer for more than a specific amount of hours or work engagement can different kinds of tax and other issues, so the idea is that this would also help with that.</p>
<p>“The Stoke acquisition made complete sense on multiple levels,” said Micha Kaufman, Founder and CEO of Fiverr, in a statement. “It supports Fiverr’s move upmarket and allows us to engage with much larger customers; It allows Fiverr to offer software solutions to businesses that already have freelancers that they work with and now can manage them easily; It allows Fiverr to pair its marketplace talent with large customers that need access to freelancers they still do not yet have a relationship with; It gives Fiverr access to the offline freelancing market that is still orders of magnitude larger than online freelancing; and finally, Stoke is a fast-growing best-in-class product with an incredible team behind it that we are delighted to add to our family.”</p>
<p>The question now is whether we&#8217;ll see LinkedIn and others following suit and looking to build similar experiences.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/fiverr-acquires-stoke-talent-for-95m-adding-freelance-management-tools-for-employers-to-its-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227620</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ByteDance reorganization offers glimpse into TikTok parent&#8217;s future</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/bytedance-tiktok-restructure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/bytedance-tiktok-restructure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ted Cruz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toutiao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video sharing app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xiaomi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zhang Yiming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ByteDance has long been celebrated as an &#8220;app factory&#8221; for its proven model of churning out apps and monetizing them through a robust backend of shared resources, from engineering to marketing support. The result is a rank of household apps &#8212; Douyin and Toutiao in China and TikTok in the rest of the world. In [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">ByteDance has long been celebrated as an &#8220;app factory&#8221; for its proven model of churning out apps and monetizing them through a robust backend of shared resources, from engineering to marketing support. The result is a rank of household apps &#8212; Douyin and Toutiao in China and TikTok in the rest of the world.</p>
<p>In the meantime, the firm has prided itself on its &#8220;flat&#8221; internal organization with a flurry of self-governing products. As of September 2020, Zhang had 14 executives reporting to him, according to data compiled by <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/org-charts/bytedance" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Information</a>.</p>
<p>But as the firm continues to flourish, its stewards recognized that a structural shakeup is needed to fit its ballooning size. That change has come. ByteDance will group its apps and operations under six new &#8220;business units&#8221;, according to an internal document seen by TechCrunch Tuesday.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227563" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Notably, Shou Zi Chew, currently chief executive at TikTok, will no longer be ByteDance&#8217;s chief financial officer. Chew, a banking executive who previously worked at Xiaomi as CFO, joined ByteDance in March as its CFO and was made TikTok&#8217;s CEO in May.</p>
<p>At the time of his appointment as the new finance boss, speculation was rife that Chew was brought in to work on ByteDance&#8217;s initial public offering.</p>
<p>But the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/china-postpones-ants-colossal-ipo-after-closed-door-talk-with-jack-ma/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">debacle of Ant Group&#8217;s planned IPO</a> and later<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/will-didis-regulatory-problems-make-it-harder-for-chinese-startups-to-go-public-in-the-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Didi&#8217;s regulatory overhaul</a> have dimmed the prospects of Chinese internet firms seeking public listings. The other and perhaps more difficult question for ByteDance is: Which of the company&#8217;s units will be listed, and where?</p>
<p>Rubo Liang, a co-founder of ByteDance, has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/zhang-yiming-steps-down-bytedance-ceo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">taken over Zhang Yiming</a> as the firm&#8217;s CEO.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The six newly minted business units are useful indicators of ByteDance&#8217;s strategic focuses in the foreseeable future. They are:</p>
<p><strong>TikTok</strong>: This unit will manage the video-sharing app and any business spawned by it, such as the firm&#8217;s e-commerce operations outside China.</p>
<p><strong>Douyin</strong>: The eponymous app is the Chinese version of TikTok and is now officially the name of a standalone business unit overseeing ByteDance&#8217;s lucrative ad-powered content businesses in China. Xigua, which features longer videos, and Toutiao, the firm&#8217;s popular news aggregator, will be folded under the unit.</p>
<p><strong>Dali Education</strong>: Dali was created in 2020 as ByteDance&#8217;s foray into the online learning sector. It now oversees the firm&#8217;s vocational learning, education hardware (like a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/bytedance-announces-its-first-gadget-in-a-big-education-push/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lamp</a> that allows busy parents to remotely keep their kids&#8217; company during homework time), <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">and campus learning initiatives.</span></p>
<p><strong>Lark</strong>: Lark, a workplace collaboration software, is ByteDance&#8217;s ambition to put Slack and G Suite in one and part of the company&#8217;s B2B bet.</p>
<p><strong>BytePlus</strong>: This is essentially the infrastructure piece of ByteDance&#8217;s B2B endeavor. The unit sells AI and data tools to enterprise clients.</p>
<p><strong>Nuverse</strong>: It&#8217;s ByteDance&#8217;s game development and publishing unit, which also manages titles intended for overseas markets. Gaming companies in China are increasingly seeking growth abroad amid regulatory uncertainties.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vsm7m2YHjG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/12/bytedance-gaming/">How ByteDance plans to crack the gaming industry</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How ByteDance plans to crack the gaming industry&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/12/bytedance-gaming/embed/#?secret=vsm7m2YHjG" data-secret="vsm7m2YHjG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>TikTok&#8217;s identity</h2>
<p>The inception of a TikTok business unit is noteworthy. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ByteDance has been distancing TikTok from the rest of its Chinese businesses ever since concerns from the West rose over the video app&#8217;s links to the Chinese government. TikTok says it stores all its data in the U.S. with backup servers in Singapore, rather than Beijing where its parent company is headquartered.</span></p>
<p>These measures aren&#8217;t enough to appease U.S. regulators&#8217; worries. In its first-ever congressional hearing in the United States, TikTok faced<a href="https://www.cruz.senate.gov/newsroom/press-releases/sen-cruz-to-tiktok-official-you-have-dodged-the-questions-more-than-any-witness-i-have-seen-in-my-nine-years-serving-in-the-senate" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> tough questions</a> and was repeatedly asked to clarify its semantics.</p>
<p>Senator Ted Cruz pressed the firm to address whether Beijing ByteDance Technology is &#8220;part of&#8221; TikTok’s &#8220;corporate group,&#8221; a term used in TikTok&#8217;s<a href="https://www.tiktok.com/legal/privacy-policy-us?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> privacy policy</a>, which states that the app &#8220;may share all of the information we collect with a parent, subsidiary, or other affiliate of our corporate group.&#8221;</p>
<p>TikTok&#8217;s representative maintained that TikTok has &#8220;no affiliation&#8221; with Beijing ByteDance Technology, ByteDance&#8217;s Chinese entity in which the government<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/21/china-roundup-bytedance-amazon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> took a stake and board seat</a> this year. That wording did not satisfy the Senator.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/bytedance-tiktok-restructure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227563</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>137 Ventures, which buys equity from private company shareholders, just raised a new fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/137-ventures-which-buys-equity-from-private-company-shareholders-just-raised-a-new-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/137-ventures-which-buys-equity-from-private-company-shareholders-just-raised-a-new-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Secondaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[137-ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anduril]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flexport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gusto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lattice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palantir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secondaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wish]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[137 Ventures, a 10-year-old, San Francisco-based investment firm that mostly buys private company shares of founders, executives, early employees, and other large shareholders of private, high-growth tech companies, has closed its fifth fund with $350 million. It’s the largest fund the outfit has raised to date (its fourth fund initially closed with $210 million in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://137ventures.com/">137 Ventures</a>, a 10-year-old, San Francisco-based investment firm that mostly buys private company shares of founders, executives, early employees, and other large shareholders of private, high-growth tech companies, has closed its fifth fund with $350 million. It’s the largest fund the outfit has raised to date (its fourth fund initially closed with <a href="https://137ventures.com/">$210 million</a> in 2019 and later ballooned to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/19/wish-and-airbnb-and-palantir-investor-justin-fishner-wolfson-doesnt-care-about-first-day-pops/">$250 million</a>).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s certainly no surprise that 137 Ventures &#8212;  which also makes small investments in primary rounds on occasion &#8212; is chugging along. Of the roughly 75 companies it has acquired stakes in over the years, it says that 13 have gone public and that seven of the 13 have gone public over the last 14 months, including Airbnb, Wish, and Palantir.</p>
<p>It has some valuable equity in its portfolio, too, including SpaceX, Gusto, Flexport, Workrise, and Curology.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227576" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The five largest investments by dollars invested since the launch of the firm&#8217;s fourth fund in 2019 are Workrise, Wonolo, Thirty Madison, Anduril, and Lattice, it says.</p>
<p>We had a quick chat with firm cofounder Justin Fishner-Wolfson yesterday to talk about the go-go market and how it&#8217;s impacting his firm. Unsurprisingly, he said that &#8220;everything is shockingly faster,&#8221; which has accelerated 137 Ventures&#8217;s work, too. There are more companies to meet with than ever before, for example, which has meant that that the firm has had to beef up a bit and that it continues to hire.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are a lot of conversations to be had,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>With private market valuations soaring so fast, his firm is also facing unprecedented competition, he conceded. He says it helps that 137 Ventures has managed to establish a brand already. There&#8217;s a benefit to having done this for a decade. Still, while one can &#8220;win deals if people think you&#8217;re helpful and smart and you&#8217;re going to be there when times are more challenging than they are today,&#8221; market participants &#8220;do have to pay market prices,&#8221; he said, and you have to &#8220;have more coverage and to make sure people know who you are. You have to work to stay in front of everybody.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Asked if employees are more or less eager to sell their shares, given that so many startups are seeing their valuations triple and even quadruple so quickly right now, he suggested they haven&#8217;t changed all that much in this market. He says there are just more of them because there are more companies that are faring well, as well as continuing to wait on an &#8220;exit&#8221; event.</p>
<p>He also says that companies are, in some cases, allowing employees and other insiders to sell earlier in the startup&#8217;s life cycle.</p>
<p>Not last, and not surprisingly, 137 Ventures is seeing more startups put processes in place far earlier when it comes to letting insiders sell a portion of their shares. Likely they need to do this in order to retain talent but also, as Fishner-Wolfson, noted, they&#8217;ve probably learned from watching earlier companies. He pointed, for example, to Palantir, which had no real restrictions on trading. &#8220;That had some positive and some negatives,&#8221; he observed.</p>
<p>As for 137 Ventures, Fishner-Wolfson insisted it isn&#8217;t playing the market buy trading its shares as they rise &#8212; and sometimes fall &#8212; in value.</p>
<p>He estimated that its average holding period is &#8220;six or seven years&#8221; and said that the firm typically waits until a company has gone public to begin exiting 137 Ventures&#8217;s investment in it. Even then it might hold the shares a while, depending on the life cycle of the fund. Said Fishner-Wolfson: &#8220;We&#8217;re trying to invest in companies that are among the most successful in their categories, so we&#8217;re trying to invest in them for a really long time.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/137-ventures-which-buys-equity-from-private-company-shareholders-just-raised-a-new-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227576</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk says Hertz hasn’t actually ordered 100,000 Tesla EVs yet</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/elon-musk-says-hertz-hasnt-actually-ordered-100000-tesla-evs-yet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/elon-musk-says-hertz-hasnt-actually-ordered-100000-tesla-evs-yet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car rental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hertz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Model 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227609</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week, a press release from Hertz indicated that the rental company had placed an order for 100,000 Tesla Model 3s. Late yesterday, however, Elon Musk tweeted that the order is far from firm.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Steve Dent</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Steve Dent is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/nvidias-new-geforce-now-rtx-3080-streams-games-at-1440p-and-120-fps/">NVIDIA&#8217;s new &#8216;GeForce Now RTX 3080&#8217; streams games at 1440p and 120 fps</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/18/foxconn-unveils-three-new-ev-prototypes/">Foxconn unveils three new EV prototypes</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Last week, a <a href="https://ir.hertz.com/2021-10-25-Hertz-Invests-in-Largest-Electric-Vehicle-Rental-Fleet-and-Partners-with-Seven-Time-Super-Bowl-Champion-Tom-Brady-to-Headline-New-Campaign" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1">press release</a> from Hertz indicated that the rental company had <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hertz-reportedly-orders-100000-teslas-in-the-single-large-ev-purchase-ever-132633765.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">placed an order</a> for 100,000 Tesla Model 3s for its rental fleet. Late yesterday, however, Elon Musk tweeted that the order is far from firm, saying that &#8220;no contract has been signed yet,&#8221; <a href="https://gizmodo.com/elon-musk-says-tesla-hasnt-signed-a-contract-with-hertz-1847979941" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1"><em>Gizmodo</em></a> has reported.</p>
<p>Hertz&#8217;s announcement stated that it made &#8220;a significant investment to offer the largest EV rental fleet in North America&#8230; [which] includes an initial order of 100,000 Tesla&#8217;s by the end of 2022.&#8221; That release and a report from <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-25/hertz-said-to-order-100-000-teslas-in-car-rental-market-shake-up" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1"><em>Bloomberg</em></a>, combined with other good news about sales in Europe, may have motivated investors to push Tesla&#8217;s value over the $1 trillion mark.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Super <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24tsla&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$tsla</a> stonks. Thank you <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@elonmusk</a> <a href="https://t.co/L5oDtnQV1v">pic.twitter.com/L5oDtnQV1v</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227609" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&mdash; Tesla Silicon Valley Club (@teslaownersSV) <a href="https://twitter.com/teslaownersSV/status/1455268419264122882?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 1, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Hertz only left bankruptcy four months ago after being purchased by distressed-debt firm Knighthead Capital Management and other firms for $6 billion. As such, announcing a purchase of 100,000 EVs valued at around $4.2 billion obviously raised eyebrows.</p>
<p>As <em>Gizmodo</em> pointed out, though, Hertz technically never said it signed a contract or purchase order for the vehicles. The phrase &#8220;an initial order of 100,000 Tesla&#8217;s by the end of 2022&#8221; could be taken to mean that the order itself and not the vehicle deliveries will happen at the end of 2022. Tesla itself never responded to the initial news.</p>
<p>Musk&#8217;s tweet came in reply to Twitter user &#8220;Tesla Silicon Valley Club,&#8221; which was thanking him for Tesla&#8217;s recent stock price rise. He appeared to want to dampen down some of that hype, however, stating that any Hertz deal would have no impact on the company&#8217;s sales and bottom line.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Tesla has far more demand than production, therefore we will only sell cars to Hertz for the same margin as to consumers. Hertz deal has zero effect on our economics.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on<a href="https://www.engadget.com/elon-musk-says-hertz-hasnt-ordered-100000-tesla-e-vs-yet-103529013.html"> Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/elon-musk-says-hertz-hasnt-actually-ordered-100000-tesla-evs-yet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227609</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LightForce Orthodontics wolfs down $50M to straighten out that crooked smile of yours</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/lightforce-orthodontics-series-c/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/lightforce-orthodontics-series-c/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dentistry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kleiner Perkins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LightForce Orthodontics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Everyone&#8217;s set of teeth are different enough that orthodontics has traditionally been part artistry, part medical witchcraft. In the late 1990s, Invisalign changed the industry with customizable aligners, but it turns out that aligners only serve 30% of orthodontics patients. For the rest, there hasn&#8217;t been much in the way of innovation &#8212; until LightForce [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Everyone&#8217;s set of teeth are different enough that orthodontics has traditionally been part artistry, part medical witchcraft. In the late 1990s, Invisalign changed the industry with customizable aligners, but it turns out that aligners only serve 30% of orthodontics patients. For the rest, there hasn&#8217;t been much in the way of innovation &#8212; until LightForce came along and shook things up. With the snappy slogan &#8220;one size fits one&#8221;, <a href="https://lightforceortho.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LightForce Orthodontics</a> creates custom, 3D-printed brackets and placement trays for braces. In this case, more custom means better: Patients enjoy shorter treatment times, and orthodontists are able to offer tooth movement treatment plans with incredible precision &#8212; down to a thousandth of a millimeter.</p>
<p>LightForce Orthodontics has seen stratospheric growth over the past year &#8212; 500% revenue growth, while the team grew by 300%. Investors paid attention, and one investor, in particular, wanted to get its fangs into the company and place itself on the cap table. Kleiner Perkins cut its teeth in the business of orthodontics 25 years ago, making a boatload of money from its investment in Invisalign. They are back for another bite of the apple, leading the $50 million Series C round into LightForce, with participation from the company&#8217;s past investors, including Matrix Partners, Tyche Partners and AM Ventures.</p>
<p>&#8220;One thing we talk about all the time here at this company is that we put patients first in every decision we make. Everything we do always goes to the lens of &#8216;is it the best thing for the patient&#8217;. Even our all-hands start with a patient: how did we help somebody? The market we are really unlocking is the teen and adolescent market, which represents 75% of all cases in the U.S. Think about adolescent psychology: that&#8217;s when kids are forming their sense of self,&#8221; explains<span style="font-weight: 400;"> CEO and co-founder of LightForce, Dr. Alfred Griffin III, DMD, PhD, MMSc, who still practices as an orthodontist four days per month. &#8220;</span>I can&#8217;t tell you how many cases I&#8217;ve seen personally as an orthodontist, where mom will come in and say &#8216;my son gets teased&#8217; for this or for that. With LightForce, we can help that patient faster and reduce the number of appointments and reduce the amount of time they have to be out of school. We get them to a better result by leveraging technology.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226176" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/lightforce-orthodontics-raises-14m-series-b-to-correct-smiles-with-3d-braces/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">previously raised a $14 million Series B round</a> just over a year ago, and wasn&#8217;t in the market for more money just yet, but when Kleiner Perkins came knocking, LightForce decided to take the call and see if there was a deal to be made.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226222" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/toofs.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226222" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2226222" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/toofs.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="321" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/toofs.png 1815w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/toofs.png?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/toofs.png?resize=300,142 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/toofs.png?resize=768,363 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/toofs.png?resize=680,321 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/toofs.png?resize=1536,725 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/toofs.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2226222" class="wp-caption-text">LightForce&#8217;s custom bracket (left) can be placed and aligned with sub-millimeter precision, in addition to being the right shape for the tooth. A traditional bracket is shown on the right. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> LightForce Orthodontics</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We raised a little bit earlier than we had planned. There were some very well-known VCs that were keeping tabs on us that had seen us in the past, but we were a bit too early for them. Kleiner Perkins was always one that was on my mind, as one that I would love to work with &#8212; especially with Wen Hsieh himself. He has a deep background in 3D printing and hard tech. He&#8217;s done a lot of the best hard-tech deals,&#8221; explains <span style="font-weight: 400;">Griffin. &#8220;Kleiner Perkins is one of the only venture capital groups that has done anything significant in orthodontics. It was 20 years ago, but Align Technology changed orthodontics, for the better in my opinion. Two value props came out of Align Technology. One was the aesthetic benefits, which unlocked the adult segment. The second thing is the digital nature of what they do.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>&#8220;A lot of these innovations come from people who are not from the industry,&#8221; says Wen Hsieh, the partner at Kleiner Perkins who led the investment. &#8220;Alfred is an orthodontist himself, and it has made a world of difference. Because he&#8217;s a doctor himself, he already knows where to insert into their workflow. What part of their normal workflow is eliminated, what part is enhanced, how they can spend more or less time, how it impacts the dental tech, how it impacts the footprint of the office, how it impacts how often the patient has to come in, and so on. Meanwhile, Alfred is taking in the knowledge from other areas, such as from simulation and from 3D printing.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If you&#8217;re sitting here scratching your head about why people can&#8217;t just use Invisalign and be done with it&#8230; I had a very similar question. It turns out that aligners can only push, not pull. Pulling teeth down to align with other teeth is something braces are great for, but aligners aren&#8217;t able to accomplish. The other aspect is compliance: Aligners have to be worn 22 hours per day, and, well, people just aren&#8217;t very good at that. As Griffin points out: &#8220;Mom isn&#8217;t going to get mad at their teenager if the treatment is going too slowly. They&#8217;ll both blame the orthodontist.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226225" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LF-New-Packaging-19.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226225" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2226225" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LF-New-Packaging-19.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LF-New-Packaging-19.jpg 4568w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LF-New-Packaging-19.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LF-New-Packaging-19.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LF-New-Packaging-19.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LF-New-Packaging-19.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LF-New-Packaging-19.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LF-New-Packaging-19.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LF-New-Packaging-19.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2226225" class="wp-caption-text">The LightForce brackets are 3D-printed, and so are the trays they come in. This enables orthodontists to place the brackets exactly where they need to go on the teeth. The new brackets are semi-translucent, which means they appear to be the same color as the teeth, leaving them much less visible. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> LightForce Orthodontics</p></div></p>
<p>This investment is good news for teeth-havers, but it&#8217;s also great news for 3D printing fans. Orthodontics is one of the world&#8217;s biggest commercial users of 3D printing technology &#8212; Invisalign is currently the world&#8217;s biggest 3D printing company &#8212; and that trend isn&#8217;t going to change as LightForce now has the bank balance to go and buy a godawful number of printers themselves.</p>
<p>With the $50 million cash-injection into the company&#8217;s war chest, the battle for the braces can commence in earnest. T<span style="font-weight: 400;">he new funds will help scale LightForce operations and go-to-market efforts to enable more </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">orthodontic practices around the country </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to combine the digital benefits seen with aligner therapy with the tooth-moving efficiency and quality outcomes seen with braces. It&#8217;s going to be an exciting, but complex journey: Scaling an operation where every set of hybrid ceramic braces is custom-printed for each client is fantastically challenging both logistically and operationally. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Scaling, mass customization is a very unique problem that most talk about in theory, but very few have dealt with in practicality,&#8221; admits Griffin. &#8220;There&#8217;s around 200 of us in the company right now, and we will probably double that over the next year. Sales and engineering are probably going to be the biggest expenses, but in terms of headcount, we will need to grow the most in manufacturing technicians, both in terms of physical and digital manufacturing.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/lightforce-orthodontics-series-c/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226176</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EV conversion startup Opibus raises $7.5M to start bus and motorcycle mass production</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/ev-conversion-startup-opibus-raises-7-5m-to-start-bus-and-motorcycle-mass-production/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/ev-conversion-startup-opibus-raises-7-5m-to-start-bus-and-motorcycle-mass-production/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Njanja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 09:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Opibus, the first company in Kenya to commercially future-proof diesel and gasoline vehicles by converting them to electric, is set to embark on an ambitious plan to mass produce electric buses and motorcycles after unlocking $7.5 million in pre series A round. The Swedish-Kenyan company raised $5 million in equity and $2.5 million in grants [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.opibus.se/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Opibus</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the first company in Kenya to commercially future-proof diesel and gasoline vehicles by converting them to electric, is set to embark on an ambitious plan to mass produce electric buses and motorcycles after unlocking $7.5 million in pre series A round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Swedish-Kenyan company raised $5 million in equity and $2.5 million in grants in a round led by Silicon Valley fund At One Ventures,  backed by Factor[e] Ventures and pan-African VC firm Ambo Ventures. The round is the company’s first major fundraise, having previously raised capital from angel investors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Opibus told TechCrunch that it is looking to deliver its first electric bus by the first quarter of next year.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227574" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are proud to be backed by globally recognized investors providing a balance between deep-tech and emerging market expertise. We have together reached a clear strategic and visionary alignment, with the conviction that mass manufacturing of electric mobility solutions in Africa will not only make the products more accessible and affordable, but also lead to one of the largest industrialization and welfare transitions of the region in modern time,” said Opibus’ CEO and co-founder, Filip Gardler.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded in 2017 by Gardler, Filip Lövström and Mikael Gånge, Opibus has over the years specialized in auto conversions, and is now moving to full electric vehicle manufacturing, starting with motorcycles and public commercial vehicles, all while developing charging and energy solutions. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The targets and objectives we’ve set for Opibus might seem bold, however it is a mission that has become more important than ever. We have a responsibility to the coming generations and the earth [as a] whole,” said Gardler. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Already, the company has started taking pre-orders of its </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/harley-davidson-spins-out-livewire-into-a-standalone-electric-motorcycle-brand/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">electric motorcycles</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, while confirming to TechCrunch that the demand is promising. Opibus bikes will start at $1,300 depending on several features including battery capacity. The company said the competitive advantage of its product includes declining operational costs of up to 60% lower that of fossil fuel alternatives.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Going forward, the company plans to move to a bigger plant as it prepares to increase its production to serve the entire African continent.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are about giving vehicles a second life but for motorcycles we see that we won&#8217;t be able to scale fast enough if we&#8217;re converting motorcycles. And since we want to design a product that&#8217;s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">better than what is already in the market, we are building our bikes from the ground up – by designing and manufacturing them in-house,” Opibus’ chief strategy and marketing officer Albin Wilson told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to Kenya, the company’s other clients are spread out in Nigeria, Sierra Leone, Ghana, Uganda, Democratic Republic of Congo and South Africa.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A switch to electric power offers countries in sub-Saharan Africa a range of gains including a reduced cost of transport and lower carbon emissions. Countries like South Africa, Mauritius and Rwanda are already ahead of the game. South Africa has drafted a roadmap for the increased production and adoption of fully electric vehicles, while Rwanda rolled-out</span><a href="https://www.newtimes.co.rw/news/rwanda-unveils-new-incentives-drive-electric-vehicle-uptake"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">incentives</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that will make it less costly to buy and operate them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The electric mobility space in Africa represents a huge opportunity; not only to provide a better service at a lower cost to customers, but also to reduce carbon emissions and avoid deadly exposure to particulate pollution on a local level,” said Factor[e] Ventures managing partner, Morgan DeFoort.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reports show that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bolt-to-expand-ev-option-in-south-africa/">electric mobility in Africa</a> is nascent but opportunities remain vast, especially if the infrastructure to support its adoption is built. Challenges facing the industry include the initial high cost of electric vehicles, a lack of charging infrastructure, low grid power connectivity, taxation and low level of awareness about EVs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With inadequate infrastructure being among the biggest setbacks in EV adoption, Opibus has started installing communal charging infrastructure to serve public transport providers. The company plans to install the charging hubs in major towns near the country’s capital city, Nairobi, as it builds out a network that will sustain the mass transport electric buses planned for launch next year. Opibus also plans to forge partnerships with mini grid companies to ensure that its motorcycle customers in rural areas have access to charging points.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company sees great potential for electric vehicles on the continent as the price of items like the solar batteries reduce significantly. It has so far converted 170 vehicles to serve different clientele including mining companies and tour firms. Its SUV conversions reach a maximum speed of 50 miles per hour, and an off-road driving range of just over 60 mph. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For its conversions, Opibus replaces diesel and gasoline engines with electric motors and controllers, served by battery packs that are fitted with minimal modifications on the chassis.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/ev-conversion-startup-opibus-raises-7-5m-to-start-bus-and-motorcycle-mass-production/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227574</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flippy, the hamburger-cooking robot, gets more capable</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/flippy-the-hamburger-cooking-robogets-a-more-capable-successor/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/flippy-the-hamburger-cooking-robogets-a-more-capable-successor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 09:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flippy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miso]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miso Robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226639</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following its recent pilot in select White Castles, Miso Robotics today announced a new version of its hamburger-cooking robotic arm, Flippy. The new version of the robot, simply named Flippy 2, is designed to further automate simple cooking tasks for fast food establishments. As Miso notes in a release, primary staff feedback on the original [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Following its r<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/white-castle-becomes-the-first-fast-food-chain-to-test-out-the-robot-fry-cook-flippy-from-miso-robotics/">ecent pilot in select White Castles</a>, Miso Robotics today announced a new version of its hamburger-cooking robotic arm, Flippy. The new version of the robot, simply named Flippy 2, is designed to further automate simple cooking tasks for fast food establishments.</p>
<p>As Miso notes in a release, primary staff feedback on the original version is that Flippy required too much human assistance on either side of its primary cooking tasks. That includes the initial handling of the uncooked foodstuff and putting the cooked food in the holding era. Basically Flippy was replacing the need to constantly monitor and adjust the food while cooking, but not much in the lead-up or follow-through.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226641" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226641" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2226641" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Flippy-2-Dispensing-and-Placing-Fries-17s.2021-10-29-17_34_41.gif" alt="" width="800" height="450" /><p id="caption-attachment-2226641" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Miso Robotics</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226639" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Per Miso CEO Mike Bell:</p>
<blockquote><p>Like all technologies, Flippy 2 has evolved significantly from its predecessor, and we are extremely grateful for the insights collected from White Castle to truly push its development forward in a real restaurant environment. “Flippy 2 takes up less space in the kitchen and increases production exponentially with its new basket filling, emptying and returning capabilities. Since Flippy’s inception, our goal has always been to provide a customizable solution that can function harmoniously with any kitchen and without disruption.</p></blockquote>
<p>Miso says the more compact version of the robot is capable of increasing throughput by nearly a third over its predecessor, while requiring significantly less human hand-holding. The second Flippy arrives as restaurants are facing widespread employment shortages amid the pandemic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/flippy-the-hamburger-cooking-robogets-a-more-capable-successor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226639</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EV startup BasiGo debuts in Nairobi after $1 million pre-seed funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/ev-startup-basigo-debuts-in-nairobi-after-1-million-pre-seed-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/ev-startup-basigo-debuts-in-nairobi-after-1-million-pre-seed-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Njanja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 08:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BasiGo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[east africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nairobi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Electric vehicle startup BasiGo has today announced the launch of its operations in Nairobi, bringing clean energy options to Kenya’s public transport industry, currently dominated by fossil-fuel buses.  The startup plans to sell locally assembled electric buses using parts from China’s EV maker BYD Automotive, the company said while announcing it had raised $1 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Electric vehicle startup</span><a href="https://www.basi-go.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">BasiGo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has today announced the launch of its operations in Nairobi, bringing clean energy options to Kenya’s public transport industry, currently dominated by fossil-fuel buses. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup plans to sell locally assembled electric buses using parts from China’s EV maker <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/byd/">BYD Automotive</a>, the company said while announcing it had raised $1 million in pre-seed funding. BasiGo also disclosed that its buses will come in 25 and 36-seater capacities, with a range of about 250 kilometers, which it says is enough to cover daily round trips.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company is planning to enter other markets within the East Africa region after establishing ground in Kenya. BasiGo is backed by a number of investors including Climate Capital, a Silicon Valley venture capital firm, and Third Derivative, an accelerator focused on climate-technology</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226946" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;For years, diesel-powered buses have been the only viable solution for bus operators in Kenya. We are excited to provide public transport operators with a new option: state-of-the-art electric buses that are more affordable, and reliable, and reduce bus operator exposure to the rising costs of diesel fuel,” said BasiGo CEO and co-founder Jit Bhattacharya.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Owing to the high initial acquisition costs, BasiGo plans to introduce a financing model that will allow its customers to purchase its EV buses at the price of their diesel equivalents, while offsetting the balance through usage-based subscription fees. BasiGo says that they will begin the pilot program after the arrival of the first bus later in the year.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The cost of electric bus technology has come down dramatically over the last 10 years, to the point where electric buses can offer significant savings compared to fossil-fuel buses. Our goal is to help bus owners in Kenya realize these savings, and in the process, help Kenya become a global leader in sustainable public transport,” said Bhattacharya.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bhattacharya is not new to the field of electric vehicles, having been a technology leader in rechargeable (lithium-ion) batteries for more than 12 years. Over the course of his career, he worked as the CEO of Mission Motors in Silicon Valley and was also a senior manager at </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/project-titan/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Project Titan</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; the secret electric car project by Apple Inc. More recently, he served as the chief technology officer of Fenix International, an off-grid solar home system company acquired by the French multinational electric utility company ENGIE in 2018.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BasiGo’s other founder, Jonathan Green, has over the past 15 years helped companies deliver renewable energy technologies to users in Africa. More recently, he held the role of strategy and operations director at Fenix International, where he led the delivery of more than 500,000 pay as you use solar systems to customers across six markets in Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s plan to launch electric buses in Kenya comes in the wake of increasing bids for the adoption of clean energy in public transport. On-demand taxi companies like Bolt and Uber have already introduced electric vehicle options as they slowly move away from vehicles using fossil fuels, which are increasingly linked to air pollution.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.iqair.com/kenya/nairobi" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A real-time project</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">IQAir, a Swiss-based air quality technology company,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> shows that vehicles and motorcycles are the main contributors to air pollution in Nairobi. According to IQAir, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">PM2.5 concentration (fine inhalable matter) in Nairobi air is currently 1.3 times higher than the WHO annual air quality guideline value. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In general the WHO estimates that air pollution causes the deaths of at least 18,000 Kenyans every year, with other researchers confirming that a transition to electric vehicles could help alleviate the situation across Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The</span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-021-00721-7.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> SSA Nature Sustainability report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> says that a switch to electric power offers countries in sub-Saharan Africa a range of gains, including affordable transport and a reduction in emissions, with fossil-fuel vehicles contributing 12% of the region’s total emissions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And while the opportunities for electric mobility remain huge, a majority of African countries lack the necessary infrastructure to support its adoption. A lack of recharging infrastructure, low grid power connectivity and generally expensive e-vehicles remain hindrances to the adoption of electric transportation options in many African countries according to a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">UNEP</span><a href="https://wedocs.unep.org/bitstream/handle/20.500.11822/25188/EMOB_OpportunitiesChallenges.pdf?sequence=2&amp;isAllowed=y" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BasiGo’s COO, Alex Mwaura, said they will tap the country’s renewable energy resource to fuel public transportation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Kenya is unique in that we have a surplus of renewable energy which can be taken advantage of by the public transport sector to make it more sustainable going forward. Nairobi’s transportation sector is evolving rapidly, and we look forward to partnering with the government and relevant agencies to grow the infrastructure for electrified public transit.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also working to bridge the infrastructure gap are electric vehicle maker Opibus and NopeaRide &#8212; Kenya’s first fully electric taxi company &#8212; which are both setting up charging hubs across Nairobi. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Opibus is the first company in Kenya to commercially future-proof diesel and gasoline vehicles by converting them to electric. The company’s conversions are popular with tour firms, which prefer them owing to their silent nature during safaris. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">NopeaRide recently </span><a href="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.40/4pc.407.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Fact-sheet-final.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">received funding</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from EEP Africa, a financing facility for early-stage clean energy in Southern and East Africa, to build more solar charging hubs in Nairobi, making it possible for the company to increase its service radius.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other emerging EV companies in Kenya include electric motorcycle manufacturer Kiri Electric, and Drive Electric, which leases electric vehicles and provides charging station installation and e-mobility consultancy.                                                      </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/ev-startup-basigo-debuts-in-nairobi-after-1-million-pre-seed-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226946</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SoftBank-backed Indian logistics startup Delhivery files for $1 billion IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/softbank-backed-indian-logistics-startup-delhivery-files-for-1-billion-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/softbank-backed-indian-logistics-startup-delhivery-files-for-1-billion-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 05:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Addition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delhivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian logistics startup Delhivery seeks to raise about $998 million in its initial public offering, the startup said in a fling with the local regulator, joining a number of other tech startups in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market to explore the public markets. The 10-year-old startup plans to issue new shares worth $669 million, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Indian logistics startup Delhivery seeks to raise about $998 million in its initial public offering, the startup said in a fling with the local regulator, joining a number of other tech startups in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market to explore the public markets.</p>
<p>The 10-year-old startup plans to issue new shares worth $669 million, while the rest of the capital will be utilized to buy existing shares, it <a href="https://www.morganstanley.com/content/dam/msdotcom/en/indiaofferdocuments/pdfs/Delhivery-Draft-Red-Herring-Prospectus.pdf">said in a filing</a> (PDF).</p>
<p>The startup, which was valued at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/30/indian-logistics-giant-delhivery-raises-277-million-ahead-of-ipo/">over $3 billion four months ago</a>, is hoping to list at a valuation of over $6 billion in the public market, Indian newspaper Economic Times <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/startups/carlyle-softbank-to-part-sell-stake-in-delhiverys-1-billion-ipo/articleshow/87467616.cms">reported earlier this week</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227561" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Backed by SoftBank, Tiger Global Management, Times Internet, The Carlyle Group, Steadview Capital, and Addition, Delhivery began its life <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/05/06/delhivery-seriesd/">as a food delivery firm</a>, but has since shifted to a full suite of logistics services in over 2,300 Indian cities and more than 17,500 zip codes.</p>
<p>The Gurgaon-headquartered firm has raised $1.37 billion in funding over the years, according to data intelligence platform Tracxn. It reported loss of $56 million on a revenue of $514 million in the financial year that ended in March this year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227564" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227564" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2227564 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/delhivery-ipo.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="496" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/delhivery-ipo.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/delhivery-ipo.jpg?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/delhivery-ipo.jpg?resize=300,145 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/delhivery-ipo.jpg?resize=768,372 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/delhivery-ipo.jpg?resize=680,329 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/delhivery-ipo.jpg?resize=1536,744 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/delhivery-ipo.jpg?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227564" class="wp-caption-text">A look at Delhivery&#8217;s performance in fiscal year 2021. (Shared by Delhivery in the IPO filing.)</p></div></p>
<p>It is among a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/01/indias-blackbuck-raises-150-million-to-digitize-freight-and-logistics-across-india/">handful of startups</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/10/rivigo-india-seriese/">attempting to digitize</a> the demand and supply system of the logistics market through a freight exchange platform.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Its platform connects consigners, agents and truckers offering road transport solutions. The startup says the platform reduces the role of brokers, makes some of its assets such as trucking — the most popular transportation mode for Delhivery — more efficient, and ensures round the clock operations.</p>
<p>This digitization is crucial to address the inefficiencies in the Indian logistics industry that has <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/d529d48c-dc1b-11e7-a039-c64b1c09b482">long stunted</a> the national economy. Poor planning and forecasting of supply and demand increases carrying costs, theft, damages and delays, analysts at Bernstein wrote in a report last month about India’s logistics market.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.delhivery.com">Delhivery</a>, which says it has delivered over 1 billion orders, works with “all of India’s largest e-commerce companies and leading enterprises,” according to its website, where it also says the startup has worked with over 10,000 customers. For the last leg of the delivery, its couriers are assigned an area that never exceeds 2 square kilometers, allowing them to make several delivery runs a day to save time.</p>
<p>Indian logistics market’s TAM (total addressable market) is over $200 billion, Bernstein analysts wrote in a report to clients earlier this year. The startup said late last year that it was planning to invest over $40 million within two years to expand and increase its fleet size to meet the growing demand of orders as more people shop online amid the pandemic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/softbank-backed-indian-logistics-startup-delhivery-files-for-1-billion-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227561</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Korean autonomous driving startup 42dot bags $88.5M Series A to accelerate its growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/korean-autonomous-driving-startup-42dot-bags-88-5m-series-a-to-support-its-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/korean-autonomous-driving-startup-42dot-bags-88-5m-series-a-to-support-its-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 05:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[42dot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[42dot, a South Korea-based autonomous Transportation-as-a-Service (TaaS) startup, announced today it has raised $88.5 million (104 billion WON) in a Series A round of funding to advance its urban mobility operating system (UMOS). The Series A brings the startup’s total raised so far to $130.1 million. The company valuation is now estimated at $425 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://42dot.ai/">42dot</a>, a South Korea-based autonomous Transportation-as-a-Service (TaaS) startup, announced today it has raised $88.5 million (104 billion WON) in a Series A round of funding to advance its urban mobility operating system (UMOS).</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The Series A brings the startup’s total raised so far to $130.1 million. The company valuation is now estimated at $425 million (500 billion WON), a source familiar with the matter said. A spokesperson at 42dot declined to comment on the valuation. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The latest funding included participation from new investors like <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/SHG/">Shinhan Financial Group</a>, Lotte Rental, Lotte Ventures, STIC Ventures, We Ventures, DA Value Investment, and others. Returning backers also joined the Series A round, but the spokesperson did not provide their information. </span><span data-preserver-spaces="true">South Korea&#8217;s several big conglomerates, including <a href="https://www.hyundai.com/worldwide/en/">Hyundai Motor</a>, Kia Motors, LG Electronics, SK Telecom and CJ Logistics, invested in the company&#8217;s $42 million pre–Series A in September 2019.   </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227545" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The Seoul-based company will use the proceeds to advance its AI-based technology, establish joint ventures and hire staff. It has 200 employees as of October, the spokesperson noted. The company</span> also plans to expand its business through investment and M&amp;A, based on its statement. In July, 42dot <a href="https://blog.naver.com/vsquare1/222433869256">signed</a> a memorandum of understanding (MOU) with South Korean financial firm Shinhan Capital to develop a mobility financial service.</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">42dot was founded in 2019 by CEO and co-founder Chang-Hyeon Song, who is also Head of TaaS team at Hyundai Motors. In April, the South Korea-based automaker <a href="https://www.hyundai.com/worldwide/en/company/newsroom/hyundai-motor-group-appoints-chang-hyeon-song-as-president-and-head-of-the-new-taas-division-0000016648">set up a new TaaS division</a> to strengthen its mobility strategies. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The lidar-free self-driving company developed an autonomous driving software and hardware solution, AKit, which uses only two types of sensors such as cameras and imaging sensor radar to perform all aspects of sensing the environment surrounding the autonomous vehicle. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">42dot also built an autonomous mobility/logistics platform called &#8220;TAP!&#8221; that offers a raft of services across ride-hailing, fleet management, demand-responsive transport, smart logistics and more. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The company’s two core solutions, Akit and TAP!, are expected to commercialize in 2023. Its clients will be primarily autonomous carmakers and mobility platform operators, the spokesperson said. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“In the future, cities will be operated under a federated fully autonomous, self-managing, self-healing logistics and transportation infrastructure. The new infrastructure will provide a much more optical and cost-effective way to move people and goods,” Chang noted in its press kit. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1DYTBZZLrQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/weride-200-million-funding/">Chinese autonomous driving startup WeRide bags $200M in funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chinese autonomous driving startup WeRide bags $200M in funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/weride-200-million-funding/embed/#?secret=1DYTBZZLrQ" data-secret="1DYTBZZLrQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Wo06glqvra"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/wayve-the-lidar-free-self-driving-startup-raises-13-6m-from-ocado/">Wayve, the lidar-free self-driving startup, raises $13.6M from Ocado</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wayve, the lidar-free self-driving startup, raises $13.6M from Ocado&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/wayve-the-lidar-free-self-driving-startup-raises-13-6m-from-ocado/embed/#?secret=Wo06glqvra" data-secret="Wo06glqvra" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/korean-autonomous-driving-startup-42dot-bags-88-5m-series-a-to-support-its-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227545</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
