<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 16:14:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Can the military academies compete with Stanford and Harvard in venture? Two veterans are raising $50M to find out</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/academy-investor-network-usaa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/academy-investor-network-usaa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 16:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USAA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2168066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Soldier-entrepreneurs are unfortunately still a rare breed in Silicon Valley, despite the region’s origins in Cold War defense spending. While the courage and perseverance required to fight in an overseas battlefield (or the office bureaucracy on base) would seem a perfect fit for the travails of the founder, the reality is that the journey from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Soldier-entrepreneurs are unfortunately still a rare breed in Silicon Valley, despite the region’s origins in Cold War defense spending. While the courage and perseverance required to fight in an overseas battlefield (or the office bureaucracy on base) would seem a perfect fit for the travails of the founder, the reality is that the journey from solider to CEO is a long and arduous transition.</p>
<p>A couple of organizations have popped up over the years to make the leap easier. For instance, <a href="https://patriotbootcamp.org">Patriot Boot Camp</a>, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/19/patriot-boot-camp-wants-to-turn-soldiers-into-entrepreneurs/">I profiled back in 2018</a>, works in the earliest days of the startup journey to help veteran founders learn the key skills of building a company and fundraising. Yet, there still remains a lack of networking and funding that particularly targeted this group of entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>That’s the opportunity that Emily McMahan and Sherman Williams, the two managing partners of <a href="https://academyinvestor.com">Academy Investor Network</a>, saw when looking at their peers at the five U.S. service academies. The firm is targeting a final first fund of $50 million, and today announced the close of its anchor investor, insurance and financial services provider USAA, which will invest $2.5 million. Prior to USAA, the fund’s first investor was <a href="https://www.scoutventures.com/">Scout Ventures</a>, which focuses on frontier tech and <a href="https://www.scoutventures.com/people">where McMahan is a venture partner</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>McMahan graduated from West Point in 2001 right as the War on Terror began. I “went really straight into the action post 9/11,” she said. From there, she pivoted into a startup targeting the federal market, before founding Capitol Post, which taught entrepreneurial skills to veterans and their spouses and also had a co-working space in northern Virginia <a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/washington/news/2019/05/01/why-a-local-veteran-entrepreneur-nonprofit-is.html">before folding into Bunker Labs in 2019</a>.</p>
<p>“My career has always been focused around community, working with entrepreneurs, and really kind of harnessing the energy of the veteran entrepreneur community,” she said. She is based in DC, and also sits on the board of Patriot Boot Camp.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2168069" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2168069" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2168069" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1066692060.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="488" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1066692060.jpg 5576w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1066692060.jpg?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1066692060.jpg?resize=300,215 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1066692060.jpg?resize=768,551 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1066692060.jpg?resize=680,488 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1066692060.jpg?resize=1536,1102 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1066692060.jpg?resize=2048,1469 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1066692060.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2168069" class="wp-caption-text">The Pentagon, headquarters of the Department of Defense. Jeremy Christensen via Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Meanwhile, Williams hails from the Naval Academy, graduating in 2003 before going on four deployments in the midst of the war in Iraq, which started just weeks before his graduation. He ultimately ended up at Chicago’s Booth School, where he studied finance and pivoted his career into investment banking focused on M&amp;A. “I knew I needed to learn a lot,” he said. I “started investing and advising startups while as a banker, and then made made the flip to work with Emily to start AIN Ventures.” He’s based in New York City.</p>
<p>The firm’s first foray into venture was building an investment syndicate composed of alums of the five service academies, which was launched in June 2020. “We&#8217;ve got astronauts, we&#8217;ve got Navy SEALs,” McMahan said. “We really think that we&#8217;re very well positioned as a group, because we&#8217;ve all lived it on active duty, and now we continue to see it and continue to serve.” The syndicate has invested in a handful of deals since launching, including into <a href="https://info.polco.us">Polco</a>, an online community engagement platform for local governments, and online identity service <a href="https://www.id.me">ID.Me</a>.</p>
<p>“This is also where a lot of our service academy grads are excited to have a seat at that table and help these companies scale, connect, hire, all of those things,” McMahan said. “So we&#8217;re really excited to be on par with some of these other institutions — the Harvards, the Stanfords — who also have these types of syndicates.“</p>
<p>Williams said the goal with the syndicate was to work out the investment processes for the firm before turning toward a more traditional VC fund model. They kicked off fundraising in January.</p>
<p>The new fund has a two-track thesis of investing in veterans across industries while also selecting startups building “dual-use” technologies that are useful to the private sector and governments. “Civic technology, disaster tech — think FEMA — defense tech, obviously the military, intelligence agencies, and space tech. Things in and around climate that will affect constituents and governments,” Williams said as examples where he sees the firm investing. “We want the company, when it achieves maturity, to achieve the majority of the revenue outside the government.”</p>
<p>The firm centers its investing around the stage right after product-market fit, although since the veterans pipeline can be a real gauntlet, Williams said the firm will selectively invest at the pre-seed stage there.</p>
<p>The firm is also seeking to diversify the ranks of both venture capitalists and founders. McMahan said, “I’m a female, Sherman&#8217;s an African American, you know, even in the military, we&#8217;re sort of a unique team, and so we think we are also able to reach out to a much broader audience of underrepresented minorities, women, and groups, and we feel like we&#8217;re pretty attractive in terms of that as a team.“</p>
<p>USAA’s anchor investment is perhaps not surprising given the financial services company’s focus on active service members and veterans. It has made other investments and sponsorships around veteran entrepreneurship, including into Patriot Boot Camp. The company has also invested directly in startups such as PrecisionHawk and Coinbase.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/academy-investor-network-usaa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2168066</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maybe neobanks will break even after all</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/maybe-neobanks-will-break-even-after-all/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/maybe-neobanks-will-break-even-after-all/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 15:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2168047</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Neobanking has yet to show that it can generate positive, growing free cash flows over a multiyear period. But their results at least indicate that such incomes could occur in time.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>The Exchange is back after its brief hiatus. <a href="https://twitter.com/abracarioca">Anna</a> and I have some really neat stuff planned, so stick with us every morning this week. &#8212; <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></em></p>
<p>Building a consumer-facing fintech company is expensive. And if you want to build one in a sector crowded by both incumbent companies and richly funded startups, it can be <em>super</em> expensive.</p>
<p>That was the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/building-a-fintech-giant-is-very-expensive/">lesson we learned in late 2020</a> by examining operating results from a number of neobanks.</p>
<p>Neobanks are essentially software layers atop banking infrastructure, offering consumers digital-first, mobile-friendly and often lower-fee banking services. The push to rethink consumer banking is a global effort, with neobanks cropping up in essentially every market you can think of. Private investors have shown up in droves to fund competing neobanks because they have the potential to secure users &#8212; customers &#8212; that generate revenues for long periods of time.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Investors have proven more than willing to fund huge investments in growth and product at many neobanks, leading to steeply negative operating results at the unicorns. In short, while American consumer fintech Chime has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/18/chime-adds-485m-at-a-14-5b-valuation-claims-ebitda-profitability/">disclosed positive EBITDA</a> &#8212; an adjusted profitability metric &#8212; many neobanks that we&#8217;ve seen numbers from have demonstrated a stark inability to paint a path to profitability.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1995211" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>That could be changing.</p>
<p>Recent results from Revolut that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/revolut-revenue-grew-by-57-in-2020/">TechCrunch covered earlier this morning</a> show that the company had a deeply unprofitable 2020. But if we dig into its quarterly results, there&#8217;s good news to be found. Neobanks could be maturing into their cost structure at last.</p>
<p>So today we&#8217;ll parse the key Revolut financial results and look at what we can dig up from Starling and Monzo. Perhaps the somewhat good financial news from Revolut is not merely to be found at just one neobank?</p>
<h2>Revolut&#8217;s 2020</h2>
<p>Our own <a href="https://twitter.com/romaindillet">Romain Dillet</a> has a broad look at Revolut&#8217;s business <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/revolut-revenue-grew-by-57-in-2020/">here</a>, if you would like a wider lens. We only care about its raw financial results at the moment.</p>
<p>Here are the big numbers:</p>
<ul>
<li>57% <strong>revenue </strong>growth from £166 million in 2019 to £261 million in 2020</li>
<li><strong>Gross profit </strong>growth of £123 million in 2020, up 215% from 2019</li>
<li><strong>Gross margin</strong> of 49% in 2020, what Revolut described as nearly a doubling</li>
<li>2020 <strong>operating loss</strong> of £122 million from £98 million in 2019</li>
<li><strong>Total loss</strong> of £168 million in 2020, up from £107 million in 2019</li>
</ul>
<p>The gist of these figures is that the company&#8217;s revenue growth was solid, but improving gross margins allowed its gross profit to spike in 2020.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/maybe-neobanks-will-break-even-after-all/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2168047</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Porsche to make high-performance batteries in joint venture with Customcells</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/porsche-to-make-high-performance-batteries-in-joint-venture-with-customcells/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/porsche-to-make-high-performance-batteries-in-joint-venture-with-customcells/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 15:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cellforce group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customcells]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Porsche]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2168077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Luxury sports car manufacturer Porsche AG is going into the battery business. The automaker said Monday it plans to open a new factory that will produce high-performance cells through a joint venture with lithium-ion battery developer Customcells. Porsche invested in “the high double-digit millions” in the new joint venture, dubbed Cellforce Group GmbH, executive board [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Luxury sports car manufacturer Porsche AG is going into the battery business. The automaker said Monday it plans to open a new factory that will produce high-performance cells through a joint venture with lithium-ion battery developer Customcells.</p>
<p>Porsche invested in “the high double-digit millions” in the new joint venture, dubbed Cellforce Group GmbH, executive board member Michael Steiner told reporters in a media briefing ahead of the announcement. The factory also benefited from a €60 million ($71.4 million) investment from the German government and the state of Baden-Württemberg, where it will be located. Chemical company BASF SE was selected to supply the cathode materials.</p>
<p>The batteries will use silicon as the anode material, which Porsche says will significantly boost the energy density and their capacity to withstand high temperatures &#8212; both important variables for racing cars, which must be recharged quickly, but challenging in battery production (batteries don’t tend to like getting very hot).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For that reason, the factory will be small-scale, at least compared to other automakers such as the 35 gigawatt-hour “gigafactory” capacity at the Tesla and Panasonic joint facility in Sparks, Nevada or even its parent company VW&#8217;s plan to bring<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/volkswagen-will-bring-240-gigawatt-hours-of-battery-production-capacity-to-europe-by-2030/"> 240 GwH of production to Europe by 2030</a>. Porsche and Customcells&#8217; aim is an annual capacity of 100 megawatt-hours, or around enough batteries for 1,000 vehicles, starting in 2024. The initial workforce is expected to grow from around 13 people to up to 80 by 2025.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XMCthUUS5n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/volkswagen-will-bring-240-gigawatt-hours-of-battery-production-capacity-to-europe-by-2030/">Volkswagen will bring 240 gigawatt hours of battery production capacity to Europe by 2030</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Volkswagen will bring 240 gigawatt hours of battery production capacity to Europe by 2030&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/volkswagen-will-bring-240-gigawatt-hours-of-battery-production-capacity-to-europe-by-2030/embed/#?secret=XMCthUUS5n" data-secret="XMCthUUS5n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The automaker has no plans to scale the technology for use in Porsche’s more mainstream lineup of vehicles, Steiner said, though he noted that there may be a chance for higher volume in the future if the company sees a potential to bring down production costs. “In this market, we are looking for special purpose cells for high-end cars and motorsports, and this is not available in the market today,” he said.</p>
<p>It may be a challenge to scale this technology to passenger vehicles. The silicon anode-based cell chemistry has not shown the capacity to function in very cold conditions or to remain stable over many charging cycles, Porsche said in a statement. But it wouldn’t be the first time that a Porsche vehicle benefited from technology developed for the race track: its leading electric model <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/porsche-taycan/">Taycan</a> borrowed many of its technical features from the Porsche 919 Hybrid racing car.</p>
<p>Although the first vehicles to use these batteries will be Porsche-made, Steiner said the technology will be made available to other brands in the Volkswagen Group, like Lamborghini or Bugatti.</p>
<p>“The battery cell is the combustion chamber of the future,” Porsche CEO Oliver Blume said in a statement Monday. “This joint venture allows us to position ourselves at the forefront of global competition in developing the most powerful battery cell and make it the link between the unmistakable Porsche driving experience and sustainability. This is how we shape the future of the sports car.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mh3Tz0Iq4N"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/giving-ev-batteries-a-second-life-for-sustainability-and-profit/">Giving EV batteries a second life for sustainability and profit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Giving EV batteries a second life for sustainability and profit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/giving-ev-batteries-a-second-life-for-sustainability-and-profit/embed/#?secret=mh3Tz0Iq4N" data-secret="mh3Tz0Iq4N" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/porsche-to-make-high-performance-batteries-in-joint-venture-with-customcells/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2168077</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden&#8217;s executive order on cybersecurity should include behavior transparency</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/bidens-executive-order-on-cybersecurity-should-include-behavior-transparency/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/bidens-executive-order-on-cybersecurity-should-include-behavior-transparency/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 14:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colonial pipeline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extrahop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software vendors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarWinds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain attack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The cyber executive order, alongside sanctions on Russia, are strong indications the Biden administration intends to take a far more proactive approach to cybersecurity. But it's not quite enough.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Ben Higgins</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ExtraHop">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/benjaminhiggins/">Ben Higgins </a>is a distinguished software engineer at cybersecurity company <a href="https://www.extrahop.com/">ExtraHop</a> and has extensive experience in protocols, parsing, encryption, security, systems and performance engineering. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The Biden administration this spring announced <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/12/executive-order-on-improving-the-nations-cybersecurity/">an executive order</a> designed to strengthen government cybersecurity defenses in the wake of several major recent hacks, including the SolarWinds, Microsoft Exchange Server and Pulse Secure incidents, which impacted numerous federal agencies and private companies. The order’s importance was underscored by the DarkSide ransomware attack on Colonial Pipeline just a few weeks later.</p>
<p>One key element of the cyber executive order is a “software bill of materials” (SBOM) that vendors would be required to provide as part of the federal procurement process. The SBOM would detail the exact software components utilized in a given product, including any open-source components, making it much easier and faster for federal agencies to determine whether they are subject to a vulnerability uncovered in one of these components.</p>
<p>The SBOM is an important step in shoring up federal cybersecurity, but it’s not enough. Understanding the software components included in various products will help agency security teams react more quickly when vulnerabilities come to light, but in other scenarios, like SolarWinds-style supply-chain attacks that surreptitiously insert software components, its impact is limited.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Establishing standards at the federal level for disclosures about software products will benefit cybersecurity in the private sector, as well as improve the overall security of the software supply chain.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>That’s why the Biden administration should extend the cyber executive order to include not only an SBOM, but also “behavior transparency.”</p>
<p>Transparency requirements are not a new concept in technology. Certificate transparency (CT) is a public ledger of all certificates issued by any public certificate authority (CA) that provides a framework for monitoring and auditing CA activity, while Apple’s recently announced <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/apptrackingtransparency">App Tracking Transparency</a> allows users to see what activity apps are tracking and opt out. Behavior transparency is a proposed application of this concept to known software behaviors.</p>
<p>The purpose of a behavior transparency framework is to enumerate the expected actions of interest that a given piece of software will take on a device or on the network. This helps security analysts distinguish between expected noise and indications of compromise. This, in turn, can give security teams an advantage in identifying the exploitation of unknown vulnerabilities in any proprietary or open-source software.</p>
<p>The good news is that the enumeration of common software behaviors is already a standard industry practice for external network activity. Most major software vendors, including <a href="https://documentation.meraki.com/General_Administration/Other_Topics/Upstream_Firewall_Rules_for_Cloud_Connectivity">Meraki</a>, <a href="https://kc.mcafee.com/corporate/index?page=content&amp;id=KB93324">McAfee</a>, <a href="https://community.tenable.com/s/article/Why-do-I-see-connections-to-chk-l2">Tenable</a>, <a href="https://support.goto.com/webinar/help/optimal-firewall-configuration-g2w060025">LogMeIn/GoToMeeting</a>, and my own company, <a href="https://docs.extrahop.com/current/eh-cloud-services/#open-access-to-cloud-services">ExtraHop</a>, already publish lists of common product behaviors. Even <a href="https://documentation.solarwinds.com/en/success_center/orionplatform/content/core-solarwinds-port-requirements.htm">SolarWinds has documentation</a> describing its network behaviors.</p>
<p>But the Biden administration can help effect critical changes that improve upon this industry practice and improve the overall security posture for public and private organizations alike.</p>
<h2>Establish standards for behavior transparency</h2>
<p>First, the cyber executive order should form a working group in partnership with representative software and security software vendors, as well as organizations such as <a href="https://www.mitre.org/">MITRE</a>, to create standards for the types of network activity that must be included for full behavior transparency.</p>
<p>At a minimum, this should include things like external network destinations, internal network connection behavior with other software components, and, where applicable, a list of associated network ports and the purposes for which those ports are used. The behavior transparency framework should also include other network behavior, especially (but not limited to) anything that looks like scanning or reconnaissance behavior.</p>
<h2>Make behavioral data available to common security tools</h2>
<p>Second, the cyber executive order should mandate that known software behaviors be published in a machine-readable format such as JSON or CSV that could be ingested into common security products like security information and event management (SIEM), firewalls, endpoint protection platforms, network detection and response, and change management tools.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RRizKLr0g9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/enterprise-security-attackers-are-one-password-away-from-your-worst-day/">Enterprise security attackers are one password away from your worst day</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Enterprise security attackers are one password away from your worst day&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/enterprise-security-attackers-are-one-password-away-from-your-worst-day/embed/#?secret=RRizKLr0g9" data-secret="RRizKLr0g9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This is a crucial distinction from the current model, in which most behaviors are listed on a webpage or in a PDF that isn’t machine-readable. With this change, common security tools could use that machine-readable behavioral data to help build baselines for activity within an organization to more quickly and accurately detect deviations that indicate compromise. Meraki is already doing this by providing its list in CSV format.</p>
<h2>Centralize access to behavioral information</h2>
<p>Third, the cyber executive order should establish a clearinghouse for behavior transparency data, administered by the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency or another appropriate federal agency. The status quo is to hunt around on a vendor’s website, consult their in-product documentation or open a support case to find out about network behavior. If the information provided is incorrect, that’s also a support case.</p>
<p>The current decentralized approach is deeply problematic. Unfettered network access for enterprise software products introduces substantial security risk &#8212; Zero Trust frameworks have been established to prevent precisely this &#8212; but typical practitioners do not have the time or expertise to individually track down the expected behaviors of each piece of enterprise software they have in the environment. Without centralized access to behavior transparency data, even the best Zero Trust implementations will have major gaps surrounding enterprise software.</p>
<p>A clearinghouse would provide a centralized repository for behavior transparency data, organized by company, product and product version. A forum like GitHub is an ideal mechanism for such a clearinghouse, providing a widely used, centralized repository for this information.</p>
<h2>Streamline feedback between users and vendors</h2>
<p>Fourth, the clearinghouse should include a mechanism by which product users can easily provide feedback to software vendors. Feedback can be in the form of issues or even pull requests, though the companies should be involved in approving changes. This way, deficiencies in the behaviors can be pointed out in a public forum. Most deficiencies will be for reasons like a product update that wasn’t reflected in the behavior transparency data, though as time goes on, companies will ideally make it a practice to make sure these are kept up to date. But there will also be true positives found.</p>
<h2>Protecting the software supply chain with behavior transparency</h2>
<p>The SolarWinds software supply chain attack, first disclosed in December 2020, illustrates and underscores the importance of behavior transparency. Prior to December 11, when FireEye first identified the vulnerability in the SolarWinds Orion software, at least two other cybersecurity companies, <a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/solarstorm-supply-chain-attack-timeline/">Palo Alto</a> and <a href="https://fidelissecurity.com/threatgeek/data-protection/ongoing-analysis-solarwinds-impact/">Fidelis</a>, identified that their SolarWinds installations communicating with the attacker-controlled “stage 1” avsvmcloud[.]com domain. Palo Alto observed and blocked additional malicious behavior, but at the time neither company determined that the communication with avsvmcloud[.]com itself was suspect. That’s due in large part to the notorious amount of “noise” involved in looking at network data.</p>
<p>But if more organizations had ready access to SolarWinds’ behavior transparency data, as well as a forum in which to compare deviations from the baseline, things might have played out differently.</p>
<p>SolarWinds Orion doesn’t reach out to a lot of external destinations, so when the first stage of the supply chain attack started hitting subdomains off of “appsync-api.eu-west-1.avsvmcloud[.]com,” an analyst on a threat hunt running a SIEM query, or a machine-learning-based EDR or NDR product armed with that information, might have more quickly determined that something was amiss.</p>
<p>Likewise, a low-friction public feedback mechanism could have tipped off SolarWinds and the industry that what seemed like noise in isolation (“appsync-api, seems legit?”) was actually something far more nefarious.</p>
<p>The cyber executive order, alongside the sanctions on Russia, are strong early indications that the Biden administration intends to take a far more proactive approach to cybersecurity. Critical to the success of these efforts will be the partnership the administration forges with private-sector technology providers. Establishing standards at the federal level for disclosures about software products will benefit cybersecurity in the private sector, as well as improve the overall security of the software supply chain.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VycnOjojFq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/bring-cisos-into-the-c-suite-to-bake-cybersecurity-into-company-culture/">Bring CISOs into the C-suite to bake cybersecurity into company culture</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bring CISOs into the C-suite to bake cybersecurity into company culture&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/bring-cisos-into-the-c-suite-to-bake-cybersecurity-into-company-culture/embed/#?secret=VycnOjojFq" data-secret="VycnOjojFq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/bidens-executive-order-on-cybersecurity-should-include-behavior-transparency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166941</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seed is not the new Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/seed-is-not-the-new-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/seed-is-not-the-new-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 14:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angel Investor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News and Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seed money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Most Series A investors today look for around $2 million in annual recurring revenues (ARR) before they lean in, but getting to that figure is a very long and thorny path.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Andy Stinnes</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/cloudappsvc">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andystinnes/">Andy Stinnes</a>, general partner at <a href="https://www.cloudappscapital.com/">Cloud Apps Capital Partners</a>, leads early-stage investments in cloud business companies and serves as active board member and adviser, offering operational support for portfolio companies based on his 20+ years in executive roles in business software.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The incredible success of the cloud business applications space in recent years has driven up valuations and fundraising across all stages of venture investment. That has in turn increased VC fund sizes, led to massive cloud IPOs and brought a new cadre of investors to further fuel the fire.</p>
<p>The median Series A raised by cloud companies these days is about $8 million and can often go well above $10 million, according to PitchBook data from the first quarter of 2021. Series Cs now routinely include secondary capital for founders, and many Series Ds are above $100 million with valuations in the billions.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			There is a widening gap in the funding continuum between angel/seed funding at inception and the new-age $10 million Series A at $2 million in ARR.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Such an influx of capital and interest has upended many structures and long-held norms about how startups are funded. Venture funds continue to grow and must write larger checks, but ever-higher valuations force many firms to hunt for opportunities earlier. The VC alphabet soup has been spilled, making A rounds look like Bs used to, and the Bs seem like the Cs of old.</p>
<p>Which begs an interesting question: Is the seed round the new Series A?</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t think so.</p>
<p>Seed rounds have certainly grown — averaging about $3 million nowadays from around $1 million to $2 million previously — but otherwise, seed investments are the same as before and remain very different from Series As.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/seed-is-not-the-new-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166840</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: China hates crypto, and the Vision Fund&#8217;s vision lives on</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/equity-monday-china-hates-crypto-and-the-vision-funds-vision-lives-on/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/equity-monday-china-hates-crypto-and-the-vision-funds-vision-lives-on/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 14:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vision Fund]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2168042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our live show is this week! And we're very excited about it! It's free, of course, so swing by and hang with us.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/83e58c97-5b25-4254-9f3e-23c166d3bb46?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a> and myself <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">here</a>.</p>
<p>Our live show is this week! And we&#8217;re very excited about it! Details <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/register-to-watch-a-livestream-recording-of-equity/">here</a>, and you can register <a href="https://hopin.com/events/tc-equity-live">here</a>. It&#8217;s free, of course, so swing by and hang with us.</p>
<p>Back on theme, we had a lot to get through this morning, so inside the show you can find the following and more:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Chinese cryptocurrency clampdown is a big damn deal: With lots of the nation&#8217;s mining capacity heading offline, there&#8217;s a scramble to relocate rigs and generally figure out what a crypto market sans China might look like.</li>
<li>In the wake of the news, the value of cryptocurrencies fell. As did shares of Coinbase this morning in pre-market trading.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebook-officially-launches-live-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-in-the-u-s/">Facebook&#8217;s Clubhouse rival is out</a>. The American social giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/spotify-launches-its-live-audio-app-and-clubhouse-rival-spotify-greenroom/">follows Spotify</a> into the live-audio market. You have to give it to modern software companies, who thought that they could be both leading tech shops and Kinko&#8217;s clones at the same time?</li>
<li>Revolut is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/revolut-revenue-grew-by-57-in-2020/">unprofitable as hell</a> but increasingly less so. That could be good news for fintech as a whole.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/20/crypto-finance-startup-amber-group-raises-100m-at-1b-valuation/">Amber Group raised $100 million</a>; <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/forto-raises-240-million-in-funding-led-by-softbank-vision-fund-2-at-1-2-billion-valuation-301316198.html">Forto raised $240 million</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>See you this Thursday at the live show!</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 AM PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jVZJYjlweo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/register-to-watch-a-livestream-recording-of-equity/">Register to watch a livestream recording of the Equity podcast!</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Register to watch a livestream recording of the Equity podcast!&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/register-to-watch-a-livestream-recording-of-equity/embed/#?secret=jVZJYjlweo" data-secret="jVZJYjlweo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/equity-monday-china-hates-crypto-and-the-vision-funds-vision-lives-on/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2168042</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hyundai completes deal for controlling interest in Boston Dynamics</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/hyundai-completes-deal-for-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/hyundai-completes-deal-for-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 13:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2168046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hyundai this morning announced that it has completed its acquisition of Boston Dynamics. The deal, which values the innovative robotics company at $1.1 billion, was announced in late-2020. The companies have not disclosed any future financial details. The South Korean automotive giant now owns a controlling interest in Boston Dynamics, previously belonging to SoftBank. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hyundai this morning announced that it has completed its acquisition of Boston Dynamics. The deal, which values the innovative robotics company at $1.1 billion, was announced in late-2020. The companies have not disclosed any future financial details.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The South Korean automotive giant now owns a controlling interest in Boston Dynamics, previously belonging to SoftBank. The Japanese investment company was effectively a transitional owner, purchasing Boston Dynamics from Google, which owned the company for just over three years.</span></p>
<p>While its time with Softbank wasn’t much longer than its stint under Google/Alphabet X, Boston Dynamics saw the commercialization of its first two products since launching nearly 30 years ago. The company brought its quadrupedal robot Spot to market and this year announced the (still upcoming) <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/this-is-boston-dynamics-next-commercial-robot/">launch of Stretch</a>, an updated version of its warehouse robot, Handle.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In a recent appearance at TechCrunch’s Mobility event, Hyundai’s Ernestine Fu discussed the planned acquisition of an 80% controlling interest in the company. Fu noted that Hyundai&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/hyundai-shrinks-its-walking-car-robot-to-carry-cargo-get-rides-from-drones/">New Horizon Studios</a> has previewed multiple “walking” car concepts that look poised to build on decades of Boston Dynamics research.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qsjxNoJ3iF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/hyundai-shrinks-its-walking-car-robot-to-carry-cargo-get-rides-from-drones/">Hyundai shrinks its &#8216;walking car&#8217; robot to carry cargo, get rides from drones</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hyundai shrinks its &#8216;walking car&#8217; robot to carry cargo, get rides from drones&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/hyundai-shrinks-its-walking-car-robot-to-carry-cargo-get-rides-from-drones/embed/#?secret=qsjxNoJ3iF" data-secret="qsjxNoJ3iF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“With New Horizon Studios, the mandate is reimagining what you can do when you combine robotics with traditional wheeled locomotion, like walking robots and walking vehicles,” Fu told TechCrunch. “Obviously the technology that [Boston Dynamics] has put together plays a key role in enabling those sorts of concepts to come to life.”</p>
<p>As it has changed hands over the years, Boston Dynamics has long insisted on maintaining its own research wing, which has given us less commercial technology, like the humanoid robot, Atlas. How this will function under the umbrella of Hyundai remains to be seen, though the company does seem to have a vested interest in maintaining a forward-looking approach.</p>
<p>“We and Hyundai share a view of the transformational power of mobility and look forward to working together to accelerate our plans to enable the world with cutting-edge automation, and to continue to solve the world’s hardest robotics challenges for our customers,&#8221; Boston Dynamics CEO Rob Playter said when the deal was announced.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CsNbi7MIyd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/experts-from-ford-toyota-and-hyundai-outline-why-automakers-are-pouring-money-into-robotics/">Experts from Ford, Toyota and Hyundai outline why automakers are pouring money into robotics</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Experts from Ford, Toyota and Hyundai outline why automakers are pouring money into robotics&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/experts-from-ford-toyota-and-hyundai-outline-why-automakers-are-pouring-money-into-robotics/embed/#?secret=CsNbi7MIyd" data-secret="CsNbi7MIyd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/hyundai-completes-deal-for-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2168046</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Music licensing marketplace Songtradr raises $50M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/music-licensing-marketplace-songtradr-raises-50m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/music-licensing-marketplace-songtradr-raises-50m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aware Super]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greencape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perennial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[songtradr]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Music licensing marketplace Songtradr this morning announced a $50 million Series D. The oversubscribed round &#8212; which features Regal, Aware Super, Perennial, Argo and Greencape &#8212; follows a $30 million raise last August, bringing the Los Angeles company’s total funding to north of $100 million. The platform licenses music to high-profile names for advertising, films, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Music licensing marketplace Songtradr this morning announced a $50 million Series D. The oversubscribed round &#8212; which features Regal, Aware Super, Perennial, Argo and Greencape &#8212; follows a<a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=songtradr+series+c&amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enUS953US953&amp;oq=songtradr+series+c&amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.5233j0j7&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8"> $30 million raise last August</a>, bringing the Los Angeles company’s total funding to north of $100 million.</p>
<p>The platform licenses music to high-profile names for advertising, films, TV, gaming and the like, including Disney, Netflix, Apple, Coca-Cola, Amazon and Google. It hosts songs from some 600,000 musicians/songwriters/rights holders.</p>
<p>The service hasn’t had any issue spending its funding to date. Earlier this month, it announced the<a href="https://www.adweek.com/agencies/b2b-licensing-platform-songtradr-acquires-creative-music-agency-massivemusic/"> acquisition of creative agency MassiveMusic</a>. Other acquisitions made in the past year include Cuesongs, Song Zu, Pretzel and Tunefind.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company says the new funding will go toward even more M&amp;As, new products and an increase in global headcount. The company is headquartered in LA, but also has offices in Europe and the Asia-Pacific region.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2168039" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2168039" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2168039" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-21-at-8.52.49-AM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-21-at-8.52.49-AM.jpg 3026w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-21-at-8.52.49-AM.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-21-at-8.52.49-AM.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-21-at-8.52.49-AM.jpg?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-21-at-8.52.49-AM.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-21-at-8.52.49-AM.jpg?resize=1536,1022 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-21-at-8.52.49-AM.jpg?resize=2048,1363 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-21-at-8.52.49-AM.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2168039" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Songtradr</p></div></p>
<p>“Songtradr is rapidly accelerating as we continue to develop our tech-enabled B2B music ecosystem and integrate our new acquisitions,” CEO Paul Wiltshire said in a press release. “Attracting such a blue-chip investor base into this round further endorses our vision of the future music industry in this rapidly evolving digital world, providing a strong foundation for the future.”</p>
<p>Wiltshire adds that the company saw a 100% y-o-y revenue growth for 2020.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jqtfPZWNvj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/generative-algorithms-are-redefining-the-intersection-of-software-and-music/">Generative algorithms are redefining the intersection of software and music</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Generative algorithms are redefining the intersection of software and music&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/generative-algorithms-are-redefining-the-intersection-of-software-and-music/embed/#?secret=jqtfPZWNvj" data-secret="jqtfPZWNvj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/music-licensing-marketplace-songtradr-raises-50m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167555</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buy now, pay later startup Kredivo doubles its debt facility from Victory Park Capital to $200M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/buy-now-pay-later-startup-kredivo-doubles-its-debt-facility-from-victory-park-capital-to-200m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/buy-now-pay-later-startup-kredivo-doubles-its-debt-facility-from-victory-park-capital-to-200m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 13:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buy now pay later]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FinAccel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kredivo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victory Park Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kredivo announced today it has secured another $100 million debt facility from Victory Park Capital (VPC). This doubles the Indonesian digital lending and credit platform’s total warehouse financing facility from VPC to $200 million. The first round was closed in July 2020. Kredivo is operated by Singapore-based fintech FinAccel. This is the largest loan facility [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.kredivo.com/">Kredivo</a> announced today it has secured another $100 million debt facility from Victory Park Capital (VPC). This doubles the Indonesian digital lending and credit platform’s total warehouse financing facility from VPC to $200 million. The <a href="https://www.victoryparkcapital.com/news/2020/11/24/kredivo-secures-100m-debt-facility-from-victory-park-capital-to-boost-indonesian-expansion/">first round </a>was closed in July 2020.</p>
<p>Kredivo is operated by Singapore-based fintech FinAccel. This is the largest loan facility it has raised so far, and is VPC’s biggest debt commitment to a fintech company outside of the United States and Europe, as well as its only investment in Southeast Asia. Kredivo will use the debt facility to help achieve its goal of serving 10 million customers in Indonesia.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IfhTAli01S"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/24/finaccel-raises-30m/">Kredivo raises $30M to build a digital credit card for Southeast Asia</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kredivo raises $30M to build a digital credit card for Southeast Asia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/24/finaccel-raises-30m/embed/#?secret=IfhTAli01S" data-secret="IfhTAli01S" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Other notable startups that have received debt financing from VPC include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/berlins-razor-group-raises-400m-to-buy-and-scale-amazon-marketplace-merchants/">Razor Group</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/factory14-raises-200m-to-jump-into-the-amazon-marketplace-roll-up-race/">factory 14</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/26/latin-america-roundup-softbank-bets-on-brazillian-unicorns-and-konfio-raises-250m-for-lending-plans/">Konfio</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/26/ipo-on-horizon-subprime-lending-startup-elevate-adds-545m-in-credit-from-victory-park-capital/">Elevate</a>.</p>
<p>Kredivo has more than three million customers and offers two main types of lending products: zero-interest 30-day &#8220;‘buy now, pay later&#8221; financing for e-commerce and offline purchases, and three-, six- and 12-month installment loans with an interest rate of 2.6% a month, or a maximum annual rate of 53.36%. Kredivo chief executive officer Akshay Garg told TechCrunch that its &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; services are typically used for small-value online purchases, while installment loans are used to finance bigger transactions, like laptops, home renovation or medical care.</p>
<p>While &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; services like Klarna, Afterpay or Affirm offer convenience to customers in the United States or Europe, in emerging markets it also serves as a tool to build credit, especially in countries that have low credit card penetration, Garg said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Yfug2FuoRD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/as-buy-now-pay-later-startups-keep-raising-capital-a-dive-into-klarna-afterpay-and-affirms-earnings/">As buy now, pay later startups keep raising capital, a dive into Klarna, Afterpay and Affirm&#8217;s earnings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As buy now, pay later startups keep raising capital, a dive into Klarna, Afterpay and Affirm&#8217;s earnings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/as-buy-now-pay-later-startups-keep-raising-capital-a-dive-into-klarna-afterpay-and-affirms-earnings/embed/#?secret=Yfug2FuoRD" data-secret="Yfug2FuoRD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“Credit is one of the largest and most complex areas of the financial services ecosystem and the fact is that Indonesia is deeply underserved on that equation,” he said. Most banks only provide secured lending, like home or car loans, and unsecured lending is rare. Garg said there are only eight million credit card holders in Indonesia, which has a population of 270.6 million, and that number has not changed in 13 years.</p>
<p>One of the reasons for Indonesia&#8217;s very low credit card penetration rate is because banks are reluctant to give unsecured loans, especially to younger customers.</p>
<p>“What we’re solving is less a convenience problem and more an access problem. We’re putting unsecured credit, or the ability to buy on credit, in the hands of urban millennials for the first time, simply because banks are just not providing them access to credit cards,&#8221; said Garg.</p>
<p>He added that Kredivo’s effective risk-scoring model allows to charge low interest rates, and its non-performing loan ratio is in the low single-digits, despite the economic impact of COVID-19, which Garg described as a “trial by fire.”</p>
<p>Like credit cards from banks, Kredivo also reports customers’ loan histories to Indonesia’s credit bureaus, so they can build credit scores. “What we’re doing is building Indonesia’s first real digital credit bureau from the ground up, and I think our risk metrics show that this is not just for the sake of some funky innovation, but something that is delivering real performance,” Garg said.</p>
<p>In a statement, VPC partner Gordon Watson said, “We have been impressed with the resilience and growth of the business and look forward to deepening our partnership with Kredivo. The company presents a unique combination of growth, scale, risk management and financial inclusion in one of the most exciting emerging markets in the world.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="I9eaOks640"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/making-sense-of-klarna/">Making sense of Klarna</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Making sense of Klarna&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/making-sense-of-klarna/embed/#?secret=I9eaOks640" data-secret="I9eaOks640" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/buy-now-pay-later-startup-kredivo-doubles-its-debt-facility-from-victory-park-capital-to-200m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167975</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WaitWhat raises $12M to double down on what comes after podcasts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/waitwhat-raises-12m-to-double-down-on-what-comes-after-podcasts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/waitwhat-raises-12m-to-double-down-on-what-comes-after-podcasts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 12:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raga Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WaitWhat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2168011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As podcasting continues to gain ground among mainstream consumers as a digital media platform alongside music, video, and the printed word, a startup that made a name for itself through building content for the medium has closed a round of funding to help it explore what comes next. WaitWhat, co-founded by two of the people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As podcasting continues to gain ground among mainstream consumers as a digital media platform alongside music, video, and the printed word, a startup that made a name for itself through building content for the medium has closed a round of funding to help it explore what comes next.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.waitwhat.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WaitWhat</a>, co-founded by two of the people who helped conceive of and build the TED digital media empire, has closed a round of $12 million, in a round led by Raga Partners, with Laurene Powell Jobs&#8217; firm <span style="font-weight: 400;">Emerson Collective, Lupa Systems, Capital One Ventures, Maywic Select Investments, GingerBread Capital, Burda Principal Investments, Cue Ball Capital, and Reid Hoffman</span> also participating.</p>
<p>WaitWhat says it plans to use the money to continue producing content in formats that have already proven very successful for it so far &#8212; to date, it has seen 70 million downloads of its work, which includes the podcasts Masters of Scale from Reid Hoffman, Meditative Story, Spark &amp; Fire, and Should this Exist? &#8212; as well as invest in its tech and R&amp;D and efforts to break new ground for new kinds of formats.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company may be best known for its podcast production, but it describes itself as a &#8220;media invention company&#8221; and June Cohen, who co-founded the company with Deron Triff, want to double down on the invention part of that description, going past podcasting to explore other ways of interacting with users.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re working on an innovative content format for physical well-being that lives inside of workouts, but will come at the experience through storytelling,&#8221; the pair said in an email (which we had to move to after our phone conversation, while they were on the road in a car, broke up. Maybe in-car calls need to be disrupted soon, too). &#8220;After physical well-being, we see intergenerational experiences (parent/child) as another interesting white space that plays into habit and human potential, and are in the early stages of developing a television series to explore this arena.&#8221;</p>
<p>An existing iteration on the podcast theme &#8212; a entrepreneur training course that it has developed in connection with its <span style="font-weight: 400;">Masters of Scale podcast, has been downloaded 10,000 times in its first 8 weeks on the market. And Meditative Story, which focuses on mindfulness, is being downloaded 750,000 times each month. In this they have focused on an important aspect of any digital service: &#8220;As with the podcast format, it&#8217;s all about habit,&#8221; they said.</span></p>
<p>But it is more than that: at a time when podcasting may still be somewhat nascent as a business model, while at the same time at the risk of starting to be too formulaic, the company&#8217;s catching attention for exploring ways to address both of those issues.</p>
<p>Its solution, in part, may be based on creative ways of presenting content to users, but also keeping a focus on strong material to use in those channels.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our aim is to build the most valuable independent portfolio of premium IP — one that&#8217;s designed around essential human needs and built with a contrarian strategy to scale,&#8221; the pair said in the email. &#8220;We see an outsized opportunity for alternative content that lives at the intersection of daily habit and fulfilling human potential. Our success is linked to how we build content ecosystems where habit and human potential come together.&#8221;</p>
<p>There is potentially a lot of money in making compelling podcasting content, of course, but for now a good chunk of that is coming in the form of M&amp;A, specifically from companies like Spotify looking to buy much bigger audiences that it can coalesce around its own advertising and paid subscription efforts, or by buying into new tech for creating and organizing this kind of content.</p>
<p>WaitWhat presents an interesting variation on that theme, by building a startup around the idea of innovating within and beyond the podcast medium, which could catch the eye again of the same players who are watching and snapping up content companies today.</p>
<p>Something interesting in how Cohen and Triff have approached fundraising is that they say that they have done it in part to &#8220;secure diversity&#8221; at the startup. In part this is about hiring people from a mix of backgrounds but also about how it approaches management and how it endorses those with whom it works.</p>
<p>&#8220;We see our fundraising rounds as a tool for securing diversity,&#8221; they noted. &#8220;We know that’s not a typical viewpoint. But we have found ways to use our fund-raising rounds to leap us forward on diversity — in a few different ways.&#8221;</p>
<p>They note that in the seed round, they raised half of the funds from investors who identify as women. &#8220;We did this by raising from women first. Most people thought we were crazy. (“Just take the money there you find it!” was the advice we got) But it’s what we believed in, and it’s what we did,&#8221; they said.</p>
<p>Then in the Series A (we covered it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/21/podcasting-startup-waitwhat-raises-4-3m-as-interest-in-audio-content-explodes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>), &#8220;our lead investors had diverse funds, but they weren’t women-led. So we created a carve-out to create balance. And raised additional funds from women-led funds to balance us out.&#8221;</p>
<p>In this latest Series B, &#8220;we shifted our focus from total dollars to representation on the Board,&#8221; they said. &#8220;We actually wrote into our term sheet that WaitWhat will always maintain gender balance on the board. In this round, we shifted to a 5-person board, so what that means is that we won’t have less than 2 people who identify as women — or less than 2 people who identify as men. Our investors haven’t seen a company request this before — but they welcomed it, and shared that they wished more companies would ask.&#8221;</p>
<p>Far from annoying the men in the room, it seems to have gotten them even more on board with the idea of purpose existing alongside business interestes.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Drawing on our background of investing in companies that have demonstrated the ability to build loyalty and community around high-quality content and experiences, we are big believers in WaitWhat’s approach to deliver durable and adaptive content, helping people become the best versions of themselves,” said Atul Joshi, founder and managing partner of Raga Partners, who led the investment for the firm. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/waitwhat-raises-12m-to-double-down-on-what-comes-after-podcasts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2168011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ban biometric surveillance in public to safeguard rights, urge EU bodies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/ban-biometric-surveillance-in-public-to-safeguard-rights-urge-eu-bodies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/ban-biometric-surveillance-in-public-to-safeguard-rights-urge-eu-bodies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 12:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrea Jelinek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biometrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EDPB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EDPS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Data Protection Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law enforcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wojciech Wiewiórowski]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2168007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There have been further calls from EU institutions to outlaw biometric surveillance in public. In a joint opinion published today, the European Data Protection Board (EDPB) and the European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS), Wojciech Wiewiórowski, have called for draft EU regulations on the use of artificial intelligence technologies to go further than the Commission&#8217;s proposal [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There have been further calls from EU institutions to outlaw biometric surveillance in public.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://edpb.europa.eu/news/news/2021/edpb-edps-call-ban-use-ai-automated-recognition-human-features-publicly-accessible_en">joint opinion</a> published today, the European Data Protection Board (EDPB) and the European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS), Wojciech Wiewiórowski, have called for draft EU regulations on the use of artificial intelligence technologies to go further than the Commission&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/europe-lays-out-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-boost-trust-and-uptake/">proposal in April</a> &#8212; urging that the planned legislation should be beefed up to include a &#8220;general ban on any use of AI for automated recognition of human features in publicly accessible spaces, such as recognition of faces, gait, fingerprints, DNA, voice, keystrokes and other biometric or behavioural signals, in any context&#8221;.</p>
<p>Such technologies are simply too harmful to EU citizens&#8217; fundamental rights and freedoms &#8212; like privacy and equal treatment under the law &#8212; to permit their use, is the argument.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The EDPB is responsible for ensuring a harmonization application of the EU&#8217;s privacy rules, while the EDPS oversees EU institutions&#8217; own compliance with data protection law and also provides legislative guidance to the Commission.</p>
<p>EU lawmakers&#8217; draft proposal on regulating applications of AI contained restrictions on law enforcement’s use of biometric surveillance in public places &#8212; but with very wide-ranging exemptions which quickly attracted major criticism from digital rights and civil society groups, as well as a number of MEPs.</p>
<p>The EDPS himself also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/eus-top-data-protection-supervisor-urges-ban-on-facial-recognition-in-public/">quickly urged a rethink</a>. Now he&#8217;s gone further, with the EDPB joining in with the criticism.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KofcQJYvh9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/meps-call-for-european-ai-rules-to-ban-biometric-surveillance-in-public/">MEPs call for European AI rules to ban biometric surveillance in public</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MEPs call for European AI rules to ban biometric surveillance in public&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/meps-call-for-european-ai-rules-to-ban-biometric-surveillance-in-public/embed/#?secret=KofcQJYvh9" data-secret="KofcQJYvh9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The EDPB and the EDPS have jointly fleshed out a number of concerns with the EU&#8217;s AI proposal &#8212; while welcoming the overall &#8220;risk-based approach&#8221; taken by EU lawmakers &#8212; saying, for example, that legislators must be careful to ensure alignment with the bloc&#8217;s existing data protection framework to avoid rights risks.</p>
<p>&#8220;The EDPB and the EDPS strongly welcome the aim of addressing the use of AI systems within the European Union, including the use of AI systems by EU institutions, bodies or agencies. At the same time, the EDPB and EDPS are concerned by the exclusion of international law enforcement cooperation from the scope of the Proposal,&#8221; they write.</p>
<p>&#8220;The EDPB and EDPS also stress the need to explicitly clarify that existing EU data protection legislation (GDPR, the EUDPR and the LED) applies to any processing of personal data falling under the scope of the draft AI Regulation.&#8221;</p>
<p>As well as calling for the use of biometric surveillance to be banned in public, the pair have urged a total ban on AI systems using biometrics to categorize individuals into &#8220;clusters based on ethnicity, gender, political or sexual orientation, or other grounds on which discrimination is prohibited under Article 21 of the Charter of Fundamental Rights&#8221;.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s an interesting concern in light of Google&#8217;s push, in the adtech realm, to replace behavioral micromarketing of individuals with ads that address cohorts (or groups) of users, based on their interests &#8212; with such clusters of web users set to be defined by Google&#8217;s AI algorithms.</p>
<p>(It&#8217;s interesting to speculate, therefore, whether<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/google-isnt-testing-flocs-in-europe-yet/"> FLoCs</a> risks creating a legal discrimination risk &#8212; based on how individual mobile users are grouped together for ad targeting purposes. Certainly,<a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/03/googles-floc-terrible-idea"> concerns</a> have been raised over the potential for FLoCs to scale bias and predatory advertising. And it&#8217;s also interesting that Google avoided running early tests in Europe, likely owning to the EU&#8217;s data protection regime.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SJl7WZOVUX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/google-isnt-testing-flocs-in-europe-yet/">Google isn&#8217;t testing FLoCs in Europe yet</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google isn&#8217;t testing FLoCs in Europe yet&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/google-isnt-testing-flocs-in-europe-yet/embed/#?secret=SJl7WZOVUX" data-secret="SJl7WZOVUX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In another recommendation today, the EDPB and the EDPS also express a view that the use of AI to infer emotions of a natural person is &#8220;highly undesirable and should be prohibited&#8221; &#8212;  except for what they describe as &#8220;very specified cases, such as some health purposes, where the patient emotion recognition is important&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;The use of AI for any type of social scoring should be prohibited,&#8221; they go on &#8212; touching on one use-case that the Commission&#8217;s draft proposal does suggest should be entirely prohibited, with EU lawmakers evidently keen to avoid any China-style social credit system taking hold in the region.</p>
<p>However by failing to include a prohibition on biometric surveillance in public in the proposed regulation the Commission is arguably risking just such a system being developed on the sly &#8212; i.e. by not banning private actors from deploying technology that could be used to track and profile people&#8217;s behavior remotely and en masse.</p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, the EDPB&#8217;s chair Andrea Jelinek and the EDPS Wiewiórowski argue as much, writing [emphasis ours]:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Deploying remote biometric identification in publicly accessible spaces means the end of anonymity in those places. Applications such as live facial recognition interfere with fundamental rights and freedoms to such an extent that they may call into question the essence of these rights and freedoms. This calls for an immediate application of the precautionary approach. <strong>A general ban on the use of facial recognition in publicly accessible areas is the necessary starting point if we want to preserve our freedoms and create a human-centric legal framework for AI.</strong> The proposed regulation should also prohibit any type of use of AI for social scoring, as it is against the EU fundamental values and can lead to discrimination.”</p></blockquote>
<p>In their joint opinion they also express concerns about the Commission&#8217;s proposed enforcement structure for the AI regulation, arguing that data protection authorities (within Member States) should be designated as national supervisory authorities (&#8220;pursuant to Article 59 of the [AI] Proposal&#8221;) &#8212; pointing out the EU DPAs are already enforcing the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) and the LED (Law Enforcement Directive) on AI systems involving personal data; and arguing it would therefore be &#8220;a more harmonized regulatory approach, and contribute to the consistent interpretation of data processing provisions across the EU&#8221; if they were given competence for supervising the AI Regulation too.</p>
<p>They are also not happy with the Commission&#8217;s plan to give itself a predominant role in the planned European Artificial Intelligence Board (EAIB) &#8212; arguing that this &#8220;would conflict with the need for an AI European body independent from any political influence&#8221;. To ensure the Board&#8217;s independence the proposal should give it more autonomy and &#8220;ensure it can act on its own initiative&#8221;, they add.</p>
<p>The Commission has been contacted for comment.</p>
<p><strong>Update: </strong>A spokesperson for the Commission pointed out that GDPR &#8212; in principle &#8212; already prohibits the use of remote biometric systems for identification purposes unless limited exceptions apply. (Such as taking place for reasons of substantial public interest.)</p>
<p>The official also noted that to be lawful any such exceptional use must be based on EU or national law; be duly justified, proportionate and subject to adequate safeguards; and would also have to comply with the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights.</p>
<p>&#8220;With the new regulation we want to create complementary rules to the data protection acquis, but not ban something that is a priori already prohibited (with certain narrow exceptions),&#8221; the spokesperson told us.</p>
<p>&#8220;For law enforcement purposes we propose to ban the use of real-time remote biometric identification systems in publicly accessible spaces which are not strictly needed to protect exhaustively listed law enforcement purposes (regarding victims of crime such as missing children; specific and imminent threats to life and human safety such as an impending terrorist attack; or investigation/detection of a limited list of serious crimes).</p>
<p>&#8220;This leads to an overall comprehensive EU approach that provides sufficient protection and limits the use of those systems to the strict minimum necessary and proportionate for the protection of overriding public interests.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The GDPR lists several grounds, which could justify this kind of processing of &#8216;special categories&#8217; of personal data, including biometric data,&#8221; they added. &#8220;The one mainly relevant ground here is &#8216;substantial public interest on the basis of EU or national law&#8217;. The law has to be proportionate to the aim pursued, respect the essence of the right to data protection and provide for suitable safeguards.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Law Enforcement Directive also lists several grounds, the most relevant one as an &#8216;authorisation by EU or national law&#8217;. Under the Law Enforcement Directive, &#8216;sensitive data&#8217; may only be processed when strictly necessary and subject to appropriate safeguards for the right and freedoms of the data subjects.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Commission official also pointed to &#8220;a number of beneficial applications outside the law enforcement field&#8221;, where they suggested biometric surveillance could provide for a public good, such as to help visually impaired people &#8212; saying that that that was why it had opted for &#8220;a more differentiated approach&#8221;, and decided against an outright ban.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">As they rightly stress, some uses of AI systems are in itself incompatible with fundamental rights, including the use of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/biometric?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#biometric</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/recognition?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#recognition</a> systems in public or publicly accessible spaces. 2/3</p>
<p>&mdash; AlgorithmWatch (@algorithmwatch) <a href="https://twitter.com/algorithmwatch/status/1406983234328608770?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 21, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The AI Regulation is one of a number of digital proposals unveiled by EU lawmakers in recent months. Negotiations between the different EU institutions &#8212; and lobbying from industry and civil society &#8212; continues as the bloc works toward adopting new digital rules.</p>
<p>In another recent and related development, the UK&#8217;s information commissioner warned <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/uks-ico-warns-over-big-data-surveillance-threat-of-live-facial-recognition-in-public/">last week</a> over the threat posed by big data surveillance systems that are able to make use of technologies like live facial recognition &#8212; although she claimed it&#8217;s not her place to endorse or ban a technology.</p>
<p>But her opinion makes it clear that many applications of biometric surveillance may be incompatible with the UK&#8217;s privacy and data protection framework.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="atZtCpPOYd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/uks-ico-warns-over-big-data-surveillance-threat-of-live-facial-recognition-in-public/">UK&#8217;s ICO warns over &#8216;Big Data&#8217; surveillance threat of live facial recognition in public</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK&#8217;s ICO warns over &#8216;Big Data&#8217; surveillance threat of live facial recognition in public&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/uks-ico-warns-over-big-data-surveillance-threat-of-live-facial-recognition-in-public/embed/#?secret=atZtCpPOYd" data-secret="atZtCpPOYd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pDAx24ZawT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/europe-lays-out-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-boost-trust-and-uptake/">Europe lays out plan for risk-based AI rules to boost trust and uptake</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe lays out plan for risk-based AI rules to boost trust and uptake&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/europe-lays-out-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-boost-trust-and-uptake/embed/#?secret=pDAx24ZawT" data-secret="pDAx24ZawT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3oP8i0VLNo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/swedens-data-watchdog-slaps-police-for-unlawful-use-of-clearview-ai/">Sweden&#8217;s data watchdog slaps police for unlawful use of Clearview AI</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sweden&#8217;s data watchdog slaps police for unlawful use of Clearview AI&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/swedens-data-watchdog-slaps-police-for-unlawful-use-of-clearview-ai/embed/#?secret=3oP8i0VLNo" data-secret="3oP8i0VLNo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rdBFwRkVbn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/05/orwellian-ai-lie-detector-project-challenged-in-eu-court/">&#8216;Orwellian&#8217; AI lie detector project challenged in EU court</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;Orwellian&#8217; AI lie detector project challenged in EU court&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/05/orwellian-ai-lie-detector-project-challenged-in-eu-court/embed/#?secret=rdBFwRkVbn" data-secret="rdBFwRkVbn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/ban-biometric-surveillance-in-public-to-safeguard-rights-urge-eu-bodies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2168007</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Station: Waymo nabs more capital, Cruise taps a $5B credit line and hints about Argo&#8217;s future</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/the-station-waymo-nabs-more-capital-cruise-taps-a-5b-credit-line-and-hints-about-argos-future/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/the-station-waymo-nabs-more-capital-cruise-taps-a-5b-credit-line-and-hints-about-argos-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argo AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cruise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lordstown Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox. Hello and welcome back to The Station, a weekly newsletter dedicated to all the ways people and packages move (today and in the future) from Point A to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to The Station, a weekly newsletter dedicated to all the ways people and packages move (today and in the future) from Point A to Point B.</p>
<p>A few Extra Crunch items highlight before we jump into things. This week, we published an interview with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/refraction-ais-matthew-johnson-roberson-on-finding-the-middle-path-to-robotic-delivery/">Refraction AI co-founder and CTO Matthew Johnson-Roberson</a> as part of an ongoing series focused on transportation founders. TechCrunch has been following autonomous delivery startup since it came out of stealth on our stage in 2019. Refraction, which built its vehicle to travel in bike lanes up to 15 miles per hour, has been testing in AnnArbor, Michigan. Now, it&#8217;s expanding to Austin. Our interview with Johnson-Roberson reveals the premise behind the company, what prompted him to step down as CEO and some of the challenges in the industry. The twist with this series? We plan to check in on every founder we interview a year after their Q&amp;A is published.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Later this month, we&#8217;ll feature an interview with Candice Xie, the CEO and co-founder of Veo.</p>
<p>Finally, we have a fresh round of recaps from the <strong>TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</strong> event held June 9. Each recap provides a rundown of the conversation as well as some key quotes from our panelists. The recaps also include the video of the session.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/how-autonomous-delivery-startups-are-navigating-policy-partnerships-and-post-pandemic-operations/">How autonomous delivery startups are navigating policy, </a><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/how-autonomous-delivery-startups-are-navigating-policy-partnerships-and-post-pandemic-operations/">partnerships, and post-pandemic operations</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/experts-from-ford-toyota-and-hyundai-outline-why-automakers-are-pouring-money-into-robotics/">Experts from Ford, Toyota and Hyundai outline why automakers are pouring money into robotics</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/investors-clara-brenner-quin-garcia-and-rachel-holt-on-spacs-micromobility-and-how-covid-19-shaped-vc/">Investors Clara Brenner, Quin Garcia and Rachel Holt on SPACs, micromobility and how COVID-19 shaped VC</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/founders-ben-schippers-and-evette-ellis-are-riding-the-ev-sales-wave/">Founders Ben Schippers and Evette Ellis are riding the EV sales wave</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/mobility-startups-can-be-equitable-accessible-and-profitable/">Mobility startups can be equitable, accessible and profitable</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Email me at <a href="mailto:kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com">kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com</a> to share thoughts, criticisms, offer up opinions or tips. You can also send a direct message to me at Twitter — <a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec">@kirstenkorosec</a>.</p>
<h2>Deal of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896226 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png" alt="money the station" width="1600" height="400" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=1536,384 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Taking autonomous vehicle technology from the &#8220;lab,&#8221; — ok, from the closed track — to commercial scale is a pricey endeavor. Not every AV developer has success raising money or access to debt. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/waymo-alphabets-self-driving-arm-raises-2-5b-in-second-external-investment-round/"><strong>Waymo</strong> does</a>.</p>
<p>The company has raised another $2.5 billion in external funding about 15 months after its first external round brought in $2.25 billion. (That round was later expanded by $700 million a few months later.) The round appears to be mostly existing investors including parent company Alphabet, Andreessen Horowitz, AutoNation, Canada Pension Plan Investment Board, Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company, Magna International, Mubadala Investment Company, Perry Creek Capital, Silver Lake, funds and accounts advised by T. Rowe Price Associates, Inc., Temasek. Tiger Global was the investor newcomer.</p>
<p>The funding announcement comes a few months after CEO John Krafcik left the company after five years in the position. The CEO position is now being held jointly by Tekedra Mawakana, former COO, and Dmitri Dolgov, who joined the original self-driving project at Google and was CTO.</p>
<p>More than $2 billion is a hefty haul. Although numerous folks,  some of whom are in the financial sector, reached out to me to share reactions of surprise that it wasn&#8217;t larger. I&#8217;m more interested in how that money is being put to work. Waymo has now brought in nearly $6 billion in outside investment since March 2020.</p>
<p><strong>Other deals that my attention &#8230;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bringg</strong>, a software developer focused on helping retailers with last-mile logistics, raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/bringg-nabs-100m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-a-last-mile-delivery-platform-for-retailers/">$100 million in a Series E round of funding</a> led by Insight Partners. Salesforce Ventures, Viola Growth, Next 47, Pereg Ventures, Harlap, GLP and Cambridge Capital &#8212; all previous backers &#8212; also invested. Bringg CEO Guy Bloch told TechCrunch that the funding will be used both to continue growing Bringg&#8217;s customer base, but also the company&#8217;s ca</p>
<p><strong>CAI International</strong>, the tansportation finance and logistics company,  agreed to a $1.1 billion takeover by Mitsubishi HC Capital. This is an all-stock deal that is comprised of $104 million worth of preferred stock and $986 million of common stock equity value, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-cai-international-m-a-mitsubishi-hc-c/mitsubishi-hc-capital-to-buy-cai-international-for-1-1-billion-idUSKCN2DU001">Reuters reported</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Cambridge Mobile Telematics</strong>, a mobile telematics and analytics, has acquired TrueMotion. The company didn&#8217;t disclose the terms. CMT will now provide telematics services to 21 out of the 25 largest auto insurers in the United States, and across more than 20 countries, including Canada, the United Kingdom, Germany, South Africa, Japan and Australia.</p>
<p><strong>Cruise</strong>, the self-driving subsidiary of GM, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cruise-secures-5b-credit-line-to-buy-electric-autonomous-cruise-origin-vehicles-from-gm/">secured a $5 billion line of credit</a> from the automaker&#8217;s financial arm to pay for hundreds of purpose-built electric and autonomous Origin vehicles as they start to roll off the assembly line. The access to the credit provided by GM Financial will push Cruise&#8217;s &#8220;total war chest&#8221; to more than $10 billion as it prepares for commercialization, CEO Dan Ammann wrote in a blog post. In short: the credit will be used to buy these Cruise Origins from GM, which is assembling the autonomous vehicles at its renamed and renovated Detroit-Hamtramck assembly plant. The factory is now called Factory ZERO.</p>
<p><strong>Electriphi</strong>, a battery management and fleet monitoring software startup based in San Francisco, was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/ford-acquires-electriphi-as-it-prepares-to-woo-ev-fleet-customers/">acquired by Ford</a>. The acquisition, the terms of which neither party would disclose, aims to round out Ford&#8217;s future EV commercial business. The automaker already has two electric commercial vehicles in pipeline, the  E-transit cargo and F-150 Lighting Pro pickup truck. Ford is betting that the software developed by the three-year-old San Francisco startup will help it capture more than $1 billion in revenue just from charging by 2030.</p>
<p><strong>Gopuff</strong>, the on-demand goods, food and alcohol delivery service, acquired fleet management platform<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/delivery-service-gopuff-acquires-rideos-for-115-million-plus/"> rideOS for $115 million</a>, sources familiar with the deal told TechCrunch. This acquisition comes just a few months after the Philadelphia-based startup announced a $1.15 billion funding round at a $8.9 billion valuation, up from $3.9 billion in October. Last fall, the company also raised $380 million and bought BevMo, a beverage retailer. Gopuff did not share its updated valuation with this new acquisition.</p>
<p><strong>KeepTruckin</strong>, a hardware and software developer that helps trucking fleets manage vehicle, cargo and driver safety, raised<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/keeptruckin-raises-190-million-to-invest-in-ai-products-double-rd-team-to-700/"> $190 million in a Series E funding round</a>, which puts the company&#8217;s valuation at over $2 billion, according to CEO Shoaib Makani. <strong>G2 Venture Partners</strong>, which just <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/g2vp-vc-raises-500-million-to-fund-tech-that-make-industries-more-sustainable/">raised a $500 million fund</a> to help modernize existing industries, participated in the round, alongside existing backers Greenoaks Capital, Index Ventures, IVP and Scale Venture Partners and funds managed by BlackRock.</p>
<p><strong>Kodiak Robotics</strong>, the Silicon Valley-based startup developing autonomous trucks, has a new investor. Tire-making giant Bridgestone has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/self-driving-trucks-startup-kodiak-robotics-snags-investment-partnership-from-bridgestone/">taken a minority stake</a> in the AV startup as part of a broader partnership to test and develop smart tire technology. While the terms of the deal weren&#8217;t disclosed, Kodiak Robotics co-founder and CEO Don Burnette told TechCrunch that this is a direct financial investment. Bridgestone CTO Nizar Trigui has also joined the Kodiak board as an observer. The two companies also formed a strategic partnership focused on advancing Bridgestone&#8217;s tire tech and fleet management system.</p>
<p><strong>MachineMetrics</strong>, a data startup focused on manufacturing, raised $20 million in Series B round led by industrial automation and robotics Teradyne. Ridgeline Ventures also participated along with existing investors Tola Capital and Hyperplane.</p>
<p><strong>Mister Car Wash</strong>, a car wash company owned by Leonard Green &amp; Partners and based in my hometown, has <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1853513/000119312521192606/d117644ds1a.htm">set the terms for its initial public offering</a>. The company said in a regulatory filing that it will issue 37.5 million with the expectation of a per share price between $15 and $17.</p>
<p><strong>Motorway</strong>, a U.K. startup that allows professional car dealers to bid in an auction for privately owned cars for sale,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/motorways-auction-platform-for-second-hand-cars-raises-67-7m-series-b-led-by-index-ventures/"> raised £48 million ($67.7 million)</a> in a Series B round led by Index Ventures, along with new investors BMW iVentures and Unbound. Existing investors Latitude and Marchmont Ventures also participated. The funding will be used to extend its platform and grow the current 160-strong team.</p>
<p><strong>PayCargo</strong>, the Freight payment platform company, <a href="https://paycargo.com/news/paycargo-secures-series-b/">raised $125 million</a> in a Series B round led by Insight Partners.</p>
<p><strong>Solid Power</strong>, a solid-state battery developer backed by Ford and BMW, locked in a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/bmw-and-ford-backed-solid-power-will-go-public-via-spac-merger-in-1-2b-deal/">deal to merge</a> with special purpose acquisition company Decarbonization Plus Acquisition Corp III, at a post-deal implied market valuation of $1.2 billion. The transaction is expected to generate around $600 million in cash, including a $165 million private investment in public equity (PIPE) transaction from investors Koch Strategic Platforms, Riverstone Energy Limited, Neuberger Berman and Van Eck Associates Corporation.</p>
<p><strong>Vertical Aerospace</strong> is yet another electric vertical takeoff and landing aircraft startup to <a href="https://www.vertical-aerospace.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pdf_Press_Release.pdf">take the SPAC path</a> to the public markets. The UK-based eVTOL developer, which is backed by American Airlines, Avolon, Honeywell, Rolls-Royce and Microsoft&#8217;s M12, has agreed to merge with special purposed acquisition company Broadstone Acquisition Corp., at an implied $2.2 billion valuation.</p>
<p>Woven Capital made an undisclosed investment in Ridecell, a platform powering digital transformations and IoT automation for fleet-driven businesses. Woven Capital is an $800 million global investment fund that supports innovative, growth-stage companies in mobility, automation, artificial intelligence, data and analytics, connectivity, and smart cities. It is the investment arm of the Woven Planet Group, a Toyota subsidiary which is dedicated to building the safest mobility in the world. Along with the investment, Ridecell and the Woven Planet Group will explore collaborative opportunities in mobility service operations.</p>
<h2>Hints at Argo&#8217;s future</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-autonomous-vehicles1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896325 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-autonomous-vehicles1.png" alt="the station autonomous vehicles1" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-autonomous-vehicles1.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-autonomous-vehicles1.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-autonomous-vehicles1.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-autonomous-vehicles1.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-autonomous-vehicles1.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-autonomous-vehicles1.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-autonomous-vehicles1.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>You might have noticed under &#8220;deal of the week&#8221; that <strong>Ford</strong> acquired a fleet management and charging monitor software company called Electriphi. When the deal was announced, I found myself wondering aloud if the software would be used by the company for its eventual commercial fleet of robotaxis? And that got me thinking about Argo AI, the startup developing the self-driving system for backers Ford and VW.</p>
<p>I was pointed to some comments made Ford CEO Jim Farley, which suggests that maybe Argo will play a larger role in commercial operations than expected. Farley was asked during the Deutsche Bank&#8217;s Global Auto Industry Conference what he thought about the convergence between what Argo will be offering and I guess Ford in terms of business model?</p>
<p><strong>Farley&#8217;s response</strong>: &#8220;Well, that&#8217;s a good question. I think Argo has proven to be very adaptive business, not just the technology. My personal opinion is that I think they deserve the opportunity to be a one-stop shop company and that they will take on more of the go-to-market responsibilities for our AV effort.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Policy corner</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2037863 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png" alt="the-station-delivery" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Welcome to Policy Corner. It&#8217;s a (relatively) short one this week folks. As a reminder, if there&#8217;s any policy or regulatory news (or tips!) that you think merits inclusion in the Corner, send me an email at <a href="mailto:aria.techcrunch@gmail.com">aria.techcrunch@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>Autonomous vehicle developers <strong>Nuro</strong> and <strong>Cruise</strong>, along with three other entities, have formed a new coalition to support a <a href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billTextClient.xhtml?bill_id=202120220SB500">California bill</a> that would require AVs to be zero emission by 2030. TechCrunch&#8217;s Rebecca Bellan was the first to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/california-bill-would-require-all-self-driving-vehicles-to-be-zero-emission-by-2025/">cover the bill</a> back in March. Notably absent from this coalition are Argo AI, which has Ford and VW has backers and customers, as well several other legacy automakers. John Davis, chief engineer at Ford Autonomous Vehicles, told Bellan back in March that the computing demands of an AV platform means that it may make more sense to transition first to a hybrid model before going full EV.</p>
<p>For Cruise&#8217;s part, it makes sense that they&#8217;d want to ratchet up their support of the bill, especially after news broke that earlier this week they&#8217;d taken out a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cruise-secures-5b-credit-line-to-buy-electric-autonomous-cruise-origin-vehicles-from-gm/">$5 billion line of credit</a> to ramp up production of their electric Cruise Origin AV.</p>
<hr />
<p>EV proponents are fired up about the possibility of taxing EVs as one way to fund the massive infrastructure investments that are currently being debated in Washington. The proposal is being mulled by legislators as they continue to negotiate the infrastructure package. Joe Britton, the Executive Director of the Zero Emission Transportation Association, called the tax proposal &#8220;the brainchild of those who want to unfairly punish EV drivers and hinder clean vehicle deployment.&#8221;</p>
<p>It seems that an EV tax could be the sacrificial lamb that some legislators are looking for, but it is important to note &#8212; as ZETA does &#8212; that battery electric vehicles are still only around 1% of the cars on the road.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>— Aria Alamalhodaei</em></p>
<h2>Notable reads and other tidbits</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896228 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png" alt="the station electric vehicles1" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Here are a few more final items to wrap up The Station.</p>
<h3>Autonomous vehicles</h3>
<p><strong>Pony.ai,</strong> the robotaxi startup that operates in China and the United States, has started <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/chinese-startup-pony-ai-plans-to-launch-a-driverless-robotaxi-service-in-california-in-2022/">testing driverless vehicles</a> on public roads in California ahead of plans to launch a commercial service there in 2022. The company said the driverless vehicle testing, which means the autonomous vehicles operate without human safety drivers behind the wheel, is happening daily on public roads in Fremont and Milpitas, California. Pony.ai is also testing its driverless vehicles in Guangzhou, China. Pony.ai said it also plans to resume a rideshare service to the public in Irvine this summer using AVs with a human safety driver. Its goal is to roll out the fully driverless service to the public in 2022.</p>
<h3>EVs and hydrogen</h3>
<p><strong>Canoo</strong>, the electric vehicle startup that recently became a publicly traded company through a merger with a SPAC, made a number of announcements during its investor day event. First on the list was news that the company plans to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/canoo-to-build-its-first-electric-vehicle-factory-in-oklahoma/">build a factory in Oklahoma</a> that will employ up to 2,000 workers. The factory will be located on a 400-acre site in the MidAmerica Industrial Park in Pryor, Oklahoma about 45 minutes from Tulsa. The facility, which the company describes as a &#8220;mega microfactory&#8221; will include a paint shop, body shop and general assembly plant and is expected to open in 2023.</p>
<p>Canoo also laid out its plans for automated driving, which I haven&#8217;t heard much about until now. The details were thin, but Canoo is planning to have its vehicles equipped with &#8220;Level 2&#8221; advanced driver assistance system, which means two primary functions &#8212; like adaptive cruise and lane keeping &#8212; are automated and still have a human driver in the loop at all times. From there, it seems the company is taking the Tesla approach and believes it can reach Level 4 autonomy through software improvements. To be clearm, Tesla is nowhere near Level 4 autonomy, which means the vehicle ccan handle all driving without the driver in the loop in certain geographic areas or conditiions. Here is the Canoo CTO&#8217;s comments about this.</p>
<blockquote><p>We&#8217;ve got an ADAS system ready for launch at Level 2, with all of the basic features, but we&#8217;ve got an OTA system — over the air upgradability — so as we continue to refine and mature and validate additional features in ADAS, we&#8217;re going to be able to upgrade over time and with our ADAS compute platform, along with the sensor suite we believe will ultimately get us to around Level 4.</p></blockquote>
<p>Finally, the company also detailed some of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/canoo-wants-to-connect-owners-to-all-of-their-vehicles-not-just-canoos/">features that may be on its app</a>, including a one-stop shop functionality that customers could use for their Canoo vehicles &#8212; and all their other cars, as well. This unusual approach to its branded vehicle app could potentially pay off big-time for Canoo in terms of user data and revenue via sales on services like tire replacements and insurance.</p>
<p><strong>Lordstown Motors</strong> is digging itself deeper into a hole it seems. The company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/lordstown-motors-ceo-and-cfo-resign-amidst-production-woes/">CEO and CFO resigned</a> following a less than stellar first quarter results in May, including news that production volumes would likely be half &#8212; from around 2,200 vehicles to just 1,000 &#8212; should the company not identify more funding. But wait. What is this?</p>
<p>The following day, hope was restored when interim CEO Angela Strand and President Rich Schmidt made a series of statements  at an Automotive Press Association event that drove up shares in the company, including that it has enough &#8220;binding orders&#8221; from customers to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/lordstown-motors-execs-cite-binding-orders-to-restore-confidence-a-day-after-ceo-cfo-resignations/">fund limited production</a> of its electric pickup truck through May 2022. Ah but hold tight because the next day Lordstown issued a regulatory filing that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/lordstown-motors-reverses-claims-about-binding-orders-for-electric-pickup-truck/">reversed those claims</a>.</p>
<p>It appears those &#8220;binding orders&#8221; were more like agreements to <em>maybe</em> lease or buy.</p>
<p><strong>Jaguar Land Rover</strong> is developing a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/jaguar-land-rover-to-develop-a-defender-like-hydrogen-fuel-cell-ev/">hydrogen fuel cell vehicle</a> based on the new Defender SUV, and plans to begin testing the prototype next year. The prototype program, known as Project Zeus, is part of JLR&#8217;s larger aim to only produce zero-tailpipe emissions vehicles by 2036. JLR has also made a commitment to have zero carbon emissions across its supply chain, products and operations by 2039. The automaker has also tapped AVL, Delta Motorsport, Marelli Automotive Systems and the U.K. Battery Industrialization Center to help develop the prototype.</p>
<p><strong>Nuro</strong>, the autonomous delivery startup, is expanding into parcel logistics through a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/autonomous-delivery-startup-nuro-moves-into-logistics-with-fedex/"> partnership with FedEx</a>. The multiyear, multiphased strategic partnership aims to test and ultimately deploy Nuro&#8217;s next-generation autonomous delivery vehicle within FedEx operations. This bot will follow Nuro&#8217;s more recent R2 bot. The deal with FedEx marks its first foray into parcels logistics. The pilot program has already started in Houston. This multiyear commitment will allow Nuro to bring its technology to more people in new ways, and eventually reach large-scale deployment, according to Cosimo Leipold, Nuro&#8217;s head of partnerships.</p>
<p><strong>Polestar</strong>, Volvo Car Group&#8217;s standalone electric performance brand, will manufacture its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/polestar-to-build-its-first-all-electric-suv-in-the-united-states/">first all-electric SUV</a> in the United States. The automaker said the Polestar 3 will be assembled at a plant shared with Volvo Cars at a factory in Ridgeville, South Carolina. The Polestar 3 follows the all-electric Polestar 2 sedan and the hybrid grand tourer Polestar 1. Production of Polestar 3 is expected to begin globally in 2022.</p>
<h3>In-car tech</h3>
<p><strong>Amazon Web Services</strong> entered into an <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210617005933/en/">agreement with Ferrari</a> to become their official cloud provider, a deal that aims to help the luxury automaker&#8217;s Scuderia Ferrari Formula One racing team launch a digital fan engagement platform <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">via its mobile app.</span></p>
<p><strong>Android Auto</strong> has <a href="https://blog.google/products/android/new-features-summer-2021">some new updates</a> including personalizing the launcher screen directly from a user&#8217;s smartphone and manually setting dark mode. Browsing content is also supposed to be easier with new tabs in media apps, a &#8220;back to top&#8221; option and an A to Z button in the scroll bar.  New app experiences have also been added to help with EV charging, parking and navigation apps are now available to use in Android Auto. Users will also be able to read and send new messages directly from apps like WhatsApp or Messages &#8212; now available globally. These Android Auto features are available on phones running Android 6.0 or above, and when connected to your compatible car.</p>
<h3>Other transportation stuff</h3>
<p><strong>Financial Times</strong> digs into the sticky issue of <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/76fdac7c-7076-47a4-bcb0-7e75af0aadab">Chinese surveillance technology</a> that is used in &#8216;smart cities&#8217; all over the world.</p>
<p><strong>GM</strong> upped the amount it says it will spend on electric and autonomous vehicle investments to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/gm-increases-ev-and-av-investments-to-35b-through-2025/">$35 billion through 2025</a> &#8212; an $8 billion increase from its previous plan announced in November 2020.</p>
<p><strong>Lux Research </strong>released a study showing that in 2020 <a href="https://www.luxresearchinc.com/hubfs/2021%20Files/2021%20Executive%20Summaries/2021%20Press%20Executive%20Summaries/Executive%20Summary%20-%20Automotive%20Battery%20Tracker%202020%20Update%20-%20Press.pdf?utm_campaign=2021.06.17%20Automotive%20Battery%20Tracker%20Press%20Release&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;_hsmi=134312398&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-8YOW1Cnj4_pA3xyvgDdGIIjrYHK7GdjXCGxE17RLh0JjarrueIF5oLCkwzljhX9B6oEA2PWEEphVrkmguB1lsV16cYKw&amp;utm_content=134311174&amp;utm_source=hs_email">electric vehicles sales</a>, meaning battery and plug-ins, increased 37% compared to 2019. The sales growth was led by 140% growth in Europe as the BEV market took off in several countries. The report noted that while Tesla remains the most popular BEV maker, but its choice of cells from LG Energy Solution in China means Panasonic lost the market share crown it had held since 2013.</p>
<p><strong>Redwood Materials</strong>, the battery recycling startup founded by former Tesla CTO JB Straubel, has purchased 100 acres of land <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/redwood-materials-is-setting-up-shop-near-the-tesla-gigafactory-as-part-of-broader-expansion/">near the Gigafactory</a> that Panasonic operates with Tesla in Sparks, Nevada as part of an expansion plan that aligns with the Biden Administration&#8217;s drive to increase adoption of electric vehicles and boost domestic battery recycling and supply chain efforts. The company said its existing 150,000-square-foot facility in Carson City, Nevada will also nearly triple in size. Redwood is adding another 400,000 square feet onto the Carson City recycling facility, which is expected to be operational by the end of the year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/the-station-waymo-nabs-more-capital-cruise-taps-a-5b-credit-line-and-hints-about-argos-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167946</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DataRails books $25M more to build better financial reporting tools for SMBs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/datarails-books-25m-more-to-build-better-financial-reporting-tools-for-smbs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/datarails-books-25m-more-to-build-better-financial-reporting-tools-for-smbs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[datarails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[excel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FP&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMBs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMEs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As enterprise startups continue to target interesting gaps in the market, we&#8217;re seeing increasingly sophisticated tools getting built for small and medium businesses &#8212; traditionally a tricky segment to sell to, too small for large enterprise tools, and too advanced in their needs for consumer products. In the latest development of that trend, an Israeli [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As enterprise startups continue to target interesting gaps in the market, we&#8217;re seeing increasingly sophisticated tools getting built for small and medium businesses &#8212; traditionally a tricky segment to sell to, too small for large enterprise tools, and too advanced in their needs for consumer products. In the latest development of that trend, an Israeli startup called <a href="https://www.datarails.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DataRails</a> has raised $25 million to continue building out a platform that lets SMBs using Excel to run financial planning and analytics like their larger counterparts.</p>
<p>The funding closes out the company&#8217;s Series A at $43.5 million, after the company <a href="https://www.accesswire.com/641342/DataRails-Secures-185-Million-Series-A-Led-by-Zeev-Ventures-to-Bring-Enterprise-Level-Financial-Planning-Solution-to-SMBs">initially raised $18.5 million in April</a> (some at the time reported this as its Series A, but it seems the round had yet to be completed). The full round includes Zeev Ventures, Vertex Ventures Israel, and Innovation Endeavors, with <span class="s3">Vintage Investment Partners added in this most recent tranche. DataRails is not disclosing its valuation, except to note that it has doubled in the last four months, with hundreds of customers and on target to cross 1,000 this year, with a focus on the North American market. It has raised $55 million in total. </span></p>
<p>The challenge that DataRails has identified is that on one hand, SMBs have started to adopt a lot more apps, including software delivered as a service, to help them manage their businesses &#8212; a trend that has been accelerated in the last year with the pandemic and the knock-on effect that has had for remote working and bringing more virtual elements to replace face-to-face interactions. Those apps can include Salesforce, NetSuite, Sage, SAP, QuickBooks, Zuora, Xero, ADP and more.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But on the other hand, those in the business who manage its finances and financial reporting are lacking the tools to look at the data from these different apps in a holistic way. While Excel is a default application for many of them, they are simply reading lots of individual spreadsheets rather than integrated data analytics based on the numbers.</p>
<p>DataRails has built a platform that can read the reported information, which typically already lives in Excel spreadsheets, and automatically translate it into a bigger picture view of the company.</p>
<p>For SMEs, Excel is such a central piece of software, yet such a pain point for its lack of extensibility and function, that this predicament was actually the germination of starting DataRails in the first place,</p>
<p class="p1">Didi Gurfinkel, the CEO who co-founded the company with Eyal Cohen (the CPO) said that DataRails’ initially set out to create a more general purpose product that could help analyze and visualize anything from Excel.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2168009" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/DataRails-PR-Image-2.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="428" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/DataRails-PR-Image-2.jpg 2250w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/DataRails-PR-Image-2.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/DataRails-PR-Image-2.jpg?resize=300,189 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/DataRails-PR-Image-2.jpg?resize=768,483 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/DataRails-PR-Image-2.jpg?resize=680,428 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/DataRails-PR-Image-2.jpg?resize=1536,967 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/DataRails-PR-Image-2.jpg?resize=2048,1289 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/DataRails-PR-Image-2.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p class="p4">&#8220;We started the company with a vision to save the world from Excel spreadsheets,&#8221; he said, by taking them and helping to connect the data contained within them to a structured database. &#8220;The core of our technology knows how to take unstructured data and map that to a central database.&#8221; Before 2020, DataRails (which was founded in 2015) applied this to a variety of areas with a focus on banks, insurance companies, compliance and data integrity.</p>
<p>Over time, it could see a very specific application emerging, specifically for SMEs: providing a platform for FP&amp;A (financial planning and analytics), which didn&#8217;t really have a solution to address it at the time. &#8220;So we enabled that to beat the market.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;They&#8217;re already investing so much time and money in their software, but they still don’t have analytics and insight,&#8221; said Gurfinkel.</p>
<p>That turned out to be fortunate timing, since &#8220;digital transformation&#8221; and getting more out of one&#8217;s data was really starting to get traction in the world of business, <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en_us/solutions/small-business/resource-center/small-business-digital-transformation.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">specifically in the world of SMEs</a>, and CFOs and other people who oversaw finances were already looking for something like this.</p>
<p>The typical DataRails customer might be as small as a business of 50 people, or as big as 1,000 employees, a size of business that is too small for enterprise solutions, &#8220;which can cost tens of thousands of dollars to implement and use,&#8221; added Cohen, among other challenges. But as with so many of the apps that are being built today to address those using Excel, the idea with DataRails is low-code or even more specifically no-code, which means &#8220;no IT in the loop,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;That’s why we are so successful,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We are crossing the barrier and making our solution easy to use.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p4">The company doesn&#8217;t have a huge number of competitors today, either, although companies like <a href="https://www.cubesoftware.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cube</a> (which also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/cube-raises-10m-more-to-help-companies-plan-their-financial-future/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recently raised some money</a>) are among them. And others like Stripe, while currently not focussing on FP&amp;A, have most definitely been expanding the tools that it is providing to businesses as part of their bigger play to manage payments and subsequently other processes related to financial activity, so perhaps it, or others like it, might at some point become competitors in this space as well.</p>
<p>In the meantime, Gurfinkel said that other areas that DataRails is likely to expand to cover alongside FP&amp;A are likely to include HR, inventory, and &#8220;planning for anything,&#8221; any process that you have running in Excel. Another interesting turn would be how and if DataRails decides to look beyond Excel at other spreadsheets, or bypass spreadsheets altogether.</p>
<p>The scope of the opportunity &#8212; in the U.S. alone there are more than 30 million small businesses &#8212; is what&#8217;s attracting the investment here.</p>
<p class="p5">“We’re thrilled to reinvest in DataRails and continue working with the team to help them navigate their recent explosive and rapid growth,” said Yanai Oron, General Partner at <span class="s6">Vertex Ventures, in a statement</span>. “With innovative yet accessible technology and a tremendous untapped market opportunity, DataRails is primed to scale and become the leading FP&amp;A solution for SMEs everywhere.”</p>
<p class="p5">“Businesses are constantly about to start, in the midst of, or have just finished a round of financial reporting—it’s a never-ending cycle,&#8221; added Oren Zeev, founding partner at Zeev Ventures. &#8220;But with DataRails, FP&amp;A can be simple, streamlined, and effective, and that’s a vision we’ll back again and again.”<br />
<b></b></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/datarails-books-25m-more-to-build-better-financial-reporting-tools-for-smbs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167972</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revolut revenue grew by 57% in 2020</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/revolut-revenue-grew-by-57-in-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/revolut-revenue-grew-by-57-in-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenger bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fintech startup Revolut has filed some financial results and is sharing details with the press. In 2020, the company reported $361 million in revenue (£261 million) — that’s a 57% increase compared to 2019 revenue of $229 million (£166 million). Interestingly, those revenue figures have been adjusted to include fair value gains on cryptocurrency assets [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Fintech startup <a href="https://www.revolut.com">Revolut</a> has filed some financial results and is sharing details with the press. In 2020, the company reported $361 million in revenue (£261 million) — that’s a 57% increase compared to 2019 revenue of $229 million (£166 million).</p>
<p>Interestingly, those revenue figures have been adjusted to include fair value gains on cryptocurrency assets — it means that Revolut holds some crypto assets on its balance sheet. Revolut made $54 million (£39 million) in fair value gains on cryptocurrency assets.</p>
<p>Gross profit reached $170 million (£123 million) last year. At the same time, the company still reports operating losses. In particular, Q1 2020 was a particularly bad quarter with $76 million (£55 million) in adjusted operating loss.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In 2020, total non-adjusted operating loss reached $277 million (£200.6 million). Like many tech companies, administrative expenses are responsible for this loss. With a staff of 2,200 people, the company spent $367 million (£266 million) on administrative costs alone. But things seem to be improving as you can see:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2168000" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2168000" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.35.57-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="814" class="size-full wp-image-2168000" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.35.57-PM.png 2020w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.35.57-PM.png?resize=150,119 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.35.57-PM.png?resize=300,239 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.35.57-PM.png?resize=768,611 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.35.57-PM.png?resize=680,541 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.35.57-PM.png?resize=1536,1221 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.35.57-PM.png?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2168000" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Revolut</p></div></p>
<p>These trends aren’t that surprising as I reported that fintech startups spent most of 2020 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/fintech-startups-are-increasingly-focusing-on-profitability/">focusing on profitability and improving their margins</a>. At the end 2020, Revolut had 14.5 million personal customers and 500,000 companies using Revolut Business.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GlJL0ZPmJ8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/fintech-startups-are-increasingly-focusing-on-profitability/">Fintech startups are increasingly focusing on profitability</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech startups are increasingly focusing on profitability&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/fintech-startups-are-increasingly-focusing-on-profitability/embed/#?secret=GlJL0ZPmJ8" data-secret="GlJL0ZPmJ8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“As the extraordinary circumstances of 2020 drove the trend towards digital financial management we continued to innovate for customers to make their financial lives easier and accelerate daily use. We launched 24 new retail and business products, expanded into the US, Japan and Australia and launched banking services in Lithuania, all while significantly improving our profitability,” founder and CEO Nikolay Storonsky said in a statement. “We began 2021 with a more resilient and productive business that will enhance our trajectory towards rapid growth.”</p>
<p>When you compare Q1 2020 to Q1 2021, things are radically different for the fintech company. Revenue increased by 130% year-over-year and gross profit grew by 300% between Q1 2020 and Q1 2021.</p>
<p>Revolut has been launching a ton of products to diversify its sources of revenue. It is increasingly becoming a financial super app with current accounts, debit cards, trading services, insurance products, premium subscriptions, cryptocurrency trading and more.</p>
<p>Interestingly, interchange revenue from card transactions represents a good chunk of the company’s revenue. In 2020, cards and interchange generated $131 million (£95 million) in revenue. Every time a Revolut customer makes a card purchase, the card scheme (Visa or Mastercard) gives back some fees to Revolut. It’s an incredibly small percentage-based fee, but it can add up when you generate millions of purchases.</p>
<p>Foreign exchange and wealth generated $111 million (£80 million) in revenue. That’s another big one. And finally, subscriptions, such as Revolut Plus, Revolut Premium and Revolut Metal, accounted for $104 million (£75 million) in revenue.</p>
<p>Those are three strong pillars that all contribute to the company’s bottom line. They all represent a bit less or a bit more than a third of the company’s overall revenue.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2168001" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2168001" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.50.54-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="338" class="size-full wp-image-2168001" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.50.54-PM.png 2492w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.50.54-PM.png?resize=150,49 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.50.54-PM.png?resize=300,99 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.50.54-PM.png?resize=768,253 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.50.54-PM.png?resize=680,224 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.50.54-PM.png?resize=1536,507 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.50.54-PM.png?resize=2048,676 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-18-at-6.50.54-PM.png?resize=50,16 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2168001" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Revolut</p></div></p>
<p>While the company has expanded aggressively over the years, the U.K. is still by far its biggest market. In 2020, 88.4% of the company’s (non-adjusted) revenue was related to its activities in the U.K. The European Economic Area without the U.K. represented 10.2% of revenue. The U.S., Japan, Australia and other markets were nearly negligible.</p>
<p>Revolut has also raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/24/revolut-extends-series-d-round-to-580-million-with-80-million-in-new-funding/">mega round</a> of funding in 2020 —&nbsp;a $500 million Series D round that was extended to $580 million in total. I wouldn’t be surprised if the company launches an initial public offering within the next 12 months.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rrduwjXYWB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/24/revolut-extends-series-d-round-to-580-million-with-80-million-in-new-funding/">Revolut extends Series D round to $580 million with $80 million in new funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Revolut extends Series D round to $580 million with $80 million in new funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/24/revolut-extends-series-d-round-to-580-million-with-80-million-in-new-funding/embed/#?secret=rrduwjXYWB" data-secret="rrduwjXYWB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/revolut-revenue-grew-by-57-in-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167999</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook officially launches Live Audio Rooms and podcasts in the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebook-officially-launches-live-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-in-the-u-s/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebook-officially-launches-live-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-in-the-u-s/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio rooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraiser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In April, Facebook announced a series of planned investments in new audio products, including a Clubhouse live audio competitor as well as new support for podcasts. Today, Facebook is officially rolling these products with the launch of Live Audio Rooms in the U.S. on iOS, starting with public figures and select Facebook Groups, and the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In April, Facebook announced a series of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/facebook-invests-in-audio-with-short-form-soundbites-feature-podcast-support-and-a-clubhouse-clone/">planned investments in new audio products</a>, including a Clubhouse live audio competitor as well as new support for podcasts. Today, Facebook is officially rolling these products with the launch of Live Audio Rooms in the U.S. on iOS, starting with public figures and select Facebook Groups, and the debut of an initial set of U.S. podcast partners.</p>
<p>The company tells us Live Audio Rooms will become available to any verified public figure or creator in the U.S. who&#8217;s in good standing with Facebook and is using either a profile or the <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/01/introducing-the-new-page-experience/">new Facebook Pages experience</a> on iOS. For Facebook Groups, the feature is launching with &#8220;dozens of groups,&#8221; we&#8217;re told.</p>
<p>Both products will become more broadly available in the weeks and months ahead, as more people, podcasts, and Groups are brought on board. Meanwhile, 100% of Facebook users in the U.S. will be able to listen to Live Audio Rooms and podcasts as of this week.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2167912" style="width: 361px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167912" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2167912" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/LAR.png?w=351" alt="" width="351" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/LAR.png 926w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/LAR.png?resize=78,150 78w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/LAR.png?resize=155,300 155w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/LAR.png?resize=768,1486 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/LAR.png?resize=351,680 351w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/LAR.png?resize=794,1536 794w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/LAR.png?resize=26,50 26w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2167912" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Much like Clubhouse or similar audio apps, Facebook&#8217;s Live Audio Rooms offer a standard set of features.</p>
<p>The event’s hosts appear in rounded profile icons at the top of the screen, while the listeners appear in the bottom half of the screen, as smaller icons. The active speaker is indicated with a glowing ring. If verified, a check appears next to their name, as well.</p>
<p>There are also options for enabling live captions, a &#8220;raise hand&#8221; tool to request to speak, and tools to share the room with others on Facebook, through things like News Feed or Group posts.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2167908" style="width: 361px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167908" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2167908" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NF-Rooms-tray.png?w=351" alt="" width="351" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NF-Rooms-tray.png 926w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NF-Rooms-tray.png?resize=78,150 78w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NF-Rooms-tray.png?resize=155,300 155w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NF-Rooms-tray.png?resize=768,1486 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NF-Rooms-tray.png?resize=351,680 351w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NF-Rooms-tray.png?resize=794,1536 794w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NF-Rooms-tray.png?resize=26,50 26w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2167908" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Facebook does things a little differently than others in some places. For instance, hosts are able to invite people to join them as a speaker in advance of the session, or they can choose listeners during the stream to join them. In each session, there can be up to 50 speakers and there&#8217;s no limit on the number of listeners, Facebook says.</p>
<p>During the session, users will be notified when friends or followers join the chat, too.</p>
<p>While listening, users can &#8220;Like&#8221; or react to the content as it streams using the &#8220;Thumbs Up&#8221; button at the bottom of the screen which connects you to Facebook&#8217;s set of emoji reactions. And with today&#8217;s official launch, listeners can also now show support to the public figure of the Live Audio Room by sending &#8220;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/help/903272529876480?id=648321075955172">Stars</a>.&#8221; These Stars can be purchased during the conversation and used at any time, similar to how they work with other Facebook Live content.</p>
<p>By sending Stars, the listener is bumped up to the &#8220;Front Row,&#8221; a special section that highlights the people who sent the Stars. This allows the event&#8217;s hosts to easily recognize their supporters and even give them a shout out during the event, if they choose.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2167911" style="width: 361px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167911" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2167911" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Stars.png?w=351" alt="" width="351" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Stars.png 926w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Stars.png?resize=78,150 78w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Stars.png?resize=155,300 155w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Stars.png?resize=768,1486 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Stars.png?resize=351,680 351w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Stars.png?resize=794,1536 794w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Stars.png?resize=26,50 26w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2167911" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Another new feature allows hosts to select a nonprofit or fundraiser to support during their conversation, and listeners and speakers can directly donate. A progress bar will show how much has been raised during the show.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2167909" style="width: 361px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167909" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2167909" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Donations.png?w=351" alt="" width="351" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Donations.png 926w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Donations.png?resize=78,150 78w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Donations.png?resize=155,300 155w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Donations.png?resize=768,1486 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Donations.png?resize=351,680 351w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Donations.png?resize=794,1536 794w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Donations.png?resize=26,50 26w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2167909" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Meanwhile, for Facebook Groups, admins can control whether moderators, group members or other admins can create a Live Audio Room. Both members and visitors can listen to the rooms in public groups, but in private groups, the rooms are limited to Group members.</p>
<p>Facebook users are alerted to all the new Live Audio Rooms via the News Feed and Notifications, and can sign up to be reminded when a room they&#8217;re interested in goes Live. Live Audio Rooms will also be discoverable within Facebook Groups, where available.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2167913" style="width: 361px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167913" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2167913" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Audio-Room-Creation.png?w=351" alt="" width="351" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Audio-Room-Creation.png 926w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Audio-Room-Creation.png?resize=78,150 78w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Audio-Room-Creation.png?resize=155,300 155w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Audio-Room-Creation.png?resize=768,1486 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Audio-Room-Creation.png?resize=351,680 351w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Audio-Room-Creation.png?resize=794,1536 794w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Audio-Room-Creation.png?resize=26,50 26w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2167913" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Among the initial set of early adopters for Facebook Live Audio Rooms are Grammy-nominated electronic music artist <a href="https://www.facebook.com/tokimonsta">TOKiMONSTA</a>; American football quarterback <a href="https://www.facebook.com/DangerRussWilson">Russell Wilson</a>; organizer, producer and independent journalist <a href="https://www.facebook.com/rosa.clemente.779">Rosa Clemente</a>; streamer and digital entertainer Omareloff; and social entrepreneur Amanda Nguyen. Others planned for the near future include<i> </i><a href="https://www.facebook.com/dsmokemusic">D Smoke</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Kehlani">Kehlani</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/reggie.watts">Reggie Watts</a>, and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/MissLisaMorales">Lisa Morales Duke</a>, to <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1GEq47UYwj4ttd6iE00YccVCQWLxxS1sVEyrLFaCQy78/edit">Dr. Jess</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/BobbyBerkOfficial">Bobby Berk</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Tina-Knowles-Lawson-106440571600237">Tina Knowles-Lawson</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/officialjoebudden">Joe Budden</a> (notably Spotify&#8217;s first big podcast star <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-08-27/spotify-loses-joe-budden-company-s-first-big-podcasting-star">who it lost last year</a>), and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/iamderay">DeRay Mckesson</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2167914" style="width: 361px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167914" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2167914" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-In-Room-Experience.png?w=351" alt="" width="351" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-In-Room-Experience.png 926w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-In-Room-Experience.png?resize=78,150 78w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-In-Room-Experience.png?resize=155,300 155w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-In-Room-Experience.png?resize=768,1486 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-In-Room-Experience.png?resize=351,680 351w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-In-Room-Experience.png?resize=794,1536 794w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-In-Room-Experience.png?resize=26,50 26w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2167914" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Facebook Groups trying the new format include Dance Accepts Everyone, Vegan Soul Food, Meditation Matters, Pow Wow Nation, OctoNation &#8211; The Largest Octopus Fan Club!, and Space Hipsters.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2167915" style="width: 361px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167915" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2167915" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Member-Profile.png?w=351" alt="" width="351" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Member-Profile.png 926w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Member-Profile.png?resize=78,150 78w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Member-Profile.png?resize=155,300 155w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Member-Profile.png?resize=768,1486 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Member-Profile.png?resize=351,680 351w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Member-Profile.png?resize=794,1536 794w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Groups-Member-Profile.png?resize=26,50 26w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2167915" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Alongside the launch of Live Audio Rooms, Facebook is also beginning to roll out its planned podcast support with a few select creators. These include <a href="https://www.facebook.com/officialjoebudden">Joe Budden</a> of The Joe Budden Podcast; “<a href="https://www.facebook.com/JessHilarious">Jess Hilarious</a>” of Carefully Reckless from The Black Effect Podcast Network and iHeartRadio; Keltie Knight, Becca Tobin, and Jac Vanek of <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/858364947626265">The LadyGang</a>; and Nicaila Matthews Okome of <a href="https://www.facebook.com/SideHustlePro">Side Hustle Pro</a>. Facebook will open up to other podcasters this summer.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2167919" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167919" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2167919" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Podcasts-Side-by-Side.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="410" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Podcasts-Side-by-Side.png 1660w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Podcasts-Side-by-Side.png?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Podcasts-Side-by-Side.png?resize=300,181 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Podcasts-Side-by-Side.png?resize=768,463 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Podcasts-Side-by-Side.png?resize=680,410 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Podcasts-Side-by-Side.png?resize=1536,925 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Podcasts-Side-by-Side.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2167919" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>To be clear, this new podcasts service is different from the recently launched <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/facebook-introduces-a-new-miniplayer-that-streams-spotify-within-the-facebook-app/">music and podcasts player in partnership with Spotify</a>, which lets users share content from Spotify to the social network. The new feature instead involves podcasts that are streamed via public RSS feeds directly on Facebook, not delivered by Spotify. However, the miniplayer for podcasts on Facebook will look like the miniplayer for the Spotify listening integration (also known as Project Boombox), and they will behave similarly. But they are not the same.</p>
<p>The new podcast listening experience lets users listen to podcasts as they browse Facebook, either in a miniplayer or fullscreen player with playback options, and even if the phone&#8217;s display is turned off. This makes Facebook, in a way, a native podcast streaming app because it allows people to listen to audio without needing another service &#8212; like Spotify or Apple Podcasts, for example.</p>
<p>Facebook had<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/facebook-invests-in-audio-with-short-form-soundbites-feature-podcast-support-and-a-clubhouse-clone/"> earlier said</a> there are over 170 Facebook users who are connected to a Page for a podcast, demonstrating user interest in podcasts on its social network.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2167924" style="width: 359px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167924" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2167924" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JoeBudden.jpeg?w=349" alt="" width="349" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JoeBudden.jpeg 843w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JoeBudden.jpeg?resize=77,150 77w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JoeBudden.jpeg?resize=154,300 154w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JoeBudden.jpeg?resize=768,1495 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JoeBudden.jpeg?resize=349,680 349w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JoeBudden.jpeg?resize=789,1536 789w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JoeBudden.jpeg?resize=26,50 26w" sizes="(max-width: 349px) 100vw, 349px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2167924" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>With the launch of the Facebook Podcast service, the company is <a href="https://www.facebook.com/podcast_terms">asking podcast creators to give it permission</a> to cache their content on Facebook&#8217;s servers, which we&#8217;re told is being done to ensure the content doesn&#8217;t violate Facebook&#8217;s Community Standards. However, because the podcasts are still being streamed via RSS feeds, they will be represented in the metrics provided by a podcaster&#8217;s hosting provider.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22537023/facebook-podcast-rss-feed-publish-clips-pages?scrolla=5eb6d68b7fedc32c19ef33b4">Last week, Facebook emailed</a> podcast page owners details on how to set up their show on Facebook, noting they can link their podcast&#8217;s RSS feed to automatically generate News Feed posts for their episodes. These are also featured on a &#8220;podcasts&#8221; tab on their Page. According to Facebook&#8217;s <a href="https://www.facebook.com/podcast_terms">Podcast Terms of Service</a>, creators are granting Facebook the right to create &#8220;derivative works,&#8221; which likely refers to an upcoming clips feature.</p>
<p>Facebook says later this summer, it will add the ability to create and share short clips from a podcast, along with other features, like captions. Longer-term, it will create social experiences around podcasts, as well. It&#8217;s also working with creators to develop and launch its new product, Soundbites, which are short-form, creative audio clips. This will launch later in 2021.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2167923" style="width: 359px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167923" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2167923" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JessHilarious.jpeg?w=349" alt="" width="349" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JessHilarious.jpeg 843w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JessHilarious.jpeg?resize=77,150 77w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JessHilarious.jpeg?resize=154,300 154w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JessHilarious.jpeg?resize=768,1495 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JessHilarious.jpeg?resize=349,680 349w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JessHilarious.jpeg?resize=789,1536 789w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FB_Podcast_JessHilarious.jpeg?resize=26,50 26w" sizes="(max-width: 349px) 100vw, 349px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2167923" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Other audio products in the works include a central listening destination and background audio listening for videos.</p>
<p>Facebook says this new destination will be a place where all the different audio formats across Facebook are available, not just podcasts, and will help users find to new things and people to listen to. More details on this project will become available later this summer.</p>
<p>Prior to today, Facebook quietly <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-11/facebook-begins-testing-clubhouse-rival-expanding-audio-suite">tested</a> Live Audio Rooms in Taiwan and internally with Facebook employees Those tests will continue. Last week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/facebook-ceo-mark-zuckerberg-hosts-first-test-of-live-audio-rooms-in-u-s/">Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg hosted the first trial</a> of the new service in the U.S., where he was joined by other Facebook execs and a few Facebook Gaming creators.</p>
<p>Zuckerberg has been bullish on the potential for audio across the social networking platform. He even appeared on Clubhouse a couple of times to discuss the topic ahead of announcing what is, essentially, Facebook&#8217;s own Clubhouse competitor.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think the areas where I’m most excited about it on Facebook are basically in the large number of communities and groups that exist,&#8221; Zuckerberg had told <a href="https://www.platformer.news/subscribe">Platformer</a>, at the time of the original announcement. &#8220;I think that you already have these communities that are organized around interests, and allowing people to come together and have rooms where they can talk is — I think it’d be a very useful thing,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Facebook expects to expand its audio products globally in the months ahead.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebook-officially-launches-live-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-in-the-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167847</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple&#8217;s App Store to face scrutiny in Germany as FCO opens &#8216;market power&#8217; proceeding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/apples-app-store-to-face-scrutiny-in-germany-as-fco-opens-market-power-proceeding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/apples-app-store-to-face-scrutiny-in-germany-as-fco-opens-market-power-proceeding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 10:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreas Mundt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bundeskartellamt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platform regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167976</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Germany&#8217;s competition authority, the FCO, has completed its Big Tech GAFA &#8216;bingo&#8217; card by opening a proceeding against Apple. As with similar investigations already opened this year &#8212; into Amazon, Facebook and Google &#8212; the proceeding will determine whether or not the iPhone maker meets the threshold of Germany&#8217;s updated competition law. The 10th amendment [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Germany&#8217;s competition authority, the FCO, has completed its Big Tech GAFA &#8216;bingo&#8217; card by opening a proceeding against Apple.</p>
<p>As with similar investigations already opened this year &#8212; into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/amazons-market-power-to-be-tested-in-germany-in-push-for-early-action-over-antitrust-risks/">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/in-latest-big-tech-antitrust-push-germanys-fco-targets-google-news-showcases-fine-print/">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/googles-data-terms-are-now-in-germanys-competition-crosshairs/">Google</a> &#8212; the proceeding will determine whether or not the iPhone maker meets the threshold of Germany&#8217;s updated competition law.</p>
<p>The 10th amendment to the law, which came into force in January, enables the <em>Bundeskartellamt</em> to intervene proactively against the practices of large digital companies &#8212; if they are determined to have &#8220;paramount significance for competition across markets&#8221; and in order to prevent them from engaging in anti-competitive practices.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Discussing the key new provision to the Competition Act (aka, the GWB Digitalisation Act and specifically Section 19a) &#8212; in a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/perspectives-on-tackling-big-techs-market-power/">panel discussion last week</a>, the FCO&#8217;s president, Andreas Mundt, explained that the competition law update had been influenced by its experience with a long running (and pioneering) case against <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/competition-challenge-to-facebooks-superprofiling-of-users-sparks-referral-to-europes-top-court/">Facebook&#8217;s superprofiling of Internet users</a>.</p>
<p>The upshot is that German competition law now has a theory of harm which entwines competition law and data protection &#8212; albeit, in the case of Apple, its tech empire is typically associated with defence (rather than abuse) of user privacy.</p>
<p>But the comprehensive amendments to German antitrust law are broadly targeted at Big Tech, with the goal of keeping markets open, fostering innovation and putting a stop to any abusive behavior, via provisions the FCO will be able to order &#8212; such an banning or restricting self-preferencing and bundling; or stopping giants tying products together to try to muscle into adjacent markets; or preventing them blocking interoperability and data access to try to lock out rivals, to name a few.</p>
<p>A mix of provisions are likely to be deployed, as tech giants are designated as addressable under the law, depending on the specifics of each case and the particular ecosystem business. So how it will operate in practice remains to be seen. So far the FCO is still in the process of determining (in each case) whether it can apply the law against GAFA.</p>
<p>For the Apple proceeding, Mundt said in a statement today that its operation of the App Store will be a &#8220;main focus&#8221; for the investigation because he said it &#8220;enables Apple in many ways to influence the business activities of third parties&#8221;.</p>
<p>“We will now examine whether with its proprietary operating system iOS, Apple has created a digital ecosystem around its iPhone that extends across several markets,&#8221; he added. &#8220;Apple produces tablets, computers and wearables and provides a host of device-related services. In addition to manufacturing various hardware products, the tech company also offers the App Store, iCloud, AppleCare, Apple Music, Apple Arcade, Apple TV+ as well as other services as part of its services business. Besides assessing the company’s position in these areas, we will, among other aspects, examine its extensive integration across several market levels, the magnitude of its technological and financial resources and its access to data.&#8221;</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.bundeskartellamt.de/SharedDocs/Meldung/EN/Pressemitteilungen/2021/21_06_2021_Apple.html;jsessionid=3BE5BF223F8A517B1CB5906C695F23C9.2_cid378">FCO also noted</a> that it has received a number of complaints against Apple &#8220;relating to potentially anti-competitive practices&#8221; &#8212; such as one from the advertising and media industry against Apple restricting user tracking with the introduction of its iOS 14.5 operating system; and a complaint against the exclusive pre-installation of the company’s own applications as a possible type of self-preferencing prohibited under Section 19a GWB.</p>
<p>&#8220;App developers also criticise the mandatory use of Apple’s own in-app purchase system (IAP) and the 30% commission rate associated with this,&#8221; it added in a press release. &#8220;In this context, the marketing restrictions for app developers in Apple’s App Store are also addressed. The latter complaint has much in common with the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/europe-charges-apple-with-antitrust-breach-citing-spotify-app-store-complaint/">European Commission’s ongoing proceeding against Apple</a> for imposing restrictions on the streaming service Spotify and accordingly preferencing its own services. Where necessary, the Bundeskartellamt will establish contact with the European Commission and other competition authorities in this regard. So far, no decision on initiating a further proceeding has been taken.&#8221;</p>
<p>Apple was contacted for comment on the FCO&#8217;s proceeding and it sent us this statement, attributed to a spokesperson:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;<span class="il">Apple</span> is proud to be an engine for innovation and job creation, with more than 250,000 jobs supported by the iOS app economy in Germany. The App Store’s economic growth and activity have given German developers of all sizes the same opportunity to share their passion and creativity with users around the world while creating a secure and trusted place for customers to download the apps they love with the privacy protections they expect. Germany is also home to <span class="il">Apple</span>’s largest engineering hub in Europe, and a new €1BN investment in our European Silicon Design Center in Munich. We look forward to discussing our approach with the FCO and having an open dialogue about any of their concerns.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Once issued by the FCO, a &#8216;paramount significance&#8217; finding lasts for five years &#8212; while any legal challenges to orders made under Section 19a are intentionally expedited, with appeals going direct to Germany&#8217;s Federal Court of Justice (which is given exclusive competence). The goal being to avoid long drawn out litigations, as has occurred in the FCO&#8217;s case against Facebook&#8217;s superprofiling &#8212; which had legal questions referred to the CJEU <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/competition-challenge-to-facebooks-superprofiling-of-users-sparks-referral-to-europes-top-court/">back in March</a>, some five years after the <em>Bundeskartellamt</em> began looking into Facebook’s data practices.</p>
<p>The coming months and years could be highly significant to how GAFA is able to operate in Europe&#8217;s largest economy &#8212; and, likely by extension, further afield in Europe and beyond as a number of jurisdictions are now paying active attention to how to regulate Big Tech.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/apples-app-store-is-now-also-under-antitrust-scrutiny-in-the-uk/">Back in March</a>, for example, the UK&#8217;s Competition and Markets Authority opened its own probe into Apple&#8217;s App Store. Simultaneously it&#8217;s working on reforming national law to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/uk-to-set-up-pro-competition-regulator-to-put-limits-on-big-tech/">create a &#8216;pro-competition&#8217; for regulating tech giants</a>.</p>
<p>While, last December, European Union lawmakers proposed the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/">Digital Markets Act</a> &#8212; also aiming to tackle the power market of so-called &#8216;gatekeeper&#8217; platforms.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/lina-khan-ftc-confirmed/">FTC appointing Lina Khan as chair</a> also appears to signify a change of direction on tech antitrust over in the US.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AP7fTYgkO6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/perspectives-on-tackling-big-techs-market-power/">Perspectives on tackling Big Tech&#8217;s market power</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Perspectives on tackling Big Tech&#8217;s market power&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/perspectives-on-tackling-big-techs-market-power/embed/#?secret=AP7fTYgkO6" data-secret="AP7fTYgkO6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5pkyD1yEyW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/competition-challenge-to-facebooks-superprofiling-of-users-sparks-referral-to-europes-top-court/">Competition challenge to Facebook&#8217;s &#8216;superprofiling&#8217; of users sparks referral to Europe&#8217;s top court</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Competition challenge to Facebook&#8217;s &#8216;superprofiling&#8217; of users sparks referral to Europe&#8217;s top court&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/competition-challenge-to-facebooks-superprofiling-of-users-sparks-referral-to-europes-top-court/embed/#?secret=5pkyD1yEyW" data-secret="5pkyD1yEyW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vpqVAKxeSJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/in-latest-big-tech-antitrust-push-germanys-fco-targets-google-news-showcases-fine-print/">In latest Big Tech antitrust push, Germany&#8217;s FCO eyes Google News Showcase fine print</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;In latest Big Tech antitrust push, Germany&#8217;s FCO eyes Google News Showcase fine print&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/in-latest-big-tech-antitrust-push-germanys-fco-targets-google-news-showcases-fine-print/embed/#?secret=vpqVAKxeSJ" data-secret="vpqVAKxeSJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eNL3Au5tOh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/amazons-market-power-to-be-tested-in-germany-in-push-for-early-action-over-antitrust-risks/">Amazon&#8217;s market power to be tested in Germany in push for &#8216;early action&#8217; over antitrust risks</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon&#8217;s market power to be tested in Germany in push for &#8216;early action&#8217; over antitrust risks&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/amazons-market-power-to-be-tested-in-germany-in-push-for-early-action-over-antitrust-risks/embed/#?secret=eNL3Au5tOh" data-secret="eNL3Au5tOh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jKdFRGhrYS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/embed/#?secret=jKdFRGhrYS" data-secret="jKdFRGhrYS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/apples-app-store-to-face-scrutiny-in-germany-as-fco-opens-market-power-proceeding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167976</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vietnamese financial services app MFast gets $1.5M pre-Series A led by Do Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/vietnamese-financial-services-app-mfast-gets-1-5m-pre-series-a-led-by-do-ventures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/vietnamese-financial-services-app-mfast-gets-1-5m-pre-series-a-led-by-do-ventures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 07:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digipay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Do Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JAFCO Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MFast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MFast, a mobile app that lets Vietnamese users in remote areas access financial services, announced today it has raised a $1.5 million pre-Series A. The round was led by Do Ventures, with participation from JAFCO Asia.  Launched in 2019 by fintech company Digipay, MFast says it has been used by 600,000 people to date. It [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2167970" style="width: 5503px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MFast3.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167970" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2167970 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MFast3.png" alt="MFast founders Phan Thanh Long and Phan Thanh Vinh" width="5493" height="3662" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MFast3.png 5493w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MFast3.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MFast3.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MFast3.png?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MFast3.png?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MFast3.png?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MFast3.png?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MFast3.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 5493px) 100vw, 5493px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2167970" class="wp-caption-text">MFast founders Phan Thanh Long and Phan Thanh Vinh</p></div></p>
<p class="p1"><a href="https://mfast.vn/">MFast</a>, a mobile app that lets Vietnamese users in remote areas access financial services, announced today it has raised a $1.5 million pre-Series A. The round was led by Do Ventures, with participation from JAFCO Asia.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Launched in 2019 by fintech company Digipay, MFast says it has been used by 600,000 people to date. It partners with financial institutions who provide services like loans and insurance, and says it has been used to distribute more than 50 billion VND (about $2.2 million USD) worth of insurance products so far, and 5,000 billion (about $217 million) in financial products.. The company told TechCrunch that it currently has 11 financial partners.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p1">MFast’s consumer credit partners include Mirae Asset, CIMB, Mcredit and Easy Credit, and its insurance partners include PVI, PTI and BSH. It claims to have a network of more than 350,000 advisors, who offers their services through the app.</p>
<p>The company pre-qualifies applicants for credit services using predictive machine learning algorithms to identify applicants with high risks of defaulting on their loans, while its insurance customers are matched with plans using a data-driven engine.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dxKlUwj6Ap"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/07/do-ventures-launches-50-million-fund-for-vietnamese-startups-backed-by-naver-vertex-and-other-notable-lps/">Do Ventures launches $50 million fund for Vietnamese startups, backed by Naver, Vertex and other notable LPs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Do Ventures launches $50 million fund for Vietnamese startups, backed by Naver, Vertex and other notable LPs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/07/do-ventures-launches-50-million-fund-for-vietnamese-startups-backed-by-naver-vertex-and-other-notable-lps/embed/#?secret=dxKlUwj6Ap" data-secret="dxKlUwj6Ap" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p class="p1">The majority, or about 75% to 80% of MFast’s users are in remote provinces or rural areas, which the company says often limits their access to banking and credit-related services.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The funding will be used to expand MFast to more cities and provinces in Vietnam, develop its technology and partner with more institutions. MFast also plans to enter other markets in the future.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0hzKwzuEZS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/jeff-raises-1m-to-build-alternative-credit-scoring-and-other-fintech-products-for-southeast-asia/">Jeff raises $1M to build alternative credit scoring and other fintech products for Southeast Asia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jeff raises $1M to build alternative credit scoring and other fintech products for Southeast Asia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/jeff-raises-1m-to-build-alternative-credit-scoring-and-other-fintech-products-for-southeast-asia/embed/#?secret=0hzKwzuEZS" data-secret="0hzKwzuEZS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/vietnamese-financial-services-app-mfast-gets-1-5m-pre-series-a-led-by-do-ventures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167969</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GrowSari, a B2B platform for small stores in the Philippines, adds investors like Temasek&#8217;s Pavilion Capital and Tencent</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/growsari-a-b2b-platform-for-small-stores-in-the-philippines-adds-investors-like-temaseks-pavilion-capital-and-tencent/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/growsari-a-b2b-platform-for-small-stores-in-the-philippines-adds-investors-like-temaseks-pavilion-capital-and-tencent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 07:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B2B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FMCG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GrowSari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MSMEs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pavilion Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sari sari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sari-sari stores are neighborhood stores in the Philippines that usually sell daily necessities and sometimes serve as community hubs, too. Today GrowSari, a startup that is digitizing sari-sari stores with features like pricing tools, inventory management and working capital loans, announced it has raised a Series B from several notable investors that brings its total [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Sari-sari stores are neighborhood stores in the Philippines that usually sell daily necessities and sometimes serve as community hubs, too. Today<a href="https://growsari.com/"> GrowSari</a>, a startup that is digitizing sari-sari stores with features like pricing tools, inventory management and working capital loans, announced it has raised a Series B from several notable investors that brings its total funding to $30 million.</p>
<p>The company’s Series B is at a rolling close, so it has not announced a final amount. The $30 million total it has raised include its seed funding and Series A, which <a href="https://the-ken.com/sea/story/growsaris-key-to-the-philippines-sari-sari-treasure/">according to the Ken was $14 million</a>. Participants in its Series B included Temasek Holdings’ private equity unit Pavilion Capital, Tencent, International Finance Corporation (IFC), ICCP SBI Venture Partners and Saison Capital, and returning investors Robinsons Retail Holdings (which is part of the Gokongwei Group), JG Digital Equity Ventures and Wavemaker Partners.</p>
<p>GrowSari was founded in 2016, and says its B2B platform is currently used by more than 50,000 stores in over 100 municipalities on Luzon, the Philippines’ largest and most populated island. Its ultimate goal is to serve one million sari-sari stores.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Im8Yd6x2jZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/indias-khatabook-raises-60-million-to-help-merchants-digitize-bookkeeping-and-accept-payments-online/">India&#8217;s Khatabook raises $60 million to help merchants digitize bookkeeping and accept payments online</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India&#8217;s Khatabook raises $60 million to help merchants digitize bookkeeping and accept payments online&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/indias-khatabook-raises-60-million-to-help-merchants-digitize-bookkeeping-and-accept-payments-online/embed/#?secret=Im8Yd6x2jZ" data-secret="Im8Yd6x2jZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>According to GrowSari, there are more than 1.1 million sari-sari stores in the Philippines, and they account for 60% of fast-moving consumer goods (FMCG) sold in the country, making them a valuable distribution channel for wholesalers. In addition to its supplier marketplace, GrowSari says it is able to give sari-sari store operators better pricing for products from about a thousand FMCG brands, including Unilever, P&amp;G and Nestle, which it claims can help stores double their earnings. Other services in the app include online telecom and utility bill payments, remittance and microfinancing for working capital loans.</p>
<p>GrowSari’s founding team includes Reymund Rollan, Shiv Choudhury, Siddhartha Kongara and Andrzej Ogonowski, who first launched the platform as a backend system for sari-sari stores to manage their logistics and inventory.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2167965" style="width: 316px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Categories.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2167965" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2167965" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Categories.jpg?w=306" alt="A screenshot of product categories in GrowSari's app" width="306" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Categories.jpg 576w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Categories.jpg?resize=68,150 68w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Categories.jpg?resize=135,300 135w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Categories.jpg?resize=306,680 306w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Categories.jpg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 306px) 100vw, 306px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2167965" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot of product categories in GrowSari&#8217;s app</p></div></p>
<p>Since most sari-sari stores are run individually, their margins are smaller than large retailers that can negotiate deals with FMCG wholesalers. GrowSari’s supplier marketplace addresses this issue by giving sari-sari stores access the Distributor List Prices seen by large stores and wholesalers. GrowSari’s marketplace does not require a minimum order, and it allows sari-sari stores on the platform to pay with cash on delivery, GrowCoins (or cash credits that can be topped up through GrowSari’s shippers, online transfers, banks or over-the-counter at convenience stores) or E-Lista, GrowSari’s seven-day loan product.</p>
<p>GrowSari’s new capital will be used to expand its userbase to 300,000 new stores in the Philippines, especially in Visayas and Mindanao, increase the size of its supplier marketplace and launch more financial products for sari-sari stores. The startup is part of a new crop of B2B platforms in Asia focused on serving micro to small-enterprises, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/bukuwarung-a-fintech-for-indonesian-msmes-scores-60m-series-a-led-by-valar-and-goodwater/">BukuWarung</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/">BukuKas</a> in Indonesia and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/indias-khatabook-raises-60-million-to-help-merchants-digitize-bookkeeping-and-accept-payments-online/">Khatabook in Indi</a>a.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SSvXKGjftt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/">BukuKas gets $50M from investors including DoorDash&#8217;s Gokul Rajaram and TransferWise founder Taavet Hinrikus</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BukuKas gets $50M from investors including DoorDash&#8217;s Gokul Rajaram and TransferWise founder Taavet Hinrikus&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/embed/#?secret=SSvXKGjftt" data-secret="SSvXKGjftt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fY2DvqcDLk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/bukuwarung-a-fintech-for-indonesian-msmes-scores-60m-series-a-led-by-valar-and-goodwater/">BukuWarung, a fintech for Indonesian MSMEs, scores $60M Series A led by Valar and Goodwater</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BukuWarung, a fintech for Indonesian MSMEs, scores $60M Series A led by Valar and Goodwater&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/bukuwarung-a-fintech-for-indonesian-msmes-scores-60m-series-a-led-by-valar-and-goodwater/embed/#?secret=fY2DvqcDLk" data-secret="fY2DvqcDLk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/growsari-a-b2b-platform-for-small-stores-in-the-philippines-adds-investors-like-temaseks-pavilion-capital-and-tencent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167962</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto finance startup Amber Group raises $100M at $1B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/20/crypto-finance-startup-amber-group-raises-100m-at-1b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/20/crypto-finance-startup-amber-group-raises-100m-at-1b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 22:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arena Holdings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dcm ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gobi Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pantera capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167930</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More mainstream venture capital firms are jumping on the crypto bandwagon as investors increasingly consider bitcoin an investable asset, despite the recent massive price drops of a few major cryptocurrencies. Amber Group, a Hong Kong-based cryptocurrency trading startup, said on Monday it has raised $100 million in a Series B funding round at a pre-money [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">More mainstream venture capital firms are jumping on the crypto bandwagon as investors increasingly consider bitcoin an investable asset, despite the recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/bitcoin-crashes-as-investors-fear-crypto-bull-market-could-be-nearing-its-end/">massive price drops</a> of a few major cryptocurrencies. Amber Group, a Hong Kong-based cryptocurrency trading startup, said on Monday it has raised $100 million in a Series B funding round at a pre-money valuation of $1 billion.</p>
<p>The latest valuation is ten times that of the company&#8217;s Series A closed in 2019, a $28 million round that counted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/coinbase-ventures/">Coinbase Ventures</a> as one of its investors. Also notably, Amber&#8217;s Series B financing was bankrolled by a list of high-profile financial and VC firms, including China Renaissance, which led the round, and Tiger Brokers, Tiger Global Management, Arena Holdings, Tru Arrow Partners, Sky9 Capital, DCM Ventures, and Gobi Partners.</p>
<p>&#8220;Many of the new investors which came in this round provide great breadth in terms of perspective, having seen many high growth companies in fast evolving industries go from 0 to 1, and 1 to 100,&#8221; Amber&#8217;s co-founder and CEO Michael Wu told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;From an employer branding perspective, we are trying to attract global talents, and many of those are potentially new to crypto. For them, seeing these more traditional and familiar names backing Amber helps make them more interested in joining Amber potentially.&#8221;</p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s past investors Pantera Capital, Coinbase Ventures, and Blockchain.com also participated in the new round.</p>
<p>In May, Babel Finance, another crypto asset manager based out of Hong Kong, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/babel-40-million-funding/">secured $40 million in funding</a> from a number of big-name institutional investors, including Amber&#8217;s investor Tiger Global.</p>
<p>Founded by a group of former investment bankers in their twenties, <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Amber <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jeffkauflin/2020/02/14/crypto-heavyweights-coinbase-polychain-and-paradigm-invest-28-million-in-hong-kong-crypto-trading-firm/?sh=3435c9e0b833">initially set out to apply machine learning algorithms to quantitative trading</a> but pivoted in 2017 to crypto when the team saw spikes in virtual currency&#8217;s trading volumes. The startup now serves </span>both institutional and individual investors, offering them algorithmic trading, electronic market-making, high-frequency trading, OTC trading, borrowing and lending, derivatives, among other products.</p>
<p>The firm launched its mobile app in the third quarter of 2020, widening its scope from institutional clients to retail consumers. Over 700 institutional customers &#8212; mainly large hedge funds, family offices, and corporations &#8212; account for over 70% of its revenues, though its consumer-facing app has grown substantially, with over 100,000 registered users as of late.</p>
<p>Amber has been profitable since its inception, according to Wu, with annualized revenues of $500 million based on figures from January to April 2021.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s business hasn&#8217;t been dampened by the recent slump in prices. Rather, its revenues from the second quarter were at an all-time record and tripling that of Q1, said Wu.</p>
<p>&#8220;Whilst the drop in prices means that our AUM [assets under management] measured in dollar terms decline, in terms of the number of coins for BTC, ETH and stablecoins, they are all still growing healthily. Meanwhile, our trading business is also still flourishing with the uptick in volatility.&#8221;</p>
<p>The startup now accounts for 2-3% of total trading volumes in major spot and derivative markets, the founder said. Its cumulative trading volumes have doubled from $250 billion since the beginning of the year to over $500 billion. Altogether, Amble manages around $1.5 billion in trading capital that varies based on BTC and ETH prices.</p>
<p>The firm now has over 330 employees worldwide across Hong Kong, Taipei, Seoul, and Vancouver. The proceeds from its Series B will go towards aggressive hiring across all fronts, from quantitative research, software development, compliance, to business development. It also plans to tap marketers and distribution channels for user acquisition, as well as work on clearing regulatory hurdles in more jurisdictions.</p>
<p>Critics have long been wary of the crypto industry&#8217;s environmental costs. On this issue, Wu countered that &#8220;Amber is not engaged in proof-of-work mining, yet.&#8221; He&#8217;s also optimistic about where the field is headed.</p>
<p>&#8220;Based on available data, over 40% of bitcoin mining is already from renewable resources. Based on trends we see with our mining clients and partners, we believe that this number will continue to go up.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>Updated the article with more quotes from the founder.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="M4S4tFPXz7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/katie-haun-on-saying-yes-to-coinbase-and-where-a16zs-crypto-fund-is-largely-placing-its-bets-now/">Katie Haun on saying yes to Coinbase and where a16z&#8217;s crypto fund is placing its bets now</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Katie Haun on saying yes to Coinbase and where a16z&#8217;s crypto fund is placing its bets now&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/katie-haun-on-saying-yes-to-coinbase-and-where-a16zs-crypto-fund-is-largely-placing-its-bets-now/embed/#?secret=M4S4tFPXz7" data-secret="M4S4tFPXz7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/20/crypto-finance-startup-amber-group-raises-100m-at-1b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167930</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dollars, deals and the importance of nondilutive capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/19/dollars-deals-and-the-importance-of-nondilutive-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/19/dollars-deals-and-the-importance-of-nondilutive-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 18:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups Weekly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2167614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, on Juneteenth, we recognize the efforts this nation still needs to put toward addressing structural racism and disparities, including in the world of tech. This week, HBCUvc, a nonprofit that aims to diversify the world of venture capital, launched a million-dollar fund. Founder Hadiyah Mujhid told me that the capital would provide nondilutive financing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today, on Juneteenth, we recognize the efforts this nation still needs to put toward addressing structural racism and disparities, including in the world of tech.</p>
<p>This week, HBCUvc, a nonprofit that aims to diversify the world of venture capital, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/hbcuvc-venture-capital-lab-fund-1-million/">launched a million-dollar fund.</a> Founder Hadiyah Mujhid told me that the capital would provide nondilutive financing to overlooked founders, which they define as Black, Indigenous and LatinX entrepreneurs, replacing the traditional angel round. But she also admitted that supporting founders wasn’t the only primary goal. Instead, she explained to me the importance of what she defines as “teaching capital.”</p>
<p>Similar to how teaching hospitals give aspiring doctors a way to practice and learn their craft before formally entering the field, the fund wants to do that for their some 230 aspiring investors that they already work with, many stemming from historically Black colleges and universities. Notably, nondilutive capital provides entrepreneurs with funding sans equity and a learning experience with lower stakes.</p>
<blockquote><p>There are a lot of organizations right now that are starting funds [with] the primary goal of supporting founders. And that’s a goal of ours, but we’re hoping to have a ripple effect of training and really providing on-ramps for the next best-in-class investors … and in order to do that, they have to have a training vehicle.</p></blockquote>
<p>While I’m not always a fan of rebranded names for capital, “teaching capital” is certainly a compelling framing. Track record is everything in this industry, and underrepresented folks often don’t have the benefit or privilege of access on their side — from a dollar or deals perspective. Scout programs have long existed to fill this gap, but I think that there is still a lacking of intentionality around who feels empowered to write an investment memo, ask questions and be new. This week, BLCK VC <a href="https://twitter.com/BLCKVC/status/1405279760624754688">launched its scout program</a> and Google for Startups launched a nondilutive financing instrument for Black founders, underscoring a growing focus in seeding diverse entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>HBCUvc’s fund was announced nearly one year after it almost shut down due to a lack of capital. Mujhid explained how the unjust killing of George Floyd led to the biggest one-day donation in her nonprofit&#8217;s lifetime, which “changed the trajectory of programming.” She also said that a lot of interest was a knee-jerk reaction, urging people to view this work as a long-term commitment.</p>
<p><em>Down the creative capital rabbit hole we go:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/27/how-capital-as-a-service-can-help-you-get-your-first-check-in-2021/">How capital as a service can help you get your first check in 2021</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/how-to-identify-unicorn-founders-when-theyre-still-early-stage/">How to identify unicorn founders when they’re still early-stage</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/dismantling-the-myths-around-raising-your-first-check/">Dismantling the myths around raising your first check</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/3-lessons-we-learned-after-raising-6-3m-from-50-investors/">3 lessons we learned after raising $6.3M from 50 investors</a></li>
</ul>
<p>In the rest of this newsletter, we’ll get into Waymo’s latest raise, the Nubank EC-1 and a Pittsburgh event that I can’t wait to nerd out about.</p>
<h2>Waymo gets way more</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1794963" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/honey-bear-laser-waymo.png" alt="" width="1024" height="544" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/honey-bear-laser-waymo.png 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/honey-bear-laser-waymo.png?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/honey-bear-laser-waymo.png?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/honey-bear-laser-waymo.png?resize=768,408 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/honey-bear-laser-waymo.png?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/honey-bear-laser-waymo.png?resize=1536,816 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/honey-bear-laser-waymo.png?resize=2048,1088 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/honey-bear-laser-waymo.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin</p>
<p>Waymo, Alphabet’s self-driving arm, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/waymo-alphabets-self-driving-arm-raises-2-5b-in-second-external-investment-round/">raised $2.5 billion</a> in its second-ever institutional round. Investors include Alphabet, Andreessen Horowitz, AutoNation, Canada Pension Plan Investment Board, Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company, Temasek and, of course, Tiger Global.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>Waymo is going external after some internal shuffling. The funding comes only months after CEO John Krafcik stepped down from his title after spending five years in that position. Last month, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/waymos-cfo-and-head-of-automotive-partnerships-are-leaving-the-autonomous-vehicle-company/">Waymo lost its CFO and head of partnerships.</a></p>
<p><em>For more, here are my favorite recaps of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021?promo=leftrail&amp;display=true">TC Sessions: Mobility</a>:</em></p>
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021?promo=leftrail&amp;display=true"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2142930 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/mobility-startups-can-be-equitable-accessible-and-profitable/">Mobility startups can be equitable, accessible and profitable</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/waabis-raquel-urtasun-explains-why-the-time-was-right-to-launch-an-av-technology-startup/">Waabi’s Raquel Urtasun explains why it was the right time to launch an AV technology startup</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/scale-ai-ceo-alex-wang-weighs-in-on-software-bugs-and-what-will-make-av-tech-good-enough/">Scale AI CEO Alex Wang weighs in on software bugs and what will make AV tech good enough</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/investors-clara-brenner-quin-garcia-and-rachel-holt-on-spacs-micromobility-and-how-covid-19-shaped-vc/">Investors Clara Brenner, Quin Garcia and Rachel Holt on SPACs, micromobility and how COVID-19 shaped VC</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>The Nubank EC-1</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2164364" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164364" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164364" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q2_L.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="686" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q2_L.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q2_L.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q2_L.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q2_L.jpg?resize=768,515 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q2_L.jpg?resize=680,456 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q2_L.jpg?resize=1536,1029 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q2_L.jpg?resize=2048,1372 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q2_L.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164364" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nigel Sussman</p></div></p>
<p>Another week, another EC-1! Marcella McCarthy wrote about Nubank, a Brazillian credit card and banking fintech company that just last week raised at a $30 billion valuation. It’s one of the most valuable startups in the world, with over 40 million users.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>As McCarthy puts it in the piece, Nubank <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1-origin/">started </a>by trying to solve a massive challenge: “How to rebuild the concept of a bank in a country where banking is widely hated, all while the incumbents heavily entrenched with the state worked to block every move.” Maybe, the story goes on to tell, it would start with California Street.</p>
<p><em>Check out each installment of the series below:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Origin story “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1-origin/">How contrarian hires and a pitch deck started Nubank’s $30 billion fintech empire</a>” (2,350 words/9 minutes)</li>
<li>Co-founder dynamics “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1-cofounder/">One woman’s drive to make a neobank as magical as Disney</a>” (1,900 words/8 minutes)</li>
<li>Launching and scaling “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1-scaling/">How Nubank’s CX strategy made it one of the most loved digital banks</a>” (2,700 words/11 minutes)</li>
<li>Market expansion and future “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1-expansion/">Which Nubank will own the financial revolution?</a>” (2,250 words/9 minutes)</li>
</ul>
<h2>Around TC</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/karin-tsai-director-of-engineering-at-duolingo-will-be-speaking-at-techcrunch-city-spotlight-pittsburgh-on-june-29/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2166245 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-2021-tsai-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-2021-tsai-1.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-2021-tsai-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-2021-tsai-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-2021-tsai-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-2021-tsai-1.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-2021-tsai-1.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-2021-tsai-1.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-2021-tsai-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>In May, thousands of you <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1/">read my Duolingo EC-1,</a> a deep dive into Pittsburgh’s favorite edtech unicorn. Now, we’re taking you to Pittsburgh to hear from Karin Tsai, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/karin-tsai-director-of-engineering-at-duolingo-will-be-speaking-at-techcrunch-city-spotlight-pittsburgh-on-june-29/">the head of engineering there</a>, as well as Carnegie Mellon University President Farnam Jahanian, Mayor Bill Peduto and a smattering of local startups.</p>
<p>Our <a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-city-spotlight-pittsburg">TC City Spotlight: Pittsburgh</a> event will be held on June 29, <a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-city-spotlight-pittsburg">so make sure to register here</a> (for free) to listen to these conversations, enjoy the pitch-off and network with local talent.</p>
<p>Also, a friendly reminder that we’re making a list of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-growth-marketers-for-startups/">the best growth marketers for startups</a>. You can help us <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">by nominating your favorites into this survey.</a></p>
<h2>Across the week</h2>
<h3>Seen on TechCrunch</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/spotify-launches-its-live-audio-app-and-clubhouse-rival-spotify-greenroom/">Spotify launches its live audio app and Clubhouse rival, Spotify Greenroom</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/harry-stebbings-turns-up-the-volume-on-20vc-with-new-140m-fund/">Harry Stebbings turns the volume up on 20VC with new $140M fund</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/every-startup-needs-an-in-house-senate/">Every startup needs an in-house senate</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/bmw-and-ford-backed-solid-power-will-go-public-via-spac-merger-in-1-2b-deal/">BMW and Ford-backed Solid Power will go public via SPAC merger in $1.2B deal</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/everyone-you-know-is-a-disney-princess-which-means-ar-is-queen/">Everyone you know is a Disney princess, which means AR is queen</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>Seen on Extra Crunch</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/the-demise-of-browser-cookies-could-create-a-golden-age-of-digital-marketing/">The demise of browser cookies could create a Golden Age of digital marketing</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/as-the-economy-reopens-startups-are-uniquely-positioned-to-recruit-talent/">As the economy reopens, startups are uniquely positioned to recruit talent</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/dear-sophie-is-it-possible-to-expand-our-startup-in-the-us/">Dear Sophie: Is it possible to expand our startup in the US?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/edtech-investors-are-flocking-to-saas-guidance-counselors/">Edtech investors are flocking to SaaS guidance counselors</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Thanks for reading, as always. Take care everyone!</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">N</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/19/dollars-deals-and-the-importance-of-nondilutive-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2167614</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
