<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 13:43:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Motivo raises $12M Series A to speed up chip design with AI</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/motivo-raises-12-5m-series-a-to-speed-up-chip-design-with-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/motivo-raises-12-5m-series-a-to-speed-up-chip-design-with-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 13:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chip design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motivo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semiconductors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chip design is a long slog of trial and error, taking years to bring a design to market. Motivo, a five year old startup from a chip industry veteran is creating software to speed up chip design from years to months using AI. Today the company announced a $12 million Series A. Intel Capital led [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chip design is a long slog of trial and error, taking years to bring a design to market. <a href="https://motivo.ai/">Motivo</a>, a five year old startup from a chip industry veteran is creating software to speed up chip design from years to months using AI. Today the company announced a $12 million Series A.</p>
<p>Intel Capital led the round along with new investors Storm Ventures and Seraph Group, as well as participation from Inventus Capital. The company reports it has now raised a total of $20 million with its previous seed funding.</p>
<p>Motivo co-founder and CEO Bharath Rangarajan has worked in the chip industry for 30 years, and he saw a few fundamental trends and issues. For starters, the chip design process is highly time-intensive, taking years to come up with a successful candidate, and typically the first to market wins.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, Moore&#8217;s Law where you fit more and more electronics onto an increasingly powerful chip increases the complexity of these designs, and once in production, there is a lot of waste producing them. Rangarajan started the company to put artificial intelligence to work on the design process and bring chips to market faster with more accuracy in the production cycle.</p>
<p>&#8220;We can train an AI engine to bring about human judgment, and do a lot of design for manufacturability on the design without causing any other issue. So we avoid all these iteration loops [and we can also] design code and validation and timing and again we&#8217;re going from weeks and months to days,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s ultimate goal is to take the chip design process and distill it down using software and intelligence from three years to three months, and while they are not there yet, they have started to attack the problem, and have a working product that looks at chip layout, the underlying RTL code that runs the chip and the netlist, which describes how the various pieces and electronics on the chip connect together.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="q7VvdgFsbq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/taiwanese-reassurances-that-water-shortages-wont-hit-chipmaking-show-climate-changes-direct-threat-to-tech/">Taiwanese reassurances that water shortages won&#8217;t hit chipmaking show climate change&#8217;s direct threat to tech</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Taiwanese reassurances that water shortages won&#8217;t hit chipmaking show climate change&#8217;s direct threat to tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/taiwanese-reassurances-that-water-shortages-wont-hit-chipmaking-show-climate-changes-direct-threat-to-tech/embed/#?secret=q7VvdgFsbq" data-secret="q7VvdgFsbq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>One other differentiator is that the company is trying to make its AI transparent to explain why it made the decisions it did. &#8220;A lot of AI is just a black box. I don&#8217;t know why the self-driving car suddenly decided to swerve here. Our AI is understandable. We built the solution so that we can tell you why the AI is saying change the chip this way, or why it&#8217;s saying change it that way,&#8221; Rangarajan explained.</p>
<p>The company has paying customers. Although it can&#8217;t name them, there is probably a limited market for this kind of software, so you could make an educated guess that it&#8217;s the chip companies, especially with Intel Capital a lead investor on this round. At this point, the company has 15 employees, 12 of them being full time with plans to double or even triple over the next year, depending on how things go.</p>
<p>Hiring is always challenging for a company with a specific engineering focus like this one, but Rangarajan says that the team is already fairly diverse, and he is definitely looking at keeping that going as he builds the company. &#8220;We have to find the right people to join the company and you&#8217;re looking for any and all sorts of great people or backgrounds. [&#8230;] In fact, the more the merrier as far as we&#8217;re concerned. We&#8217;ve got very experienced people who&#8217;ve grown up in the industry and we&#8217;ve still built up a fairly diverse team here,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>For now, he plans to keep the office hybrid where people who want to come in can come in, but people who don&#8217;t want to like those with younger kids who aren&#8217;t vaccinated yet, can continue to work from home, he said. And that flexibility should continue even after offices open more completely.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YnFmPMGUkg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/semiconductors-in-2021/">2021 will be a calmer year for semiconductors and chips (except for Intel)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;2021 will be a calmer year for semiconductors and chips (except for Intel)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/semiconductors-in-2021/embed/#?secret=YnFmPMGUkg" data-secret="YnFmPMGUkg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/motivo-raises-12-5m-series-a-to-speed-up-chip-design-with-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189135</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Youreka Labs spins out with $8M to provide smart mobile assistant apps to field workers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/youreka-labs-spins-out-with-8m-to-provide-smart-mobile-assistant-apps-to-field-workers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/youreka-labs-spins-out-with-8m-to-provide-smart-mobile-assistant-apps-to-field-workers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill Karpovich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boulder Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grotech Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Synaptic Advisors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Youreka Labs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188979</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company is developing robotic smart mobile assistants that enable frontline workers to perform their jobs more safely and efficiently.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mobile field service startup <a href="https://youreka.io/">Youreka Labs Inc.</a> raised an $8 million Series A round of funding co-led by Boulder Ventures and Grotech Ventures, with participation from Salesforce Ventures.</p>
<p>The Maryland-based company also officially announced its CEO — Bill Karpovich joined to lead the company after previously holding executive roles with General Motors and IBM Cloud &amp; Watson Platform.</p>
<p>Youreka Labs spun out into its own company from parent company Synaptic Advisors, a cloud consulting business focused on the customer relationship management transformations using Salesforce and other artificial intelligence and automation technologies.</p>
<p>The company is developing robotic smart mobile assistants that enable frontline workers to perform their jobs more safely and efficiently. This includes things like guided procedures, smart forms and photo or video capture. Youreka is also embedded in existing Salesforce mobile applications like Field Service Mobile so that end-users only have to operate from one mobile app.</p>
<p>Youreka has identified four use cases so far: healthcare, manufacturing, energy and utilities and the public sector. Working with companies like Shell, P&amp;G, Humana and the Transportation Security Administration, the company’s technology makes it possible for someone to share their knowledge and processes with their colleagues in the field, Karpovich told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>“In the case of healthcare, we are taking complex medical assessments from a doctor and pushing them out to nurses out in the field by gathering data into a simple mobile app and making it useful,” he added. “It allows nurses to do a great job without being doctors themselves.”</p>
<p>Karpovich said the company went after Series A dollars because it was “time for it to be on its own.” He was receiving inbound interest from investors, and the capital would enable the company to proceed more rapidly. Today, the company is focused on the Salesforce ecosystem, but that can evolve over time, he added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding will be used to expand the company’s reach and products. He expects to double the team in the next six to 12 months across engineering to be able to expand the platform. Youreka boasts 100 customers today, and Karpovich would also like to invest in marketing to grow that base.</p>
<p>In addition to the use cases already identified, he sees additional potential in financial services and insurance, particularly for those assessing damage. The company is also concentrated in the United States, and Karpovich has plans to expand in the U.K. and Europe.</p>
<p>In 2020, the company grew 300%, which Karpovich attributes to the need of this kind of tool in field service. Youreka has a licensing model with charges per end user per month, along with an administrative license, for the people creating the apps, that also charges per user and per month pricing.</p>
<p>“There are 2.5 million jobs open today because companies can’t find people with the right skills,” he added. “We are making these jobs accessible. Some say that AI is doing away with jobs, but we are using AI to enhance jobs. If we can take 90% of the knowledge and give a digital assistant to less experienced people, you could open up so many opportunities.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FZ7c7BURxY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/enhanced-computer-vision-sensors-raise-manufacturing-stakes-for-robots-as-a-service/">Enhanced computer vision, sensors raise manufacturing stakes for robots as a service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Enhanced computer vision, sensors raise manufacturing stakes for robots as a service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/enhanced-computer-vision-sensors-raise-manufacturing-stakes-for-robots-as-a-service/embed/#?secret=FZ7c7BURxY" data-secret="FZ7c7BURxY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/youreka-labs-spins-out-with-8m-to-provide-smart-mobile-assistant-apps-to-field-workers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188979</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wonder Brands picks up $20M, aims to build marketplace of Latin American e-commerce brands</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/wonder-brands-picks-up-20m-aims-to-build-marketplace-of-latin-american-e-commerce-brands/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/wonder-brands-picks-up-20m-aims-to-build-marketplace-of-latin-american-e-commerce-brands/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 13:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ALLVP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CoVenture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federico Malek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Groupon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MercadoLibre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Breitstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mountain Nazca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nicolás Gonzalez Luna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victory Park Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wonder Brands]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[E-commerce roll-up companies are big in the United States, and Wonder Brands wants to be that for Latin America.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">E-commerce roll-up companies are big in the United States, and <a href="https://wonderbrands.co/">Wonder Brands</a> wants to be that for Latin America.</p>
<p>The Mexico-based company closed on $20 million in seed funding, co-led by ALLVP and Mountain Nazca, with participation from CoVenture, Victory Park Capital, GFC, QED (Fontes), Korify Capital and Endeavor Catalyst.</p>
<p>Wonder Brands co-founders Nicolás Gonzalez Luna and Federico Malek came together to start the company in January 2021 to acquire digital brands in the MercadoLibre and Amazon ecosystem. It then leverages its technology to scale their operations and grow sales by taking care of the marketing, analytics, supply chain management and working capital needs of the companies. It focuses on companies in the areas of home and garden, sports and fitness, beauty and personal care.</p>
<p>“MercadoLibre has a larger share, but Amazon is entering the region quickly, so there is not one dominating marketplace. MercadoLibre may have half the market, but then it is more balanced between a number of different platforms,” Gonzalez Luna told TechCrunch. “That diversification means operations here are more complex than the classic Amazon seller. Negotiations take longer and require more discussion about who you are to get the trust in you. That’s why we will be doing fewer, but larger deals than our U.S. counterparts.”</p>
<p>Malek’s background is on the commerce side, having worked at Argentinian insurtech company iunigo.com before founding e-commerce fulfillment company Avenida.com, which was acquired by Groupon in 2010. He then worked as Groupon’s managing director in the region. He knew Gonzalez Luna, whose background includes Goldman Sachs where he focused on M&amp;A.</p>
<p>Michael Breitstein, principal at CoVenture, said his firm has made a variety of investments on the debt and equity sides of e-commerce and believes Malek and Gonzalez Luna provide a “great one-two punch” with their backgrounds, as well as the ability to raise capital and build out a platform.</p>
<p>Though there is a lot of competition to acquire digitally native companies in the $1 million revenue range, Malek said Wonder Brands will focus on larger sellers and operators, with a deal target of at least $5 million in revenue. They are also taking a “buy and build” approach rather than the “buy and consolidate” business model many of the other roll-up companies have, he added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With its approach, the company’s goal is to enable its acquired companies to sell on multiple channels. It provides support in four areas: category management and brand development, marketing and performance, technology to automate processes like inventory and logistics and operations to manage all of the channels needed. For example, in Latin America, inventory has to be consolidated into one warehouse, but then separated depending on the sales channel, Malek.</p>
<p>Acquiring and scaling companies is big business. London-based Hahnbeck Business Systems, an e-commerce M&amp;A firm that <a href="https://www.hahnbeck.com/fba-acquirers">tracks funding</a> to FBA (fulfillment by Amazon) acquirers all over the world, reports that e-commerce roll-up companies raised $7.24 billion in disclosed funding to date.</p>
<p>According to the different sources, reports say Latin American e-commerce company MercadoLibre has a market cap of between $70 billion and $94.billion. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.digitalcommerce360.com/2021/04/29/what-percentage-of-products-on-amazon-are-sold-by-marketplace-sellers/">marketplace merchants</a> accounted for 55% of units sold on Amazon.com, according to the retailer. In 2020, that accounted for $300 billion in sales, <a href="https://www.marketplacepulse.com/articles/amazon-gmv-in-2020">according to Marketplace Pulse</a> estimates based on Amazon disclosures.</p>
<p>The seed financing enables Wonder Brands to invest in building a team to focus on the four support areas and marketing. The company has 20 employees currently and plans to triple that in the next month. The funding is also complementing larger debt facilities that the company has available to acquire brands. Its target is to make six or seven acquisitions this year.</p>
<p>The company is on target to achieve $55 million in revenue by the end of the year and will then move toward $100 million in revenue in the next 12 months, Malek said. It currently operates in Mexico and plans to begin operations in Brazil by the end of 2021.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1upGGkNEVJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/e-commerce-roll-ups-present-the-next-wave-of-disruption-in-consumer-packaged-goods/">E-commerce roll-ups are the next wave of disruption in consumer packaged goods</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;E-commerce roll-ups are the next wave of disruption in consumer packaged goods&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/e-commerce-roll-ups-present-the-next-wave-of-disruption-in-consumer-packaged-goods/embed/#?secret=1upGGkNEVJ" data-secret="1upGGkNEVJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/wonder-brands-picks-up-20m-aims-to-build-marketplace-of-latin-american-e-commerce-brands/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188898</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plex&#8217;s new feature matches your &#8216;sonically similar&#8217; music to make playlists</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/plexs-new-feature-matches-your-sonically-similar-music-to-make-playlists/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/plexs-new-feature-matches-your-sonically-similar-music-to-make-playlists/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year, media software maker Plex released Plexamp, a subscriber-only music app whose name was a nod to the classic Winamp player it aimed to replace. Today, the company is upgrading the app with a new feature called Super Sonic, which offers new ways to mix up your playlists &#8212; including by matching songs that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last year, media software maker Plex released <a href="https://plexamp.com/">Plexamp</a>, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/media-software-maker-plex-launches-new-subscriber-only-apps-for-music-and-server-management/">subscriber-only music app</a> whose name was a nod to the classic Winamp player it aimed to replace. Today, the company is <a href="https://www.plex.tv/blog/super-sonic-get-closer-to-your-music-in-plexamp/">upgrading the app with a new feature called Super Sonic,</a> which offers new ways to mix up your playlists &#8212; including by matching songs that are &#8220;sonically&#8221; similar, instead of by metadata alone &#8212; like matching based on musical genre, for example.</p>
<p>The company explains that Super Sonic is designed to use the music&#8217;s sound to understand how different tracks relate to one another in your library. This is a different way of approaching a large music catalog and brings to mind something like Pandora&#8217;s Music Genome where songs are categorized based on attributes, like mood, tone, or beats per minute, among others.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2188969" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/sonically-similar-albums-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="209" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/sonically-similar-albums-1.png 2496w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/sonically-similar-albums-1.png?resize=150,46 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/sonically-similar-albums-1.png?resize=300,92 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/sonically-similar-albums-1.png?resize=768,236 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/sonically-similar-albums-1.png?resize=680,209 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/sonically-similar-albums-1.png?resize=1536,473 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/sonically-similar-albums-1.png?resize=2048,630 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/sonically-similar-albums-1.png?resize=50,15 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>But unlike the Music Genome, where trained musicologists analyze songs across hundreds of attributes, Super Sonic uses technology.</p>
<p>The new sonic analysis feature in Plexamp leverages a neural network and A.I. to map all the tracks, albums and artists in your library. Super Sonic extracts around 50 parameters from its analysis, which are then weighted appropriately. &#8220;Sonically similar&#8221; refers to two points in N-dimensional space being close to one another, Plex says.</p>
<p>The setup process for using the new feature is fairly CPU-intensive and can take hours or even days to complete, depending on your library&#8217;s size. However, once finished, you&#8217;ll be able to use a whole new set of features for discovering music. This can be particularly helpful in particular if you listen to a lot of indie or obscure music, where metadata may be limited or perhaps not available at all.</p>
<p>After the analysis is complete, a new &#8220;Related Tracks&#8221; feature will let you see which tracks you have that are sonically similar, which can sometimes lead to surprises that you wouldn&#8217;t have otherwise found if only matching on standard metadata.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Another addition, &#8220;Mixes for You,&#8221; will cluster the songs you&#8217;ve had on heavy rotation into mixes, but then add sonically similar tunes alongside your recent favorites. The server will also look back in time to make a few historical mixes based on past habits, too, so you have more to explore.</p>
<p>The company is also rolling out new radio features to address the removal of the popular Plex Mix feature a few years ago, after a metadata provider change. It now sees the new Sonic data as a way to replace the feature with Track Radio and Album Radio, which play either tracks or full albums that are sonically similar, respectively.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2188973" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/track-and-album-radios.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="434" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/track-and-album-radios.png 1693w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/track-and-album-radios.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/track-and-album-radios.png?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/track-and-album-radios.png?resize=768,490 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/track-and-album-radios.png?resize=680,434 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/track-and-album-radios.png?resize=1536,980 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/track-and-album-radios.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Other additions arriving alongside the Super Sonic launch include a new way to organize and filter albums by type (e.g. demos, live albums, etc.) and an &#8220;on this day&#8221; feature that reminds you of notable album milestones &#8212; like album releases that took place 20, 30 or 50 years ago.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2188972" style="width: 505px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2188972" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2188972" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-types-crop-1.png?w=495" alt="" width="495" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-types-crop-1.png 890w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-types-crop-1.png?resize=109,150 109w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-types-crop-1.png?resize=218,300 218w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-types-crop-1.png?resize=768,1055 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-types-crop-1.png?resize=495,680 495w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-types-crop-1.png?resize=36,50 36w" sizes="(max-width: 495px) 100vw, 495px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2188972" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Plex</p></div></p>
<p>To use the new sonic analysis feature, Plex users will need to be paid Plex Pass subscribers, and will need to be running Plex Media Server v1.24.0 on a macOS, Windows or Linux machine. ARM CPUs are not supported, however.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2188971" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2188971" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2188971" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/on-this-day-crop-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="332" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/on-this-day-crop-1.png 1263w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/on-this-day-crop-1.png?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/on-this-day-crop-1.png?resize=300,146 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/on-this-day-crop-1.png?resize=768,375 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/on-this-day-crop-1.png?resize=680,332 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/on-this-day-crop-1.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2188971" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Plex</p></div></p>
<p>Plex has been working over the years towards making its subscription service more appealing to power users, who are a smaller part of the company&#8217;s some <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/plex-launches-a-subscription-based-retro-game-streaming-service-plex-arcade/">25 million</a> registered users. But the company is no longer fully dependent on subscriber revenue to remain profitable, as it&#8217;s expanded into the free, ad-supported streaming market and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plex-raises-50m-growth-round-to-fuel-ad-supported-streaming-expansions/">raised funding</a>.</p>
<p>Today, Plex&#8217;s larger focus is on expanding the streaming business into areas like rentals, purchases and subscription content. But as Super Sonic proves, the team at Plex will continue to explore technology that will appeal to its core audience of digital media collectors and enthusiasts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/plexs-new-feature-matches-your-sonically-similar-music-to-make-playlists/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188910</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reddit is raising up to $700M in Series F funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/reddit-is-raising-up-to-700m-in-series-f-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/reddit-is-raising-up-to-700m-in-series-f-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this year, Reddit raised $250 million, bringing the 16-year-old site up to around $800 million in total funding. Today, it announced plans for an even more massive windfall, with a Series F led by Fidelity. The company confirmed with TechCrunch that has raised $410 million thus far, with plans to raise up to $700 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/reddit-raises-250-million-in-series-e-funding/">Reddit raised $250 million</a>, bringing the 16-year-old site up to around $800 million in total funding. Today, it announced <a href="https://redditblog.com/2021/08/12/reddit-secures-funding-to-continue-growth-plans/">plans for an even more massive windfall</a>, with a Series F led by Fidelity. The company confirmed with TechCrunch that has raised $410 million thus far, with plans to raise up to $700 million, putting Reddit at a $10 billion valuation.</p>
<p>The company says funding will go toward building out community and advertising efforts and increasing headcount.</p>
<p>“These efforts require us to grow our teams and make smart bets on how to make Reddit better, faster, easier to use, and more empowering for communities,” Reddit writes. “We are also evolving as a business, maturing, and building the operational structures that will help propel us into the future with transparency, values and integrity.”</p>
<p>As we noted back in February, an extraordinarily strange couple of years found the content aggregation service playing a key role in rollercoaster stock figures for companies like Gamestop and AMC, by way of the r/WallStreetBets subreddit. It also kicked off 2021 with a short Super Bowl spot. All of that helped lead to a doubling of the company’s valuation to $6 billion.</p>
<p>For now, it seems, the hype train is continuing. In Q2, Reddit broke $100 million in advertising revenue for the first time, marking a 192% year-over-year increase for the quarter. The site now attracts 50 million daily visitors and hosts 100,000 active subreddits. In March, it announced Drew Vollero would be joining on the site’s first-ever CFO, after assisting with Snap&#8217;s IPO efforts, four years prior.</p>
<p>In an <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/12/technology/reddit-new-funding.html">interview with <em>The New York Times</em></a>, cofounder Steve Huffman notes that it hadn&#8217;t planned to raise another round so quickly, but ultimately couldn&#8217;t turn down what Fidelity was offering. He adds that the funding will also factor into Reddit&#8217;s eventual IPO plans.</p>
<p>“We are still planning on going public, but we don’t have a firm timeline there yet,” he told the paper. “All good companies should go public when they can.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DLtbI6Bub7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/reddit-raises-250-million-in-series-e-funding/">Reddit raises $250 million in Series E funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Reddit raises $250 million in Series E funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/reddit-raises-250-million-in-series-e-funding/embed/#?secret=DLtbI6Bub7" data-secret="DLtbI6Bub7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/reddit-is-raising-up-to-700m-in-series-f-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189124</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok to add more privacy protections for teenaged users, limit push notifications</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/tiktok-to-add-more-privacy-protections-for-teenaged-users-limit-push-notifications/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/tiktok-to-add-more-privacy-protections-for-teenaged-users-limit-push-notifications/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 11:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188801</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok today becomes the latest tech company to roll out increased protections for minors on its platform in the wake of increased regulatory scrutiny. The company says it will introduce a series of product changes for teen users aged 13 to 17, aimed at making their TikTok experience more private, safer and less addictive. TikTok&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok today becomes the latest tech company to roll out increased protections for minors on its platform in the wake of increased regulatory scrutiny. The company says it will introduce a series of product changes for teen users aged 13 to 17, aimed at making their TikTok experience more private, safer and less addictive. TikTok&#8217;s news follows similar moves recently announced by other tech companies catering to teens, including<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/google-to-introduce-increased-protections-for-minors-on-its-platform-including-search-youtube-and-more/"> Google and YouTube,</a> as well as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-to-default-young-teens-to-private-accounts-restrict-ads-and-unwanted-adult-contact/">Instagram.</a></p>
<p>The changes TikTok plans to roll out over the coming months will address in-app messaging, the public nature of users&#8217; videos, the default download settings for videos and TikTok&#8217;s use of push notifications.</p>
<p>This expands on the changes to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/tiktok-update-will-change-privacy-settings-and-defaults-for-users-under-18/">privacy settings and defaults</a> for users under the age of 18 that TikTok introduced in January. At the time, TikTok debuted stricter rules for teens aged 13 to 15 and slightly more permissive settings for users 16 to 17 focused on default account types, commenting and the use of TikTok&#8217;s interactive features, like Stitch and Duet.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0GbdnWOESb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/tiktok-update-will-change-privacy-settings-and-defaults-for-users-under-18/">TikTok update will change privacy settings and defaults for users under 18</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok update will change privacy settings and defaults for users under 18&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/tiktok-update-will-change-privacy-settings-and-defaults-for-users-under-18/embed/#?secret=0GbdnWOESb" data-secret="0GbdnWOESb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Now, TikTok says new users aged 16 to 17 will have their Direct Message setting be set to &#8220;No One&#8221; by default and existing users would be prompted to review and confirm their settings the next time they use the messaging feature.</p>
<p>The company won&#8217;t prevent teens from using Direct Messages, however, but they will have to make a more explicit choice to do so.</p>
<p>The app will also now display a pop-up message when a teen under the age of 16 publishes their first video that asks them to choose who can watch their content &#8212; either followers, friends only or only themselves. (The &#8220;Everyone&#8221; option is disabled.) Before, TikTok <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/tiktok-update-will-change-privacy-settings-and-defaults-for-users-under-18/">had limited</a> who would come across the accounts belonging to teens under the age of 16, which would reduce the visibility of their content to only followers they approved, when using the default settings. Now, it&#8217;s more directly pushing teens to make a choice about how public they want their content to be &#8212; and they have to decide in order for the video to be published, TikTok notes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2188841" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2188841" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2188841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-visibility-prompt.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-visibility-prompt.png 750w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-visibility-prompt.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-visibility-prompt.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-visibility-prompt.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-visibility-prompt.png?resize=709,1536 709w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-visibility-prompt.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2188841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TikTok</p></div></p>
<p>TikTok also said it will disable Duet and Stitch for users under 16, but this is not new &#8212; it was a part of the privacy changes that rolled out in January.</p>
<p>Separately, teens 16 to 17 will now be asked to make a decision about whether or not their videos can be downloaded by others. While TikTok won&#8217;t prevent the teens from making their content downloadable, it will pop up a box that asks them to reconfirm their choice, while reminding them that this means the videos could be shared to other platforms. (Downloads remain disabled for users 13 to 15, meanwhile.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2188842" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2188842" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2188842" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-downloads-prompt.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-downloads-prompt.png 750w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-downloads-prompt.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-downloads-prompt.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-downloads-prompt.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-downloads-prompt.png?resize=709,1536 709w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-downloads-prompt.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2188842" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TikTok</p></div></p>
<p>The final change is perhaps the most interesting because it&#8217;s something neither YouTube nor Instagram introduced: TikTok will limit push notifications.</p>
<p>Younger teens ages 13 to 15 won&#8217;t receive any push notifications after 9 PM, while those aged 16 to 17 won&#8217;t receive any notifications after 10 PM. (The notifications resume the following morning at 8 AM).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YybdG0SGFD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/google-to-introduce-increased-protections-for-minors-on-its-platform-including-search-youtube-and-more/">Google to introduce increased protections for minors on its platform, including Search, YouTube and more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google to introduce increased protections for minors on its platform, including Search, YouTube and more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/google-to-introduce-increased-protections-for-minors-on-its-platform-including-search-youtube-and-more/embed/#?secret=YybdG0SGFD" data-secret="YybdG0SGFD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This part of the update is reflective of TikTok&#8217;s global mindset and its parent company&#8217;s Chinese roots. Today, China is in the midst of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/the-china-tech-crackdown-continues/">a tech crackdown</a>, encompassing antitrust regulations, data security practices, tech business models and even social mores &#8212; like the addictive nature of video games, which <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/03/tencent-netease-shares-tank-after-chinese-media-calls-gaming-opium.html">state media equated to a drug like &#8220;opium.&#8221;</a></p>
<p>TikTok, too, has been called out as one of the most <a href="https://medium.com/dataseries/how-tiktok-is-addictive-1e53dec10867">addictive</a> social apps on the market, thanks to its advanced personalization technology, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/03/tencent-netease-shares-tank-after-chinese-media-calls-gaming-opium.html">interactive design and simple interface,</a> and <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/01/18/digital-crack-cocaine-the-science-behind-tiktoks-success/?sh=5823e97a78be">psychological tricks</a> that activate the pleasure center of users brains. The company <a href="https://www.bustle.com/p/tiktoks-new-screen-time-prompts-remind-users-to-take-a-breather-21816527">already inserts</a> &#8220;take a break&#8221; videos inside its main feed, because users have been losing hours to scrolling the app. Its decision to limit notifications is yet another acknowledgment of the app&#8217;s ability to lead users &#8212; and particularly younger users &#8212; to create negative digital media habits. By preventing notifications during certain hours, TikTok can point potential regulators to a feature that demonstrates it&#8217;s doing something to address that problem.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dK6W0y7bUu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/the-china-tech-crackdown-continues/">The China tech crackdown continues</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The China tech crackdown continues&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/the-china-tech-crackdown-continues/embed/#?secret=dK6W0y7bUu" data-secret="dK6W0y7bUu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The changes come at a time when there&#8217;s a broader shift in the industry in terms of how tech companies cater to their younger users, as concerns about screen time, addictiveness, online abuse, data collection, privacy and more have been brought to light.</p>
<p>In the U.S., Congress has been pressuring companies to do more to protect younger users from the more harmful and negative impacts of technology.</p>
<p>One <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/07/29/coppa-update-teenagers-online/">key piece of legislation in the works</a> is an update to the decades-old children&#8217;s privacy law, COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act). A new bill, the Protecting the Information of our Vulnerable Children and Youth Act, would expand COPPA to include teens under the age of 18 and prevent tech companies from using targeted advertising, among other things.</p>
<p>As a result, tech companies have been revamping their products to make teens&#8217; experience more private and they&#8217;ve increased protections, including over how teens&#8217; data is collected and used by advertisers.</p>
<p>TikTok was early to take action on protections to teens, as a result of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/27/musical-ly-tiktok-fined-5-7m-by-ftc-for-violating-childrens-privacy-laws-will-update-app-with-age-gate/">multimillion-dollar fine</a> by the U.S. Federal Trade Commission for earlier violations of children&#8217;s privacy laws in a crackdown by the government agency that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/04/ftc-sells-kids-privacy-cheap/">later extended to YouTube.</a> Beyond the privacy changes from earlier in the year and take a break reminders, TikTok also led the market by<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/tiktok-to-launch-parental-controls-globally-disable-direct-messaging-for-users-under-16/"> bundling parent controls inside its app</a> with the Family Pairing feature. The company also offers other resources for parents, including <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/safety/resources/safety-videos?lang=en&amp;appLaunch=web" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">educational safety videos</a> and <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/safety/resources/safety-videos?lang=en&amp;appLaunch=web" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">parental guides.</a> And it brought in outside experts to advise on policy creation, with the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/18/tiktok-brings-in-outside-experts-to-help-it-craft-moderation-and-content-policies/">introduction</a> of the TikTok Content Advisory Council.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our priority is to ensure teens on TikTok have a safe and age-appropriate experience as they create and share on our platform,&#8221; said Tracy Elizabeth, TikTok&#8217;s Global Minor Safety Policy Lead, in a statement about today&#8217;s changes. &#8220;This announcement builds on our industry-leading efforts to make all accounts under 16 private by default, age-restrict features like direct messaging, and empower parents with Family Pairing,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>TikTok told us the features will roll out globally, over time, but couldn&#8217;t share a specific timeframe.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bFB0nPbGhS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-to-default-young-teens-to-private-accounts-restrict-ads-and-unwanted-adult-contact/">Instagram to default young teens to private accounts, restrict ads and unwanted adult contact</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Instagram to default young teens to private accounts, restrict ads and unwanted adult contact&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-to-default-young-teens-to-private-accounts-restrict-ads-and-unwanted-adult-contact/embed/#?secret=bFB0nPbGhS" data-secret="bFB0nPbGhS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/tiktok-to-add-more-privacy-protections-for-teenaged-users-limit-push-notifications/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188801</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Contact, a platform for creatives backed by Maisie Williams, raises $1.9M Seed led by Founders Fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/contact-a-platform-for-creatives-backed-by-maisie-williams-raises-1-9m-seed-led-by-founders-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/contact-a-platform-for-creatives-backed-by-maisie-williams-raises-1-9m-seed-led-by-founders-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 10:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abe Burns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cortex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deliveroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[depop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[designer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Wahlforss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Farfetch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion designer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason Calacanis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joe white]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maisie williams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soundcloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thom browne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the pandemic digitizing every aspect of our lives, the Creator Economy has taken off like never before, with some estimates saying it&#8217;s now a $100Bn+ market. And yet, managing your professional life as a model, actor, writer or designer remains a mish-mash of emails, manual booking processes, and dreaded PDFs. Creatives face late payments, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With the pandemic digitizing every aspect of our lives, the Creator Economy has taken off like never before, with some estimates saying it&#8217;s now a $100Bn+ market. And yet, managing your professional life as a model, actor, writer or designer remains a mish-mash of emails, manual booking processes, and dreaded PDFs. Creatives face late payments, often opaque industry practices, even as top talent agencies have collectively achieved a valuation of $20Bn in value. But while modeling talent can be charged as much as a 20-40% commission fee, social media has been gradually displacing traditional agencies by reducing the barriers to entry and making talent more accessible. However, as everyone knows, social media is nowhere near a place anyone can manage their career.</p>
<p>Late last year the <a href="https://contact.xyz/">Contact</a> platform launched, initially offering models a way to take bookings and manage some aspects of their work. It’s now looking to address the wider problems referred to above, with a new round of funding involving some key players in the creative industries.</p>
<p>It’s backed and supported by Maisie Williams, best known for her work on Game of Thrones, who has become Creative Strategist and Advisor to the startup after becoming a passionate advocate for better conditions for creatives in the industry.</p>
<p>Contact has now raised a $1.9 million (£1.4 million) Seed round of funding led by Founders Fund. Also participating is LAUNCH (the fund led by investors Jason Calacanis), Sweet Capital (via Pippa Lamb), Rogue VC (via Alice Lloyd George) and Angel investors Simon Beckerman (co-founder of Depop), Eric Wahlforss (co-founder of SoundCloud and now Dance), Abe Burns and Joe White.</p>
<p>Although Contact’s initial incarnation is addressing the modeling world, its vision is far bigger. Contact co-founder and CEO Reuben Selby — a fashion designer who was formerly of William’s founding team, when she started her career — has worked with Nike, Thom Browne, and JW Anderson. He says the platform aims to become a scalable back-end solution across the $104.2 Billion Creator Economy, “democratizing” access to the world’s best creative talent.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2189109" style="width: 782px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2189109" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Reuben.jpeg" alt="Reuben Selby" width="772" height="512" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2189109" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Reuben.jpeg 772w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Reuben.jpeg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Reuben.jpeg?resize=300,199 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Reuben.jpeg?resize=768,509 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Reuben.jpeg?resize=680,451 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Reuben.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 772px) 100vw, 772px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2189109" class="wp-caption-text">Reuben Selby</p></div></p>
<p>Selby, who recently spoke about <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/drnancydoyle/2021/06/17/get-ready-for-gen-z-in-neurodiversity-collaborative-authentic-intersectional-and-ethical-or-else/?sh=38c9ba781c3b">being a founder with autism</a> is also the founder and creative director of his own label <a href="https://reubenselby.co/">Reuben Selby</a>, and co-founder of <a href="https://cortexcreatives.co/">Cortex</a> a creative agency and community. Selby is joined by CTO Josh McMillan previously of Deliveroo, Daisie, the Government Digital Service, and among others.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While its competitors might, broadly speaking, include <a href="http://Patreon.com">Patreon</a>, <a href="https://creatively.life/">Creatively</a>, and <a href="https://the-dots.com/">The Dots</a>, it’s fair to say that Contact’s vision to bring many aspects of these platforms under one roof could be described as ambitious, it is also tantalising.</p>
<p>In a radical move for what is an industry dominated by agencies, individuals and businesses can discover and book creators and creative services directly, without going through an agency.</p>
<p>Contact initially launched its platform in October 2020 with the ability to discover and book fashion models, but post-fundraising plans to roll out other creative verticals such as photographers, stylists, videographers, and more.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/marketingweb.png" alt="" width="672" height="517" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2189112" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/marketingweb.png 672w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/marketingweb.png?resize=150,115 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/marketingweb.png?resize=300,231 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/marketingweb.png?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 672px) 100vw, 672px" /></p>
<p>Selby says the idea for Contact has been informed by his own personal experiences trying to break into the creative industry as a model, photographer, and creative director. After finding scant methods for secure and safe ways to get paid &#8211; while booking companies lacked basic technological tools &#8211; he realized that ‘middle-men&#8217; and agencies were there main ones that benefitted, taking cuts on both sides and often still delivering a sub-par-product.</p>
<p>So how does Contact work?</p>
<p>When a Creator joins, they are able to showcase their portfolio across different creative services and take direct bookings.</p>
<p>A business can then browse and discover talent using filters, shortlist creative talent, providing details about the job, and book creators directly. Creatives can accept or reject jobs via the web platform or, soon, via a smartphone app. Once the job has been completed, the talent gets paid out via Contact.</p>
<p>Since soft-launching within the modeling vertical, Contact says it has onboarded almost 600 creatives and over 1,400 clients including Depop, Farfetch, Nike, Vivienne Westwood, and Vogue. Users of the platform have increased 100% YoY, says the startup.</p>
<p>Selby says Contact intends to remain in the background and allow the talent to brand itself independently across different verticals. Crucially, Contact does not take money from creators, only booking companies, from which it will levy a 20% fee on transactions.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/profile-top.png" alt="" width="672" height="476" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2189110" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/profile-top.png 672w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/profile-top.png?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/profile-top.png?resize=300,213 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/profile-top.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 672px) 100vw, 672px" /></p>
<p>Commenting, Trae Stephens, Partner at Founders Fund, said: “We are always excited when we find founders who seem to have been born to build a specific company. Reuben definitely seems like one of those founders. We are really excited to watch the company scale and expand into new creative verticals.”</p>
<p>Pippa Lamb, Partner at Sweet Capital, added: “The team at Contact have been pushing frontiers in the creator economy long before ‘the creator economy’ became a buzzword. Contact possesses a rare combination of world-class technical talent with the raw innovation of today’s most creative minds. We are excited about this next chapter.”</p>
<p>Williams, best known for playing Arya Stark on Game of Thrones, is no stranger to working on startups. She previously contributed to the <a href="https://www.daisie.com/">Daisie</a> platform, which continues to connect creators with one another to work on each others’ projects, helping creators <a href="https://techcrunch.com/video/maisi-williams-daisie-interview/">find collaborators for their art</a>.</p>
<p>But clearly her desire to disrupt the creative world largely controlled by ‘middle men’ was not sated by the experience.</p>
<p>Speaking to me in an exclusive interview, Williams and Selby outlined their vision:</p>
<p>Selby said the existing marketplace for models is just the start: “The vision has always been about creatives, and getting creatives paid for their work. We basically started out in one vertical, the modeling industry… and we&#8217;re in the process of rolling out new verticals so bringing on photographers, makeup artists, stylists, etc. But that&#8217;s a very very small part of the overall vision.”</p>
<p>He said the focus now is “on the distribution of work, how that relationship works with that audience, how they can monetize it. So it&#8217;s basically giving them a toolkit to monetize their creativity rather than just the physical constraints. That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re exploring right now. We have this marketplace but we see that as being a very small part, but the larger piece.”</p>
<p>He said the marketplace model can connect brands directly to creators or creatives, but, he said, brands continue to have a great deal of power: “The creators are just sitting there waiting for somebody to give them something. So we&#8217;re now working out how they can just distribute by their own work and monetize it in their own ways, with the back end of how all of the logistics work, and the operational side handled by the product that we&#8217;ve built, handling the payments and the licensing and insurance.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/portfolio.png" alt="" width="671" height="597" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2189111" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/portfolio.png 671w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/portfolio.png?resize=150,133 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/portfolio.png?resize=300,267 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/portfolio.png?resize=50,44 50w" sizes="(max-width: 671px) 100vw, 671px" /></p>
<p>Despite being a major Hollywood star, Williams told me the creative and entertainment industry she’s familiar with and works in remains stuck in an old world of emails and links, rather than the kinds of platforms the tech industry is used to building and using: “Being someone who has been represented by talent agencies for my career, that whole interaction online is emails. At no point are any of the assets digitised. There&#8217;s no ‘vault’ where all of my scripts go. There&#8217;s no place where I can upload all of my audition tapes. It&#8217;s always just a link in an email. There’s not really an industry standard. From an agency perspective, none of the work that they is very streamlined or directional.”</p>
<p>She says that need to change: “There&#8217;s a casting process and at the moment, and it&#8217;s a hugely dated way of doing things between the casting directors and the actors, the writers etc. We want to build a very streamlined process.”</p>
<p>Speaking about the investors he’s assembled to back Contact, Selby said the team chose Founders Fund to be their lead investor because of their approach: &#8220;The way that they work with founders… I found that personally very empowering. [They] give you a lot of freedom and space to think creatively. So there was a clear alignment.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/desk-and-mob.png" alt="" width="731" height="660" class="breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-2189113" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/desk-and-mob.png 731w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/desk-and-mob.png?resize=150,135 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/desk-and-mob.png?resize=300,271 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/desk-and-mob.png?resize=680,614 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/desk-and-mob.png?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 731px) 100vw, 731px" /></p>
<p>Talking about the other Angel investors in the round he said: “People like Eric and Simon are majorly connected in fashion and music culture in general.”</p>
<p>Speaking about how the entertainment industry might react to Contact, Williams said: “Actors have many other things that they do. Being able to have a platform that they can monetize all those other things is really important, especially because, as an actor you spend a lot of time unemployed.” But said the system is constructed in such as a way that “you’re only valuable as the auditions your agent puts you up for. It’s not very inspiring or rewarding. So a lot of actors make their own shows on  streaming platforms or create their own documentaries or sell their work in other ways.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/confirm.png" alt="" width="841" height="1455" class="vertical aligncenter size-full wp-image-2189114" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/confirm.png 841w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/confirm.png?resize=87,150 87w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/confirm.png?resize=173,300 173w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/confirm.png?resize=768,1329 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/confirm.png?resize=393,680 393w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/confirm.png?resize=29,50 29w" sizes="(max-width: 841px) 100vw, 841px" /></p>
<p>She said Contact wants to be able to facilitate that through the platform, and for creatives to have more independence: “The film industry and the music industry is full of incredibly talented people who are multi-talented across many different industries. But they are still, kind of held by representatives and agencies and record labels or managers who have a lot of power in, sort of, keeping them ‘small’. Being able to introduce something which can offer so many other tools, I think, is really important.”</p>
<p>It’s clear that the vision Selby, his co-founders, and Williams have, is very big. The question is, will they be able to pull it off?</p>
<p>It has to be said, however, that the combination of a passionate Gen-Z-influential team (with added star power), a full-blown technology platform, heavyweight US investors, and Angels pulled from creative industries certainly points to the potential for success.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/contact-a-platform-for-creatives-backed-by-maisie-williams-raises-1-9m-seed-led-by-founders-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189106</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Construction tech startup Agora raises $33M in Tiger Global-led round amid 760% YoY ARR growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/construction-tech-startup-agora-raises-33m-in-tiger-global-led-round-amid-760-yoy-arr-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/construction-tech-startup-agora-raises-33m-in-tiger-global-led-round-amid-760-yoy-arr-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 10:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jerry Yang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Hartz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael ovitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procurement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Agora, a startup that has built a materials management platform for contractors, has raised $33 million in a Series B round of funding led by Tiger Global Management. 8VC, Tishman Speyer, Yahoo co-founder Jerry Yang, Michael Ovitz, DST, LeFrak and Kevin Hartz also participated in the financing, which brings the startup’s total raised since its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.helloagora.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Agora</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a startup that has built a materials management platform for contractors, has raised $33 million in a Series B round of funding led by Tiger Global Management.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">8VC, Tishman Speyer, Yahoo co-founder Jerry Yang, Michael Ovitz, DST, LeFrak and Kevin Hartz also participated in the financing, which brings the startup’s total raised since its 2018 inception to about $45 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Construction tech is one of those sectors that has not historically been considered “sexy” in a startup world that often favors glitzier technology. But construction fuels the commercial and real estate industries, which in turn impacts all of us in one way or another.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, the $10 trillion construction industry has long been plagued with productivity challenges. In fact, according to McKinsey,</span><a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/Business%20Functions/Operations/Our%20Insights/Reinventing%20construction%20through%20a%20productivity%20revolution/MGI-Reinventing-construction-A-route-to-higher-productivity-Full-report.pdf"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">labor productivity</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> growth in the industry has been stagnant since 1947.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2189035" style="width: 347px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2189035" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2189035 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Quick-Order-iPhone-1.jpg?w=337" alt="" width="337" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Quick-Order-iPhone-1.jpg 2564w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Quick-Order-iPhone-1.jpg?resize=74,150 74w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Quick-Order-iPhone-1.jpg?resize=148,300 148w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Quick-Order-iPhone-1.jpg?resize=768,1552 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Quick-Order-iPhone-1.jpg?resize=337,680 337w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Quick-Order-iPhone-1.jpg?resize=760,1536 760w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Quick-Order-iPhone-1.jpg?resize=1014,2048 1014w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Quick-Order-iPhone-1.jpg?resize=25,50 25w" sizes="(max-width: 337px) 100vw, 337px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2189035" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Agora</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maria Rioumine</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and Ryan Gibson founded Agora with the mission of making it easier for commercial trade contractors to order and track materials, automate manual data entry and give everyone involved in the procurement process a single platform by which they can communicate with each other. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The end goal is to help projects move along faster, and contractors to avoid unnecessary delays by reducing building costs. The bigger picture impact, Agora hopes, is that its SaaS platform can help make the “built environment faster and more efficient to build,” and thus help make cities “more affordable and accessible to all.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">San Francisco-based Agora is tackling the problem in a very specific, niche way that is proving to be popular both with contractors and investors alike. Rather than attempting to be a blanket solution for all trades, Agora is focusing on specific trade verticals, one by one. For example, it started out with electrical and is now moving into mechanical.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Last year, there was more than $101 billion worth of electrical work done. Our customers work on all types of products,” Rioumine told TechCrunch. “For example, we have customers that do power stations, some that build hospitals and others that build school classrooms and university campuses, and still others that build churches and casinos. The work that these contractors do is so essential.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Agora’s annual recurring revenue has grown 760% year over year while its customer base is up 6x during the same time frame, according to the company. It has also tripled its headcount to 45 people and today is processing $140 million in annualized materials volume for its customers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup wasn’t actively raising for the Series B &#8212; instead, investors were proactively offering term sheets, Rioumine said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“A few investors that knew us well approached us about preempting the round,” she told TechCrunch. “Twelve days after the first </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">conversation, we had multiple term sheets.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tiger Global Partner John Curtius said he was drawn to Agora’s “unique” trade-specific approach.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In his view, the startup is “defining the future of procurement in construction.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Agora is solving a huge and critical problem,” Curtius wrote via email. “Billions of dollars a year are wasted because of inefficient procurement processes and breakages in the supply chain.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JFuxedfScl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/despite-the-hype-construction-tech-will-be-hard-to-disrupt/">Despite the hype, construction tech will be hard to disrupt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Despite the hype, construction tech will be hard to disrupt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/despite-the-hype-construction-tech-will-be-hard-to-disrupt/embed/#?secret=JFuxedfScl" data-secret="JFuxedfScl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform specifically does things like give contractors the ability to: customize templates, create pre-approved materials lists and easily reorder frequently needed items, order from a catalogue that offers more than 400,000 SKUs and eliminate manual data entry, which reduces errors and automates basic processes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By bringing both field and office teams onto one digital platform, Agora claims it saves office teams 75% of the time they spend processing purchase orders, and field teams 38% of the time their foremen spend on materials management. In total, the company said its technology can provide up to $300,000 of potential annual savings for its average customer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to use its new capital to hire across a number of teams, as well as continue to expand beyond 30 states and into other trade verticals.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There has been this really heavy underinvestment in tech in construction for a long time,” Rioumine said. On average, the technology spend as a proportion of revenue in construction is about 1.5%, “which is actually the lowest of the industries out there where the median is 3.3%,” she added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“So when we think about just how large this industry is and how little productivity improvements there have been recently, I think now we have this amazing opportunity to really invest in technology and bring it on to the job sites and into trade contractors’ hands.&#8221;</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bnjGgDl6sH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/doxel-raises-40m-from-insight-a16z-to-become-the-waze-for-construction/">Doxel raises $40M from Insight, a16z to become the &#8216;Waze for construction&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Doxel raises $40M from Insight, a16z to become the &#8216;Waze for construction&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/doxel-raises-40m-from-insight-a16z-to-become-the-waze-for-construction/embed/#?secret=bnjGgDl6sH" data-secret="bnjGgDl6sH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/construction-tech-startup-agora-raises-33m-in-tiger-global-led-round-amid-760-yoy-arr-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188858</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Consumer goods software company Aforza bags $22M to open US headquarters</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/consumer-goods-software-company-aforza-bags-22m-to-open-u-s-headquarters/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/consumer-goods-software-company-aforza-bags-22m-to-open-u-s-headquarters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 10:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aforza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bonfire ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brett Queener]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daher Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DN Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dominic Dinardo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ed Butterworth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marc Benioff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Next47]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nick Eales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188872</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Built on Salesforce and Google Cloud platforms, consumer goods companies can use Aforza to digitally transform product distribution and customer engagement.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://aforza.com/">Aforza</a>, developing cloud and mobile apps for consumer goods companies, announced a $22 million Series A round led by DN Capital.</p>
<p>The London-based company’s technology is built on the Salesforce and Google Cloud platforms so that consumer goods companies can digitally transform product distribution and customer engagement to combat issues like unprofitable promotions and declining market share, Aforza co-founder and CEO Dominic Dinardo told TechCrunch. Using artificial intelligence, the company recommends products and can predict the order a retailer can make with promotions and pricing based on factors like locations.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.appsruntheworld.com/top-10-consumer-packaged-goods-software-vendors-and-market-forecast/">global market for consumer packaged goods apps</a> is forecasted to reach $15 billion by 2024. However, the industry is still using outdated platforms that, in some cases, lead to a loss of <a href="https://www.oliverwyman.com/content/dam/oliver-wyman/global/en/2014/aug/2012_CEU_POV_Getting%20Availability%20Right_ENG.pdf">5% of sales</a> when goods are out of stock, Dinardo said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2188880" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2188880" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2188880" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Aforza-Trade-Promotion-Designer-Mobile-Image.png" alt="" width="1024" height="786" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Aforza-Trade-Promotion-Designer-Mobile-Image.png 1177w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Aforza-Trade-Promotion-Designer-Mobile-Image.png?resize=150,115 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Aforza-Trade-Promotion-Designer-Mobile-Image.png?resize=300,230 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Aforza-Trade-Promotion-Designer-Mobile-Image.png?resize=768,589 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Aforza-Trade-Promotion-Designer-Mobile-Image.png?resize=680,522 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Aforza-Trade-Promotion-Designer-Mobile-Image.png?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2188880" class="wp-caption-text">Aforza&#8217;s trade promotion designer mobile image. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Aforza</p></div></p>
<p>Dinardo and his co-founders, Ed Butterworth and Nick Eales, started the company in 2019. All veterans of Salesforce, they saw how underserved the consumer goods industry was in terms of moving to digital.</p>
<p>Aforza is Dinardo’s first time leading a company. However, from his time at Salesforce he feels he got an education like going to “Marc Benioff’s School of SaaS.” The company raised an undisclosed seed round in 2019 from Bonfire Ventures, Daher Capital, DN Capital, Next47 and Salesforce Ventures.</p>
<p>Then the pandemic happened, which had many of the investors leaning in, which was validation of what Aforza was doing, Dinardo said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Even before the pandemic, the consumer goods industry was challenged with new market entrants and horrible legacy systems, but then the pandemic turned off pathways to customers,” he added. “Our mission is to improve the lives of consumers by bringing forth more sustainable products and packaging, but also helping companies be more agile and handle changes as the biggest change is happening.”</p>
<p>Joining DN Capital in the round were Bonfire Ventures, Daher Capital and Next47.</p>
<p>Brett Queener, partner at Bonfire Ventures, said he helped incubate Aforza with Dinardo and Eales, something his firm doesn’t typically do, but saw a unique opportunity to get in on the ground floor.</p>
<p>Also working at Salesforce, he saw the consumer goods industry as a major industry with a compelling reason to make a technology shift as customers began expecting instant availability and there were tons of emerging startups coming into the direct-to-consumer space.</p>
<p>Those startups don’t have a year or two to pull together the kind of technology it took to scale. With Aforza, they can build a product that works both online and off on any device, Queener said. And rather than planning promotions on a quarterly basis, companies can make changes to their promotional spend in real time.</p>
<p>“It is time for Aforza to tell the world about its technology, time to build out its footprint in the U.S. and in Europe, invest more in R&amp;D and execute the Salesforce playbook,” he said. “That is what this round is about.”</p>
<p>Dinardo intends on using the new funding to continue R&amp;D and to double its employee headcount over the next six months as it establishes its new U.S. headquarters in the Northeast. It is already working with customers in 20 countries.</p>
<p>As to growth, Dinardo said he is using his past experiences at startups like Veeva and Vlocity, which was acquired by Salesforce in 2020, as benchmarks for Aforza’s success.</p>
<p>“We have the money and the expertise — now we need to take a moment to breathe, hire people with the passion to do this and invest in new product tiers, digital assets and even payments,” he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="al8OzgvYGF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/11/salesforce-ventures-invested-300m-in-automattic-while-salesforce-was-building-a-cms/">Salesforce Ventures invested $300M in Automattic while Salesforce was building a CMS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce Ventures invested $300M in Automattic while Salesforce was building a CMS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/11/salesforce-ventures-invested-300m-in-automattic-while-salesforce-was-building-a-cms/embed/#?secret=al8OzgvYGF" data-secret="al8OzgvYGF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/consumer-goods-software-company-aforza-bags-22m-to-open-u-s-headquarters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188872</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Talkdesk’s valuation jumps to $10B with Series D for smart contact centers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/talkdesks-valuation-jumps-to-10b-with-series-d-for-smart-contact-centers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/talkdesks-valuation-jumps-to-10b-with-series-d-for-smart-contact-centers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 09:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acxiom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alpha Square Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Franklin Templeton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fujitsu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sumo logic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talkdesk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TI Platform Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiago Paiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trivago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Viking Global Investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whale Rock Capital Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zendesk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Talkdesk uses artificial intelligence and machine learning to improve customer service for mid-market and enterprise businesses.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.talkdesk.com/">Talkdesk</a>, a provider of cloud-based contact center software, announced $230 million in new Series D funding that more than triples the company’s valuation to $10 billion, Talkdesk founder CEO Tiago Paiva confirmed to TechCrunch.</p>
<p>New investors Whale Rock Capital Management, TI Platform Management and Alpha Square Group came on board for this round and were joined by existing investors Amity Ventures, Franklin Templeton, Top Tier Capital Partners, Viking Global Investors and Willoughby Capital.</p>
<p>Talkdesk uses artificial intelligence and machine learning to improve customer service for midmarket and enterprise businesses. It counts over 1,800 companies as customers, including IBM, Acxiom, Trivago and Fujitsu.</p>
<p>“The global pandemic was a big part of how customers interact and how we interacted with our customers, all working from home,” Paiva said. “When you think about ordering things online, call, chat and email interactions became more important, and contact centers became core in every company.”</p>
<p>San Francisco-based Talkdesk now has $498 million in total funding since its inception in 2011. It was <a href="https://beta.techcrunch.com/2012/05/22/talkdesk/">a Startup Battlefield contestant</a> at TechCrunch Disrupt NY in 2012. The new funding follows a <a href="https://www.talkdesk.com/news-and-press/press-releases/talkdesk-raises-143-million-in-series-c-funding/">$143 million Series C</a> raised last July that gave it a $3 billion valuation. Prior to that, Talkdesk brought in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/03/talkdesk-nabs-100m-at-more-than-1b-valuation-for-its-smart-call-centers/">$100 million</a> in 2018.</p>
<p>The 2020 round was planned to buoy the company’s growth and expansion to nearly 2,000 employees, Paiva said. For the Series D, there was much interest from investors, including a lot of inbound interest, he said.</p>
<p>“We were not looking for new money, and finished last year with more money in the bank that we raised in the last round, but the investors were great and wanted to make it work,” Paiva said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Half of Talkdesk’s staff is in product and engineering, an area he intends to double down in with the new funding as well as adding to the headcount to support customers. The company also has plans to expand in areas where it is already operating — Latin America, Europe, Asia and Australia.</p>
<p>This year, the company unveiled new features, including Talkdesk Workspace, a customizable interface for contact center teams, and Talkdesk Builder, a set of tools for customization across workspaces, routing, reporting and integrations. It also launched contact center tools designed specifically for financial services and healthcare organizations and what it is touting as the “industry’s first human-in-the-loop tool for contact centers and continues to lower the barrier to adopting artificial intelligence solutions.”</p>
<p>In addition to the funding, Talkdesk appointed its first chief financial officer, Sydney Carey, giving the company an executive team of 50% women, Paiva said. Carey has a SaaS background and joins the company from Sumo Logic, where she led the organization through an initial public offering in 2020.</p>
<p>“We were hiring our executive team over the past couple of years, and were looking for a CFO, but with no specific timeline, just looking for the right person,” Paiva added. “Sydney was the person we wanted to hire.”</p>
<p>Though Paiva didn’t hint at any upcoming IPO plans, TI Platform Management co-founders Trang Nguyen and Alex Bangash have followed Paiva since he started the company and said they anticipate the company heading in that direction in the future.</p>
<p>“Talkdesk is an example of what can happen when a strong team is assembled behind a winning idea,” they said in a written statement. “Today, Talkdesk has become near ubiquitous as a SaaS product with adoption across a broad array of industries and integrations with the most popular enterprise cloud platforms, including Salesforce, Zendesk and Slack.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YOCZD7gCOO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/29/leverage-ai-to-optimize-customer-service-outcomes/">Leverage AI to optimize customer service outcomes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Leverage AI to optimize customer service outcomes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/29/leverage-ai-to-optimize-customer-service-outcomes/embed/#?secret=YOCZD7gCOO" data-secret="YOCZD7gCOO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/talkdesks-valuation-jumps-to-10b-with-series-d-for-smart-contact-centers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188865</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Adia Sowho helped steer Thrive Agric through the pandemic crisis</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/how-adia-sowho-helped-steer-thrive-agric-through-the-pandemic-crisis/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/how-adia-sowho-helped-steer-thrive-agric-through-the-pandemic-crisis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 09:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adia Sowho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thrive Agric]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nigeria&#8217;s less than two-decade-old ecosystem is evolving fast. But behind the funding and legitimate hype, there&#8217;s without a doubt plenty of learning that needs to be done in running a startup. In retrospect, founders in Nigeria do tremendous work when you consider the kind of harsh market they operate in. They are deserving of all [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nigeria&#8217;s less than two-decade-old ecosystem is evolving fast. But behind the funding and legitimate hype, there&#8217;s without a doubt plenty of learning that needs to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be done</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in running a startup.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In retrospect, founders in Nigeria do tremendous work when you consider the kind of harsh market they operate in. They are deserving of all the praise they get. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, some questionable antics require addressing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are instances when founders know their companies are dying but would rather sink with it (without having a plan) than let someone else lead. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Or other instances where founders know there&#8217;s a need to hire someone as CEO to blitz scale their companies but would rather settle for mediocre growth</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stories where startups take drastic actions to save or scale a company are few and far between. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">relatively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> short time in the startup scene, <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/adiasowho">Adia Sowho</a>, one of the well-known operators around the region, has been fortunate to experience and live through one</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year, she <a href="https://www.benjamindada.com/thrive-agric-ceo-steps-down/">became the CEO of Thrive Agric</a>, an agriculture fintech company, guiding it through a turnaround after <a href="https://techpoint.africa/2020/10/06/thrive-agric-defaulting-insurance/">the COVID-19 pandemic induced a crisis</a> in the business</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before that, she worked as the VP of Growth and managing director, Nigeria, for fintech platform Migo. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And outside the startup scene, she was the director of Digital Business at telecom operator 9mobile and is currently <a href="https://technext.ng/2021/08/02/mtn-appoints-thrive-agrics-ceo-adia-sowho-as-its-first-female-cmo/">the chief marketing officer of mobile telecoms giant MTN Nigeria</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TechCrunch sat down with Sowho to share her experience working as a telecom executive, an operator with Thrive Agric and Migo, her view on how operators can work with founders, her decision to leave the startup scene and how her new journey is all according to plan.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>What was your career like before becoming an operator in tech?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I had a long career across different parts of the mobile telecom space, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">specifically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, with my last role being responsible for digital business</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Digital business in a telco is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">essentially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that arm of the telco that interfaces with third parties, often startups who have products more innovative than what the telco might have, in its current portfolio, and of interest to customers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I got that department in its </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">inception</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at 9mobile and grew it to a $100 million revenue aspect of the business. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In doing that, I interacted with various sectors and launched a couple of music apps, gaming platforms, content platforms from like, short-form two minutes to longer forms</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We also did mobile advertising, the Internet of Things and financial services. But the telco industry is very massive, and the infrastructure is very old and difficult to shift into the internet economy. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">After that, I was looking for something else to do and having </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been bitten by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the startup bug because my team was </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">essentially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the internal startup to 9mobile, I was looking for more of that excitement</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. And I guess I wanted to put my money where my mouth was.</span></p>
<p><strong>So, why Migo, since a lot of startups existed at the time? I mean, we&#8217;re talking early 2018 here.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After 9mobile, I decided to go to Migo because I felt like financial services was critical and the bedrock of a holistic financial system with four elements — savings, credit, insurance and payments</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So in the Nigerian tech scene, a little bit was happening in savings, but to me, it was not a priority in a country that didn&#8217;t have a massive GDP per capita. This period was also still in the early stages of Flutterwave and Paystack and we had </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> started waking up to payments in a big way. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But there was very little happening in credit. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I could walk into my bank and get a loan only if the company I worked for </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was known</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to that bank, and the bank had some visibility of that company&#8217;s finances as well</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It was still tough to access credit. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">That&#8217;s why I joined Migo, because I felt like if you don&#8217;t solve your financial services problem, you can&#8217;t </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">really</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> do anything else. After all, it&#8217;s the underlying infrastructure that everything else needs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>How was your experience at the fintech startup?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I joined, the team was very small at that time. Everyone could fit into one conference room, and then, I started building out the Nigeria business as the managing director. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I hired the team to start delivering products through partnerships and got the userbase to over a million users before leaving. So that was definitely a fun but trying experience. It taught me a lot about myself, and I definitely got first-hand experience of the challenge of building and leading a startup in emerging markets.</span></p>
<p><strong>Did anything transpire within the startup that led to you leaving?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let&#8217;s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">say I wanted to start a new journey. I mean, look, COVID hit a lot of businesses hard, and in your startup journey, you have to make some directional changes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Migo has now more </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">cleanly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> focused on embedded finance, which required making some changes within the organization, and that happened with COVID</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> seemed like a good time to leave, which I did, plus </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I might</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have been a bit burnt out, as I was exhausted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> when I left.</span></p>
<p><strong>But you joined Thrive Agric four months after leaving?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, it was a few months after, that&#8217;s interesting [laughs]. So I mean, we&#8217;ve talked about how I </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was drawn</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to financial services because that&#8217;s sort of fundamental to economic development. With <a href="https://www.thriveagric.com/">Thrive Agric</a>, I definitely felt the same: we eat food. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are millions of smallholder farmers in Nigeria. What Thrive does in consolidating their output to be</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> sold</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to local off-takers is a critical aspect of Nigeria&#8217;s future</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N3Dvb4Es81"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/20/seven-africa-focused-startups-present-at-y-combinators-demo-day/">Seven Africa-focused startups present at Y Combinator’s Demo Day</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Seven Africa-focused startups present at Y Combinator’s Demo Day&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/20/seven-africa-focused-startups-present-at-y-combinators-demo-day/embed/#?secret=N3Dvb4Es81" data-secret="N3Dvb4Es81" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s food security. If you sit down and think about the Global Sustainable Development Goals, food security shows up somehow, right? So for me, even though I was still trying to rest, I couldn&#8217;t say no. It felt like a call to service to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">help them figure out what was wrong and try to get them out of the crisis; I </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">really</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> didn&#8217;t want to see a company like that die.</span></p>
<p><strong>I remember it was a rough period for the company. How challenging was it, as it was a new experience for you? </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oh, it was pretty tough. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don&#8217;t think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I&#8217;ve apologized for anything I&#8217;ve ever done in my life as much as I did that period. It was definitely intense to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be confronted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with the rage of thousands of people at the same time. It&#8217;s a one-of-a-kind experience. It definitely wasn&#8217;t enjoyable, but then again, everybody was under pressure.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The rage was definitely understandable. I couldn&#8217;t challenge or argue with it. It was valid, but at the same time, so many companies worldwide suffered due to the pandemic. Sure, Thrive could have handled things </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">better; obviously,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that&#8217;s why I joined.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But it was a tough job keeping customers happy and protecting the founders because there were many people ready to take some very extreme measures, as you can imagine, but we managed to all </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">largely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> survive it</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>In a nutshell, how did you bring the company out of the crisis it was facing?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I stepped in, I was </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">extremely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> focused on addressing the problem. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It took me a while to meet the whole company because I was </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">keenly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> focused on the specific teams, people and resources </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">required</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to solve the problem first</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was only after creating a plan that I could start looking at the rest of the company to address what systemic issue led to the problem. There&#8217;s no chronic problem in a startup that is not led or supported by something systemic within the startup.</span></p>
<p><strong>Let&#8217;s talk about the problem. What exactly happened?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Essentially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the challenge with Thrive was a timing issue. Thrive works with the farmers to grow crops. They deliver fertilizer and seeds, and the farmers grow the crops. We support farmers during harvest and manage them getting the harvest to the warehouse. Then we take the goods from the warehouse into the market and sell them to our clients.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So COVID prevented farmers from accessing the farms. It prevented us from accessing the markets to sell the goods. It prevented us from going to the farms to gather the produce and take them to sell.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the lockdown, you can&#8217;t do any of that because you can&#8217;t move. You can&#8217;t deliver seeds to the farmers; the farmers cannot plant, you cannot get people to support them with harvest, you cannot receive the goods. So the fundamental ability for the company to make money </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was compromised</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When that happened, it wasn&#8217;t a problem anybody had seen before. The team didn&#8217;t know how to react and did not pass on the bad news to subscribers. And bad news is always tough to deliver. What it created was this timing issue and that&#8217;s why though we were able to pay back, we did with delay. We wanted to honor the obligations to subscribers. The business model does work. It&#8217;s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that Thrive wasn&#8217;t prepared for a pandemic, but </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">eventually</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we&#8217;ve been able to catch up a little bit.</span></p>
<p><strong>Your case with Thrive Agric is quite unique because you were brought as someone with managerial experience to help the company. That&#8217;s not the case generally within the ecosystem. Some founders rarely want to relinquish their position even if the company is going downhill. Why do you think this is so?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> part of it is because startup culture comes from Silicon Valley and startup culture there prefers to rely on less-experienced people at the beginning. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And to be honest, experience and innovation are not comfortable bedfellows because when you have experience, you will lean on what </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is tried</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and tested</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. When you&#8217;re trying to be innovative, you are throwing away what </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is tried</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and tested.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2189046" style="width: 568px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2189046" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2189046 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/PhotoPictureResizer_210812_014246576_crop_820x1000.jpg?w=558" alt="Adia Sowho" width="558" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/PhotoPictureResizer_210812_014246576_crop_820x1000.jpg 820w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/PhotoPictureResizer_210812_014246576_crop_820x1000.jpg?resize=123,150 123w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/PhotoPictureResizer_210812_014246576_crop_820x1000.jpg?resize=246,300 246w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/PhotoPictureResizer_210812_014246576_crop_820x1000.jpg?resize=768,937 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/PhotoPictureResizer_210812_014246576_crop_820x1000.jpg?resize=558,680 558w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/PhotoPictureResizer_210812_014246576_crop_820x1000.jpg?resize=41,50 41w" sizes="(max-width: 558px) 100vw, 558px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2189046" class="wp-caption-text">Adia Sowho (Ex-CEO, Thrive Agric; CMO, MTN Nigeria)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">essentially,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the challenge that African founders now have is that we have to find a way to localize that context. But going to my first point, we can also see that Google and Facebook made changes when necessary. With Facebook, it was Sheryl Sandberg. Google did with Eric Schmidt. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maybe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> our startups have to do it a little bit earlier and a little bit more </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">informally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> first, and that&#8217;s fine because of the lack of infrastructure existing in the country</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Experience helps you know where someone may have tried something or made a mistake before. That&#8217;s why my joining Thrive made sense. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I&#8217;m happy to see that there is more interest in welcoming people with experience and quite a few more people feel emboldened to make the jump into startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I believe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the trend is changing, although it can be definitely difficult when you want a long career. To jump into the startup culture, you have to throw away many comforts and embrace an extremely dynamic environment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>How would you say Thrive Agric is faring now?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because I took a systemic approach to manage the team and the startup, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I believe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> they are on better footing. Now, the founders and the senior team can a little bit more </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">comfortably</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> see around corners. The only thing you can do with risk is to manage it or prevent it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I got into Thrive, I was </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">highly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> focused on what went wrong, understanding the causality and retraining the team to better see around those kinds of corners</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">That work continues. I stay on as an advisor because I want to ensure the company&#8217;s continued success for the same reason I gave before: food security</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I mean, Thrive is one of three companies that the Central Bank of Nigeria </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is satisfied</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with giving support to deliver</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> food security nationwide</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It means that the sky is the limit </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in terms of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> growth because </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thrive is aggregating 100,000 farmers in the country just this year. The growth potential for this company is astounding.</span></p>
<p><strong>So, in all this, what does your experience at Thrive tell you about startups and the Nigerian tech ecosystem in general?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Startup life is hard in countries that are infrastructure rich. It is harder in countries that are infrastructure light. In Nigeria and Africa, that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">internally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> forces startups to build infrastructure that they don&#8217;t have. But the problem for some is that when they build it, they individualize it, which kind of sucks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But at the same time, the low-hanging fruit around here is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> amazing. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I&#8217;m excited by the potential and possibility of creating a new version of what the economy can look like by tapping into the internet and connectivity</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So for me, there are definitely opportunities to support startups differently. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">maybe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that&#8217;s going to be the focus of my work with the ecosystem going forward. Figuring out how to help the ecosystem build better products and run better startups based on my experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since I can&#8217;t </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">obviously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> go in and do that for everybody, I&#8217;ll try to figure out a way to share my knowledge at scale.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DKdFRtqdid"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/02/nigeria-is-becoming-africas-unofficial-tech-capital/">Nigeria is becoming Africa’s unofficial tech capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nigeria is becoming Africa’s unofficial tech capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/02/nigeria-is-becoming-africas-unofficial-tech-capital/embed/#?secret=DKdFRtqdid" data-secret="DKdFRtqdid" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>How will you do that now that you&#8217;ve left the startup scene and gone back to the corporate world with MTN?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, let&#8217;s talk about infrastructure. You know, if you think about your startup with MTN as a partner, what does the trajectory of that startup now look like? It&#8217;s massive. So that&#8217;s why I took this role.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I&#8217;m still doing a lot of startup ecosystem work. For me, there is a telco role in all future unicorn stories. That requires empathy on both sides to happen. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve talked about, written about, been working for years, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> figuring out how to make these relationships work better</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. I guess that&#8217;s why, you know, a candidate like me was appealing to the company. I&#8217;m keen to go there and continue the same work at scale with the knowledge I have.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/how-adia-sowho-helped-steer-thrive-agric-through-the-pandemic-crisis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188767</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter locks account of India&#8217;s largest opposition party</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/twitter-locks-account-of-india-congress-largest-opposition-party/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/twitter-locks-account-of-india-congress-largest-opposition-party/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 06:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189078</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter has locked the account of Indian National Congress, the South Asian nation&#8217;s largest opposition party, for violating its rules. The Indian National Congress wrote about the Twitter episode on Facebook Thursday. &#8220;When our leaders were put in jails, we were not scared then why would we be afraid of closing our Twitter accounts now. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter has locked the account of Indian National Congress, the South Asian nation&#8217;s largest opposition party, for violating its rules.</p>
<p>The Indian National Congress wrote about the Twitter episode on Facebook Thursday.</p>
<p>&#8220;When our leaders were put in jails, we were not scared then why would we be afraid of closing our Twitter accounts now. We are Congress, this is the message of the people, we will fight, we will keep fighting. If it is a crime to raise our voice to get justice for the rape victim girl, then we will do this crime a hundred times. Jai Hind&#8230; Satyamev Jayate,&#8221; it said.</p>
<p>Rohan Gupta, the head of social media for Congress, alleged that Twitter had taken the step at the direction of the ruling Bharatiya Janata Party, adding that the firm had also suspended profiles of several of the party&#8217;s senior leaders.</p>
<p>In a statement, a Twitter spokesperson said the company&#8217;s rules are enforced judiciously and impartially for everyone on our service.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have taken proactive action on several hundred Tweets that posted an image that violated our Rules, and may continue to do so in line with our range of enforcement options. Certain types of private information carry higher risks than others, and our aim is always to protect individuals’ privacy and safety. We strongly encourage everyone on the service to familiarise themselves with the Twitter Rules and report anything they believe is in violation,&#8221; the spokesperson added.</p>
<p>The locking of the Indian National Congress&#8217; account has prompted some new criticism for the American firm. &#8220;We strongly condemn the blocking of the accounts of the Indian National Congress and senior leaders of the Congress party,&#8221; tweeted Derek O&#8217; Brien, from the All India Trinamool Congress party.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Last week, Twitter suspended the account of Rahul Gandhi (pictured above), the former president of the Indian National Congress, after he tweeted pictures with the family of a nine-year-old who was allegedly raped and murdered. The company was shortly reached by the National Commission for Protection of Child Rights, an Indian statutory body, which said the Congress leader&#8217;s tweets violated the privacy of a minor victim.</p>
<p>The new episode is Twitter&#8217;s latest headache in India, a key overseas market for American firms.</p>
<p>After months-long public tension with the Indian government, Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/twitter-now-in-compliance-with-india-new-it-rules-government-says/">finally complied with the South Asian nation&#8217;s new IT law</a>, which went into effect in May, a lawyer for New Delhi said in a court Tuesday.</p>
<p>Twitter, which was facing heat from the Indian government for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/twitter-takes-actions-on-over-500-accounts-in-india-amid-government-warning/">not blocking some tweets</a> that the Indian government had deemed objectionable earlier this year, had requested a few additional months to comply with the new rules that mandate all significant social media firms &#8212; any service with more than 5 million users, per the Indian government &#8212; to appoint officials in the country to address on-ground concerns in the country.</p>
<p>The move is expected to deescalate the tension between the two. Twitter <a href="https://www.thenewsminute.com/article/twitter-labels-sambit-patras-tweet-cong-toolkit-manipulated-media-149257">labeled a tweet from Sambit Patra</a>, the spokesperson of India’s ruling party BJP, in May as “manipulated media.” Days later, a special squad of Delhi police that investigates terrorism and other crimes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/delhi-police-run-by-indias-central-government-raids-twitter-offices-over-manipulated-label/">made a surprise visit to two of Twitter’s offices</a> in the country to seek information about Twitter’s rationale to term Patra’s tweets as manipulated. At the time, Twitter said it was “concerned by recent events regarding our employees in India and the potential threat to freedom of expression for the people we serve.”</p>
<p><em>This is a developing story. More to follow&#8230;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/twitter-locks-account-of-india-congress-largest-opposition-party/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189078</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s Eruditus valued at $3.2 billion in $650 million fundraise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/india-eruditus-valued-at-3-2-billion-in-650-million-fundraise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/india-eruditus-valued-at-3-2-billion-in-650-million-fundraise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 06:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eruditus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Vision Fund 2]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mumbai-based Eruditus, which works with top universities globally to offer more than 100 executive-level courses to students in over 80 nations, said on Thursday it has raised $650 million in a new financing round led by Accel and SoftBank Vision Fund 2. The new financing round &#8212; which includes both primary and secondary transactions &#8212; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mumbai-based Eruditus, which works with top universities globally to offer more than 100 executive-level courses to students in over 80 nations, said on Thursday it has raised $650 million in a new financing round led by Accel and SoftBank Vision Fund 2.</p>
<p>The new financing round &#8212; which includes both primary and secondary transactions &#8212; values the ten-year-old Indian startup at $3.2 billion, up from about $700 million a year ago. The Canada Pension Plan Investment Board also participated in the new round.</p>
<p><a href="http://eruditus.com/">Eruditus</a>, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/31/chan-zuckerberg-initiative-backs-indian-education-startup-eruditus-in-113-million-fundraise/">counts Chan Zuckerberg Initiative and Sequoia Capital India among its backers</a>, maintains a tie-up with over 30 top-tier universities, including MIT, Harvard, Columbia, Cambridge, INSEAD, Wharton, UC Berkeley, IIT, IIM and NUS. The universities and Eruditus work to develop courses that are aimed at offering higher education to students. These courses cost anything between $5,000 to $40,000.</p>
<p>The startup said it will deploy the fresh funds to develop more courses and build new products.</p>
<p>“With this fundraise, we’re excited to scale our unique business model, continue to deliver strong learning outcomes, and grow our global impact at a rapid rate,&#8221; said Ashwin Damera, co-founder and chief executive of Eruditus. Damera has sold stake worth as much as $100 million in the new round.</p>
<p>The new fundraise comes at a time when Indian startups are raising record capital from high-profile investors. India, which is the world’s second largest internet market, has produced over 23 unicorns this year (Eruditus is the 23rd), up from 11 last year and 6 in 2019. Some investors have also doubled down on the South Asian market after China, one of the other rare big growth markets, enforced a series of regulatory changes that has wiped hundreds of billions of dollars in recent weeks.</p>
<p>“With the rapid rate of technological disruption, continuous upskilling is necessary in today’s job market,” said Sumer Juneja, Partner at SoftBank Investment Advisers, in a statement. “The company’s partnerships with elite universities, and use of technology and data to create and deliver high quality courses positions Eruditus to lead in this space.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Eruditus is SoftBank&#8217;s second major bet on India&#8217;s edtech market. The Japanese investment firm has also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/indias-online-learning-platform-unacademy-raises-150-million-at-1-45-billion-valuation/">backed Unacademy</a>.</p>
<p>UpGrad, a Bangalore-based startup that specializes in higher education and upskilling courses, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/india-upgrad-enters-unicorn-club-with-185-million-fundraise/">joined the unicorn club</a> earlier this week. VerSe Innovation, which operates news aggregator service Dailyhunt and short video apps Josh, said early Thursday that it has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/india-verse-raises-over-450-million-to-expand-dailyhunt-and-josh-apps-globally/">raised over $450 million in a new financing round</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eRCGaEmeyo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/mapping-out-one-edtech-companys-200m-bet-on-lifelong-learning/">Mapping out one edtech company’s $200M bet on lifelong learning</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mapping out one edtech company’s $200M bet on lifelong learning&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/mapping-out-one-edtech-companys-200m-bet-on-lifelong-learning/embed/#?secret=eRCGaEmeyo" data-secret="eRCGaEmeyo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/india-eruditus-valued-at-3-2-billion-in-650-million-fundraise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189080</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s VerSe Innovation raises over $450 million to expand Dailyhunt and Josh apps globally</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/india-verse-raises-over-450-million-to-expand-dailyhunt-and-josh-apps-globally/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/india-verse-raises-over-450-million-to-expand-dailyhunt-and-josh-apps-globally/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 04:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dailyhunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[josh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[VerSe Innovation, the parent firm of popular news aggregator Dailyhunt and short video app Josh, said on Thursday it has raised over $450 million in a new financing round, just five months after securing $200 million, as the Indian startup looks to expand its offerings to international markets. Siguler Guff, Baillie Gifford, affiliates of Carlyle [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">VerSe Innovation, the parent firm of popular news aggregator Dailyhunt and short video app Josh, said on Thursday it has raised over $450 million in a new financing round, just five months after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/07/dailyhunt-and-joshs-parent-firm-raises-over-100-million/">securing $200 million</a>, as the Indian startup looks to expand its offerings to international markets.</p>
<p>Siguler Guff, Baillie Gifford, affiliates of Carlyle Asia Partners Growth II and others financed VerSe Innovation’s Series I round, while existing investors Sofina Group, Qatar Investment Authority and BCap participated.</p>
<p>VerSe Innovation said in a statement that its valuation has more than doubled in the past five months without disclosing a precise figure. The startup was valued at over $1 billion in its Series H financing round. <strong>Update</strong>: VerSe Innovation&#8217;s valuation is &#8220;nearing $3 billion&#8221; in the new round, said a person familiar with the matter.</p>
<p>The Google and Microsoft-backed startup claimed that Josh, which has amassed over 115 million monthly active users, 56 million of whom use the app each day. Dailyhunt, the startup said, has amassed over 300 million monthly active users.</p>
<p>Josh competes with scores of short video apps including Moj and MX TakaTak. All these apps mushroomed after India <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/29/india-bans-tiktok-dozens-of-other-chinese-apps/">banned TikTok over cybersecurity concerns</a> in mid-2020 to cash in on the opportunity. ByteDance&#8217;s app identified India as its biggest international market, where it had courted over 200 monthly active users.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2189119" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2189119" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2189119 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/india-short-video-apps-download.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="330" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/india-short-video-apps-download.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/india-short-video-apps-download.jpg?resize=150,48 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/india-short-video-apps-download.jpg?resize=300,97 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/india-short-video-apps-download.jpg?resize=768,247 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/india-short-video-apps-download.jpg?resize=680,219 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/india-short-video-apps-download.jpg?resize=1536,495 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/india-short-video-apps-download.jpg?resize=50,16 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2189119" class="wp-caption-text">Monthly download for short video apps in India, per mobile insight firm App Annie. Data sourced by TechCrunch from an industry executive.</p></div></p>
<p>Moj, which claims to have over 100 million users, is operated by Tiger Global-backed ShareChat that was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/india-sharechat-valued-at-3-billion-in-145-million-fundraise/">valued at $2.88 billion in a financing round</a> it unveiled last month. MX TakaTak&#8217;s parent firm, MX Player, is also currently engaging with investors to raise a round that would value the startup at over $1 billion, according to three people aware of the development.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>VerSe Innovation is betting on building a family of apps that serves users in scores of local languages. Dailyhunt, for instance, offers its content in 14 languages from over 100,000 content partners and creators. And it plans to replicate the same strategy as it looks to expand in international markets, VerSe Innovation said.</p>
<p>The startup said it also plans to invest in broadening its AI / ML stack to offer users more personalized experience.</p>
<p>The new fundraise comes at a time when Indian startups are raising record capital from high-profile investors. India, which is the world&#8217;s second largest internet market, has produced over 20 unicorns this year, up from 11 last year and 6 in 2019. Some investors have also doubled down on the South Asian market after China, one of the other rare big growth markets, enforced a series of regulatory changes that has wiped hundreds of billions of dollars in recent weeks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/india-verse-raises-over-450-million-to-expand-dailyhunt-and-josh-apps-globally/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189069</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AppWorks closes third fund with $150M for Taiwan and Southeast Asia startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/appworks-closes-third-fund-with-150m-for-taiwan-and-southeast-asia-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/appworks-closes-third-fund-with-150m-for-taiwan-and-southeast-asia-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AppWorks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taiwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AppWorks, the Taipei-based venture capital firm focused on Taiwan and Southeast Asia, announced today it has closed its oversubscribed third fund, raising $150 million. AppWorks Fund III’s limited partners include Taiwan Mobile, Axiom Asia Private Capital, Fubon Life, TransGlobe Life, Hongtai Group, Wistron, Cathay Life, Phison Electronics and Taiwan’s National Development Fund. Many of these [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://appworks.tw/">AppWorks</a>, the Taipei-based venture capital firm focused on Taiwan and Southeast Asia, announced today it has closed its oversubscribed third fund, raising $150 million. AppWorks Fund III’s limited partners include Taiwan Mobile, Axiom Asia Private Capital, Fubon Life, TransGlobe Life, Hongtai Group, Wistron, Cathay Life, Phison Electronics and Taiwan’s National Development Fund. Many of these LPs also participated in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/03/17/appworks-50m/">AppWorks’ $50 million second fund in 2014</a>.</p>
<p>AppWorks’ total assets under management (AUM) is now $212 million. As part of Fund III’s close, AppWorks is <a href="https://appworks.tw/works/">recruiting </a>new investment associates and analysts, especially ones who will focus on sourcing deals throughout Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>Jamie Lin, the firm’s chairman and founding partner, told TechCrunch that Fund III had an initial target of $100 million, but surpassed it because of the strong performance of AppWorks’ second fund.</p>
<p>Fund II’s portfolio includes Lalamove and 91APP, and at the end of July 2021, its total value to paid-in (TVPI), or the return multiple net of fees, reached 3.3x. By comparison, the top quartile of global VC and private equity funds launched around the same time have a TVPI of 2.4x, according to data from Cambridge Associates. Fund II also achieved internal rate of return (IRR) of 34.7%, compared to 26.1% for the other funds.</p>
<p>Founded in 2009, AppWorks started its accelerator program before launching a $11 million debut fund in 2012. AppWorks’ ecosystem now includes 414 active startups that have collectively raised $4.3 billion, and have an aggregate valuation of $17.4 billion. Over the next 10 years, AppWorks’ goal is to increase that to 1,000 active startups with a collective value of more than $100 billion.</p>
<p>Lin said AppWorks has a strong incoming pipeline because many startups in its ecosystem, including ones run by accelerator alumni and its mentor network of about 100 seasoned entrepreneurs, have reached product-market fit, are scalable and need to raise funding to accelerate growth.</p>
<p>Fund III is earmarked for a portfolio of about 40 startups, split evenly between investments starting at $2 million in Series A to Series C rounds, and seed-stage investments. Seed-stage checks can range in size from about $50,000 to $200,000, depending on a startup’s needs. Part of the fund’s capital will also go toward AppWorks’ current portfolio companies as they reach maturation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>AppWorks’ three main investment themes are Southeast Asia, blockchain and artificial intelligence.</p>
<p>Lin said that many of AppWorks accelerator graduates over the past three to five years are from Singapore, Malaysia, Vietnam and, increasingly, Indonesia and the Philippines. (AppWorks also serves as an LP in about 15 seed funds across Southeast Asia, which helped it maintain strong deal flow despite pandemic travel restrictions).</p>
<p>AppWorks’ current blockchain investments include Dapper Labs, Animoca Brands and Splinterlands. Lin is especially keen on NFTs and their “ability to bridge the physical world and digital world,” plus blockchain’s potential to change how people game (for example, the play-to-earn model Splinterlands is known for).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E4N7ZqDok1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/explosive-inclusive-potential-nfts/">The explosive (and inclusive) potential of NFTs in the creative world</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The explosive (and inclusive) potential of NFTs in the creative world&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/explosive-inclusive-potential-nfts/embed/#?secret=E4N7ZqDok1" data-secret="E4N7ZqDok1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Investing in a mix of seed- and growth-stage deals means Fund III’s schedule will be more evenly spread out. The approach is “better for LPs, but also mostly comes from our philosophy of putting founders front and center,” Lin said. “A lot of our accelerator alumni startups are by first-time founders, so they need help all the way from seed stage. Many of our mentors have already raised seed or Series A rounds, and they come to us when they need someone to lead a Series B of $10, $15 or $20 million. It stems from our particular deal flow, since we’re mainly supporting our alumni founders and mentors, so we have two very different types of deal flows.”</p>
<p>Fund III has already backed AppWorks accelerator alumni like Pickone, WeMo Scooter, Omnichat, XREX, Blocto, SoopahGenius and Docosan. Investments from its mentor network include Carousell, Dapper Labs, Tiki, Dcard, Yummy Corp and Animoca Brands.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yH1kFktKr0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/want-to-double-your-rate-of-return-seek-counsel-from-experienced-executives/">Want to double your rate of return? Seek counsel from experienced executives</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Want to double your rate of return? Seek counsel from experienced executives&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/want-to-double-your-rate-of-return-seek-counsel-from-experienced-executives/embed/#?secret=yH1kFktKr0" data-secret="yH1kFktKr0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NEhZQnkr5L"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/the-roadmap-to-startup-consolidation-in-southeast-asia-is-becoming-clearer/">The roadmap to startup consolidation in Southeast Asia is becoming clearer</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The roadmap to startup consolidation in Southeast Asia is becoming clearer&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/the-roadmap-to-startup-consolidation-in-southeast-asia-is-becoming-clearer/embed/#?secret=NEhZQnkr5L" data-secret="NEhZQnkr5L" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/appworks-closes-third-fund-with-150m-for-taiwan-and-southeast-asia-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188539</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mushroom-based meat alternative startup Fable Food raises $6.5M AUD, will launch in the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/mushroom-based-meat-alternative-startup-fable-food-raises-6-5m-aud-will-launch-in-the-u-s/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/mushroom-based-meat-alternative-startup-fable-food-raises-6-5m-aud-will-launch-in-the-u-s/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 23:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fable Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat alternative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat substitutes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plant-based food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sydney, Australia-based Fable Food is the latest plant-based food startup to announce funding. The company, which uses mushrooms in its meat alternatives, has raised $6.5 million AUD (about $4.8 million USD) in a seed round led by Blackbird Ventures, the Australian venture capital firm whose portfolio also includes Canva, Culture Amp and SafetyCulture. Other participants [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Sydney, Australia-based <a href="https://fablefood.co/">Fable Food </a>is the latest plant-based food startup to announce funding. The company, which uses mushrooms in its meat alternatives, has raised $6.5 million AUD (about $4.8 million USD) in a seed round led by Blackbird Ventures, the Australian venture capital firm whose portfolio also includes Canva, Culture Amp and SafetyCulture. Other participants included agriculture and food tech venture firm AgFunder, sustainability-focused Aera VC and Better Bite Ventures, along with Singapore-based produce importer Ban Choon Marketing and former Sequoia Capital partner Warren Hogarth.</p>
<p>Fable is preparing to launch in the United States by the end of this year. In Australia, its products are available at retailers like Woolworths, Coles and Harris Farm Markets, along with restaurants including Grill’d, which recently started serving its Meaty Mushroom Burger Pattie at 136 locations. Fable’s products are also available at restaurants in Singapore and the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>The startup was founded in 2019 by fine dining chef turned chemical engineer and mycologist (mushroom scientist) Jim Fuller, organic mushroom farmer Chris McLoghlin and Michael Fox, whose previous startup was Shoes of Prey.</p>
<p>Fox, Fable’s chief executive officer, told TechCrunch in an email that after being a vegetarian for six years, he recently became a vegan “for a mix of health, environmental and ethical reasons.”</p>
<p>“Talking to my friends and family, a lot of people want to reduce their meat consumption for the same reasons but they find it challenging because they love the taste and texture of meat and giving it up is hard,” Fox said. He wanted to find a way to make it easier for people to transition to plant-based foods, and spoke to several chefs who suggested using mushrooms as a base ingredient. Then Fox met Fuller and McLoghlin, who were in the process of developing meat alternatives using mushrooms.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IIZ0dkuYrM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/next-gen-foods-to-launch-its-plant-based-chicken-in-the-u-s-after-raising-a-20m-seed-extension-from-investors-like-ggv/">Next Gen Foods to launch its plant-based chicken in the US after raising a $20M seed extension from investors like GGV</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Next Gen Foods to launch its plant-based chicken in the US after raising a $20M seed extension from investors like GGV&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/next-gen-foods-to-launch-its-plant-based-chicken-in-the-u-s-after-raising-a-20m-seed-extension-from-investors-like-ggv/embed/#?secret=IIZ0dkuYrM" data-secret="IIZ0dkuYrM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“When we met, we realized we shared the same values and goals and had complementary skill sets,” said Fox. “We shared a common desire to help end industrial agriculture and wanted to make our food system more ethical, healthy, sustainable and lower its greenhouse gas emissions.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Fable&#8217;s first products include a substitute for pulled pork, braised beef and beef brisket (Fuller grew up in Texas eating slow-cooked meats and wanted to recreate the experience), along with a line of ready-made meals. The company uses shiitake mushrooms, which Fox explained are “very flavorful with their natural umami flavors, they are a slow-growing mushroom so they naturally have the fleshy fibers that give the meaty bite you typically get from animal proteins, and have the right chemical composition that when cooked allow us to taste flavors that are found in animal products.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2188574" style="width: 463px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2188574" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2188574 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/7.-Credit-Natalie-Nguyen-–-Fable_ReadyMeals.jpg?w=453" alt="Fable's ready-made meals" width="453" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/7.-Credit-Natalie-Nguyen-–-Fable_ReadyMeals.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/7.-Credit-Natalie-Nguyen-–-Fable_ReadyMeals.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/7.-Credit-Natalie-Nguyen-–-Fable_ReadyMeals.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/7.-Credit-Natalie-Nguyen-–-Fable_ReadyMeals.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/7.-Credit-Natalie-Nguyen-–-Fable_ReadyMeals.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/7.-Credit-Natalie-Nguyen-–-Fable_ReadyMeals.jpg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/7.-Credit-Natalie-Nguyen-–-Fable_ReadyMeals.jpg?resize=1365,2048 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/7.-Credit-Natalie-Nguyen-–-Fable_ReadyMeals.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 453px) 100vw, 453px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2188574" class="wp-caption-text">Fable&#8217;s ready-made meals. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fable</p></div></p>
<p>Fuller serves as Fable’s chief science officer and the startup leverages his experience as a chef/chemical engineer/mycologist to create the right combinations of flavor, aroma and texture while keeping processing and ingredients to a minimum. For example, its braised beef alternative is made with shiitake mushrooms, seven other ingredients and salt and pepper.</p>
<p>Fable also announced today it has appointed Dan Joyce, who was previously safety and compliance software company SafetyCulture’s general manager of Europe, the Middle East and Africa, as chief growth officer to head global sales and marketing. It will launch in the U.S. through a combination of partnerships with restaurants and meal kit companies.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eNeycjoxaS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/i-cant-believe-its-not-meat/">I can&#8217;t believe it&#8217;s not meat! Mycelium meat replacement company aims for summer launch of first products</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;I can&#8217;t believe it&#8217;s not meat! Mycelium meat replacement company aims for summer launch of first products&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/i-cant-believe-its-not-meat/embed/#?secret=eNeycjoxaS" data-secret="eNeycjoxaS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Other startups that use mushrooms as basis for meat alternatives include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/i-cant-believe-its-not-meat/">Meati</a> and <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/chloesorvino/2021/04/15/maker-of-mushroom-sourced-bacon-raises-40-million-to-reach-grocers-at-scale/?sh=3e7d436a72d1">AtLast</a>. Fox said a main difference is that those two startups ferment mycelium, or the root structure of fungi, instead of using mushrooms, which are the fruiting body of fungi.</p>
<p>Fable’s new funding will be used for research and development, expanding its production and manufacturing capacity in Australia and other countries. The company is keeping its product pipeline under wraps for now, but Fox said it plans to develop mushroom-based substitutes for pork, chicken, lamb and other animal proteins.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dnvLM00nfh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/30/whats-beyond-beyond-meat-and-impossible-foods-in-the-future-of-food/">What&#8217;s beyond Beyond Meat and Impossible Foods in the future of food?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What&#8217;s beyond Beyond Meat and Impossible Foods in the future of food?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/30/whats-beyond-beyond-meat-and-impossible-foods-in-the-future-of-food/embed/#?secret=dnvLM00nfh" data-secret="dnvLM00nfh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/mushroom-based-meat-alternative-startup-fable-food-raises-6-5m-aud-will-launch-in-the-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188567</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tinder&#8217;s interactive &#8216;Swipe Night&#8217; stories return after a 20 million user turnout</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/tinders-interactive-swipe-night-stories-return-after-a-20-million-user-turnout/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/tinders-interactive-swipe-night-stories-return-after-a-20-million-user-turnout/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 22:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gossip girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tinder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the last year, Tinder has experimented with creative ways for people to connect beyond just swiping right. Pandemic or not, it&#8217;s hard to make the first move &#8212; so why not break the ice by weathering a virtual apocalypse with a potential date? Today, Tinder announced that it will launch its second &#8220;Swipe Night&#8221; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Over the last year, Tinder has experimented with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/tinder-to-roll-out-new-48-hour-in-app-events-called-vibes/">creative ways</a> for people to connect beyond just swiping right. Pandemic or not, it&#8217;s hard to make the first move &#8212; so why not break the ice by weathering a virtual apocalypse with a potential date? Today, Tinder <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-08-11-Tinder-Orders-More-Swipe-Night-Following-Transformative-20-Million-Member-Turnout-and-26-Increase-in-Matches">announced</a> that it will launch its second &#8220;Swipe Night&#8221; series after its first installment garnered engagement from over 20 million users.</p>
<p>Tinder launched Swipe Night in 2019 as an interactive &#8220;choose your own adventure&#8221; story at a time when the app had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/20/tinders-interactive-series-swipe-night-could-bring-a-needed-boost-to-user-engagement/">experienced</a> a decline in one of its user engagement metrics and saw a dip in quarterly revenue. In the months since, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-match-group-results/match-quarterly-revenue-hit-by-slowing-tinder-growth-idUSKBN22H2VV">COVID slowed Tinder&#8217;s revenue</a> further, but more recently, it&#8217;s been <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-04/match-group-revenue-beats-estimates-delivers-positive-outlook?sref=gni836kR">rebounding</a>.</p>
<p>Noting that its user base was<a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/introducing-swipe-night"> half Gen Z</a> (ages 18-25), Tinder hired now 25-year-old director Karena Evans, who has also directed music videos for Drake, as well as the premiere of HBO Max&#8217;s &#8220;Gossip Girl&#8221; reboot. The Swipe Night story invited users to choose what they would do in the apocalypse, swiping left or right to indicate their decisions as a character in the story. Based on how they swiped, users would get matched with other Swipe Night participants, and their choices would appear on their Tinder profile.</p>
<p>&#8220;All of this new information will make for plenty of material for post-apocalyptic banter,&#8221; the company had <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/introducing-swipe-night">said</a>.</p>
<p>Skeptics might find this to be an inorganic way to boost user engagement and matches, but on Swipe Nights, there was a 26% increase in matches compared with a typical Sunday night, <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-08-11-Tinder-Orders-More-Swipe-Night-Following-Transformative-20-Million-Member-Turnout-and-26-Increase-in-Matches">Tinder now reports</a>. The interactive video series was even <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-06-25-Tinder-Wins-Entertainment-Grand-Prix-for-Swipe-Night-at-Cannes-Festival-2021">recognized</a> at the prestigious Cannes Film Festival.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wvJhVXQGHOg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>The next installment for Swipe Night will be a &#8220;Gen Z whodunnit,&#8221; Tinder announced today.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The upcoming series will utilize Tinder&#8217;s &#8220;Fast Chat,&#8221; the quick chat feature that powers <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-06-22-Tinder-Expands-Into-Video-and-Social-Experiences">Tinder&#8217;s new &#8220;Hot Takes&#8221; experience</a> where users can talk before matching. On Swipe Night, Fast Chat will allow users to analyze clues and work together to solve the mystery, even if they haven&#8217;t already matched.</p>
<p>Tinder says Swipe Night will debut in the app&#8217;s &#8220;Explore&#8221; section, which is a newer part of the Tinder app that gives members different ways to meet beyond just swiping. The section was <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-06-22-Tinder-Expands-Into-Video-and-Social-Experiences">announced</a> last month as part of a group of features targeting Gen Z users, along with Hot Takes and video profiles.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QbCECL2RXu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/">Extra Crunch members save money with Partner Perks and event discounts</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Extra Crunch members save money with Partner Perks and event discounts&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/embed/#?secret=QbCECL2RXu" data-secret="QbCECL2RXu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VyDhGJXUat"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/match-group-to-add-live-audio-and-video-to-its-dating-app-portfolio-starting-in-2021/">Match Group to add audio and video chat, including group live video, to its dating app portfolio</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Match Group to add audio and video chat, including group live video, to its dating app portfolio&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/match-group-to-add-live-audio-and-video-to-its-dating-app-portfolio-starting-in-2021/embed/#?secret=VyDhGJXUat" data-secret="VyDhGJXUat" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/tinders-interactive-swipe-night-stories-return-after-a-20-million-user-turnout/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188907</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: FEMA tests national emergency alert system for first time since pandemic began</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/daily-crunch-fema-tests-national-emergency-alert-system-for-first-time-since-pandemic-began/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/daily-crunch-fema-tests-national-emergency-alert-system-for-first-time-since-pandemic-began/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 22:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188848</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for August 11, 2021. If you are a Twitter user, today has proven to be a divisive day, thanks to some design changes. We also have hardware news, mobility news, a few very neat funding rounds and even some startup media news. It’s a great day for a roundup. Also, if you are in the United States, you may have noticed a missive from FEMA today. FEMA is the U.S. Federal Emergency Management Agency, and it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/fema-emergency-alert-system/">just ran a test of its emergency alert system</a>, or EAS. Given that the world appears to be constantly on fire, sick or underwater, it’s a good time for such an endeavor.</p>
<p>Before we go on, Disrupt is hosting <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/hear-how-cityblock-healths-toyin-ajayi-carbon-healths-eren-bali-and-forwards-adrian-aoun-see-tech-impacting-access-to-health-at-disrupt-2021/">some of the most interesting founders in health tech</a>, and we’ll have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/dont-miss-these-special-breakout-sessions-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/">some pretty darn cool breakout sessions to boot</a>. Disrupt is going to rock. &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Dyn4EEdsUM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/dont-miss-these-special-breakout-sessions-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/">Don’t miss these special breakout sessions at TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Don’t miss these special breakout sessions at TechCrunch Disrupt 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/dont-miss-these-special-breakout-sessions-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/embed/#?secret=Dyn4EEdsUM" data-secret="Dyn4EEdsUM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/twitter-redesigns-website-with-new-font-less-clutter-and-high-contrast-features/">Twitter’s redesign turns heads:</a> </strong>That Twitter is in the midst of something akin to a product renaissance is well known, with the social media provider working on a host of projects at once. Hell, Twitter is even working on <em>TweetDeck</em>. Today, however, Twitter stirred the pot with a web and mobile redesign that included a new font. <em>Quelle horreur !</em> No, but really, people are mad.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/heres-everything-samsung-announced-this-morning/">Here’s everything that Samsung announced today:</a></strong> As expected, Samsung held a hardware event today. What did the hardware giant show off? The Galaxy Watch 4, the Galaxy Z Fold 3 (the folding smartphone affair), the Galaxy Z Flip 2 (a smaller folding smartphone) and new headphones. If you are not into the iOS ecosystem, this is for you.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/vcs-unfazed-by-chinese-regulatory-shakeups-so-far/"><strong>China’s regulatory shakeup not harming venture investment. Yet.</strong></a><strong> </strong>After the Chinese government started a wide-ranging crackdown on a host of domestic industries that it either found too powerful, too unregulated or too monopolistic, what impact the changes would have on startups and venture capital have been open questions. Early Q3 data indicates that things haven’t changed too much, <em>yet</em>. But with SoftBank potentially pausing Chinese deals, larger startup investment could suffer.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Before we get into our usual digest of the latest and greatest funding rounds from the worlds of venture capital and high-growth startups, two product-related notes.</p>
<p>First, Airtable just bought something! Yes, <strong>Airtable</strong>, the roughly $5.8 billion spreadsheet of the future is making deals. Well, one. The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/airtable-makes-bayes-its-first-acquisition-to-up-its-data-visualization-game/">company bought <strong>Bayes</strong></a>, what TechCrunch called an “early-stage visualization startup” that also features a no-code focus. If you love Airtable, this could be good news.</p>
<p>Second, <strong>Medium</strong> is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/medium-revamps-its-partner-program-launching-new-eligibility-requirements-and-referral-bonuses/">shaking up its business model yet again</a>. Again. Yes, one more time. This time, the company is changing its partner program. Now writers on Medium can drive their own subscriptions, snagging half the long-term revenue net of fees. This feels a little Substack-y, but not in a bad way. Despite Medium’s inability to decide what it is, I remain modestly hopeful for the company thanks to my profession of getting paid to make words appear on the internet.</p>
<p>Now, some funding rounds for your enjoyment!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/doxel-raises-40m-from-insight-a16z-to-become-the-waze-for-construction/"><strong>$40M for construction-focused computer vision:</strong></a><strong> </strong>That’s the headline from Doxel’s latest round, led by Insight Partners. The Series B brings the company’s total raised capital to just over $56 million. Doxel uses computer vision to track the progress of construction sites. It’s a neat model, and, per the company, it still has its full Series A in the bank thanks to “growth and bookings traction” of sufficient size that it has been “cash flow neutral” since its last raise. Why would Doxel raise if it didn’t need money? Because it could pad its accounts at a new, higher price implying minimal dilution. And you always want to raise when you don’t need to. It’s far cheaper than waiting for a cash crunch.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/e-commerce-as-a-service-platform-cart-com-picks-up-98m-to-give-brands-scaling-tools/"><strong>Cart.com raises $98 million:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Does the name Cart.com sound familiar? It might. Why? Because the Houston-based e-commerce tooling company has now raised three times this year. So you may recall it from the other two times it put capital onto its balance sheet in 2021. The company has now raised $143 million in total.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/founded-by-a-freshworks-alum-sales-commission-platform-everstage-gets-1-7m-seed/"><strong>Everstage raises $1.7M for sales commissions software:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The old startup adage of <em>build software to replace manual spreadsheet processes </em>is alive and well, it turns out. Everstage wants to take sales commissions, today “calculated on spreadsheets by finance teams” that provide limited visibility to salespeople, and turn them into highly limpid software. Salespeople will dig this, given how complex commissions can be and how critical they are to sales comp totals.</li>
<li>Finally, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/pave-gets-y-combinator-to-back-better-startup-compensation-tools-again/"><strong>Pave raises $16M</strong></a> to help companies “benchmark, plan and communicate compensation to their employees.” Akin to how sales commissions can be Gordian in their heft, employee comp is a knotty issue. Pave wants to provide more data to companies so that they can make better &#8212; and, we hope, more equitable &#8212; compensation decisions and generally improve employee lives. We dig this.</li>
</ul>
<h2>The gray revolution: Fundraising within the older adult space</h2>
<p>Although older adults are one of the fastest-growing demographics, they&#8217;re quite underserved when it comes to consumer tech.</p>
<p>The global population of people older than 65 will reach 1.5 billion by 2050, and members of this cohort — who are leading longer, active lives — have money to spend.</p>
<p>Still, most startups persist in releasing products aimed at serving younger users, says Lawrence Kosick, co-founder of GetSetUp, an edtech company that targets 50+ learners.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you can provide a valuable, scalable service for the older adult market, there’s a lot of opportunity to drive growth through partnerships.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="i6lyJqU7tx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/the-gray-revolution-fundraising-within-the-older-adult-space/">The gray revolution: Fundraising within the older adult space</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The gray revolution: Fundraising within the older adult space&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/the-gray-revolution-fundraising-within-the-older-adult-space/embed/#?secret=i6lyJqU7tx" data-secret="i6lyJqU7tx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>All right, listen, public tech companies were more than busy today. So, we’re going to be brief so that we can cram as much news in here as we can:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/nortonlifelock-avast-merger/"><strong>NortonLifeLock is combining with Avast in an $8.1B deal:</strong></a> This is big news for the cybersecurity space. TechCrunch called this the third-largest cybersecurity acquisition of all time.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/google-launches-android-12-beta-4-hitting-the-platform-stability-milestone/"><strong>Android 12 reaches “platform stability” in its fourth beta:</strong></a> That means developers can build for the new Android without worrying about changing code. My real question: When was the last time that you or I got excited about a new mobile OS iteration? Frankly, Windows 11 is more exciting than anything Android or iOS has dropped lately.</li>
<li>And then there was<strong> a whole mess of transport news</strong>. TechCrunch has a review of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/ford-f-150-hybrid-the-2021-rumble-before-the-lightning-ev-strikes/">new hybrid F-150 truck</a>, if you are into moving things. We also have news that Hyzon Motors has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/hyzon-motors-has-begun-shipping-hydrogen-fuel-cell-trucks-to-customers/">started shipping hydrogen fuel cell trucks</a>, which is pretty cool. Amazon’s $1.5 billion cargo hub <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/amazons-1-5-billion-u-s-air-cargo-hub-is-open-for-business/">is now up and running</a>, which means faster package deliveries so that you don’t have to walk to buy razors. And <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/joby-aviation-makes-its-public-trading-debut-on-the-nyse/">Joby Aviation has completed its SPAC combination</a>, meaning that the VTOL taxi company is now public.</li>
<li>One more: I am excited to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/a-close-look-at-singapores-thriving-startup-ecosystem/">read this dive into Singapore’s startup scene!</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how these surveys are shaping our coverage, check out this interview Eric Eldon did with Julian Shapiro, “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/the-art-of-startup-storytelling-with-julian-shapiro/">The art of startup storytelling with Julian Shapiro</a>.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oEhjvJXwQb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/the-art-of-startup-storytelling-with-julian-shapiro/">The art of startup storytelling with Julian Shapiro</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The art of startup storytelling with Julian Shapiro&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/the-art-of-startup-storytelling-with-julian-shapiro/embed/#?secret=oEhjvJXwQb" data-secret="oEhjvJXwQb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/daily-crunch-fema-tests-national-emergency-alert-system-for-first-time-since-pandemic-began/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188848</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lordstown will deliver its Endurance truck to &#8216;select early customers&#8217; early next year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/lordstown-will-deliver-its-endurance-truck-to-selected-early-customers-early-next-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/lordstown-will-deliver-its-endurance-truck-to-selected-early-customers-early-next-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 21:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lordstown Motors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188929</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The beleaguered EV startup Lordstown Motors is on track to begin production of its flagship electric truck Endurance, but only select customers will begin to receive vehicles early next year, executives said during a second quarter earnings call. Executives struck a cautious tone in the second-quarter earnings call as they tried to assuage shareholder concerns [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The beleaguered EV startup Lordstown Motors is on track to begin production of its flagship electric truck Endurance, but only select customers will begin to receive vehicles early next year, executives said during a second quarter earnings call.</p>
<p>Executives struck a cautious tone in the second-quarter earnings call as they tried to assuage shareholder concerns and address the near-term realities of bringing its first vehicle to market without any revenue to offset its costs. Lordstown&#8217;s approach, at least this quarter, was to try and reduce operating costs from the previous quarter, helping it offset its increase in capital expenditures.</p>
<p>Lordstown reported a net loss of $108 million, a 13.7% improvement from the first quarter loss of $125 million. Its net losses are more than tenfold higher than the -$7.9 million it reported in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Lordstown cut research and development spending by 17% from the previous quarter to $76.5 million.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, it increased its capital expenditures to $121 million from $53 million in the first quarter. Lordstown also increased its capital expenditure guidance for the year, from $250 million to $275 million to a $375 million to $400 million range, a spike related to its need to prepay for equipment.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2188930" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2188930" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2188930" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-11-at-15.49.08.png" alt="" width="1024" height="461" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-11-at-15.49.08.png 1966w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-11-at-15.49.08.png?resize=150,68 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-11-at-15.49.08.png?resize=300,135 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-11-at-15.49.08.png?resize=768,346 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-11-at-15.49.08.png?resize=680,306 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-11-at-15.49.08.png?resize=1536,692 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-11-at-15.49.08.png?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2188930" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://lordstownmotors.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lordstown Motors <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The decline in R&amp;D expenses was due to declines in purchases of vehicle components, as many of those were acquired in prior quarters, Lordstown interim CFO Becky Long said during an investor call. However, legal expenses were $9 million higher than last quarter, due to costs related to a special committee and a Securities and Exchange Commission investigation over whether Lordstown exaggerated pre-sales. (The fun doesn’t stop there — the company is also <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001759546/000110465921092686/tm218118-5_posam.htm">under investigation</a> by the U.S. Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of New York.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Lordstown was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/troubled-ev-company-lordstown-motors-gets-400m-lifeline-in-stock-sale-agreement/">thrown a life vest</a> earlier this summer, when investment firm Yorkville Advisors agreed to purchase up to $400 million of Lordstown’s shares. The company is “now exploring a variety of other financing options, including non-dilutive private strategic investments and debt,” interim CEO Angela Strand said during an investor call. The company is also still pursuing a loan with the U.S. Department of Energy, Long said during the call.</p>
<p>Although the company said it was still on track to begin production of the Endurance at the end of September, only “select early customers” will begin to receive vehicles in the first quarter of 2022, followed by commercial deliveries in the second quarter. Strand said this deployment plan is to allow fleet customers time to build out charging infrastructure and to manage supply chain challenges.</p>
<p>One thing that distinguishes the company from some of its competitors is its manufacturing plant — a 6.2 million square foot former General Motors plant in Lordstown, Ohio. It’s now looking like the company is exploring different ways to turn a profit off this asset. Strand said “serious discussions” were underway with potential partners to use Lordstown’s facility to manufacture their products, suggesting the company is eager to find additional sources of revenue to offset its mounting expenses. &#8220;This is a critical strategic pivot for us, a decision that we believe will lead to significant new revenue opportunities for Lordstown,&#8221; she said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="usiZzxZcBm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/lordstown-motors-slashes-production-forecast-for-its-electric-pickup/">Lordstown Motors slashes production forecast for its electric pickup</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lordstown Motors slashes production forecast for its electric pickup&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/lordstown-motors-slashes-production-forecast-for-its-electric-pickup/embed/#?secret=usiZzxZcBm" data-secret="usiZzxZcBm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We are exploring multiple partnership constructs,” she added. “That includes contract manufacturing, that includes licensing, in addition to producing our own vehicles,” she added.</p>
<p>The Lordstown executive team has not had a smooth summer. The company announced in June the resignations of both CEO Steve Burns and CFO Julio Rodriguez, who were replaced in an interim capacity by Strand and Roof respectively. Lordstown was founded as an offshoot of Burns’ company Workhorse Group — the same company that said it had sold 11.9 million shares, or nearly three-quarters of its stake, since the beginning of July. The company is actively searching for a CEO and CFO, Strand said.</p>
<p>Lordstown was riding high in late 2020, when it announced its SPAC merger with a value of $1.6 billion. Its shares soared to $31.80 apiece at their 52-week highs. They’ve since plummeted to $5.94.</p>
<p>“We still plan to be first to market, particularly in the commercial fleet space,” Strand said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XaWTf05Niy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/dogs-of-lordstown/">Dogs of Lordstown</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dogs of Lordstown&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/dogs-of-lordstown/embed/#?secret=XaWTf05Niy" data-secret="XaWTf05Niy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/lordstown-will-deliver-its-endurance-truck-to-selected-early-customers-early-next-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188929</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Desktop Metal is acquiring industrial 3D printing company ExOne</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/desktop-metal-is-acquiring-industrial-3d-printing-company-exone/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/desktop-metal-is-acquiring-industrial-3d-printing-company-exone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 21:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Desktop Metal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of its earnings call this week, Desktop Metal announced plans to acquire ExOne. The Pennsylvania-based firm creates a variety of different industrial 3D printers for industries like aerospace, automotive, medical and defense. More recently, we wrote about the company’s portable 3D printing factories, which are effectively mobile additive manufacturing stations built inside of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As part of its earnings call this week, Desktop Metal announced <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210811005852/en">plans to acquire ExOne</a>. The Pennsylvania-based firm creates a variety of different industrial 3D printers for industries like aerospace, automotive, medical and defense. More recently, we wrote about the company’s portable 3D printing factories, which are effectively mobile additive manufacturing stations built inside of shipping containers.</p>
<p>We wrote about ExOne back in February, when the company was granted $1.6 million from the DoD, in hopes of taking the systems out into the field. Each unit contains a 3D scanning station with computer and a variety of different ruggedized industrial machines, including a metal and ceramic printer, curing oven, fiber-reinforced plastic printer and a compression modeling station.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="j3f5sdDqBF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/exone-gets-1-6m-dod-contract-to-build-a-3d-printing-factory-in-shipping-container/">ExOne gets $1.6M DoD contract to build a 3D printing ‘factory’ in shipping container</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ExOne gets $1.6M DoD contract to build a 3D printing ‘factory’ in shipping container&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/exone-gets-1-6m-dod-contract-to-build-a-3d-printing-factory-in-shipping-container/embed/#?secret=j3f5sdDqBF" data-secret="j3f5sdDqBF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“Over the last two years, we’ve really focused on providing our technology into government-type applications: DoD, NASA, DoE,” ExOne’s CEO John Hartner told TechCrunch when that news broke. “Sometimes people talk about disrupting the supply chain and getting decentralized manufacturing. This is decentralized and forward-deployed, if you will. Be it an emergency, humanitarian mission or frontlines for a war fighter.”</p>
<p>Today’s transaction, which is valued at $575 million, finds Desktop Metal purchasing all of ExOne’s common stock.</p>
<p>“We are thrilled to bring ExOne into the DM family to create the leading additive manufacturing portfolio for mass production,” Desktop Metal CEO Ric Fulop said in a release. “We believe this acquisition will provide customers with more choice as we leverage our complementary technologies and go-to-market efforts to drive continued growth. This transaction is a big step in delivering on our vision of accelerating the adoption of additive manufacturing 2.0.”</p>
<p>Desktop Metal has been actively pursuing acquisitions to grow out its 3D printing portfolio since it announced plans to go public via SPAC last August. In January, it acquired EnvisionTEC for $300 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We are excited to join forces with Desktop Metal to deliver a more sustainable future through our shared vision of additive manufacturing at high production volumes,” Hartner said of today&#8217;s announcement. “We believe our complementary platforms will better serve customers, accelerate adoption of green technologies, and drive increased shareholder value. Most importantly, our technologies will help drive important innovations at meaningful production volumes that can improve the world.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EZWC3GfQ9I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/desktop-metal-buys-fellow-3d-printing-company-envisiontec-for-300m/">Desktop Metal buys fellow 3D printing company EnvisionTEC for $300M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Desktop Metal buys fellow 3D printing company EnvisionTEC for $300M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/desktop-metal-buys-fellow-3d-printing-company-envisiontec-for-300m/embed/#?secret=EZWC3GfQ9I" data-secret="EZWC3GfQ9I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mDDtmF6Kkd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/06/as-covid-19-surges-3d-printing-is-having-a-moment/">As COVID-19 surges, 3D printing is having a moment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As COVID-19 surges, 3D printing is having a moment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/06/as-covid-19-surges-3d-printing-is-having-a-moment/embed/#?secret=mDDtmF6Kkd" data-secret="mDDtmF6Kkd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/desktop-metal-is-acquiring-industrial-3d-printing-company-exone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188935</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
