<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 13:18:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Castiron serves up a $6M seed round to support &#8216;food artisans&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/castiron-serves-up-a-6m-seed-round-to-support-food-artisans/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/castiron-serves-up-a-6m-seed-round-to-support-food-artisans/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 13:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bit.ly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bowery capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Josephson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic hasn&#8217;t been easy for anyone, but the food service industry has been hit particularly hard. More than 90,000 restaurants and bars have closed, leaving workers unemployed in an already precarious industry. And those who kept their jobs faced the stressful demands of customer-facing work in a pandemic. In response to the changed industry [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The pandemic hasn&#8217;t been easy for anyone, but the food service industry has been hit <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/aliciakelso/2022/01/14/most-independent-restaurants-experienced-a-sales-decrease-of-more-than-50-in-december/?sh=6404cf885fa8">particularly hard</a>. More than <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/GMA/Food/omicrons-affect-restaurant-industry-shows-dire-restaurant-relief/story?id=82248396">90,000 restaurants</a> and bars have closed, leaving workers unemployed in an already precarious industry. And those who kept their jobs faced the stressful demands of customer-facing work in a pandemic.</p>
<p>In response to the changed industry landscape, food service veterans are launching their own businesses, whether they&#8217;re delivering take-out meals in their neighborhood or mailing cans of kombucha around the country. &#8220;People tell them that they make great cakes, or that their sourdough is better than everybody else&#8217;s, or their hot sauce is amazing,&#8221; explained Castiron founder and CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/markjosephson/">Mark Josephson</a>. &#8220;And they dream of selling and building a business, but they end up spending 75% of their time on things other than what they&#8217;re good at.&#8221; He&#8217;s talking about everything that isn&#8217;t cooking: building a website, keeping track of finances and other administrative tasks.</p>
<p>So, he created <a href="http://castiron.me">Castiron</a>, an e-commerce solution for independent chefs. Today, Castiron announced a $6 million seed funding round today from Bowery Capital, Foundry Group and High Alpha. A veteran of the tech industry, Josephson is a three-time CEO &#8212; he previously helmed outside.in, which sold to AOL, later leading Bit.ly for seven years &#8212; but Castiron is the first company he&#8217;s founded.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258304" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Launched in October, Castiron provides its users (which it calls &#8220;food artisans&#8221;) with customizable e-commerce websites, which include dynamic inventory management, order fulfillment tools, newsletter and marketing tools and more. Castiron doesn&#8217;t start making money until the food artisan makes money &#8212; then, the platform takes 10%, plus a standard 2.9% + $0.30 payment processing fee.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2258311" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/castiron-2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="394" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/castiron-2.png 4768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/castiron-2.png?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/castiron-2.png?resize=300,174 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/castiron-2.png?resize=768,445 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/castiron-2.png?resize=680,394 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/castiron-2.png?resize=1536,889 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/castiron-2.png?resize=2048,1186 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/castiron-2.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;In deciding to start this company, it was important to me after having done five, six or seven different startups that with this one, we were truly aligned with our customers. So I only want to be successful if our customers are successful,&#8221; he told TechCrunch. &#8220;Our customers are risk averse, so it&#8217;s important that we have a no-risk product for customers to try.&#8221;</p>
<p>Right now, Castiron only operates in the United States, where laws pertaining to home food businesses (cottage food laws) vary from state to state. But given the increasing rate of unemployment since the onset of the pandemic, many states have <a href="https://www.pewtrusts.org/en/research-and-analysis/blogs/stateline/2021/10/29/pandemic-prompts-officials-to-relax-rules-on-home-businesses">made it easier</a> to legally run independent food businesses. Currently, Josephson estimates that about 40% of Castiron&#8217;s users run local delivery businesses, 40% sell products for pickup, and 20% ship their goods out. He said that &#8220;several hundred&#8221; users have set up shop on Castiron, but that this seed round will help fund a hiring push to scale the business.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;This push of entrepreneurs who are building small businesses is a huge part of our economy going forward,&#8221; Josephson noted. &#8220;I&#8217;ve been in media, digital media, software marketing, and there&#8217;s nothing like this. And like, honestly, I have boxes of chocolate chip cookies, and roasted coffee beans, and biscotti, and sourdough, and hot sauce showing up at my house. It&#8217;s like, what&#8217;s what&#8217;s wrong with that? What could be better?&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/castiron-serves-up-a-6m-seed-round-to-support-food-artisans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258304</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Faeth Therapeutics closes $20M seed to turn nutrition into a pillar of cancer treatment</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/faeth-therapeutics-closes-20m-seed-to-turn-nutrition-into-a-pillar-of-cancer-treatment/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/faeth-therapeutics-closes-20m-seed-to-turn-nutrition-into-a-pillar-of-cancer-treatment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chemotherapy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nutrition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oncology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tumor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A hot bowl of pad thai simmers in front of you. The taste and texture is exactly what you might expect from a quick takeout dinner, but it&#8217;s not just a meal – it’s medicine.  This hypothetical bowl of pad thai, would be part of a cancer-fighting regimen created by startup Faeth Therapeutics. The meal [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A hot bowl of pad thai simmers in front of you. The taste and texture is exactly what you might expect from a quick takeout dinner, but it&#8217;s not just a meal – it’s medicine. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This hypothetical bowl of pad thai, would be part of a cancer-fighting regimen created by startup Faeth Therapeutics. The meal itself would be specifically tailored to “starve your tumor” (which has been genetically scrutinized by scientists already), and work in combination with established cancer drugs and therapies. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This “precision nutrition” approach to cancer treatment is admittedly  new, but Faeth therapeutics, founded in 2019, is hoping to be the first to bring this approach into the clinic. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What really led to the founding of the company is three independent groups of world class scientists, each realizing that we were basically ignoring a massive part of human biology and the treatment of cancer,” Anand Parikh, founder and CEO of Faeth Therapeutics tells TechCrunch. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258591" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I jokingly call this the Manhattan Project of cancer biology. They were each approaching this problem differently, but  landed on this idea that we have to change nutrition for cancer patients in order to not only potentiate existing therapeutics, but also to help develop new ones that target these nutrient vulnerabilities.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.faeththerapeutics.com/">Faeth Therapeutics</a> announced a $20 million seed round on Tuesday</span><b>. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">This represents the 15-person company’s first round of external financing. The round was co-led by Khosla Ventures and Future Ventures. It also includes participation from S2G Ventures, Digitalis, KdT Ventures, Agfunder, Cantos and Unshackled. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the first things to notice about Faeth Therapeutics is the scientific team behind it. Faeth’s cofounders include: </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Siddhartha Mukherjee, author of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Emperor of All Maladies </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(winner of a <a href="https://www.pulitzer.org/winners/siddhartha-mukherjee">2011 Pulitzer Prize for General Nonfiction</a>) and an oncologist at Columbia University; Lewis Cantley, director of Weill Cornell’s Meyer Cancer Center and discoverer of the PI3K signaling pathway, and Karen Vousden, Chief Scientist of Cancer Research UK, and Group Leader at the Francis Crick Institute. Vousden is known for her work on the p53 tumor suppressor protein. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cantley and </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nrc2715"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vousden</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in particular, have been some of the first to deeply probe the connection between metabolism and cancer treatment. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nrclinonc.2018.28"><span style="font-weight: 400;">PI3K</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a cell signaling pathway that affects cell metabolism, growth, survival and proliferation, but is often dysregulated in cancer patients. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are drugs that look to target this pathway, however Cantley’s work suggests that some patients end up with hyperglycemia, which might end up triggering this dysregulated pathway anyway. Instead, he has shown that lowering insulin levels through </span><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6197057/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">dietary interventions</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> can help avoid that re-activation, and aid the drug&#8217;s performance. For example, </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-018-0343-4"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a mouse study</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> published in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nature</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> showed that placing mice on a keto diet (low-carb, high fat) could reduce glycogen stores and prevent spikes that might be hampering the drug’s effectiveness.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So far, the preclinical research has been intermittently promising, but still requires a lot more work (as Mukherjee <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/05/magazine/its-time-to-study-whether-eating-particular-diets-can-help-heal-us.html">notes</a> in his own op-ed describing Cantley’s work).</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> But Parikh notes that there’s still a lot of room to improve this research, and approach nutrition based medicine in a more targeted way. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think what a lot of people have done is say: keto diet, glioblastoma, let’s go. But there’s a layer deeper than that,” he says. [Note: the keto diet has also <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6589986/">been deployed</a> in certain glioblastoma cases]. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“If a person has pancreatic cancer, we&#8217;ve figured out that the way that a pancreatic tumor works, you may have higher needs for certain nutrients. In this case, maybe amino acids. And what we do is we create diets that are depleted in those particular amino acids.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A big part of Faeth’s mission, adds Parikh, is to use this funding to expand and deepen research in this area. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nutrition and health are clearly linked, and nutrition </span><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5181206/#:~:text=Conclusion%3A%20Adherence%20to%20a%20high,overall%20mortality%20in%20this%20population."><span style="font-weight: 400;">does have an impact</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on cancer outcomes. But this is an area of research that can draw some well-deserved skepticism. When it comes to diet and health, it can be easy to fall from scientific fact, into myth territory pretty easily. Critically, this research isn’t touting a “miracle diet” or a “diet-based cure” for cancer. Rather the company is aiming to interrogate how nutrition can become a “fifth pillar” of cancer care through scientific study. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Faith is already gearing up three trials that will look to interrogate the connection emerging from preclinical research.  </span><a href="http://v"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A metastatic pancreatic cancer trial combining</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a reduced amino acid diet with a gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">chemotherapy regimen is in development. The company also </span><a href="https://www.clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05183295?term=Faeth+Therapeutics&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">has another trial</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> aimed at metastatic colorectal cancer. Finally, a trial on insulin-suppressing diets will be posted on clinicaltrials.gov in the coming weeks, per Parikh. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Should the connection prove powerful enough to warrant a treatment, Parikh imagines a version of cancer care where high quality meals (like the aforementioned Pad Thai) and cancer drugs can work together to achieve better outcomes. A patient would still go through radiotherapy or chemotherapy, but go home and have doctor-prescribed meals delivered to their door (Parikh adds that the meals have been developed by “world-class chefs). Then, the patient would follow up with a nutritionist if concerns arise. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But for now, Parikh says the focus will be almost entirely on bringing this research into the clinical stage.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They&#8217;ve done as much work as they possibly can pre-clinically and so we&#8217;ve raised this round to move into the clinic. And we&#8217;re doing early stage trials to confirm safety, obviously, but also see whether there&#8217;s a signal of efficacy as well,” he says. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/faeth-therapeutics-closes-20m-seed-to-turn-nutrition-into-a-pillar-of-cancer-treatment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258591</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How one founder is building a sustainable platform for proactive mental health care</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/how-one-founder-is-building-a-sustainable-platform-for-proactive-mental-health-care/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/how-one-founder-is-building-a-sustainable-platform-for-proactive-mental-health-care/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 12:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote theray]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[therapy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week Darrell and Jordan talk with Real CEO and Founder, Ariela Safira. Real is a therapy platform that aims to make mental healthcare more accessible by offering group sessions and curriculums a user can engage with any time. While in college, Ariela had her first encounter with the mental health care system and realized [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This week Darrell and Jordan talk with Real CEO and Founder, Ariela Safira. Real is a therapy platform that aims to make mental healthcare more accessible by offering group sessions and curriculums a user can engage with any time. While in college, Ariela had her first encounter with the mental health care system and realized that people were only seeking help for their mental health when they were in crisis. She then spent years studying the ways people seek care and how therapy could be more accessible and effective. In this conversation as they dive into everything from the research that lead her to found Real to religion to the merits of Goop. CW: suicide and attempted suicide.</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwCotybrbEFX8yli-thpevQ4E4rLOtITXUQl6htZpoTguSiA/viewform">Take our listener survey</a> and let us know a bit about yourself and what you think of FOUND.</p>
<p>Links from the episode:</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258727" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/real-raises-10m-from-lightspeed-megan-rapinoe-and-others-to-rethink-therapy/">Jordan&#8217;s TechCrunch Article</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.join-real.com/">Real </a></li>
</ul>
<p>Connect with us:</p>
<ul>
<li>On<a href="https://twitter.com/found"> Twitter</a></li>
<li>On<a href="https://www.instagram.com/foundpod/"> Instagram</a></li>
<li>Via email: found@techcrunch.com</li>
<li>Call us and leave a voicemail at (510) 936-1618</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/c0d6bf82-910d-4212-b61f-27abe823470b?dark=false&amp;show=true" width="100%" height="480px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/how-one-founder-is-building-a-sustainable-platform-for-proactive-mental-health-care/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258727</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wayve raises $200M Series B led by Eclipse for its AI for autonomous delivery vehicles</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/wayve-raises-200m-series-b-led-by-eclipse-for-its-ai-for-autonomous-delivery-vehicles/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/wayve-raises-200m-series-b-led-by-eclipse-for-its-ai-for-autonomous-delivery-vehicles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 12:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baillie Gifford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Balderton Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D1 Capital Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eclipse Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moore Strategic Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pieter abbeel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard branson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wayve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yann LeCun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[British autonomous vehicle startup Wayve has raised a $200 million Series B funding round from investors to scale its technology and expand its partnerships with commercial fleets. Wayve is aiming to be a major player in the arena of Robo-deliveries and logistics. It’s now raised a total of $258 million to date, for its technology, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">British autonomous vehicle startup Wayve has raised a $200 million Series B funding round from investors to scale its technology and expand its partnerships with commercial fleets. Wayve is aiming to be a major player in the arena of Robo-deliveries and logistics.</p>
<p>It’s now raised a total of $258 million to date, for its technology, which relies largely on commodity video cameras around the vehicle tied to on-vehicle AI-driven software, making it highly responsive to its surroundings as it relies less on being connected to 4 or 5G networks.</p>
<p>Eclipse Ventures, a previous investor, led the round. Other participating investors include D1 Capital Partners, Baillie Gifford, Moore Strategic Ventures and Linse Capital, as well as Microsoft and Virgin, and early-stage investors Compound and Balderton Capital. They join strategic investor Ocado Group and angel investors including Sir Richard Branson, Rosemary Leith, Linda Levinson, David Richter, Pieter Abbeel, and Yann LeCun.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258733" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Wayve CEO Alex Kendall says Wayve’s test vehicles have managed to successfully negotiate not only London but also cities its vehicles have never been to previously. Given UK streets are typically medieval in layout, this is no mean feat.</p>
<p>Ocado, the UK online grocery technology company, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/wayve-the-lidar-free-self-driving-startup-raises-13-6m-from-ocado/">previously invested</a> $13.6 million in Wayve and entered into an autonomous delivery trial with the startup, as has British supermarket chain Asda.</p>
<p>Wayve says its AV2.0 technology is designed specifically for fleet operators, combining a camera-first approach with an embedded AI that continually learns from driving data provided by Wayve&#8217;s other partner fleets. The startup&#8217;s view is that this makes it a more scalable AV platform than so-called “AV1,0” which requires lots of input from data outside the vehicle like traffic reports, street maps and a complex array of sensors.</p>
<p>Seth Winterroth, Partner, Eclipse Ventures said: “As the industry struggles to solve self-driving with traditional robotics, it is becoming increasingly clear that AV2.0 is the right pathway to build a scalable driving intelligence that can help commercial fleet operators deploy autonomy faster.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Speaking to TechCrunch Kendall added: “I think this funding round is a signal from the market that we are transitioning from proving out the core technology to now having earned the right to scale and be commercially deployed. When we started the business in 2017, that was the peak hype cycle point of autonomous vehicles, with billions of dollars already invested. Everyone thought it was a year away.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;And to go and build a contrarian startup to compete against trillion dollar tech giants might have been a little bit crazy. But the proof points have allowed us to move to this next level of scale. This is our ability to test in multiple cities. The fact that we&#8217;ve trained a system in London, and gone UK wide in Manchester Coventry, Leeds, Liverpool, all over the UK. Plus all these commercial partners and the incredible talent that we&#8217;ve been able to attract to our team,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/wayve-raises-200m-series-b-led-by-eclipse-for-its-ai-for-autonomous-delivery-vehicles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258733</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pinwheel raises $50M Series B at $500M valuation for its income verification APIs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/pinwheel-raises-50m-series-b-at-500m-valuation-for-its-income-verification-apis/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/pinwheel-raises-50m-series-b-at-500m-valuation-for-its-income-verification-apis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anita Ramaswamy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amex Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anish Basu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Curtis Lee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earned wage access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Round Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Franklin Templeton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ggv capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[income]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kurt Lin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pinwheel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teacher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upfront ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venmo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wells Fargo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Six months after its $20 million Series A, payroll connectivity platform Pinwheel just announced that it has nabbed another $50 million in a round led by new investor GGV Capital.  Pinwheel serves neobanks and fintechs like Block, Acorns, and Current by providing application programming interfaces (APIs) linked to payroll, income, and employment data. Historically, systems [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Six months after its </span><a href="https://www.finextra.com/pressarticle/87907/pinwheel-raises-20m-series-a-for-payroll-connectivity"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$20 million Series A</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, payroll connectivity platform Pinwheel just announced that it has nabbed another $50 million in a round led by new investor GGV Capital. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.pinwheelapi.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pinwheel</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> serves neobanks and fintechs like Block, Acorns, and Current by providing application programming interfaces (APIs) linked to payroll, income, and employment data. Historically, systems for providing such data are inefficient and clunky, a problem Pinwheel’s cofounders recognized when they were working on a startup that helped companies provide pre-tax benefits to their employees. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kurt Lin, Anish Basu, and Curtis Lee, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/pinwheel-is-the-api-platform-for-income-verification-that-every-fintech-and-neobank-needs/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">who met through prior work experiences</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, ran into a roadblock in implementing their original solution because they found they had difficulty connecting to payroll systems. That’s when they decided to pivot into building an API to solve this problem at a large scale instead, Lin told TechCrunch in an interview.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258581" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s APIs allow its customers to access more robust information about individuals’ payroll and employment, in part because they track “non-traditional” sources of income like payments made through gig platforms like Uber or apps like Venmo, Lin said. Its flagship products include direct-deposit switching, income and employment data, and paycheck-linked lending, and the data it aggregates spans nearly 80% of people employed in the United States, according to the company. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pinwheel’s customers can use this information for a range of applications – from offering earned wage access to employees, which allows them to access money as soon as they’ve earned it rather than waiting for a paycheck to be deposited in their bank account, to enabling paycheck-linked loans, which are considered less risky than traditional unsecured loans that require borrowers to make a voluntary bank transfer to repay the funds.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite competition from other players in the somewhat-crowded payroll API space, Pinwheel has demonstrated significant traction in the market and hopes to differentiate itself by building an entire “income layer” of data for its customers that extends beyond just payroll information. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its platform executes over 4.6 million processes per month, a 400x increase from last year, and the company leads its market in customer conversion rates, the company says. Pinwheel grew its annual recurring revenue by 177x in 2021, according to the company, though Lin declined to share any further detail on its historical or current revenue numbers.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lin said its success can be attributed to three key factors – commercial traction, an experienced team, and a mission-driven approach focused on “improving financial outcomes for customers who don’t have access to affordable financial products.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“One of our customers, for example, may be a teacher or a nurse who may be in the same job for five or six years, may have a FICO [credit score] of 550, and thus be declined from any affordable financial product. We can actually show that their income stability is totally there, they&#8217;ve been employed for a long time, and they&#8217;re actually going to perform much better [in repaying a loan],” Lin said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pinwheel has hired a number of its employees from $13.4 billion API company Plaid, known for enabling bank account connectivity for fintechs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We&#8217;re the only player that has actually been able to not just take one or two [hires from Plaid], but we actually have a number of former employees on our team. Our VP of engineering came from Plaid, our head of commercial came from Plaid, a lot of the core engineers were actually building the platform at Plaid as well. We have all this institutional knowledge of how to do this the right way, which has really allowed us to outperform our competition because of having those folks on the team,” Lin said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pinwheel is also the only company providing direct deposit switching and payroll data that is classified as a Consumer Reporting Agency (CRA) in compliance with the Fair Credit Reporting Act, meaning that if consumers are adversely affected by Pinwheel’s data, the company would be legally accountable. While operating as a regulated CRA requires a “herculean amount of work,” it shows that Pinwheel is willing to “stand behind the integrity of [its] data,” Lin said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A number of strategic investors also backed Pinwheel for the first time in the Series B round, including AMEX Ventures (American Express’s VC arm), Indeed, Kraken Ventures, Franklin Templeton. Existing investors Coatue, First Round Capital, and Upfront Ventures, participated as well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pinwheel plans to use the fresh funds to triple its 70-person employee base, two-thirds of whom are engineers. Although the team will stay engineering-heavy because of the technical nature of its API-focused business, Pinwheel also plans to make some hires to advance its go-to-market strategy, revenue expansion, and marketing presence, Lin said. It eventually plans to expand into areas like tax preparation by helping companies leverage its income data in new ways, Lin said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just after Pinwheel first came out of stealth mode in June 2020, the company received over 130 inbound messages from big banks like Wells Fargo and Citi, as well as a number of major fintechs, Lin said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It was kind of this lightbulb moment for us because we realized that the platform that we&#8217;re building is basically like a growth engine for all of consumer finance,” Lin said. “Whether you are a new digital bank, whether you are a PFM [personal finance management company], whether you are a new tax product, or a bank, or a lender who just needs better data for underwriting, there is something in the building blocks of our platform that actually allows you to build not just what you want to do now, but the future of your roadmap for 5-10 years from now.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/pinwheel-raises-50m-series-b-at-500m-valuation-for-its-income-verification-apis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258581</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Permiso emerges from stealth with $10M to tackle the next wave of cloud security</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/permiso-stealth-cloud-security/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/permiso-stealth-cloud-security/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 12:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Databricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FireEye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foundation capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palo alto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Point72 Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2257939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Permiso, a Palo Alto-based startup that provides cloud identity detection and response for cloud infrastructures, has launched from stealth with $10 million in seed funding. The company, founded by former FireEye executives Paul Nguyen and Jason Martin, joins an influx of cloud security startups that have emerged since the start of the pandemic, which saw [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Permiso, a Palo Alto-based startup that provides cloud identity detection and response for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/cloud-infrastructure/">cloud infrastructures</a>, has launched from stealth with $10 million in seed funding.</p>
<p>The company, founded by former <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/fireeye/">FireEye</a> executives Paul Nguyen and Jason Martin, joins an influx of cloud security startups that have emerged since the start of the pandemic, which saw organizations rush to digitize their operations to support employees working from home.</p>
<p>While arguably 18 months late to a now already-crowded market, Nguyen and Martin believe their detection response product is ready for the next wave of cloud security. The idea was inspired by conversations with Permiso’s angel investors, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/netflix/">Netflix</a>, who said that their number one problem in the cloud was identity.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2257939" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“We started to realize that identity is the lynchpin that tells that story of what’s happening in your cloud, and it’s also the foundation for how you build detection in the cloud,” Nguyen tells TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Permiso provides organizations with visibility for identities in their cloud infrastructure to give real-time insights into who is in the environment and what they are doing. This, the startup claims, allows for simple and efficient attribution of access, activity, and changes occurring in monitored environments, helping organizations to spot malicious or anomalous behaviors that could indicate compromised credentials, policy violations, or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/10/insider-threats-startups-protect/">insider threats</a>.</p>
<p>“We’re a little ahead of the market,&#8221; Martin said. &#8220;No one, as far as we’re aware, other than the custom products that cloud-forward companies build for themselves, is focused on anchoring all activity around identity, the resources in that environment, and how they interact.”</p>
<p>Permiso is billed as “built by experts, usable by non-experts”, which the startup says is key given the growing skills shortage in the cloud security market. “When we looked at teams that were transitioning from on-prem[ise] to the cloud, it was like speaking English and trying to learn Farsi as a completely new language. It’s starting from zero” said Nguyen.</p>
<p>“We built for 1% of the market for years, but that gets you 1% of the market. Now we’re going after the 99%.&#8221;</p>
<p>The startup’s $10 million seed round was led by <a href="https://www.google.com/search?client=safari&amp;rls=en&amp;q=Point72+Ventures+techcrunch&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;oe=UTF-8">Point72 Ventures</a> and included Foundation Capital, Work-Bench, 11.2 Capital, Rain Capital. It was also backed by a number of security industry leaders, including Jason Chan, former VP of Information Security at Netflix; Travis McPeak, head of Product Security at Databricks; and Tyler Shields, CMO at JupiterOne.</p>
<p>Permiso will use the funds to triple its current 15-person team and expand its current customer footprint.</p>
<p>“Our investors have all solved this identity problem at scale in cloud-native problems, but other companies won’t get to this point for another year or two,&#8221; said Martin.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dRHifQTlTu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/were-still-just-scratching-the-surface-of-the-clouds-potential/">We&#8217;re still just scratching the surface of the cloud&#8217;s potential</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;We&#8217;re still just scratching the surface of the cloud&#8217;s potential&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/were-still-just-scratching-the-surface-of-the-clouds-potential/embed/#?secret=dRHifQTlTu" data-secret="dRHifQTlTu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/permiso-stealth-cloud-security/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2257939</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Verana Health closes $150M to glean more detail from electronic health records</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/verana-health-closes-150m-to-glean-more-detail-from-electronic-health-records/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/verana-health-closes-150m-to-glean-more-detail-from-electronic-health-records/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 11:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronic health records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical imaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural language processing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2257775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Verana Health, a company focused on collecting and organizing troves of medical data, announced a $150 million Series E funding round on Friday. This round comes as the company sets its sights on new types of medical data, invests in organizing traditionally messy forms of information (like physician notes) and aims to extract more usable [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Verana Health, a company focused on collecting and organizing troves of medical data, announced a $150 million Series E funding round on Friday. This round comes as the company sets its sights on new types of medical data, invests in organizing traditionally messy forms of information (like physician notes) and aims to extract more usable insights from Electronic Health Records (EHRs). </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.veranahealth.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Verana Health</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/verana-health-aims-to-organize-and-analyze-doctors-clinical-data-sets-whether-patients-like-it-or-not/"> organizes and analyzes</a> electronic health record systems run by three professional organizations: The American Academy of Ophthalmology, The American Academy of Neurology, and The American Urological Association. Then, it delivers insight back to practitioners, researchers, and life sciences companies. Since its founding in 2018, Verana has become an exclusive data management partner for these professional networks, CEO Sujay Jadhav tells TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This current round was led by Johnson &amp; Johnson Innovation, and Novo Growth. Existing investors GV (formerly Google Ventures), Casdin Capital, and Brook Byers joined the round. New investors include Merck Global Health Innovation Fund, THVC, and Breyer Capital. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2257775" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the moment, Verana focuses on three major disease areas: ophthalmology, neurology, and urology. From there, says Jadhav, Verana provides two pillar products. There’s VeraQ a </span><a href="https://www.veranahealth.com/verana-health-launches-veraq-qdata/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“population health engine”</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> encompassing 90 million patients and data spanning seven years and Qdata, which can link existing data with information from other sources (like insurance claims or medical imaging, more on that later), and provide data sets designed for specific, observational studies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A fair question to ask of any company looking to provide data-driven insights is: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What insights are you providing, exactly? </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jadhav provides a few examples. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For instance, the company recently worked with a startup looking to conduct a study on a rare disease not typically captured in ICD-10 billing codes. Verana used natural language processing and manual curation to scan through patient symptoms and procedure history to help identify clinics that might have enough patients with the condition to participate. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the commercial side of things, another client has used Verana to monitor the post-approval safety and uptake of medical products. Verana helped by analyzing treatment patterns and the demographics of who used the product, looking for safety signals. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Whenever health records are in the picture patient privacy is paramount. <span style="font-weight: 400;">Jadhav notes that all patient information is de-identified. “We have a very clear delineation internally. So, 27 people have access to identifiable data, we then we de-identify it and whatever we provide to the pharma sector etc is always de-identified as well,” he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">De-identified health records are already used to conduct research. EHR analysis, for instance, has facilitated </span><a href="https://www.cell.com/med/fulltext/S2666-6340(21)00237-3"><span style="font-weight: 400;">studies</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on the real-world safety and effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines extremely quickly. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, experts have also </span><a href="https://hai.stanford.edu/news/de-identifying-medical-patient-data-doesnt-protect-our-privacy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised concerns</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that de-identified data could be “re-identified” through a combination of machine learning or combination with other datasets. For instance, a </span><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2719130"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2018 study</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">JAMA Health Policy </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">argued that this was possible with physical activity data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jadhav says that patients can opt-out of data sharing at any point in the process. Though, the most straightforward approach seems to be at the doctor’s office level. For instance, </span><a href="https://www.aao.org/iris-registry/requirements"><span style="font-weight: 400;">you can ask your ophthalmologist</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, in writing, to not share EHR data with IRIS (the dataset provided by the American Academy of Ophthalmology), if you choose. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the moment, Verana&#8217;s dataset is largely centered around these patient registries. However, the company is already investing in both gleaning </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">more </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">from these records, and integrating other types of data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For instance, Verana is using natural language processing techniques to extract themes from physician notes that don’t fit into most data structures. (Keep in mind </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-75544-1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">de-identifying textual data in EHR records</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is an area of active reach in and of itself.) But for certain disease areas, Jadhav notes that these physician notes are a big untapped resource: </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In certain therapeutic areas, such as urology, we are finding that there is some structured data there. [But] a lot of the value is around unstructured data. More specifically around physician notes.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company has also integrated insurance claims data, and has developed a technique to integrate imaging data. For instance, the company </span><a href="https://iovs.arvojournals.org/article.aspx?articleid=2775387"><span style="font-weight: 400;">published an abstract</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on an algorithm that was able to match IRIS EHRs and imaging data with 83 percent accuracy. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With this current round Verana is aiming to “fuel current growth” using their current business model, per Jadhav. But it also has some specific plans laid out. The company aims to enhance the quality of analysis they can already provide, scale-up clinical trial insights, as well as fund natural language processing projects. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This round brings the company’s total funding to $280 million. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/verana-health-closes-150m-to-glean-more-detail-from-electronic-health-records/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2257775</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Score another win for Istanbul gaming startups: Dream Games raises $255M at a $2.75B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/score-another-win-for-istanbul-gaming-startups-dream-games-raises-255m-at-a-2-75b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/score-another-win-for-istanbul-gaming-startups-dream-games-raises-255m-at-a-2-75b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 11:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258716</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yet more funding is finding its way to Istanbul&#8217;s gaming startups. Today, Dream Games &#8212; the casual games developer behind the hit game Royal Match &#8212; is announcing a $255 million Series C that values the startup at $2.75 billion. This Series C is being led by Index Ventures, with Makers Fund, IVP, funds and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Yet more funding is finding its way to Istanbul&#8217;s gaming startups. Today, <a href="https://dreamgames.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dream Games</a> &#8212; the casual games developer behind the hit game Royal Match &#8212; is announcing a $255 million Series C that values the startup at $2.75 billion.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">This Series C is being led by Index Ventures, with Makers Fund, IVP, funds and accounts managed by BlackRock, Kora and Balderton Capital also participating. The funding will be used both to continue investing in and developing Royal Match, and to work on its next launch, which is expected later this year. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The funding underscores a few important trends: we are seeing a very heated pace of competition in this space right now; games (and especially casual games) are really coming into their own when it comes to venture funding and adopting the growth and approach of startups; and maybe most importantly for this story: investors are very keen on getting in on the action. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258716" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Today&#8217;s news comes</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> just six months after Dream Games raised </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/dream-games-raises-155m-at-a-1b-valuation-as-its-royal-match-puzzle-game-hits-a-royal-flush/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$155 million at a $1 billion valuation</a> (that round was led by Index and Makers Fund)<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, and one day after another Istanbul games startup, Spyke, announced a </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/turkeys-spyke-raises-55m-in-a-seed-round-to-bring-a-social-twist-to-casual-mobile-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$55 million seed round</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">. </span></p>
<p>Dream and Spyke share some DNA: both are founded by people who were either founders or senior members of the team at Peak Games, another gaming startup that was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/01/zynga-acquires-turkeys-peak-games-for-1-8b-after-buying-its-card-games-studio-for-100m-in-2017/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired</a> by Zynga in 2020 for $1.8 billion.</p>
<p>Royal Match is currently one of the highest grossing mobile games on the market. It will be worth watching to see how and if Dream Games follows it up. From what the company has said in the past, and today, those follow ups might not necessarily come in the form of more games in rapid succession, but in extending the franchises that are already successful and spacing out new developments over periods of years with less pressure to produce new titles over months.</p>
<p>“We believe in Pixar’s approach,” co-founder and CEO Soner Aydemir said in an interview in June. “When Pixar started, it was very low frequency, a movie every 2-3 years but eventually the rate increased. And it will be similar for us. This year we need to focus on Royal Match but if we can find a way to create other games, we will.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">As with Spyke&#8217;s view that its big competition might be the TikTok&#8217;s of the world, not just other games developers, so too does Dream eye up the entertainment industry as a bigger competitive threat. Indeed that&#8217;s not just because they too can publish games and build sticky brands, but they are after the same slice of leisure time as Dream among consumers.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Investors are willing to bet here because of Dream Games&#8217; track record in gaining audience so far.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“The success and growth of Royal Match exceeded all of our expectations,” said Stephane Kurgan, the Index Ventures partner who led the investment, and former chief operating officer at King, in a statement. “In eight months, Royal Match has become one of the most played mobile games of 2021. Dream Games has assembled one of the best teams in the industry, with  a rare combination of creative talent, engineering expertise and relentless work ethic. They’ve already shifted the norms around what counts as excellence in mobile gaming, and we’re excited to see where they go next.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/score-another-win-for-istanbul-gaming-startups-dream-games-raises-255m-at-a-2-75b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258716</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China&#8217;s digital yuan wallet now has 260 million individual users</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/chinas-digital-yuan-wallet-now-has-260-million-individual-users/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/chinas-digital-yuan-wallet-now-has-260-million-individual-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 10:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alipay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mybank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People's Bank of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shenzhen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeBank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeChat Pay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yuan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the fastest-growing apps in China right now, by installs, is the central bank&#8217;s digital yuan wallet. 261 million individual users (as opposed to enterprises), about one-fifth of the population, have set up e-CNY wallets so far, and 87.5 billion yuan ($13.78 billion) worth of transactions has been made using the digital fiat currency, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">One of the fastest-growing apps in China right now, by installs, is the central bank&#8217;s digital yuan wallet. 261 million individual users (as opposed to enterprises), about one-fifth of the population, have set up e-CNY wallets so far, and 87.5 billion yuan ($13.78 billion) worth of transactions has been made using the digital fiat currency, Zou Lan, head of financial markets at the People&#8217;s Bank of China (PBOC), <a href="http://m.thepaper.cn/rss_newsDetail_16337430?from=sohu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> at a <a href="http://www.scio.gov.cn/xwfbh/xwbfbh/wqfbh/47673/47730/index.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">press event</a> on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Over the past two years, China has been piloting the use of digital yuan in a number of major cities, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/11/china-digital-yuan-shenzhen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shenzhen</a>. People needed to enter a draw and apply to be early users in the beginning. Then at the start of 2022, in a clear sign of accelerating the trial, the PBOC made the e-CNY wallet available on the iOS and Android stores in China.</p>
<p>The digital yuan is by no means a manifestation of cryptocurrency, which is banned in China. The PBOC has <a href="http://www.pbc.gov.cn/en/3688110/3688172/4157443/4293696/2021071614584691871.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">deemed</a> bitcoin and the likes highly volatile, speculative, lacking intrinsic value, and pointed out that cryptocurrencies could be an instrument of money-laundering.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258708" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The e-CNY aspires to achieve different results. Issued by the central bank, it serves as the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/11/china-digital-yuan-shenzhen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statutory, digital version of China&#8217;s cash in circulation</a>, or &#8220;M0&#8221;; indeed, the regulator intends to make e-yuan payments <a href="http://www.pbc.gov.cn/en/3688110/3688172/4157443/4293696/2021071614584691871.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">work even without the internet</a>, using NFC technology.</p>
<p>According to a research paper <a href="http://www.pbc.gov.cn/en/3688110/3688172/4157443/4293696/2021071614584691871.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published</a> by the Working Group on e-CNY Research and Development at the central bank last year, the digital yuan aims to:</p>
<ul>
<li>diversify the forms of cash provided to the public by<br />
the central bank, satisfy the public’s demand for digital cash and support financial inclusion;</li>
<li>support fair competition, efficiency and safety of retail payment services; and</li>
<li>echo the international initiative and explore the improvement of cross-border payment.</li>
</ul>
<p>Though the e-CNY wallet is now downloadable in the Chinese app stores, only users in a list of pilot cities and at the upcoming Winter Olympics venue can actually sign up, top up their accounts, and spend the virtual currency at one of the 8 million &#8220;pilot scenarios,&#8221; such as making purchases on Alibaba and paying Didi rides.</p>
<p>To exchange cash into e-CNY, users will have to move money from one of the commercial banks authorized by the PBOC to operate and circulate the digital currency, including digital-only banks like Tencent-backed WeBank and Ant-backed MyBank.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In terms of its relationship with China&#8217;s popular payments services, the PBOC said in its report that e-CNY is supposed to &#8220;complement&#8221; rather than replace WeChat Pay and Alipay. For instance, it could support anonymity for small value transactions just like physical cash. In other cases, large amounts of funds sent from a provincial government to a town<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/11/china-digital-yuan-shenzhen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> could be paid in e-CNY</a> to prevent corruption using the digital currency&#8217;s traceable capabilities.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, though, e-CNY still needs to compete with the private payments giants on user experience, if it wants to achieve a meaningful active user base.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Nx5WDOW2HR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/11/china-digital-yuan-shenzhen/">China&#8217;s digital yuan tests leap forward in Shenzhen</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China&#8217;s digital yuan tests leap forward in Shenzhen&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/11/china-digital-yuan-shenzhen/embed/#?secret=Nx5WDOW2HR" data-secret="Nx5WDOW2HR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/chinas-digital-yuan-wallet-now-has-260-million-individual-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258708</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kenyan low-cost ISP Poa Internet secures $28 million in round led by AfDB-backed Africa50, plans to link region with cheap, limit-free connectivity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/kenyan-low-cost-isp-poa-internet-secures-28-million-in-round-led-by-afdb-backed-africa50-plans-to-link-region-with-cheap-limit-free-connectivity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/kenyan-low-cost-isp-poa-internet-secures-28-million-in-round-led-by-afdb-backed-africa50-plans-to-link-region-with-cheap-limit-free-connectivity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Njanja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[east africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet connectivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[west africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258675</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 2020, Africa50, an infrastructure financier backed by the Africa Development Bank (AfDB) Group and a good number of African governments, hosted an innovation challenge that sought affordable and reliable solutions for last-mile internet connectivity across the continent. A proposal by Poa Internet, a Kenyan startup beat 673 others from across the world as a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In 2020, Africa50, an infrastructure financier backed by the Africa Development Bank (AfDB) Group and a good number of African governments, hosted an innovation challenge that sought affordable and reliable solutions for last-mile internet connectivity across the continent. A proposal by <a href="https://poa.co.ke/">Poa Internet</a>, a Kenyan startup beat 673 others from across the world as a result of which it was added to Africa50’s investment pipeline in addition to winning a cash prize.</p>
<p>Slightly over one year after the win, the internet service provider (ISP) has received $28 million in a Series C funding round led by Africa50, bringing the total amount it has raised to date to $36 million. Also participating in the latest round was <a href="https://novastarventures.com/">Novastar Ventures</a>, one of the firm’s earliest backers.</p>
<p>Poa plans to use the new funding to grow its reach, first across Kenya then progressively to other countries in the continent.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258675" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“We are focused on Kenya at the moment, but the problem we&#8217;re solving is continent-wide. And for us, it&#8217;s not just about getting people some connectivity. Our aim is to get a lot of people online and to give them a meaningful internet experience like the ability to stream videos, without worrying about how much data they&#8217;re consuming,” Poa Internet’s co-founder and CEO, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahalsall/?originalSubdomain=ke">Andy Halsall</a>, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Poa Internet currently serves over 12,000 customers (homes and small businesses) in Nairobi’s low and middle-income neighborhoods, and tens of thousands more through its street Wi-Fi connections. The startup has laid out its fiber network in neighborhoods that are typically not the first target markets for its competitors like Safaricom Home by East Africa’s biggest telco Safaricom, Faiba by Jamii Telecommunication Limited and Zuku.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2258680" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2258680" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2258680" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Founding-Team.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Founding-Team.jpeg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Founding-Team.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Founding-Team.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Founding-Team.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Founding-Team.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Founding-Team.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Founding-Team.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2258680" class="wp-caption-text">Poa Internet founding team from left to right: Mike Puchol (CTO), Andy Halsall (CEO), Chris Rhodes (COO) and DJ Koeman (CBDO)<strong>. Image Credits:</strong> Poa Internet</p></div></p>
<p>Poa Internet charges its customers a monthly fee of about $13, which is half the market rate, giving it a competitive edge. Its customers also have unlimited data usage, another aspect that makes their products attractive to internet users in the country, where major ISPs offer monthly subscription bundles with data caps.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup has also set up Wi-Fi hotspots in public areas, where users pay about $0.18 for 1 GB of data, 10 times cheaper than the country’s telcos charge for a similar bundle of non-expiring internet.</p>
<p>“Our internet speeds are 4mbps, which is fast enough for video, because everyone wants to stream Netflix, use YouTube, download movies and make video calls. So, we&#8217;ve designed our service to be fast enough to deliver video, but most importantly, our price is a winning factor,” said Halsall.</p>
<p>“Our primary focus is to get the price as low as possible and to operate in the communities that don&#8217;t have fiber connectivity or are unlikely to get fiber. Therefore, we&#8217;re not really going to compete really against anyone because we are going after a market sector that is not well served.”</p>
<p>Affordability remains one of the main roadblocks to internet access across the continent and Poa Internet service has been trying to solve this puzzle since it entered <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/13/kenyan-bnpl-startup-lipa-later-eyes-more-african-markets-after-raising-12-million/">Kenya</a> in 2015.</p>
<p>Africa, and more narrowly sub-Saharan Africa, has the most expensive internet prices in the world, and this negatively impacts on the continent’s ability to grow its digital economies and to adapt to situations like the Covid pandemic. The pandemic’s containment measures, for instance, required most people to work from home and for students to continue learning online &#8212; but this remained impractical in most countries across the continent due to the lack of necessary gadgets and internet connectivity, partly due to underdeveloped infrastructure and pricing.</p>
<p>Benefits of affordable data and a more connected continent are massive in that as more people get connected sectors such as e-commerce and e-learning will experience a take-off.</p>
<p>There were 303 million people, which is less than a third of the population, connected to the mobile internet according to the 2021 GSM Association, an industry organization representing mobile operators, mobile economy <a href="https://data.gsmaintelligence.com/research/research/research-2021/the-mobile-economy-2021">report</a>. This figure is expected to grow to about 40% of this population by 2025. However, while mobile internet contributes a great deal in getting people online, as Halsall hinted earlier, the experience of limited connectivity is incomparable to freedom that comes with a limitless connection.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2258683" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2258683" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2258683" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Poa-Internet-targets-low-and-middle-income-neighborhoods.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Poa-Internet-targets-low-and-middle-income-neighborhoods.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Poa-Internet-targets-low-and-middle-income-neighborhoods.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Poa-Internet-targets-low-and-middle-income-neighborhoods.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Poa-Internet-targets-low-and-middle-income-neighborhoods.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Poa-Internet-targets-low-and-middle-income-neighborhoods.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Poa-Internet-targets-low-and-middle-income-neighborhoods.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Poa-Internet-targets-low-and-middle-income-neighborhoods.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2258683" class="wp-caption-text"><strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Poa Internet currently serves homes and small businesses in Nairobi’s low and middle-income neighborhoods, and tens of thousands more through its street Wi-Fi connections. </span>Image Credits:</strong> Poa Internet (Brian Otieno)</p></div></p>
<p>“Poa has been instrumental in bridging the needs of last- mile connectivity, and their ultra-low-cost solutions can be used to address the significant connectivity gaps in Kenya and across the continent as a whole. This is particularly important at a time when societies and economic activities are increasingly becoming digitized as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic,” said Africa50 managing director and head of infrastructure investments at Africa50, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/razahasnani/">Raza Hasnani</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.africa50.com/">Africa50</a> currently has 31 shareholders including the AfDB, the Central Bank of West African States (BCEAO), Bank Al-Maghrib (the Central Bank of the Kingdom of Morocco, and 28 African countries.</p>
<p>“Increasing access to reliable and affordable internet connectivity is strongly aligned with the key pillars of Africa50’s strategy, and we are excited to be part of this high impact journey and to support Poa’s growth in Africa,” said Hasnani.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/kenyan-low-cost-isp-poa-internet-secures-28-million-in-round-led-by-afdb-backed-africa50-plans-to-link-region-with-cheap-limit-free-connectivity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258675</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hero MotoCorp, Engine No. 1 join Gogoro&#8217;s PIPE, bringing it up to $285M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/hero-motocorp-engine-no-1-join-gogoros-pipe-bringing-it-up-to-285m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/hero-motocorp-engine-no-1-join-gogoros-pipe-bringing-it-up-to-285m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aeon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery swapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DCJ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gogoro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hero MotoCorp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yadea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gogoro, the Taiwanese company best known for its electric Smartscooters and swappable battery infrastructure, has just added current strategic partner Hero MotoCorp, activist and impact investment firm Engine No. 1 and another investor to its PIPE investment, bringing the total funding to $285 million, up from $257 million. The oversubscribed PIPE (private investment in public [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Gogoro, the Taiwanese company best known for its electric Smartscooters and swappable battery infrastructure, has just added current strategic partner Hero MotoCorp, activist and impact investment firm Engine No. 1 and another investor to its PIPE investment, bringing the total funding to $285 million, up from $257 million.</p>
<p>The oversubscribed PIPE (private investment in public equity) round, which includes investors like Foxconn (Hon Hai), GoTo, Temasek, Generation Investment Management and others, comes to Gogoro in addition to the $345 million coming from Poema Global, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/gogoro-will-go-public-on-nasdaq-after-2-35b-spac-deal/">the special purpose acquisition company that Gogoro is expected to merge with</a> in Q1 2022.</p>
<p>“This additional funding, in addition to our recent F-4 filing, keeps us on track for closing in Q1,&#8221; said Bruce Aitken, chief financial officer of Gogoro, in a statement. &#8220;We have three investor groups in our PIPE. Existing investors who wanted to continue to support our vision, new strategic investors who can help us scale and new institutional investors. Adding Hero MotoCorp and Engine No. 1 continues to validate our strategy and plans. Hero MotoCorp is a key OEM and expansion partner and Engine No. 1 will provide strategic guidance on how environmental impact can drive economic value.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258670" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In April last year, Gogoro partnered with Hero MotoCorp, a market leader in India and one of the world&#8217;s largest two-wheeled vehicle makers, to build a joint battery-swapping network in India. HeroMotoCorp will also launch electric two-wheelers using Gogoro technology under its own brand.</p>
<p>Gogoro currently has market dominance in Taiwan, <a href="https://electrek.co/2021/12/21/gogoro-is-silently-crushing-the-domestic-electric-scooter-competition-and-its-not-even-close/">accounting for over 63,000 e-scooter registrations</a> in the country in the first 11 months of 2021. Its next closest competitor, Aeon, had just over 7,000 registrations. But Gogoro has its sights set on globally scaling its battery swapping infrastructure, which is where partnerships with local vehicle makers like Hero and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/10/gogoro-launches-battery-swapping-stations-in-china/">Chinese companies Yadea and DCJ</a> come in.</p>
<p>&#8220;As we go tackle these large markets, we need as many friends on our side as possible,&#8221; Horace Luke, founder and CEO of Gogoro, told TechCrunch. &#8220;It&#8217;s one thing to say, &#8216;We will partner with you and use your technology,&#8217; but it&#8217;s another to say, &#8216;We&#8217;re going to put money into your company to ensure that you have enough capital to actually light up my market.&#8217; So having vehicle partners coming in is great because it makes the conversation so much easier.&#8221;</p>
<p>The capital will also help Gogoro ensure momentum as it scales into new markets. While the company has accumulated over $1 billion in revenue and over 450,000 battery swapping subscribers over the past five years, it&#8217;s still not yet profitable.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re still not yet bottom line positive,&#8221; said Luke. &#8220;We still have a little way to go to build the scale that we need to in order to breakeven. Having more capital will help with that.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/hero-motocorp-engine-no-1-join-gogoros-pipe-bringing-it-up-to-285m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258670</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blossom Capital closes $432M fund for Series A deals in Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/blossom-capital-closes-432m-fund-for-series-a-deals-in-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/blossom-capital-closes-432m-fund-for-series-a-deals-in-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 09:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Lim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blossom Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goPuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ophelia brown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[European startups collectively raised a record $100 billion+ in funding in 2021, a sign of their swelling ranks, ambitions and stature. Now, a VC in London has closed a record round of funding to cater specifically to that opportunity. Blossom Capital, which makes investments in European startups at the Series A stage, has raised $432 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">European startups collectively raised <a href="https://stateofeuropeantech.com/chapter/europe-global-tech-force/article/kicking-full-gear/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a record $100 billion+ in funding in 2021</a>, a sign of their swelling ranks, ambitions and stature. Now, a VC in London has closed a record round of funding to cater specifically to that opportunity. <a href="https://www.blossomcap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blossom Capital</a>, which makes investments in European startups at the Series A stage, has raised $432 million in its third fund, from a mix of limited partners that span Europe and the U.S. At $432 million, is the largest fund to date focused on European startups&#8217; Series A rounds, Blossom said.</p>
<p>(Note: Balderton closed a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/balderton-closes-600m-fund-its-biggest-yet-earmarked-for-early-stage-investments/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$600 million round for &#8220;early stage&#8221; investments last year</a>, so this I guess gives Blossom room to claim to be the biggest to focus on Series A alone.)</p>
<p>Founded by Ophelia Brown, formerly of Index Ventures and Local Globe, Blossom&#8217;s growth has mirrored that of the startup landscape in Europe.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258586" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>For years, all the action happened in Silicon Valley &#8212; so much so that even when startups were hatched in Europe, the U.S. is where they went to find traction and grow, raise serious money, and hire talent. VCs based there often even mandated startups move to the U.S., and specifically the Bay Area, as a condition of funding.</p>
<p>But over time, the Valley became more expensive and competitive. So both founders, and investors &#8212; armed with ever more money from LPs keen to reap the rewards of a rapidly-growing tech industry &#8212; have started to do business further afield. That trend was given a big fillip in the wake of Covid-19, which shifted perceptions on where and how we should work. Now, the Valley VCs are opening and funding operations here to meet the opportunity.</p>
<p>If one of the best attributes of a venture capitalist is that he or she can spot (and then fund) a trend early on, it&#8217;s a pretty strong vote of confidence that Blossom was very prescient in identifying how things would evolve for startups in Europe.</p>
<p>&#8220;We launched back in 2018 thinking there was a gap in Series A funding,&#8221; Brown said. &#8220;Now we see that opportunity set growing each year, and not just in London, Paris and Berlin, but a lot of other cities in Europe.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In keeping with that, so too have the size of rounds grown here.</p>
<p>A decade ago, it was not uncommon for a Series A for a European startup to be under $5 million. But in 2021, the <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/878807/median-venture-capital-deal-size-in-europe-by-series/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">median size</a> started to push $10 million, and is often much, much higher than this. Of course, this is still being outpaced by rounds in the U.S., where the median Series A in 2021 was <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/startups-rounds-vc-inflation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$13 million</a>, but again can be much higher than this. (And I&#8217;m willing to bet that as we see more successful exits, major growth milestones, and skyrocketing valuations come around the corner, Series A rounds across the different regions will converge to be level with each other.)</p>
<p>The VCs making their way into Europe, meanwhile, are less competitors right now than partners, looking to Blossom for better local insights for future deals. Co-investment partners have included Accel, Addition, Coatue, Greenoaks and Tiger Global, the company says.</p>
<p>Blossom has to date been a generalist VC, investing in a pretty diverse range of startups that have included instant delivery startup Dija (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/after-acquiring-dija-and-fancy-instant-grocery-startup-gopuff-launches-in-the-uk-en-route-to-european-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired by GoPuff</a> last year); payments specialist Checkout.com (which last week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/checkout-com-raises-450-million-and-reaches-15-billion-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> a $450 million round that valued it at $15 billion); business forecasting specialist <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/14/pigment-series-b-business-planning/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pigment</a>; and cybersecurity, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/omnichannel-customer-messaging-platform-superchat-raises-15-6m-round-led-by-blossom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">messaging</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/api-video/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">video startups</a> and more.</p>
<p>This latest fund will mostly follow the same course, save for one very notable exception: one-third of it has been earmarked specifically for cryptocurrency startups.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s an area where Brown said she and firm were interested early on &#8212; she said she personally bought her first bitcoin back in 2012 &#8212; and despite some of the speculation and volatility that have been hallmarks of the cyrpto market, she remains optimistic that there will be some significant companies emerging out of that in the longer term.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.moonpay.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Moonpay</a>, a platform that lets people buy and sell cryptocurrency using fiat currency, is the firm&#8217;s first big investment in the space: it was part of the startup&#8217;s an eye-watering $555 million Series A in November last year (as we said, these rounds were sometimes significantly higher than $10 million).</p>
<p>Going forward, managing partner Alex Lim (who joined Blossom recently from IVP) said that the firm wants to do more in crypto infrastructure, Web3 and protocols, and more consumer services.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our focus is to invest early,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It&#8217;s not just a bubble. There are markets being created here.&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2258710" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blossom-Partners.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blossom-Partners.jpg 6820w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blossom-Partners.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blossom-Partners.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blossom-Partners.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blossom-Partners.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blossom-Partners.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blossom-Partners.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blossom-Partners.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>It&#8217;s notable that Blossom was founded and is led by a woman (Imran Ghory, the third partner, is pictured above left, with Lim and Brown). Females remain a rarity in venture capital, especially in Europe. Brown said that diversity is a significant factor for Blossom, but it&#8217;s approach is to work with portfolio companies to bring more diversity into their ranks, rather than use that as part of the overall investment thesis.</p>
<p>&#8220;We don’t think about diversity in terms of [our investment] agenda but in terms of how do they think about building that into their team or products, or addressing it with customers,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>It will be interesting to see how the influx of yet more capital will impact how startups in Europe grow over the longer term, not just how they scale but whether that impacts their exit prospects, too. It was not that long ago that a promising startup in Europe most often took one of two routes: move to the U.S. to grow, or get acquired.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we invest in a company, we assume it’s a standalone business for the longer term, and I think the chances of that have now significantly increased,&#8221; Brown said. &#8220;Selling a company for more than $250 million was practically impossible 10 years ago. Now startups have a lot more options.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/blossom-capital-closes-432m-fund-for-series-a-deals-in-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258586</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finclusion raises $20M to build out credit-led neobank offering across Africa</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/finclusion-raises-20m-to-build-out-credit-led-neobank-offerings-across-africa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/finclusion-raises-20m-to-build-out-credit-led-neobank-offerings-across-africa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 09:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christian Angermayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FairMoney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Future Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kuda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lendable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nairobi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Namibia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southern Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tanzania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TymeBank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[west africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The digital banking space in Africa is taking shape as neobanks on the continent grow in numbers like their global counterparts. Venture capital bet from institutional investors in this class of fintechs is massive and in the latest development from Africa, it seems individual investors appetite is increasing likewise. Finclusion Group, a fintech that uses [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The digital banking space in Africa is taking shape as neobanks on the continent grow in numbers like their global counterparts</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Venture capital bet from institutional investors in this class of fintechs is massive and in the latest development from Africa, it seems individual investors appetite is increasing likewise.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.finclusiongroup.com/">Finclusion Group</a>, a fintech that uses AI algorithms to provide financial services to African customers via an array of credit-centric products, has raised $20 million in debt and equity pre-Series A financing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investors in the round include Andela and Flutterwave co-founder Iyin Aboyeji (who invested via his VC firm Future Africa), LendInvest founder Christian Faes and ComplyAdvantage founder Charlie Delingpole.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258606" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Others include Amandine Lobelle, Jai Mahtani, Sudeep Ramnani, Jonathan Doerr, Richard Aseme (RCA Ventures), Klemens Hallmann, among others. They join the likes of Manuel Koser, Alexander Schuetz and Christian Angermayer, Leo Stiegeler, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">investors in the company’s previous round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finclusion’s debt financing, which makes up the larger share </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">of the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">overall</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> round, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was provided by local currency funds in Eswatini and South Africa. It follows the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.pymnts.com/news/investment-tracker/2021/african-fintech-finclusion-raises-20m-for-https://ventureburn.com/2021/09/african-fintech-platform-finclusion-group-secures-20-million-in-funding/nterprise-development/">$20 million debt facility</a> supplied by emerging markets debt provider Lendable last September.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fintech intends to grow existing operations in South Africa, Eswatini, Kenya, Namibia and Tanzania and expand into Mozambique and Uganda.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to a statement by the company, the expansion, facilitated by the recent financing, is part of Finclusion’s strategy to “drive financial inclusion within market segments that have </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">traditionally</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">been underserved</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> across the African continent, with a current focus on southern and eastern Africa.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since its </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">inception</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2018, Finclusion has built consumer-facing credit products to close the credit gap in countries where it operates.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s SmartAdvance, where Finclusion, via employer partnerships, offers solutions for employees’ financial well-being. Its wage streaming product provides payroll loans and future wage loans where employees can take loans off the back of their salary, deduct from their payroll, and lend through employer relationships. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Africa-focused fintech has disbursed over $300 million worth of loans to more than 240,000 customers up until this point</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Following the Lendable debt capital raise in September, the group has recorded an uptick in monthly disbursements, increasing 140% over the last 18 months. Finclusion’s loan book also grew 30% from December 2020 to December 2021.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite this growth, Finclusion only has 28,000 customers with active loans outstanding, almost 10% of the total customers the company has served since 2018.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is one of the reasons we are going into a neobank strategy to maintain old and new users rather than </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">effectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> churning them out,” said chief executive Timothy Nuy to TechCrunch on why the credit provider is transforming into a neobank now.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nuy affirmed that it had always been Finclusion’s intention to become a neobank. Leading with a credit-led approach— which several digital banks across Africa such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/nigerian-digital-bank-carbon-hit-240m-in-payments-processed-last-year-up-89-from-2019/">Carbon</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/tiger-global-leads-42m-series-b-in-nigerian-credit-led-neobank-fairmoney/">FairMoney</a> have adopted—was a great customer acquisition tool for the company, he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">African customers are in dire need of credit. But from a long term perspective of a company offering </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> loans, it can be hard to compete with other lenders that provide deposits and investments, financial services that any lender, backed with years of customers’ credit history, can </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">efficiently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> cross-sell.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finclusion, taking a cue from other credit-first neobanks, has started diversifying its offerings. Nuy said the company has an insurance product and plans to offer savings products, cards and buy now, pay later offerings via a merchant network in a bid to form a pan-African neobank.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So far, the well-funded digital banks on the continent are either in a single country or, at most, two countries. Carbon operates in Nigeria and Kenya; FairMoney has customers in Nigeria and India; Kuda, a deposit-led neobank <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/kuda-the-african-challenger-bank-raises-55m-at-a-500m-valuation/">worth half a billion dollars</a> in its last round, only serves customers in Nigeria; and Patrice Motsepe-backed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/south-african-digital-bank-tymebank-lands-109m-from-uk-and-phillippines-investors/">TymeBank</a> focuses on South Africa. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A pan-African approach doesn’t </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">necessarily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> mean more customers (Finclusion, despite its presence in five countries, has fewer customers than the aforementioned digital banks). Still, Finclusion’s strategy is pretty ambitious compared to other digital banks’ play-it-safe model.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> there’s a lot of similarities, often between regional markets. Many things we do for South Africa will work the same way as in Nairobi. A lot of what we do there, we can use it in Kampala and Dar es Salaam with some adjustments,” said Nuy on how Finclusion operates across </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">multiple</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> markets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Rolling it [digital banking] out across </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">multiple</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> countries, if you have the operational experience, isn’t difficult. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that’s where we have an edge that we can build towards a pan-African play quicker than others. And </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that experience is something that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">really</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> sets us apart right now.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finclusion also uses a holistic tech stack that gets </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">continuously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> upgraded with specific amendments in each country. This way, the company can scale across </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">multiple</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> geographies simultaneously and efficiently, said the chief executive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, the company has administrative hubs to oversee operations in its five markets</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. With one each in Kenya and South Africa for the eastern and southern regions (its tech teams are also in these countries), Finclusion says it will open another in West Africa soon.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having proven that it can raise institutional debt (over $32 million in the last six months from Lendable and 12 local currency facilities) and build credit histories of thousands of customers, Finclusion needs to increase its efforts on distribution to reach neobank-like numbers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its employer partnerships offering provides an avenue to achieve </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">this. With over 1.2 million employees working for its existing employer partners, Finclusion says it holds many potential users at its disposal to activate in the long run.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NuCXj0UTI6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/13/fintech-farm-nabs-7-4m-to-launch-neobanks-in-nigeria-and-other-emerging-markets/">Fintech Farm nabs $7.4M to launch neobanks in Nigeria and other emerging markets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech Farm nabs $7.4M to launch neobanks in Nigeria and other emerging markets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/13/fintech-farm-nabs-7-4m-to-launch-neobanks-in-nigeria-and-other-emerging-markets/embed/#?secret=NuCXj0UTI6" data-secret="NuCXj0UTI6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/finclusion-raises-20m-to-build-out-credit-led-neobank-offerings-across-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258606</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LiveHive wants to be a ‘one stop shop’ for online yoga teachers, PTs  and other coaches</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/livehive-wants-to-be-a-one-stop-shop-for-online-yoga-teachers-pts-and-other-coaches/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/livehive-wants-to-be-a-one-stop-shop-for-online-yoga-teachers-pts-and-other-coaches/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 09:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LiveHive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoga]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yoga, personal trainers and other kinds of online coaches have a bewildering array of platforms on which they can launch their class, either in platforms specializing in verticals (PTs) or more general ones. A new UK player hopes &#8211; perhaps a little optimistically &#8211; hopes to make inroads into this market with a ‘one stop [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Yoga, personal trainers and other kinds of online coaches have a bewildering array of platforms on which they can launch their class, either in platforms specializing in verticals (PTs) or more general ones.</p>
<p>A new UK player hopes &#8211; perhaps a little optimistically &#8211; hopes to make inroads into this market with a ‘one stop shop’ for live online coaches.</p>
<p><a href="https://livehive.biz/">LiveHive</a> is aimed at anyone coaching online &#8211; from yoga teachers to professionals offering specialist expertise, personal trainers, influencers and lifestyle gurus. In other words, it’s trying to be all things to all coaches, whether full time, part time, or as as a side income.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258140" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The B2B platform offers a browser-based video studio; integrated payments and payouts; automatic recordings; integrated social media, as well a SMS and email notifications for clients.</p>
<p>Co-founder and CEO of LiveHive, Dave Nicholson said: “Looking at the UK’s growing knowledge economy, it was clear that providing live online coaching as a business was too technically complex, time consuming and confusing. LiveHive makes the entire process simpler, easier and more effective for all involved.”<br />
 <br />
LifeHive has bootstrapped to date and now plans a seed round.</p>
<p>It is of course up against some large and better-funded players including Moxie and Kuula.tv.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/livehive-wants-to-be-a-one-stop-shop-for-online-yoga-teachers-pts-and-other-coaches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258140</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigerian restaurant management platform Orda gets $1.1M, wants to be the Toast of Africa</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/nigerian-restaurant-management-platform-orda-gets-1-1m-wants-to-be-the-toast-of-africa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/nigerian-restaurant-management-platform-orda-gets-1-1m-wants-to-be-the-toast-of-africa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 07:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud based software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EPOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hustle fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Idris Ayo Bello]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inventory management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LoftyInc Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magic fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mentorships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microtraction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[point-of-sale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cloud-based point of sales for small, medium and large-sized restaurants has increased tremendously in both size and popularity. The market, dominated by incumbents like Toast and upcoming players such as MarginEdge and Brazil’s Zak, has its value pegged at over $70 billion globally and is expected to reach $116 billion in the next four years. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cloud-based point of sales for small, medium and large-sized restaurants has increased </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">tremendously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in both size and popularity. The market, dominated by incumbents like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/toast-the-restaurant-management-platform-has-raised-250m-at-a-2-7b-valuation/">Toast</a> and upcoming players such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/marginedge-a-restaurant-management-software-company-raises-18m/">MarginEdge</a> and Brazil’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/digital-restaurant-startup-zak-orders-up-new-capital-on-mission-to-be-toast-of-latam/">Zak</a>, has its value pegged at over $70 billion globally and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is expected</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to reach $116 billion in the next four years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As with most technologies, Africa is playing catch up in this food-tech segment. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">But a few startups are paying attention to the market, positioning themselves to become top players when it matures</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. One such startup is Nigeria’s <a href="https://orda.africa/">Orda</a>, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">formerly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> known as StarKitchens. Today, it is announcing that it has secured a $1.1 million pre-seed round to scale its software across Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company, which describes itself as a ‘cloud-based restaurant operating system built for African chefs and food business owners,’ had its round led by pan-African investor LoftyInc Capital.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258517" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other institutional investors include Techstars Boulder, Magic Fund, Hustle Fund, Norrsken Foundation, Microtraction, DFS Labs, Oxford Seed Fund, Enza Capital, Agrolay Advisors, and angel investors such as Buycoins’ Ire Aderinokun, Jesse Ovia and Ademola Adesina.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While big restaurants and restaurant chains are often capable of setting their management systems or using well-known point-of-sale providers, thousands of smaller restaurants in Africa rely on offline methods such as pen and paper to produce receipts and make reconciliations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orda’s addressable market is this segment of Africa’s restaurant industry. With its cloud-based software, Orda wants these businesses not to rely on manual ways of managing their businesses. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There are two kinds of restaurants where the majority of our focus is on &#8212; the bukkas [local restaurants] and the small restaurants, for instance,” Orda co-founder and CEO <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/guyfuti">Guy Futi</a> told TechCrunch in an interview.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“These are the restaurants that have been using paper and pen and then that spend three to four hours on reconciliation</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They don’t have access to software that does analytics and inventory management right off the gate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, we decided to build a cloud-based restaurant software tailor-made for Africa’s massive chefs and restaurant industry</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The typical examples of food or restaurant-focused tech businesses help restaurants make online deliveries, such as Jumia Food or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/glovo-to-double-down-african-investment-in-the-next-12-months-but-will-it-stay-put/">Glovo</a>; others try to handle entire supply chains like YC-backed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/vendease-gets-3-2m-to-help-hotels-and-restaurants-buy-food-supplies-in-africa/">Vendease</a>. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orda’s full-stack and end-to-end approach &#8212; a result of constant building and iteration according to CTO <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/adinlewa-akinwale-a59625117">Fikayo Akinwale</a> &#8212; helps restaurants manage these processes online while integrating local payments, logistics, inventory management and business analytics features.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Orda </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was built</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from a near 18 months of a collaborative customer feedback loop. We listened to everything, from how African restaurants reconcile inventory, how customers pay, to how they handle logistics and more. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We can </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">confidently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> say that no one has done as much work as we have to build an end-to-end solution for our food business owners.”, said the CTO in a statement</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Restaurants who use the management platform also have access to a dashboard that allows them to accept and process orders from food delivery services Jumia Food, Glovo, Bolt Food, and in-store, website, social media channels like WhatsApp.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orda claims no other company in its space has made similar integrations. These integrations, including an ePos solution that restaurants can operate in remote areas with little or no internet coverage, give Orda an edge </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the market, said Futi.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Futi also remarked that the adoption from restaurants in markets where it operates (Nigeria and Kenya) has been “very seamless,” adding that the cloud-based software doubles its growth rate every three weeks. In a statement, Orda said its gross merchandise value (GMV) grows 15% week-on-week while processing up to 10,000 transactions weekly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Currently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Orda charges restaurants between $5 (~₦2,500) to $50 (~₦30,000) monthly to access its software. Having closed its pre-seed and working towards raising a seed round, the CEO said Orda would build out financial products, especially in lending, and venture into processing payments for restaurants.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orda is somewhat replicating the business model of companies like Toast that have noticed massive growth after launching fintech technology solutions</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year, 80% of the U.S. company’s <a href="https://pos.toasttab.com/news/toast-announces-third-quarter-2021-financial-results">third-quarter revenue of $486.4 million</a> came from payment processing and offering financial products; however, most of its total costs incurred came from the segment as well</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We want to become like the Toast of Africa,” expressed the chief executive, adding that Orda would also double down on its white-label mobile applications (similar to Toast Takeout) for restaurants that leverage its cloud-based infrastructure to operate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Futi, who founded the company with Akinwale,</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/medomwande/"> Mark Edomwande,</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/olakunle-ogungbamila/"> Kunle Ogungbamila</a>, and<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/namir-el-khouri-9b77a253/"> Namir El-Khouri</a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2020, said with the new and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">subsequent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> funding, Orda is working on an expansion into South Africa by the end of this year. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Idris Ayo Bello, the managing partner of lead investor <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/loftyinc-capital-launches-third-fund-at-10m-for-a-more-diverse-portfolio-of-african-startups/">LoftyInc Capital</a>, said this of the investment, “We loved investing in Orda because it is building the core digital infrastructure for restaurants across Africa. The team has done the hard work of figuring out the core problems that African restaurant owners are facing and is building a solution that can revolutionise the food business across the continent.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/nigerian-restaurant-management-platform-orda-gets-1-1m-wants-to-be-the-toast-of-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258517</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spendesk is the fifth French startup to reach unicorn status this month</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/spendesk-is-the-fifth-french-startup-to-reach-unicorn-status-this-month/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/spendesk-is-the-fifth-french-startup-to-reach-unicorn-status-this-month/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 06:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spend management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spendesk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fintech startup Spendesk is announcing that it has raised an extension to its Series C round. Tiger Global is investing $114 million (€100 million) in the startup. Following today’s funding round, the company says that is has reached a valuation of more than $1.14 billion (more than €1 billion). In other words, Spendesk is a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Fintech startup <a href="http://spendesk.com">Spendesk</a> is announcing that it has raised an extension to its Series C round. Tiger Global is investing $114 million (€100 million) in the startup. Following today’s funding round, the company says that is has reached a valuation of more than $1.14 billion (more than €1 billion).</p>
<p>In other words, Spendesk is a new unicorn in the French tech ecosystem. Funding news has been accelerating over the last few months in France. In January alone, five startups announced that they have crossed the threshold to reach unicorn status —&nbsp;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/payroll-startup-payfit-is-frances-latest-unicorn-as-it-raises-289-million/">PayFit</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/09/ankorstore-reaches-2-billion-valuation-two-years-after-launching-its-wholesale-marketplace/">Ankorstore</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/business-banking-startup-qonto-raises-552-million-at-5-billion-valuation/">Qonto</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/16/warehouse-robotics-system-exotec-raises-335-million/">Exotec</a> and Spendesk.</p>
<p>Back Market, an e-commerce marketplace focused on refurbished smartphones and electronics devices, has also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/back-market-reaches-5-7b-valuation-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/">raised a mega round</a> and reached a $5.7 billion valuation.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258559" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Let’s go back to Spendesk. The startup offers an all-in-one corporate spend management platform for medium companies in Europe. Originally focused on virtual cards for online payments, the company has expanded its product offering to tackle everything related to corporate spending.</p>
<p>Spendesk customers can order physical cards for employees, team members can use the platform to pay outstanding invoices, file expense reports, manage budgets and generate spending reports. By offering everything in a single service, Spendesk wants to simplify accounting and approvals in general so that money moves more freely.</p>
<p>The startup defines its platform as a “7-in-1 spend management solution”, meaning that Spendesk is no longer just a product that lets you order debit cards for your employees.</p>
<p>“We have had this goal since the beginning — we really want to become this platform, this operational system to manage your spending,” co-founder and CEO Rodolphe Ardant told me. “When we started working on the product, we looked at each use case and designed the right workflow for that.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In particular, Spendesk helps you formalize your internal processes. You can define team budgets, set up complicated approval workflows for expensive payments, automate some pesky tasks, such as VAT extraction.</p>
<p>“We target mid-market clients. Those are customers with 50 to 1,000 employees. We have a few clients that are bigger than that and a few clients that are smaller than that,” Ardant said.</p>
<p>And the company currently has 3,500 clients — around&nbsp;half of them are based in France while other clients are mostly based in Germany and the U.K. Clients have spent €3 billion through Spendesk in 2021 alone.</p>
<p>With its central positioning in the financial stack, Spendesk needs to interface perfectly with other financial tools — banks on one side and ERP products on the other side.</p>
<p>The startup currently supports many of the popular accounting tools used by European companies, such as Xero and Datev. Spendesk customers can also export transaction batches and import them into Sage, Cegid and other accounting software solutions.</p>
<p>Spendesk is also working on automating the integrations with your bank accounts, which could be particularly useful for companies with multiple bank accounts. For instance, you could imagine setting up a rule that automatically triggers a transfer between your German bank account and your Spendesk account when you want to pay a German supplier.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2258561" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2258561" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Spendesk_Mobile-App.png" alt="" width="1024" height="576" class="size-full wp-image-2258561" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Spendesk_Mobile-App.png 2240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Spendesk_Mobile-App.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Spendesk_Mobile-App.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Spendesk_Mobile-App.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Spendesk_Mobile-App.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Spendesk_Mobile-App.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Spendesk_Mobile-App.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Spendesk_Mobile-App.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2258561" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Spendesk</p></div></p>
<h2>Spend management in Europe</h2>
<p>Spendesk isn’t the only spend management solution in Europe. There are some competitors, such as <a href="https://www.pleo.io/en">Pleo</a>, which recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/pleo-picks-up-200m-at-a-4-7b-valuation-to-build-the-next-generation-of-business-expense-management/">reached a $4.7 billion valuation</a>, and <a href="https://www.soldo.com">Soldo</a> — another well-funded competitor as it has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/soldo-raises-180m-for-its-expense-management-platform-for-businesses/">raised $180 million</a> last year.</p>
<p>In the U.S. as well, companies like <a href="https://www.brex.com">Brex</a> and <a href="https://ramp.com">Ramp</a> have reached sky-high valuations. And yet, Spendesk doesn’t think it has the same positioning as American startups.</p>
<p>“On the American market, it shouldn&#8217;t be called the spend management industry — it’s the corporate card industry. Players like Brex and Ramp position themselves as a payment method,” Spendesk co-founder and CEO Rodolphe Ardant told me. “Europe’s corporate culture is a culture of debit — not credit. We don’t provide payment methods, we provide a process.”</p>
<p>It’s a slight difference in product positioning, so it’s going to be interesting to see if a European spend management startup can successfully enter the U.S. and vice versa.</p>
<p>When it comes to business model as well, Spendesk considers itself as a software-as-a-service company with recurring subscriptions. The startup didn’t want to share any hard numbers for its revenue. Its CEO just said that Spendesk’s revenue “more than doubles every year.”</p>
<p>With today’s funding round, Spendesk plans to triple the size of its team over the next two years. The company plans to have 1,000 employees by the end of 2023.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/spendesk-is-the-fifth-french-startup-to-reach-unicorn-status-this-month/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258559</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto.com expands venture arm to $500 million to back early-stage web3 startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/crypto-com-500-million-fund-web3/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/crypto-com-500-million-fund-web3/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 02:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alameda Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Crypto.com, a popular cryptocurrency exchange, has extended its venture arm&#8217;s fund size to $500 million as it looks to more aggressively back early-stage startups to help the nascent ecosystem grow, following similar moves by rivals Binance, Coinbase and FTX. The broadening of Crypto.com Capital comes less than a year after the Singapore-headquartered firm unveiled its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Crypto.com, a popular cryptocurrency exchange, has extended its venture arm&#8217;s fund size to $500 million as it looks to more aggressively back early-stage startups to help the nascent ecosystem grow, following similar moves by rivals Binance, Coinbase and FTX.</p>
<p>The broadening of Crypto.com Capital comes less than a year after the Singapore-headquartered firm unveiled its maiden fund of $200 million. The fund, unlike those of many of its rivals, has no LPs (meaning, it&#8217;s fully financed by the firm&#8217;s balance sheet.)</p>
<p>The maiden fund, whose individual checks run up to $10 million in size, has been so far deployed to back about 20 startups including YGG SEA, multi-chain crypto portfolio tracker DeBank, cross-chain token infrastructure Efinity and Ethereum scaling solution Matter Labs.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258617" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Crypto.com will continue to focus on backing early-stage startups, said Jon Russell, who joined the firm as a general partner this month, in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>With the fund, Crypto.com is broadly focusing on gaming, decentralized-finance and startups innovating on cross-chain solutions. But he cautioned that the industry could change and expand, as it has in recent years, to areas “we don’t know about,” hence the firm is keeping an eye out on everything.</p>
<p>Tuesday’s announcement also further illustrates the growing involvement of cryptocurrency exchanges in being the rainmaker – and beneficiary – of the ecosystem which encompasses the industry in which they operate.</p>
<p>FTX, which has backed over 15 startups, last week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/15/the-race-to-fund-cryptos-future-sure-is-expensive/">announced a $2 billion crypto fund</a>. Its founder, Sam Bankman-Fried, also owns Alameda Research, a venture firm that has backed close to 100 web3 startups.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Coinbase Ventures, the investment arm of the only crypto exchange that is publicly traded, and Binance, the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchange by trading volume, are also among the most prolific investors in the web3 space.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2258633" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2258633" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2258633 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/venture-investment-crypto-2021.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="602" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/venture-investment-crypto-2021.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/venture-investment-crypto-2021.jpg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/venture-investment-crypto-2021.jpg?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/venture-investment-crypto-2021.jpg?resize=768,385 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/venture-investment-crypto-2021.jpg?resize=680,341 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/venture-investment-crypto-2021.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2258633" class="wp-caption-text">Venture investment in crypto / web3 in 2021 by category (Image credits: Galaxy Digital)</p></div></p>
<p>The funding activity in the space, even as most of the aforementioned names often co-invest in startups, is at an all-time high. VCs invested more than $33 billion in crypto/web3 startups in 2021, more than all prior years combined, Galaxy Digital, another prolific investor in the space, wrote in a recent report.</p>
<p>“Valuations in the crypto/blockchain space were 141% higher than the rest of the venture capital space in Q4, highlighting a founder-friendly environment and the intense competition among investors for deal allocations,” the report added.</p>
<p>Scores of venture capital firms have also raised new funds for their crypto investments. Just last year, Andreessen Horowitz <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/andreessen-horowitz-triples-down-on-blockchain-startups-with-massive-2-2-billion-crypto-fund-iii/">added a $2.2 billion crypto fund</a>, Paradigm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/crypto-vc-firm-paradigm-debuts-monster-2-5-billion-fund/">unveiled a $2.5 billion fund</a>, and Hivemind Capital Partners announced a $1.5 billion fund. Katie Haun, who co-led a16z&#8217;s $2.2 billion crypto fund, has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/katie-haun-is-splitting-off-from-a16z-to-launch-her-own-crypto-fund/">left the firm to launch her own crypto-focused fund</a>.</p>
<p>Russell – a former journalist who previously had stints at TechCrunch, The Next Web, and The Ken – said Crypto.com is backing startups to help the ecosystem grow.</p>
<p>“If you’re in the industry, it’s in your interest to help companies grow in the ecosystem and the ecosystem itself to grow,” he said. (Worth pointing out that Solana, Avalanche, Polkadot &#8212; as well as some of their major investors &#8212; are also aggressively backing startups that are building applications for the native blockchains.)</p>
<p>The startups Crypto.com backs are under no obligation to list their tokens on Crypto.com over any of its rivals or offer the exchange any other preferential treatment, he said. The exchange team similarly doesn’t have a soft spot for the investment arm’s portfolio firms, he added.</p>
<p>(What&#8217;s up with the career move? “I’ve been crypto curious for a number of years but I wasn’t gasping to dive in full-time. This project appeals to me because Crypto.com is ambitious but yet it does things the right way. There’s certainly a lot of hype and hot air in crypto and web3 right now, but it’s impossible to ignore the talent that’s pouring into the industry,&#8221; he said.)</p>
<p>Crypto.com, which started its life as a blog of professor Matt Blaze (who <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/07/rip-crypto/">sold the domain to the crypto exchange</a>), has aggressively expanded in the past year as it looks to court more users. The Singapore-headquartered firm last year agreed to pay more than $700 million for the naming rights of the Staples Center in Los Angeles. The downtown Los Angeles complex has been rebranded as Crypto.com Arena for the next 20 years.</p>
<p>The firm, which bills itself as the &#8220;fastest-growing&#8221; crypto exchange, said at the time of the announcement that the move is positioned to make cryptocurrencies mainstream. Crypto.com, which processes trade volumes of over $2.5 billion every day, also teamed up with Hollywood star Matt Damon last year to promote the brand and cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>The Damon-starring ad equated buying crypto tokens and NFTs to one of the greatest and boldest accomplishments in the history of humankind. Hyperbole, to be sure, but having the most mainstream American actor as Crypto.com’s celebrity sponsor has certainly helped bring the trading platform, and all that it sells, into the mainstream. The ad went viral and also attracted criticism for being cringeworthy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/crypto-com-500-million-fund-web3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258617</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Focused on smaller cities, Vietnamese social commerce startup Mio raises $8M Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/focused-on-smaller-cities-vietnamese-social-commerce-startup-mio-raises-8m-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/focused-on-smaller-cities-vietnamese-social-commerce-startup-mio-raises-8m-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mio App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[produce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258592</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mio, the Vietnamese social commerce platform, has raised an $8 million Series A, less than a year after announcing its seed round. The funding was led by Jungle Ventures, with participation from Patamar Capital and Oliver Jung. Existing investors investors GGV, Venturra, Hustle Fund, iSEED SEA and Gokul Rajaram also returned for the round. TechCrunch [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://mioapp.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mio</a>, the Vietnamese social commerce platform, has raised an $8 million Series A, less than a year after announcing its seed round. The funding was led by Jungle Ventures, with participation from Patamar Capital and Oliver Jung. Existing investors investors GGV, Venturra, Hustle Fund, iSEED SEA and Gokul Rajaram also returned for the round.</p>
<p>TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/mio-a-social-commerce-startup-focused-on-smaller-cities-and-rural-areas-in-vietnam-raises-1m-seed/">first covered Mio at the time of its $1 million seed funding in May 2021</a>. Founded in 2020, Mio is a group buying platform that focuses on selling fresh produce and groceries in Tier 2 and 3 cities in Vietnam. The company is able to offer next day delivery because it built a logistics infrastructure that enables it to send produce directly from farms to customers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oC0gR6guX6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/mio-a-social-commerce-startup-focused-on-smaller-cities-and-rural-areas-in-vietnam-raises-1m-seed/">Mio, a social commerce startup focused on smaller cities and rural areas in Vietnam, raises $1M seed</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258592" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mio, a social commerce startup focused on smaller cities and rural areas in Vietnam, raises $1M seed&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/mio-a-social-commerce-startup-focused-on-smaller-cities-and-rural-areas-in-vietnam-raises-1m-seed/embed/#?secret=oC0gR6guX6" data-secret="oC0gR6guX6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The Series A brings Mio’s total raised to $9.1 million, and will be used to expand its logistics and fulfillment system, enter new areas in Vietnam and add new product categories like fast-moving consumer goods (FMCG) and household appliances.</p>
<p>Mio co-founder and chief executive officer Trung Huynh said that since TechCrunch first covered Mio seven months ago, it has achieved 10x gross merchandise value growth, a 10x increase in agents, or resellers, and grew its team from 60 people to 240. It now fulfills more than 10,000 pieces of fresh produce per day, operating in Ho Chi Minh, Thu Duc, Binh Duong, Dong Nai and Long An, with plans to expand into northern Vietnam.</p>
<p>The numbers “strengthened our conviction in this model and its potential,” he said. “We need fresh capital to accelerate hiring, product development and supply chain to keep up with the pace of growth as we deepen our presence in existing geographies and expand to new provinces.”</p>
<p>Mio is able to offer next day deliveries because its vertically integrated mayor layers of the value chain, including procurement, warehousing, order sorting and bulk delivery. The startup owns the majority of its logistics infrastructure and uses its own fleet of couriers. Its ability to delivery fresh produce directly from farms to customers in less than 16 hours contributed to higher customer retention and growth, Huynh said, and it will continue to shorten delivery times. .</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Mio resellers are called Mio Partners. Huynh said one of the driving factors behind Mio is targeting the right people for the program, or “housewives and stay-home-moms in lower income regions who love sharing value-for-money products to their social circle of friends.”</p>
<p>They aggregate orders, usually from friends and family, and orders are delivered to them in batches for distribution. The startup claims Mio Partners can make up to $400 a month, including a 10% commission on each order and additional commissions based on the monthly performance of other resellers they referred to the program.</p>
<p>“There is a strong possibility” that Mio will expand beyond Vietnam, Huynh said, “but will only be considered at a more appropriate time after we successfully built our playbook for Vietnam.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="95KCHcGjBh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/super-an-indonesian-hyperlocal-social-commerce-startup-raises-28m-led-by-softbank-ventures-asia/">Super, an Indonesian hyperlocal social commerce startup, raises $28M led by SoftBank Ventures Asia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Super, an Indonesian hyperlocal social commerce startup, raises $28M led by SoftBank Ventures Asia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/super-an-indonesian-hyperlocal-social-commerce-startup-raises-28m-led-by-softbank-ventures-asia/embed/#?secret=95KCHcGjBh" data-secret="95KCHcGjBh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/focused-on-smaller-cities-vietnamese-social-commerce-startup-mio-raises-8m-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258592</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korean HR automation platform flex raises $32M Series B at a $287M valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/south-koreas-hr-software-platform-flex-raises-32m-series-b-at-a-287m-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/south-koreas-hr-software-platform-flex-raises-32m-series-b-at-a-287m-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resources management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258380</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Korea-based human resources management platform flex announced today it has closed a $32 million Series B round at a valuation of $287 million. The latest funding, which brings its total raised to $42 million, was led by Greenoaks, with participation from DST Global Partners.   The startup’s mission is to enable corporations to automate and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">South Korea-based human resources management platform <a href="https://flex.team/"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">flex</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> announced today it has closed a $32 million Series B round at a valuation of $287 million. The latest funding, which brings its total raised to $42 million, was led by </span><a href="https://www.greenoaks.com/"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Greenoaks</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">, with participation from <a href="https://dst-global.com/">DST Global Partners</a>.  </span></p>
<p>The startup’s mission is to enable corporations to automate and streamline manual human resources work processes and focus more on people. Its automation tools optimize the employee experience to ensure seamless data flow across groups for use in payroll, e-signature support, on/offboarding and people analytics. <span data-preserver-spaces="true">It also plans to launch performance review and talents relation management tools in the first quarter of 2022. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“At flex we define HR as Human Relations, not Human Resources. We believe HR teams deserve world-class software to manage and service their employees, but today it’s clear that many organizations still use spreadsheets or legacy products to make ends meet, said Haenam Chang, CEO of flex. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258380" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The two-year-old startup will use the proceeds to scale operations to meet demand, advance its HR automation and SaaS products and increase its headcount.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The Series B funding comes on the back of growth in revenue of almost ten times, compared to last year, driven by a number of product launches and new customers. The startup has primarily been serving SMBs in the IT sector. However, flex plans to expand the addressable market by targeting new industries in the SMB space this year. It did not disclose any user or customer numbers when asked. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Currently, flex is focused on growing in South Korea by offering a SaaS solution that modernizes the HR functions and processes, which have been slow to adapt to technical progress over the past 20 years. The company said its deep understanding of cultural nuances in people management and the HR regulations in the country help flex to be well-positioned to offer a set of products tailored to South Korean businesses.  </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“While some companies have adopted solutions to track and improve how they manage their employees, most still rely on gut instinct or insufficient data to make ad-hoc decisions on employees. At flex, we empower customers with a reliable source of employee data and a rich set of tools to manage their people, maximizing individual and organizational performance. Our goal isn’t just to provide a great HR software solution – it’s to empower companies to better track and manage their most important assets, their people,&#8221; Chang said. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“Korea is one of the world’s largest and most dynamic economies but has historically lacked a native solution for companies to manage and pay their employees – leaving businesses frustrated and left to develop their own homegrown solutions,” said Josh Cho of Greenoaks. “Now, flex is rapidly building the country’s first next-generation human resources information system and payroll platform. We are excited about their vision for an end-to-end product that will let companies handle all their HR functions in a single place, from performance management to recruiting to payroll and more.” </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/south-koreas-hr-software-platform-flex-raises-32m-series-b-at-a-287m-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258380</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s Arya raises $60 million to provide farmers with finance and post-harvest services</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/arya-post-harvest-services-india-agritech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/arya-post-harvest-services-india-agritech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 23:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lightrock India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quona Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian agritech startup Arya, which reaches hundreds of thousands of farmers in the South Asian market and helps them store and sell their produce and secure credit, has raised $60 million in a new financing round as it enters a new phase of growth. Asia Impact SA, Lightrock India and Quona Capital co-led the $46 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Indian agritech startup Arya, which reaches hundreds of thousands of farmers in the South Asian market and helps them store and sell their produce and secure credit, has raised $60 million in a new financing round as it enters a new phase of growth.</p>
<p>Asia Impact SA, Lightrock India and Quona Capital co-led the $46 million Series C financing round. US International Development France Corporation and others provided an additional $14 million as debt. The new round values the eight-year-old, Noida-based startup at $300 million, a person familiar with the matter said.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.arya.ag">Arya</a> is attempting to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/arya-raises-21-million-for-its-agritech-and-finance-platform/">solve three challenges</a> that have distressed farmers in India for decades. Only about a third of the yields they produce reaches the big markets, where most of the sales occur, creating an uneven concentration that continues to deprive millions of farmers from being able to efficiently store and sell their produce.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2258589" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The vast majority of farmers struggle to find buyers for their yields, and they typically go through a cash crunch until they have sold the produce.</p>
<p>Arya, co-founded by Prasanna Rao, is addressing this through a network of close to 10,000 warehouses, up from about 1,500 a year ago, it has seeded across 21 Indian states. By making these warehouses available to farmers near their farms, the startup has made it possible for them to be able to store their produce for the first time.</p>
<p>The warehouse is designed to store grain produce from the farmers for about three months and gives them insurance coverage. Farmers are able to monitor in real-time as the produce leaves their farm to the nearby warehouse, establishing a level of transparency and trust that is crucial to court farmers, said Rao in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>At the warehouse, Arya also helps farmers connect with buyers and provides them the option to negotiate on prices. “Because we hold the commodity in our warehouses, we have complete visibility into quantity and quality. This is how we are able to establish a connect between the buyer and seller,” he said, adding that the startup has visibility into grains worth over $2 billion on its platform.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup has devised a level of sophistication that it is able to spin up a new warehouse within two days in any region they are required, he said. Arya doesn&#8217;t own these warehouses and instead revamps warehouses owned by other businesses. There are over 100,000 of such warehouses spread across the country and most of them are being under-utilised.</p>
<p>Arya works with farmer associations to reach the farmers. The farmers can use Arya.ag website or use traditional ways such as guidance provided in-person to use the platform and clear any confusions.</p>
<p>But the work isn&#8217;t done there.</p>
<p>As we have seen in the case of<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/indian-e-commerce-udaan-raises-250-million/"> tens of millions of neighbourhood stores in India</a>, the farmers also rely heavily on the earnings they make from selling their current batches of produce before being able to start a new season of cropping.</p>
<p>Arya works with banks and non-banking financial institutions to help these farmers secure loans, allowing them to get back to work while their produces are sold. The $18 million it has raised as debt in the new round is meant to provide credit to the farmers who financial institutions don&#8217;t find credit-worthy, he said, adding that in the past one year, the startup has grown its financing book by three times.</p>
<p>&#8220;Arya’s unparalleled reach across rural India, coupled with its tech-driven integrated service model, has made it one of the fastest-growing agri-commerce platforms in India,&#8221; said Varun Malhotra, Partner at Quona Capital, in a statement. &#8220;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Arya is successfully bridging the trust gap in post-harvest agri transactions through complete transparency and assurance on quality, quantity and payments. We are excited to deepen our partnership with Arya.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Once an overlooked sector, scores of startups and tech giants are exploring ways to tap what is one of the world’s largest annual harvest of grains. I<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ndia’s agri-tech industry has the potential to reach about $24 billion in revenue by 2025, according to consultancy firm EY. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Amazon recently began offering real-time advice and information to farmers to help them inform their decisions on crops. Microsoft is working with 100 villages to deploy AI and build a platform.</span></p>
<p>Rao said it has been heartening to see more players in the industry to pay attention to the sector. He said Arya alone is hoping to have a network of over 60,000 warehouses in the next four years and is also evaluating acquiring smaller startups to fuel faster growth.</p>
<p>“Through the pandemic, we have seen Arya transform agri-commerce across India,” said Matteo Pusineri, director of Asia Impact SA, in a statement.</p>
<p>“Arya will help accomplish Asia Impact&#8217;s vision to integrate rural under-served farming communities across Asia to markets at scale. We are confident that Arya, under the leadership of Prasanna Rao, Anand Chandra and Chattanathan Devarajan, will greatly contribute to a unique ecosystem supporting the sustainable growth story of rural India.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/arya-post-harvest-services-india-agritech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258589</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
