<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 07:59:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Nokia launches a laptop with India&#8217;s Flipkart</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/nokia-launches-a-laptop-with-flipkart-in-india/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/nokia-launches-a-laptop-with-flipkart-in-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 07:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nokia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10 Home]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086476</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nokia, the 155-year-old iconic firm that has manufactured a range of items from rubber to cables to phones and telecommunications equipment, is ready to expand to a new category. The Finnish firm on Monday launched the Nokia PureBook X14 laptop in collaboration with Walmart -owned Flipkart for the Indian market. The Nokia PureBook X14, which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/nokia" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="nokia">Nokia, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> the 155-year-old iconic firm that has manufactured a range of items from rubber to cables to phones and telecommunications equipment, is ready to expand to a new category.</p>
<p>The Finnish firm on Monday launched the Nokia PureBook X14 laptop in collaboration with <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/walmart" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="walmart">Walmart <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>-owned <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/flipkart" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="flipkart">Flipkart <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> for the Indian market.</p>
<p>The Nokia PureBook X14, which is priced at Indian rupees 59,990 ($815), features a 14-inch full-HD display and is powered by Intel’s 10th generation quad-core i5 processor with up to 4.2GHz turbo speed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The laptop, which ships pre-installed with Windows 10 Home, sports a 512GB NVMe SSD and 8 GB DD4 RAM.</p>
<p>Its other specs include: 86% screen-to-body ratio and 178-degree viewing angles, matte black finish, Dolby Atmos-powered speakers, Face Unlock with Windows Hello, Intel UHD 620 Graphics with 1.1GHz Turbo GPU, Bluetooth 5.1, two USB 3.1 ports, one USB 2.0 port, and one USB Type C port as well as dedicated ports for HDMI and ethernet. The Nokie PureBook X14, which weighs about 1.1kg, will last up to 8 hours on a single charge.</p>
<p>Flipkart, which has grown its private label and brand ecosystems in recent years, is the design and manufacturing partner for the new laptop. Like it does with Motorola, Flipkart has inked a licensing agreement with the Finnish firm, a representative of Flipkart told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The laptop will be exclusively sold through Flipkart in India, which is also the only market for this particular device.</p>
<p>“Launching the Nokia brand into this new product category is testament to our successful collaboration with Flipkart. We are excited to offer consumers in India a Nokia branded laptop which brings innovation to address a gap in the market, as well as the style, performance and reliability that the Nokia brand is known for, said Vipul Mehrotra, VP for Brand Partnerships at Nokia, in a statement.</p>
<p>The Indian laptop market has attracted several new firms in recent years, including Xiaomi, which launched a range of affordable laptops in the country this year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/nokia-launches-a-laptop-with-flipkart-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086476</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China fines Alibaba, Tencent&#8217;s e-book subsidiary over anti-trust violations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/china-literature-alibaba-fined/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/china-literature-alibaba-fined/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 07:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Chinese government is moving to curb the power of some of China&#8217;s most influential internet companies. The country&#8217;s top market regulator announced Monday that it is fining Alibaba and China Literature, Tencent&#8217;s e-book spinoff, for failing to report their past acquisition deals for clearance. The cases involve Alibaba&#8217;s equity investments in major Chinese mall [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Chinese government is moving to curb the power of some of China&#8217;s most influential internet companies. The country&#8217;s top market regulator <a href="http://www.samr.gov.cn/xw/zj/202012/t20201214_324336.html">announced</a> Monday that it is fining Alibaba and China Literature, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/08/china-literature-makes-stellar-public-debut/">Tencent&#8217;s e-book spinoff</a>, for failing to report their past acquisition deals for clearance.</p>
<p>The cases involve Alibaba&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/10/alibaba-intime-2-6-billion/">equity investments in major Chinese mall operator Intown</a> and China Literature&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/13/tencent-spinoff-china-literature-to-buy-new-classics-media-for-2-2b-in-content-consolidation-play/">acquisition of film studio New Classics Media</a>. The firms are each subject to a fine of 500,000 yuan ($76,000), according to the notice. Though a paltry amount compared to the size of the companies&#8217; multi-billion-dollar deals, the penalty is expected to sound an alarm to other industry players, a spokesperson for the market regulator <a href="http://www.samr.gov.cn/xw/zj/202012/t20201214_324336.html">said</a> at a press conference.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VMoY12PO7K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/china-antitrust-rules-on-internet-industry/">China proposes antitrust law ahead of Singles&#8217; Day shopping spree</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China proposes antitrust law ahead of Singles&#8217; Day shopping spree&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/china-antitrust-rules-on-internet-industry/embed/#?secret=VMoY12PO7K" data-secret="VMoY12PO7K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Alibaba has in recent years been expanding into offline retail, in part through aggressive acquisitions. Tencent, which has built up a digital entertainment empire, has similarly invested in outside partners to help broaden its territory.</p>
<p>The companies failed to seek regulatory clearance though neither deal was deemed to be &#8220;excluding or restricting market competition.&#8221; As such, the market authority ordered a fine rather than a breakup in accordance with China&#8217;s anti-trust laws, it said.</p>
<p>China Literature says it is strictly following the regulatory order to work on compliance and clearance requirements. Alibaba cannot be immediately reached for comment.</p>
<p>The merger <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/tencent-huya-douyu-merger/">between games streaming giants Huya and Douyu</a>, both Tencent-backed, is also under investigation by the anti-trust regulator.</p>
<p>The Alibaba and China Literature cases mark the first time that China has fined companies structured as &#8220;variable interest entities&#8221; over market concentration violations. The VIE corporate structure is popular among Chinese internet firms for it lets them operate as domestic firms controlled by foreign entities, but the setup is controversial for it has allowed companies to find regulatory loopholes.</p>
<p>The Chinese anti-trust law, which began seeking public comment in January, is currently under revision, the market regulator said at the press event. Last month, the government <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/china-antitrust-rules-on-internet-industry/">unveiled a set of draft rules</a> specifically targeting monopolistic behavior among internet firms, though regulations are expected to be complicated, as industry experts noted.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">&#8230; stop these BigCos when they also clearly provide many benefits, and ofc the geopolitical realities, makes it all very complicated. Will the platforms get more regulated in China? Yes. Will they get broken up? Doesn&#39;t look like it&#39;s going that direction just yet? /end</p>
<p>&mdash; Rui Ma 马睿 (@ruima) <a href="https://twitter.com/ruima/status/1328392087956455427?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/china-literature-alibaba-fined/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086461</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Appboxo gets $1.1 million seed to build a mini-app ecosystem for all developers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/appboxo-gets-1-1-million-seed-to-build-a-mini-app-ecosystem-for-all-developers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/appboxo-gets-1-1-million-seed-to-build-a-mini-app-ecosystem-for-all-developers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appboxo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mini apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pioneered by WeChat almost four years ago, mini-apps are now common in China and India, and gaining traction in other markets, too. Mini-apps, or lightweight apps designed for integration into host apps, allow smartphone users to access several services through one app, saving them data and storage space. They also give host apps more ways [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/09/wechat-mini-programs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pioneered by WeChat</a> almost four years ago, mini-apps are now common in China and India, and gaining traction in other markets, too. Mini-apps, or lightweight apps designed for integration into host apps, allow smartphone users to access several services through one app, saving them data and storage space. They also give host apps more ways to make revenue. But most mini-app ecosystems are currently tied to a specific app or company. <a href="https://appboxo.com/">Appboxo</a>, a Singapore-based startup, wants to make mini-apps more accessible by allowing any developer to turn their app into a &#8220;super app.&#8221;</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/appboxo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="appboxo">Appboxo <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> announced today it has closed $1.1 million in seed funding, led by FF APAC Scout, a Founders Fund vehicle; 500 Startups’ Southeast Asia-focused 500 Durians fund; Plug and Play Ventures; and Antler. The new funding will be used on product development and to add more mini-apps to Appboxo’s ecosystem.</p>
<p>The startup currently works with about 10 host apps, including Booking.com, Klook and Zalora, and has about 80 mini-apps on its platform. Examples of how host apps have used mini-apps include travel apps that added hotel, restaurant and activities bookings; and mobile wallets that integrated insurance-buying and e-commerce services.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Appboxo was founded in 2019 by chief executive officer Kaniyet Rayev and chief technology officer Nursultan Keneshbekov while participating in Antler’s Singapore incubator program. Rayev told TechCrunch that the two initially wanted to build an all-in-one travel app, with different travel-related services integrated into one platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;But when we actually started developing it, we realized there is no easy way to plug in third-party services,&#8221; Rayev said. They began thinking of ways for developers to create and offer mini-apps as a plug-and-play solution.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CwcpX05o56"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/10/india-super-apps/">India&#8217;s most popular services are becoming super apps</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India&#8217;s most popular services are becoming super apps&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/10/india-super-apps/embed/#?secret=CwcpX05o56" data-secret="CwcpX05o56" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The mini-app economy is currently siloed, with apps or companies like WeChat, ByteDance, Meituan, Paytm, PhonePe, Grab and Go-jek either developing mini-apps for their own use, or running mini-app marketplaces for their users. But last year, the W3C Chinese Web Interest Group started looking at ways to standardize mini-apps. The group, including people from Alibaba, Baidu, Huawei, Intel, Xiaomi and China Mobile, <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/mini-app-white-paper/">published the first working draft of its white paper</a> in September 2019 about how mini-apps can be created to work across platforms.</p>
<p>&#8220;It was a really perfect time for us to read that paper, because it was around the time we started our platform,&#8221; said Rayev.</p>
<p>Adding mini-apps can increase engagement because users open apps more frequently if they can access different services through it. It also gives app developers more ways to generate revenue through affiliate partnerships, commissions or transactions fees.</p>
<p>But many native app developers simply don’t have the resources to develop their own mini-apps, so Appboxo simplifies the process with an SDK that allows them to integrate any of its platform&#8217;s mini-apps. A second barrier for many app developers is working out business and development partnership deals with mini-apps, so AppBoxo helps guide them through the process, too.</p>
<p>Since Appboxo is based in Singapore, a lot of its current users in Southeast Asia, and it also plans to target India, too. While mini-apps are less common in Europe and the United States, where most smartphone owners still use apps with one core offering, Rayev said that is starting to change. For example, Uber <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/04/uber-eats-uber-eats/">announced</a> it was merging its ride-hailing and food delivery service, Uber Eats, into one app, last year, while Snap introduced Minis a few months ago.</p>
<p>AppBoxo already has partners in Europe, and &#8220;the whole super app concept is coming to the Western world,&#8221; Rayev added. &#8220;Hopefully we can find some new partners in the rest of the world as well.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="p7DAyBtLdC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/20/snap-turns-on-minis-bite-sized-third-party-apps-in-snapchat/">Snap turns on Minis, bite-sized third-party apps in Snapchat</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Snap turns on Minis, bite-sized third-party apps in Snapchat&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/20/snap-turns-on-minis-bite-sized-third-party-apps-in-snapchat/embed/#?secret=p7DAyBtLdC" data-secret="p7DAyBtLdC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/appboxo-gets-1-1-million-seed-to-build-a-mini-app-ecosystem-for-all-developers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086464</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ola to invest $327M to set up &#8216;the world&#8217;s largest scooter factory&#8217; in Tamil Nadu</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/ola-to-invest-327-million-to-set-up-the-worlds-largest-scooter-factory-in-tamil-nadu/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/ola-to-invest-327-million-to-set-up-the-worlds-largest-scooter-factory-in-tamil-nadu/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 07:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scooter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ola said on Monday that it has signed a memorandum of understanding with the government of Tamil Nadu in India to set up what it claims would be the &#8220;world’s largest scooter manufacturing facility&#8221; in the South Indian state as the Indian ride-hailing firm begins a new push with electric vehicles. The SoftBank-backed Indian ride-hailing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/ola" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="ola">Ola <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said on Monday that it has signed a memorandum of understanding with the government of Tamil Nadu in India to set up what it claims would be the &#8220;world’s largest scooter manufacturing facility&#8221; in the South Indian state as the Indian ride-hailing firm begins a new push with electric vehicles.</p>
<p>The SoftBank-backed Indian ride-hailing firm said it will invest about $327 million in setting up the factory, which it says would create almost 10,000 jobs and have an initial capacity to produce 2 million electric vehicles in a year.</p>
<p>The move comes as Ola plans to launch and expand its two-wheeler electric vehicles in several markets in the next two quarters, according to a person familiar with the matter. Ola Electric, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/28/ola-ev-business-ola-electric-mobility/">spun out of the startup last year</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/ola-electric-acquires-etergo-to-launch-own-line-of-electric-two-wheelers-this-year/">acquired Amsterdam-based Etergo earlier this year</a>. The Dutch has a fleet of scooters that uses swappable, high energy battery that delivers a range of up to 240 km (149 miles). The startup plans to replicate production of similar model of vehicles, the person said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Ola launched its two-wheeler business, which like the cabs business sees someone drive a passenger around, in 2016 and has created livelihoods for over 300,000 people in India. One of India&#8217;s most valuable startups, Ola has made <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/12/ola-bike-150-cities-towns-india/">big bets on two-wheeler in recent years</a> to expand the reach of its services to smaller cities and towns across the country. (Compared to four-wheeler, two-wheeler and three-wheeler offer a much more affordable ride to customers and zip faster in busy traffic.)</p>
<p>In a statement, Ola said the new factory would improve India’s electric vehicle ecosystem and serve customers in Europe, Asia, and Latin American among other markets.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are excited to announce our plans to set up the world’s largest scooter factory. This is a significant milestone for Ola and a proud moment for our country as we rapidly progress towards realising our vision of moving the world to sustainable mobility solutions across shared and owned mobility. This will be one of the most advanced manufacturing facilities in the world. This factory will showcase India’s skill and talent to produce world class products that will cater to global markets,” said Bhavish Aggarwal, Chairman and Group CEO of Ola, in a statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/ola-to-invest-327-million-to-set-up-the-worlds-largest-scooter-factory-in-tamil-nadu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086466</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reddit acquires Dubsmash</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/reddit-acquires-dubsmash/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/reddit-acquires-dubsmash/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dubsmash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reddit announced that it has acquired short video platform Dubsmash. The deal’s terms were undisclosed. Dubsmash will retain its own platform and brand, and Reddit will integrate its video creation tools. Its co-founders, Suchit Dash, Jonas Drüppel and Tim Specht, will join Reddit. According to Crunchbase data, the app has raised $20.2 million from investors [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/reddit" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="reddit">Reddit <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a href="https://redditblog.com/2020/12/13/reddit-welcomes-video-platform-dubsmash-to-team/">announced</a> that it has acquired short video platform <a href="https://dubsmash.com/">Dubsmash</a>. The deal’s terms were undisclosed. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/dubsmash" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="dubsmash">Dubsmash <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> will retain its own platform and brand, and Reddit will integrate its video creation tools. Its co-founders, Suchit Dash, Jonas Drüppel and Tim Specht, will join Reddit.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/dubsmash/company_financials">Crunchbase data</a>, the app has raised $20.2 million from investors including Lowercase Capital, Index Ventures, Eniac Ventures, Heartcore Capital and Sunstone Life.</p>
<p>Dubsmash is now one of TikTok’s biggest rivals, but struggled for several years after a brief stint of popularity in 2015 during its first incarnation as a lip-sync video app. In 2017 it began transforming itself into a social platform and moved its headquarters from Berlin to Brooklyn. By the beginning of this year, Dubsmash’s share of the United States’ short-form video market was second only to TikTok when counted by app installs, and it <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/facebook-snap-held-talks-to-buy-tiktok-rival-dubsmash">reportedly held acquisition talks with Facebook and Snap</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TbFe2pzVAW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/31/dubsmash-songs/">How Dubsmash revived itself as #2 to TikTok</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Dubsmash revived itself as #2 to TikTok&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/31/dubsmash-songs/embed/#?secret=TbFe2pzVAW" data-secret="TbFe2pzVAW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Credit for much of Dubsmash’s success goes to Black and Latinx users. While many of TikTok’s highest-profile stars are white, Dubsmash is known for its large communities of Black and Latinx content creators. The polarization between the two apps began to gain more attention earlier this year, when <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/02/13/style/the-original-renegade.html">the New York Times published a piece</a> about how dance moves by Black Dubsmash stars are frequently appropriated without credit by TikTok influencers, which means their creators miss out on opportunities like larger followings, brand deals and industry connections.</p>
<p>Reddit <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2020/06/reddit-racism-open-letter/612958/">has its own issues with racism</a>, and has been criticized for not doing enough to stop hate speech or giving moderators of subreddits targeted by racist trolls enough support.</p>
<p>Last year, founder and former chief executive officer Alexis Ohanian called for his position on Reddit’s board to be filled with a Black candidate when he stepped down, which current CEO Steve Huffman said the company would honor as part of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/announcements/comments/gxas21/upcoming_changes_to_our_content_policy_our_board/">a larger effort to address hate speech on the platform</a> announced during anti-racism demonstrations after the killing of George Floyd by a police officer. Ohanian’s position was filled by Y Combinator CEO Michael Seibel.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="q6o5L1qzvn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/reddit-names-ycs-michael-seibel-to-board-following-co-founder-alexis-ohanians-exit/">Reddit names YC’s Michael Seibel to board, following co-founder Alexis Ohanian’s exit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Reddit names YC’s Michael Seibel to board, following co-founder Alexis Ohanian’s exit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/reddit-names-ycs-michael-seibel-to-board-following-co-founder-alexis-ohanians-exit/embed/#?secret=q6o5L1qzvn" data-secret="q6o5L1qzvn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In its announcement today, Reddit linked its acquisition of Dubsmash to its inclusion efforts, acknowledging that the app’s &#8220;communities are driven by young, diverse creators—about 25 percent of all Black teens in the U.S. are on Dubsmash, and females represent 70 percent of users.&#8221;</p>
<p>It also said the integration of Dubsmash’s video creation tools will enable Reddit’s users to &#8220;express themselves in original and authentic ways that are endemic to our communities.&#8221;</p>
<p>Since <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/08/17/reddit-rolls-out-its-own-video-platform/">launching native videos in 2017</a>, Reddit said usage has increased sharply, growing 2X in 2020 alone. Much of Reddit’s content is still text-based, however, with video, gifs and images often shared from other sources, so Dubsmash’s integration can help Reddit build out its own video platform.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/reddit-acquires-dubsmash/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086455</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An even bigger battle for gig worker rights is on the horizon</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 15:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig workers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prop 22]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ride hailing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the year ahead, we'll likely see lobbying efforts from both gig companies and gig worker organizations — as well as more lawsuits.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When California voters passed Proposition 22 with 58.6% of the vote, they agreed with Uber, Lyft, DoorDash, Instacart and Postmates that gig workers should not be employees who are entitled to myriad labor rights. The proposition they passed stated that gig workers should be independent contractors who receive the limited benefits proposed by those companies.</p>
<p>&#8220;The first feeling I had was shock, disbelief and hurt,&#8221; Vanessa Bain, a worker-organizer with Gig Workers Collective, told TechCrunch. &#8220;It didn&#8217;t feel good to think that my fellow Californians voted to strip people like myself and my co-workers of our labor rights.&#8221;</p>
<p>But Prop 22 does not mark the end of the battle of the status of gig workers. Gig workers, lawyers and activists affiliated with Gig Workers Rising, Gig Workers Collective, the National Employment Law Project and the Working Partnerships for Families are all gearing up to redouble their efforts in the New Year. But the same goes for gig companies. Uber and Lyft are ready to take legislation similar to Prop 22 into other parts of the country and the world.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			In the year ahead, we will likely see lobbying efforts from both gig companies and gig worker organizations alike, as well as more lawsuits.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>&#8220;We didn&#8217;t have time for more grieving because as soon as it passed, every company signaled they&#8217;re looking to expand this model to the national level, which means our organizing needs to adjust accordingly,&#8221; Bain said.</p>
<p>So, really, the fight has just begun. In the year ahead, we will likely see lobbying efforts from both gig companies and gig worker organizations alike, as well as more lawsuits.</p>
<hr />
<p>In 2019, the California state legislature passed Assembly Bill 5, which became law in January 2020.</p>
<p>AB 5 mandated that companies apply the ABC test to determine how to classify their workers. According to the ABC test, in order for a hiring entity to legally classify a worker as an independent contractor, it must prove the worker:</p>
<ul>
<li>A — is free from the control and direction of the hiring entity.</li>
<li>B — performs work outside the scope of the entity’s business, and</li>
<li>C — is regularly engaged in an “independently established trade, occupation or business of the same nature as the work performed.”</li>
</ul>
<p>Many have argued that gig economy companies do not pass the ABC test, while the companies themselves have, of course, argued that they do. As AB 5 made its way through the state legislature, gig companies banded together with their competitors to fight a collective enemy: labor rights for their respective workforces.</p>
<p>In August 2019, Uber and Lyft kicked off that fight with an initial $60 million put toward the ballot measure now known as Prop 22. Between August 2019 and November 2020, that number skyrocketed to around $205 million and brought in contributions from other companies like Postmates (now owned by Uber), Instacart and DoorDash. All that funding makes Proposition 22 the most expensive ballot measure in California since 1999.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2069448" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069448" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2069448 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229135593.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="688" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229135593.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229135593.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229135593.jpg?resize=300,202 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229135593.jpg?resize=768,516 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229135593.jpg?resize=680,457 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229135593.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069448" class="wp-caption-text">Uber driver Sergei Fyodorov discusses why he supports a yes vote on Proposition 22 in Oakland, California on October 9, 2020. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> JOSH EDELSON/AFP via Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>On the other side, major donors in opposition of Prop 22 included Service Employees International Union, United Food &amp; Commercial Workers and International Brotherhood of Teamsters. They collectively contributed $15.9 million.</p>
<p>The ballot measure, which goes into effect this month, implements a few key benefits:</p>
<ul>
<li>An earnings guarantee of at least 120% of minimum wage while picking up or dropping off passengers.</li>
<li>30 cents per engaged mile for expenses.</li>
<li>A healthcare stipend.</li>
<li>Occupational accident insurance for on-the-job injuries.</li>
<li>Automobile accident and liability insurance.</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p>Ahead of the Prop 22 vote, Cherri Murphy, a ride-share driver for Uber and Lyft and lead organizer at Gig Workers Rising, was heavily involved in Gig Workers Rising&#8217;s efforts to combat the millions of dollars tech companies put into ensuring gig workers would be classified as independent contractors.</p>
<p>&#8220;We had a hell of a fight,&#8221; Murphy told TechCrunch. &#8220;We were up against a $205 million campaign but I still had to believe that we could win.&#8221;<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081210</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Original Content podcast: David Fincher presents a compelling character study in &#8216;Mank&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/original-content-mank/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/original-content-mank/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Original Content podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Mank&#8221; is a change of pace for director David Fincher — instead of exploring the world of startup backstabbing (&#8220;The Social Network&#8221;), political backstabbing (&#8220;House of Cards&#8221;) or actual stabbings (&#8220;Seven,&#8221; &#8220;Zodiac,&#8221; &#8220;Gone Girl,&#8221; &#8220;Mindhunter&#8221; etc.), Fincher takes us back to &#8217;30s and &#8217;40s Hollywood. Working from a script by Fincher&#8217;s late father Jack, the movie [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;Mank&#8221; is a change of pace for director David Fincher — instead of exploring the world of startup backstabbing (&#8220;The Social Network&#8221;), political backstabbing (&#8220;House of Cards&#8221;) or actual stabbings (&#8220;Seven,&#8221; &#8220;Zodiac,&#8221; &#8220;Gone Girl,&#8221; &#8220;Mindhunter&#8221; etc.), Fincher takes us back to &#8217;30s and &#8217;40s Hollywood.</p>
<p>Working from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/11/david-fincher-mank-netflix/">a script by Fincher&#8217;s late father Jack</a>, the movie is shot and edited to pay homage to the classic studio films of that era — especially &#8220;Citizen Kane,&#8221; whose co-writer Herman Mankiewicz (played by Gary Oldman) is the &#8220;Mank&#8221; of the film&#8217;s title.</p>
<p>The story jumps back-and-forth in time, showing how Mank became acquainted — and then disillusioned — with newspaper tycoon William Randolph Hearst (Charles Dance) and his mistress Marion Davies (Amanda Seyfried), and how he drew on that knowledge while writing &#8220;Kane&#8221; for Orson Welles (Tom Burke).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That might not sound like a particularly dramatic setup for a film — as we acknowledge in the latest episode of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/original-content-podcast/">the Original Content podcast</a>, &#8220;Mank&#8221;&#8216;s self-consciously old-fashioned filmmaking and its making-of-a-movie premise can make it feel a bit insider-y, like it&#8217;s footnote to another film.</p>
<p>But ultimately, the movie works whether or not you&#8217;ve seen &#8220;Citizen Kane.&#8221; Fincher captures both the glamor and the ugliness of the studio system, while Oldman delivers a mesmerizing performance as a talented writer who&#8217;s been content to joke and drink away his talent — until he finds himself driven to write one of the greatest movies of all time, which will turn many of his former friends and allies into enemies.</p>
<p>In addition to reviewing &#8220;Mank,&#8221; we also discuss the ambitious streaming plans that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-investor-day/">Disney outlined at its investor day this week</a>.</p>
<p>You can listen to our review in the player below, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/original-content/id1271763098" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">subscribe using Apple Podcasts</a> or find us in your podcast player of choice. If you like the show, please let us know by leaving a review on Apple. You can also <a href="https://twitter.com/originalcontent">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="mailto:originalcontent@techcrunch.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">send us feedback directly</a>. (Or suggest shows and movies for us to review!)</p>
<p><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/9e3f9520-773c-4249-9a6f-47497c0e0d44?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/original-content-mank/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086423</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: Strange Days Indeed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/gillmor-gang-strange-days-indeed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/gillmor-gang-strange-days-indeed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 23:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086426</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The place we’re in, the valley of the dolls between the vote and the Inauguration, is overshadowed by the battle to save our lives. The vaccines look promising, and so does the persistence of the Trumpster to play his games. Somehow we have to live with that, on both sides. In the business we’re in, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/ue2LJZFHQMU?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>The place we’re in, the valley of the dolls between the vote and the Inauguration, is overshadowed by the battle to save our lives. The vaccines look promising, and so does the persistence of the Trumpster to play his games. Somehow we have to live with that, on both sides. In the business we’re in, the technology industry, broadband has penetrated to the point we can survive with a reasonable degree of fidelity to the world COVID erased.</p>
<p>This week’s move by WarnerMedia to release all 2021 pictures on HBO Max and in theaters is both a capitulation to reality and a political gambit to negotiate with theater owners. Disney, with their theme parks and investments in streaming crescendoing in layoffs and rebuilding, announced a mix of 80% streaming with only 20% theatrical. Trump’s TikTok deadline has already passed, and the administration is pretending to not pay attention in order to keep negotiations for a buyout alive. The incoming government talks of a working bromance between Biden and McConnell. It’s the opposite of reality TV, or TV reality.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Newsletters straddle mainstream and social media, rolling up links that blur the credibility of publications with the Wild West of uncredentialed freelancers. Some of these voices are playing the newsletter sweepstakes, choosing to move from a salaried position to their own subscription model. For those publications funded in part by a paywall, the transition to a newsletter comes with opportunity and risk. Selling a subscription for a single voice competes with the bundled voices of a paywall publication eventually diluting potential readers’ available funds. We’re seeing this same subscription saturation dynamic in the rise of streaming networks.</p>
<p>Another trend, notification-based news, is making inroads with live streaming over social networks. The pandemic has forced many students into working from home over Zoom for interactive sessions mixed with traditional lecture-type webinars. Events normally covered by trade publications have yielded at least for now to influencer and analyst driven watch parties. Podcasts forego subscription and advertiser revenue for lead generation and industry traction. The 24/7 nature of work from anywhere fights for eyelid time with binge viewing, listening, and reading.</p>
<p>Beyond the virus’s impact on audiences, the productions themselves have new challenges. The FX series Fargo ceased production in March, as did ABC’s Grey’s Anatomy. When you see the completed shows, it’s fascinating to try and guess which scenes were shot under the much tighter strictures of the fall. Grey’s Anatomy used the pandemic as a plot point, but it took a few shows for the actors to settle into a more relaxed rhythm. Pre-pandemic footage from the abbreviated series’ previous season lived uncomfortably alongside the new material to cover the transitional story line.</p>
<p>Citizen Kane, considered broadly as the best film Hollywood ever made, spawned a Netflix production about the author of the screenplay, one Herman J. Mankiewicz. Presented in black and white with Kane-like musical scoring and the original film’s innovations in deep focus photography and low angle shots that include the ceilings of sets, the story uses flashbacks and time-jumping to great effect. It’s streaming meets MGM’s catch phrase from the time: All the stars in the heavens. Director David Fincher tells the New York Times how he overshoots by 20% the number of pixels so he can post process and polish the rough edges and camera jiggles into a precise reflection of the intricate vision of his cinema universe.</p>
<p>40 years ago this week John Lennon was murdered by a troubled fan. I was watching Monday Night football when Howard Cosell broke in with the news. What was left of my childhood vanished in that moment. I was newly divorced, struggling to keep my momentum going, no idea of what our world would become, and stupid with sadness over someone I’d never met. The Beatles was this magic machine, a coalition of the fleeting imperfection of the group and the unifying perfection of what they had accomplished.</p>
<p>The days tick by. The vaccine trucks roll. The Supreme Court denies another desperate move to overturn the will of the people. Nobody told me there’d be days like these. Strange days indeed.</p>
<p style="text-align: center">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/frank-radice" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="frank-radice">Frank Radice, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/michael-markman-6388" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="michael-markman-6388">Michael Markman, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/keith-teare" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="keith-teare">Keith Teare, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/denis-pombriant" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="denis-pombriant">Denis Pombriant, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/brent-leary" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="brent-leary">Brent Leary, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/steve-gillmor" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="steve-gillmor">Steve Gillmor <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>. Recorded live Friday, December 4, 2020.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p>For more, <a href="https://gillmorgang.substack.com">subscribe to the Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> &#8230; and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/gillmor-gang-strange-days-indeed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086426</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Human Capital: Dr. Timnit Gebru says Google&#8217;s memo was &#8216;dehumanizing&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/human-capital-dr-timnit-gebru-says-googles-memo-was-dehumanizing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/human-capital-dr-timnit-gebru-says-googles-memo-was-dehumanizing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 23:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Human Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to Human Capital, where I break down the latest in diversity, equity and inclusion, and labor in tech. This week, Twitter dropped its latest diversity report and Tesla released its first one ever. Meanwhile, Google CEO Sundar Pichai apologized for the way things went down with Dr. Timnit Gebru, a prominent researcher in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Welcome back to Human Capital, where I break down the latest in diversity, equity and inclusion, and labor in tech. This week, Twitter dropped its latest diversity report and Tesla released its first one ever. Meanwhile, Google CEO Sundar Pichai apologized for the way things went down with Dr. Timnit Gebru, a prominent researcher in artificial intelligence ethics.</p>
<p>Sign up here to get this as a weekly newsletter in your inbox every Friday at 1 p.m.</p>
<p><b>Google’s Sundar Pichai will investigate events that led up to Dr. Timnit Gebru’s exit</b></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In light of artificial intelligence researcher Dr. Timnit Gebru’s exit from Google last week, Google </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/google-ceo-says-company-will-review-events-leading-up-to-dr-timnit-gebrus-departure/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO Sundar Pichai sent a memo to staffers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.axios.com/sundar-pichai-memo-timnit-gebru-exit-18b0efb0-5bc3-41e6-ac28-2956732ed78b.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">obtained by Axios</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, saying the company would investigate “the circumstances that led up to Dr. Gebru’s departure, examining where we could have improved and led a more respectful process.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Pichai’s memo, he said the company needs to “accept responsibility for the fact that a prominent Black, female leader with immense talent left Google unhappily.” He also noted how it’s had a “ripple effect” through underrepresented communities at Google.</span></p>
<p>In response, <a href="https://twitter.com/timnitGebru/status/1336777379730116615">on Twitte</a>r, Gebru said she didn&#8217;t see any plans for accountability. Instead, she said she saw &#8220;further gaslighting.&#8221; In an <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/12/10/timnit-gebru-googles-dehumanizing-memo-paints-me-as-an-angry-black-woman/">interview with Venture Beat, </a>Gebru said Pichai&#8217;s memo is &#8220;dehumanizing&#8221; and makes her &#8220;sound like an angry Black woman.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p>They paint me as this angry Black woman because they put you in this terrible workplace, and if you speak up about it, then you become a problem, and then they start talking about de-escalation strategies.</p>
<p>You write emails, they get ignored. You write documents, and they get ignored. Then you discuss how it’s being done and then they talk about you as if you’re like some angry Black woman who needs to be contained.</p></blockquote>
<p><b>More Black women and Latinas are founding startups, according to Project Diane</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since 2018, the number of Black women and Latina founders doubled from 334 startups to more than 650, </span><a href="https://www.projectdiane.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">according to Project Diane</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. These women have also raised more money than they did in 2018, but they’re still raising less than the national average. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This year, Black women and Latina founders raised $3.1 billion compared to just $1 billion in 2018. Still, the median seed round for Black women is $125,000 and $200,000 for Latina founders, while the national median seed is $2.5 million.</span></p>
<p><b>Tesla finally released a diversity report</b></p>
<p><a href="https://www.tesla.com/sites/default/files/downloads/2020-DEI-impact-report.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tesla released its first-ever diversity report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, showing the company is 34% white, 22% Hispanic, 10% Black, 21% Asian and 7% “additional groups” in the United States. Those breakdowns are not bad, but it’s worth noting Tesla employs many of those folks in its factories, which are </span><a href="https://qz.com/1756552/tesla-workers-report-a-racist-work-environment-at-new-york-factory/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">notoriously</span></a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/30/business/tesla-factory-racism.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">problematic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and have been the subject of allegations around racism and discrimination.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the leadership level, Tesla is 59% white, 25% Asian, 4% Black and 4% Hispanic. Just 1% of those in leadership roles are from “additional groups.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, Tesla’s gender diversity is objectively bad. Men account for 79% of Tesla’s overall workplace and 83% of its leaders in the United States.</span></p>
<p><b>Twitter shows slight improvement in latest diversity report</b></p>
<p><a href="https://careers.twitter.com/en/tweep-life/diversity.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Twitter released its latest quarterly diversity report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> showing an increase in the representation of women, Black, Latinx and multiracial employees across the whole company. Additionally, representation of women and Black people increased at the leadership level. Despite those gains, Twitter is still 56.7% male and 41% white. </span></p>
<p><b>Uber wants drivers and delivery workers to get priority access to COVID-19 vaccine</b></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/uber-wants-drivers-and-delivery-workers-to-get-priority-access-to-covid-19-vaccine/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi sent a letter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to all 50 governors asking them to prioritize giving drivers and delivery workers the vaccine as essential workers. In the letter, Khosrowshahi argues that the work of drivers and delivery people has become essential. That&#8217;s why Uber wants them to get the vaccine &#8220;quickly, easily and for free,&#8221; he wrote in the letter. Additionally, Uber has offered to help share information about the vaccine and encouraging those who are eligible to get vaccinated.</span></p>
<p><b>Apple was reportedly complicit in violating Chinese labor laws</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Three former Apple Supplier Responsibility employees </span><a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/apple-turned-blind-eye-to-supplier-breaches-of-chinese-labor-laws?utm_content=article-5108&amp;utm_campaign=article_email&amp;utm_source=sg&amp;utm_medium=email"><span style="font-weight: 400;">recently said the company</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> did nothing when its suppliers violated the temporary worker labor law in China. That law required that no more than 10% of a factory’s workforce be temporary workers. According to The Information, Apple didn’t take action because it was worried about an increase in costs, a drain on resources and delays in product launches. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/human-capital-dr-timnit-gebru-says-googles-memo-was-dehumanizing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086135</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to find your next VC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/how-to-find-your-next-vc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/how-to-find-your-next-vc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 21:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[braze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s broadly based on the daily column that appears on Extra Crunch, but free, and made for your weekend reading. Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Subscribe here.  Ready? Let’s talk money, startups and spicy IPO rumors. Welcome to the depths of December, a time in which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange,<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/chris-dean" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="person" data-entity="chris-dean"> a </a>weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s broadly based on </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/"><em>the daily column that appears on Extra Crunch</em></a><em>, but free, and made for your weekend reading. Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Subscribe <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">here</a>. </em></p>
<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Ready? Let’s talk money, startups and spicy IPO rumors.</em></p>
<div class="newsletter__block__body">
<div class="newsletter__block__body-text">
<p>Welcome to the depths of December, a time in which the news cycle should be slowing down. Instead it’s accelerating, giving me the firm worry that our holiday cycle is going to be mostly work this year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Regardless, we have no time for my usual bullshitting, so let’s get right to work.<b> First up: How to find your next venture capitalist.</b></p>
<p>There’s a VC firm called <a href="https://www.newstack.vc/">New Stack</a> that focuses on leading first institutional rounds into startups that are not based in San Francisco and New York. As you can imagine, part of its job is helping its portfolio companies — <a href="https://www.newstack.vc/#portfolio">here</a>, in case you wanted to peek — find their next investor.</p>
<p>So, New Stack’s Nate Pierotti tells The Exchange, his team crafts next-round plans with their portfolio companies so that the startups can avoid wasting time when they go out to raise a new round. Per Pierotti, these plans are popular with both founders and VCs alike.</p>
<p>A bit ago New Stack asked around 400 founders what their venture pain points are, an exercise that I presume many VCs execute to better understand their market. Something that came out of the study was that many founders wanted help finding their next investor.</p>
<p>In light of the results, New Stack decided to help, putting together a public version of their next-round tool. It’s called Venture Rank, and <a href="https://www.vc-rank.com/">you can check it out here</a>. If you tell it about your startup, it will suggest some funds to talk to, with over 1,700 in its database.</p>
<p>Why bring all this up? Aside from always looking for an excuse to cover Midwest startup activity, we spend a lot of time in this newsletter talking about companies busy leaving their venture capital days behind them. Here was a chance to talk about a resource that founders still in the venture mix can actually use.</p>
<p>The Exchange: <b>Not</b> just public SaaS multiples!</p>
<div class="newsletter__block">
<div class="newsletter__block__header">
<h2>Market Notes, Market News</h2>
</div>
<div class="newsletter__block__body">
<div class="newsletter__block__body-text">
<p>I presume that by now you are caught up on all things <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/doordash" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="doordash">DoorDash <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> IPO (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/doordash-ipo-pricing/">pricing</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">trading</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/how-doordash-and-c3-ai-can-defend-their-red-hot-ipo-valuatons/">the future</a>), C3.ai (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/the-ipo-market-looks-hot-as-airbnb-and-c3-ai-raise-price-targets/">pricing</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/how-doordash-and-c3-ai-can-defend-their-red-hot-ipo-valuatons/">trading</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/how-doordash-and-c3-ai-can-defend-their-red-hot-ipo-valuatons">the future</a>), and Airbnb (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/airbnb-said-to-price-ipo-between-67-and-68/">pricing</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/">trading</a>). What follows presumes you are read-up.</p>
<p>To kick off Market Notes this weeks, some Market News: <a href="https://www.braze.com/">Braze</a> has grown 60% during the first three quarters of its fiscal year.</p>
<p>Sadly, while the New York-based customer engagement software startup joined the $100 million ARR club <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/13/the-newest-members-of-the-100m-arr-club/">just under a year ago</a>, we can’t just say that it’s at $160 million ARR today. Why not? The company has moved to counting GAAP revenue instead of ARR, so its growth number doesn’t correspond to the old metric.</p>
<p>And the time period for the 60% figure ran from February 2020 through October (it’s common for SaaS companies to start their fiscal year after January so that their fourth quarters don’t wrap up right after Christmas). But I <i>would not</i> be surprised if <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/braze" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="braze">Braze <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> was at an ARR mark of $160 million or more.</p>
<p>According to its CEO, Bill Magnuson, the company has not raised funds since its October 2018-era Series E worth $80 million. The startup has been growing quickly, without the need to take on more capital to fund its growth.</p>
<p>What impact has COVID-19 had on the company? Magnuson said that Braze was probably ahead of its pre-COVID plan, but that it has re-forecasted on a rolling basis this year as the economy has changed. On the customer front, the CEO said that growth may have been similar without COVID, but different. He used an analogy of a balloon, COVID squeezed some parts of the balloon — market sectors in our analogy — but also enlarged some other parts of the balloon at the same time. Same balloon volume post-COVID, but a different market shape.</p>
<p>Is the move to GAAP indicative of a move towards an IPO? Not really, Magnuson said. Braze likes to compare its results to those of other companies to see how it can improve and where, he added, so having standard metrics helps.</p>
<p>But let’s be clear: Braze is big enough to go public, doesn’t burn that much money, and is watching companies go out at nigh-comical multiples. Surely the temptation is there.</p>
<p>And speaking of IPOs, let’s talk about a few. I got on the horn with a different players from the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/airbnb" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="airbnb">Airbnb <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and DoorDash debuts this week, which I have condensed to their respective key points for today in the honor of space:<b></b></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Why DoorDash’s CFO is bullish on post-pandemic consumer demand:</b> Talking to Prabir Adarkar was good fun as he is both voluble and limpid. That is an excellent combination in a person from which you hope to learn something. I wanted to know what DoorDash was thinking about post-pandemic demand for food delivery. I have a slightly pessimistic take. Adarkar, as you expected, is more bullish. After discussing how the company’s huge IPO will provide the company with a cushion as it looks to more deeply penetrate the food market, and expand into new verticals, we got around to the point. The CFO argued that once users have downloaded the DoorDash app and used it a few times, it’s very sticky. He expects that stickiness to persist even after COVID-19 is behind us. And, he added, more restaurants have joined in the last few months, so the service has itself improved. That could help keep users engaged when they are allowed outside.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><b>Why Airbnb’s chief strategy officer (CSO) is bullish on post-pandemic consumer demand:</b> Nathan Blecharczyk, one of Airbnb’s founders and CSO, talked The Exchange through his company’s post-pandemic demand thesis. First, travel will return as soon as people are allowed to go outside. That’s good for Airbnb. And, he said, Zoom is not going away — people may take a long weekend in an Airbnb and work the Friday and relax during the weekend, for example. With international travel coming back, and a cultural shift toward remote work, Airbnb could wind up with a larger marker in 2021 than it had in 2019. We’ll see.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><b>Sequoia partner Alfred Lin on this week’s IPO pricing and results:</b> Finally from our call log, an investor. Sequoia was in both DoorDash and Airbnb, with Lin on the board of each. We chatted a bit about the IPOs, a convo from which something stood out. Lin explained, in response to my questions about the extreme prices that some IPOs were commanding after their debuts, that Airbnb had been expensive during its private life, as well. You have to pay up sometimes for the standouts, the argument seemed to go. From a venture perspective, I vibe with the point. From a public investor perspective, I understand it less. But that’s why the stock market is fun.</li>
</ul>
<p>Before we catch up on some small things, after I covered <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/okr-focused-koan-raises-1m-adds-free-tier/">OKR-focused Koan raising another $1 million</a>, OKR-focused <a href="https://www.ally.io/">Ally.io</a> — <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/ally-raises-15m-series-b-to-scale-its-okr-focused-service/">which I have written about before</a> — reached out with some data on its growth. A sucker for such information, here’s the gist: Ally grew its revenues 3.3x in 2020, adding 500 customers in the process and seeing 145 expansions from existing customers. Ally cited a need for more planning tools for a hybrid (office and remote) working world as a driver of demand. Koan declared a similar situation as its impetus for releasing a free tier of its software.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/21/why-is-everyone-making-okr-software/">OKR market was hot earlier this year</a>. I suppose it still is.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="newsletter__block">
<div class="newsletter__block__header">
<div id="wpcontent">
<div id="wpbody" role="main">
<div id="wpbody-content">
<div class="wrap">
<div class="newsletter__preview-container newsletter__template--exchange">
<div class="newsletter__block">
<div class="newsletter__block__header">
<h2>Various and Sundry</h2>
</div>
<div class="newsletter__block__body">
<div class="newsletter__block__body-text">
<p>Alright. In no particular order, here are some very interesting things from this week that I could not write whole posts about:</p>
<ul>
<li>Denver-based <a href="https://range.vc/">Range Ventures</a> has put together a $23 million fund. Why do we care? It’s focused on Denver. I did not know that the Denver scene was mature enough to warrant its own firm. I suppose I am behind on this one.</li>
<li>Brazilian software company <a href="https://www.intelipost.com.br/en/">Intelipost</a> raised $32 million this week, led by Riverwood Capital. E-commerce and logistics are hot in 2020, and Intelipost does both. This is one to keep an eye on.</li>
<li>Chicago’s <a href="https://cardr.com/">CarDr</a> raised $5 million in what it calls “launch and seed funding” from Red Fort Capital. The startup uses AI to help its team execute car diagnostics — hence, calling itself Car Doctor. According to the company, it sells to consumers, dealers, and banks alike. And the startup has earmarked about 75% of its new capital for engineering expenses, which implies that it has lots more to build in the future (a good thing, mind.) On the economics front, the company told The Exchange that it has good margins, but that they work out to be slightly lower than some SaaS companies due to the cost of AI computing time. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/21/do-ai-startups-have-worse-economics-than-saas-shops/">We’ve written about that</a>!</li>
<li>API-security focused <a href="https://salt.security/">Salt Security</a> raised $30 million this week. I am a dork for all things API, so to see the API-security space raise this much in a single round caught my attention. Sequoia led the Series B. Salt raised a $20 million Series A in June. (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/skyflow-raises-17-5m-more-to-help-companies-protect-your-personal-data/">The trend of two rounds in 2020 continues</a>!)</li>
<li>A startup named <a href="https://www.beyondidentity.com/">Beyond Identity</a> raised $75 million this week. I am at a loss regarding what “passwordless” identity means, but I hope it works, as I constantly need to update my Okta password, which makes me sad.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.adaventures.com/">Ada Ventures</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/ada-ventures-closes-first-fund-at-50m-investing-in-diverse-founders-tacking-societys-problems/">closed a $50 million fund</a>. The European group intends “to invest in diverse founders tacking societal problems.” Hard to not be into that mission.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now it’s time to put on some heavy metal, play Civ 6, and not think about news for a bit.</p>
<p>Hugs —</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/how-to-find-your-next-vc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086246</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investors double down on tech stocks in massive DoorDash, Airbnb, C3.ai IPOs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/investors-double-down-on-tech-stocks-in-massive-doordash-airbnb-ipos/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/investors-double-down-on-tech-stocks-in-massive-doordash-airbnb-ipos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Eldon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 19:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups Weekly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086272</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Editor’s note: Get this free weekly recap of TechCrunch news that any startup can use by email every Saturday morning (7 a.m. PT). Subscribe here. Maybe it is a stock market bubble, or a tech-stock bubble at least. And maybe DoorDash, Airbnb and C3.ai and their bankers should have priced higher regardless to take advantage of all [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><strong>Editor’s note:<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/bilal-zuberi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="person" data-entity="bilal-zuberi"> </a></strong><em>Get this free weekly recap of TechCrunch news that any startup can use by email every Saturday morning (7 a.m. PT). <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters?_ga=2.28241148.139228165.1581112174-1679447956.1560885729">Subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Maybe it is a stock market bubble, or a tech-stock bubble at least. And maybe DoorDash, Airbnb and C3.ai and their bankers should have priced higher regardless to take advantage of all of the enthusiasm. It&#8217;s hard to avoid reactions like that, after DoorDash, for example, doubled its final private share price to $102 for its public debut on Wednesday — only to see the price climb to $175 at the end of the week.</p>
<p>Or maybe none of this will matter, because the future is way bigger and the companies are going to get there regardless. That&#8217;s what <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/early-doordash-investor-dismisses-froth-talk-says-company-could-grow-10x-from-here/">Saar Gur tells Connie Loizos</a> this week about DoorDash, which he had invested in many years ago:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>I actually started my career at Lehman Brothers on the investment banking team, and so having seen the IPO process, while I can appreciate [frustration that a] company left some money on the table based on the pricing, the tactical challenge [is that] it’s very hard to predict. You know what the market will bear once it moves to retail investors.</p>
<p>What’s exciting to me is [that] DoorDash is raising money because they are just getting started. I do think this could be a $500 billion-plus company. There’s so much to be excited about. As for the capital-raising event, I think it’s hard for the bankers to know where it will land with the broader market, so I’m not as negative as maybe some others.</p></blockquote>
<p>Here&#8217;s the blow-by-blow coverage of the craziest tech IPO week in the craziest (IPO) year in decades, resuming from where I left off last Friday:</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/doordash-amps-its-ipo-range-ahead-of-blockbuster-ipo/">DoorDash amps its IPO range ahead of blockbuster IPO</a> (EC)</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/the-ipo-market-looks-hot-as-airbnb-and-c3-ai-raise-price-targets/">The IPO market looks hot as Airbnb and C3.ai raise price targets</a> (EC)</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/wish-wants-to-be-the-amazon-for-the-rest-of-us-will-retail-investors-buy-it/">Wish wants to be the Amazon for the rest of us; will retail investors buy it?</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/doordash-ipo-pricing/">DoorDash said to price at $102 per share, doubling its final private price</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/airbnb-said-to-price-ipo-between-67-and-68/">Airbnb said to price IPO between $67 and $68</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/as-several-marketplace-unicorns-prepare-ipos-a-vc-digs-into-the-data/">While several marketplace unicorns prepare IPOs, a VC digs into the data</a> (EC)</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">DoorDash, C3.ai skyrocket in public market debuts</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/how-doordash-and-c3-ai-can-defend-their-red-hot-ipo-valuatons/">How DoorDash and C3.ai can defend their red-hot IPO valuations</a> (EC)</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/">Airbnb’s first-day pop caps off a stellar week for tech IPOs</a> (EC)</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/in-public-and-private-markets-cloud-earnings-and-valuations-heat-up/">In public and private markets, cloud earnings and valuations heat up</a> (EC)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2086337" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086337" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2086337" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-5.25.13-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="482" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-5.25.13-PM.png 2156w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-5.25.13-PM.png?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-5.25.13-PM.png?resize=300,141 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-5.25.13-PM.png?resize=768,361 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-5.25.13-PM.png?resize=680,320 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-5.25.13-PM.png?resize=1536,722 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-5.25.13-PM.png?resize=2048,963 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-5.25.13-PM.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086337" class="wp-caption-text">Photo via Natasha Mascarenhas</p></div></p>
<h2>Meet Natasha Mascarenhas, your future Startups Weekly newsletter author</h2>
<p>The year is coming to a close for my time writing this newsletter, too. I&#8217;m going to be returning full-time to my regular job editing Extra Crunch and stuff in the back offices here at TechCrunch virtual HQ. My colleague <a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/natasha-mascarenhas/">Natasha Mascarenhas</a> will be taking over starting next week.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re in good hands. In fact you may have noticed many of her articles and her weekly contributions to Equity showing up here already. Since joining us from Crunchbase News earlier this year, she&#8217;s been covering early-stage startups and the San Francisco tech scene in general, with a big focus on edtech. We have a lot more planned across Equity, Extra Crunch and more, and she&#8217;ll be able to tie it all together around her daily coverage. Stay tuned for an action-packed 2021 (and <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">follow her on Twitter in the meantime</a>).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2086330" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nextiva-screenshot.png" alt="" width="1024" height="708" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nextiva-screenshot.png 2764w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nextiva-screenshot.png?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nextiva-screenshot.png?resize=300,208 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nextiva-screenshot.png?resize=768,531 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nextiva-screenshot.png?resize=680,470 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nextiva-screenshot.png?resize=1536,1063 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nextiva-screenshot.png?resize=2048,1417 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nextiva-screenshot.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<h2>How to bootstrap to $200m+ in revenue</h2>
<p>Alex Wilhelm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/05/how-one-company-reached-revenues-of-200m-without-vc-money/">hears from one startup founder</a> who has taken a bit of an alternative approach to building a SaaS company. Here&#8217;s more:</p>
<blockquote><p>Now north of $200 million in revenue, [<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/nextiva" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="organization" data-entity="nextiva">Nextiva</a>] is a quiet giant and, notably, has not taken venture capital funding along its path to scale. Chatting with CEO and co-founder Tomas Gorny, I got to dig a little under the skin of the company’s history. It goes a little something like this: After moving to California in 1996 at the age of 20, Gorny eventually founded a web hosting company in 2001 after working for tech companies during the dot-com boom. The web hosting company wound up selling to another company <a href="https://www.pehub.com/endurance-buys-ipower/">called Endurance International in 2007</a>, which sold as a combined entity for around a billion dollars in 2011, later going public before <a href="https://clearlake.com/endurance-international-group-announces-agreement-to-be-acquired-by-clearlake-capital-group-l-p-for-9-50-per-share/">being taken private</a> last month for $3 billion — you can read this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2010/01/26/weebly-web-host-endurance/">TechCrunch piece that mentions Endurance from 2010</a> for a bit of the historical record.</p>
<p>Gorny founded Nextiva in 2008, focused on what it describes today as “UcaaS,” or unified communications as a service. The startup grew to about $40 million in annual recurring revenue (ARR), at which point it ran into issues with a third-party system that would integrate hardware, and support and services software, which sparked a shift in its thinking. The company set out to build a platform.</p>
<p>Nextiva expanded horizontally, adding CRM software, analytics and other functionality to its broader suite as it scaled. And it grew efficiently; starting with money from its founding team, Gorny told TechCrunch that even if he had used someone else’s money, he would have built the company in the same manner.</p></blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1791263" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-155389485.jpg" alt="digitally generated image of money tornado." width="1024" height="651" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-155389485.jpg 5760w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-155389485.jpg?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-155389485.jpg?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-155389485.jpg?resize=768,488 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-155389485.jpg?resize=680,432 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-155389485.jpg?resize=1536,976 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-155389485.jpg?resize=2048,1301 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-155389485.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<h2>So why does TechCrunch cover so many early-stage funding rounds, anyway?</h2>
<p>Here&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/06/3-views-on-the-future-of-the-funding-round-story/">Natasha&#8217;s take</a>, from a little explainer we did this week following some Twitter conversations:</p>
<blockquote><p>The reason I love writing about tech and do the sometimes formulaic funding-round story is because I meet people who are crazy enough to bet their entire legacy on a napkin-stage idea. That’s the story, and the surprise and the tension. The dollar sign is just the first way in.</p></blockquote>
<p>Having raised fundings that got covered in TechCrunch, and having written many many funding round articles over the year, I agree. The funding round is often the only way to prove that you have traction, if you are trying to get more attention.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2083807" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2083807" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2083807" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Klarna_Sebastian_Siemiatkowski.jpg" alt="Klarna CEO and co-founder Sebastian Siemiatkowski" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Klarna_Sebastian_Siemiatkowski.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Klarna_Sebastian_Siemiatkowski.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Klarna_Sebastian_Siemiatkowski.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Klarna_Sebastian_Siemiatkowski.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Klarna_Sebastian_Siemiatkowski.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Klarna_Sebastian_Siemiatkowski.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Klarna_Sebastian_Siemiatkowski.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Klarna_Sebastian_Siemiatkowski.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2083807" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<h2>The Klarna founding story</h2>
<p>Swedish fintech decacorn Klarna pioneered new ways for users to buy online without credit cards over the decade, and is now battling rivals large and small across the world. How did it all happen? Steve O&#8217;Hear sits down with founder <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/making-sense-of-klarna/">Sebastian Siemiatkowski for an exclusive in-depth interview</a> that Extra Crunch subscribers have been eating up this week. Here&#8217;s his description:</p>
<blockquote><p>In a wide-ranging interview, Siemiatkowski confronts criticisms head on, including that Klarna makes it too easy to get into debt, and that buy now, pay later needs to be regulated. We also discuss Klarna’s business model and the balancing act required to win over consumers and keep merchants onside.</p>
<p>We also learn how, under his watch and as the company began to scale, Klarna missed the next big opportunity in fintech, instead being usurped by Adyen and Stripe. Siemiatkowski also shares what’s next for the company as it ventures further into the world of retail banking after gaining a bank license in 2017.</p></blockquote>
<p>Here&#8217;s a painfully fascinating excerpt from Siemiatkowski:</p>
<blockquote><p>One of the drawbacks that we had at the company was that none of the three co-founders had any engineering background; we couldn’t code. We were connected to five engineers that by themselves were amazing engineers, but we had a slight misunderstanding. Their idea was that they were going to come in, build a prototype, ship it, and then leave for 37% of the equity. Our understanding was that they were going to come in, ship it, and if it started scaling they would stay with us and work for a longer period of time. This is the classic mistake that you do as a startup.</p></blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_2085111" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085111" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2085111" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facebook-ftc.jpg" alt="Facebook logo and FTC seal" width="1024" height="544" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facebook-ftc.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facebook-ftc.jpg?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facebook-ftc.jpg?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facebook-ftc.jpg?resize=768,408 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facebook-ftc.jpg?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facebook-ftc.jpg?resize=1536,816 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facebook-ftc.jpg?resize=2048,1088 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facebook-ftc.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2085111" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<h2>Those Facebook antitrust lawsuits</h2>
<p>It seems that the US government has finally had enough of Facebook&#8217;s aggressive expansion and acquisition practices. After years of light regulation, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/">the Federal Trade Commission and</a>, separately, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/">49 state attorneys general</a> are suing to break up social networking company. You can find lots of commentary about the details on TechCrunch and elsewhere.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s my take for you to remember, as you watch headlines about this continue into next year: Facebook was always ready. I covered the company closely during its early years, and even back then it was talking about being <em>the</em> operating system for the internet, like Microsoft Windows was for desktop. The implied and whispered goal was to get as big as possible before regulations inevitably hit, like what Microsoft did. Here we are, with Facebook in a leading market position, with a massive army of lawyers who have been preparing for years. Without getting further into the lawsuits or political landscape where it&#8217;s all happening&#8230; I don&#8217;t expect a breakup. But maybe new restrictions on acquisitions or something could limit growth potential? Its big wins this decade have been from acquisitions.</p>
<p>One boring scenario I don&#8217;t see discussed much is simply that its products remain the phone book of the era for much of the world. Somewhat regulated this way or that way in various jurisdictions and banned outright in some — and very big and successful still.</p>
<h2>Around TechCrunch</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/tc-sessions-space-2020-launches-next-week/">TC Sessions: Space 2020 launches next week</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/announcing-the-final-agenda-for-tc-sessions-space-2020/">Announcing the final agenda for TC Sessions: Space 2020</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/dont-miss-the-university-research-showcase-at-tc-sessions-space-2020/">Don’t miss the university research showcase at TC Sessions: Space 2020</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/hear-the-latest-from-kayhan-space-and-firehawk-aerospace-at-tc-sessions-space/">Hear the latest from Kayhan Space and Firehawk Aerospace at TC Sessions: Space</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/give-the-gift-of-extra-crunch-for-25-off/">Give the gift of Extra Crunch for 25% off</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/extra-crunch-partner-perk-find-peace-of-mind-with-spotify-for-mindfulness-sleep-app-aura/">Extra Crunch Partner Perk: Find peace of mind with ‘Spotify for Mindfulness &amp; Sleep’ app Aura</a></p>
<h2>Across the week</h2>
<p><em>TechCrunch</em></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/survey-americans-think-big-tech-isnt-so-bad-after-all/">Survey: Americans think Big Tech isn’t so bad after all</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/despite-the-pandemic-small-business-optimism-persists/">Despite the pandemic, small business optimism persists</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/06/mixtape-podcast-making-technology-accessible-for-everyone/">Mixtape podcast: Making technology accessible for everyone</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/macron-promotes-european-tech-ecosystem-in-an-interview-with-zennstrom/">Macron promotes European tech ecosystem in an interview with Zennström</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/equity-monday-airbnb-pricing-sequoia-makes-money-and-early-stage-rounds/">Equity Monday: Airbnb pricing, Sequoia makes money and early-stage rounds</a></p>
<p><em>Extra Crunch</em></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/what-to-expect-while-fundraising-in-2021/">What to expect while fundraising in 2021</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/3-ways-the-pandemic-is-transforming-tech-spending/">3 ways the pandemic is transforming tech spending</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/05/why-sapphires-jai-das-thinks-the-salesforce-slack-deal-could-succeed/">Why Sapphire’s Jai Das thinks the Salesforce-Slack deal could succeed</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/china-watches-and-learns-from-the-us-in-ar-vr-competition/">China watches and learns from the US in AR/VR competition</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/is-2020-bringing-more-edtech-rounds-than-ever-or-does-it-simply-feel-that-way/">Is 2020 bringing more edtech rounds than ever, or does it simply feel that way?</a></p>
<h2>#EquityPod</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/do-the-celebrities-help-the-startups-or-do-the-startups-help-the-celebrities/">From Alex</a>:</p>
<p><em>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast (<a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">now on Twitter!</a>), where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</em></p>
<p><em>What a week, yeah? Instead of the news cycle slowing as the year races to a close, things are still as hot as ever. We have funding rounds big and small, IPOs, first-day extravaganza and more.</em></p>
<p><em>Luckily we had the whole crew around — <a href="https://twitter.com/cgates123">Chris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">me</a>. Here’s the rundown:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Career Karma <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/career-karma-series-a/">raised $10 million</a>, and we have thoughts and concerns.</em></li>
<li><em>Skyflow <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/skyflow-raises-17-5m-more-to-help-companies-protect-your-personal-data/">raised $17.5 million</a> in an effort to try to get the Equity team to understand the nuances of different encryption types.</em></li>
<li><em>Calm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/calm-raises-75m-more-at-2b-valuation/">raised $75 million</a>, which felt pretty reasonable given reports and its fundraising history.</em></li>
<li><em>Squire <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/squire-series-c/">tripled its valuation</a> in a new round that included $45 million in equity capital along with some debt.</em></li>
<li><em>We also talked about the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">DoorDash and C3.ai IPO pops</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/airbnb-said-to-price-ipo-between-67-and-68/">where Airbnb priced</a>, and who is coming next.</em></li>
<li><em>We rounded off with what’s up with TikTok stars investing in tech startups. Danny was not a fan.</em></li>
</ul>
<p><em>And that’s that! If you aren’t tired, have you even been paying attention?</em></p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/investors-double-down-on-tech-stocks-in-massive-doordash-airbnb-ipos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086272</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Week in Apps:  Apple scolds adtech, Facebook hit with antitrust suits, Twitter buys Squad</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/this-week-in-apps-apple-scolds-adtech-facebook-hit-with-antitrust-suits-twitter-buys-squad/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/this-week-in-apps-apple-scolds-adtech-facebook-hit-with-antitrust-suits-twitter-buys-squad/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 15:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[This Week In Apps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to This Week in Apps, the weekly TechCrunch series that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy. The app industry is as hot as ever, with a record 204 billion downloads and $120 billion in global consumer spend in 2019. Not including third-party Chinese app stores, iOS and Android [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Welcome back to This Week in Apps, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/">the weekly TechCrunch series</a> that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy.</p>
<p>The app industry is as hot as ever, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/app-stores-saw-record-204-billion-app-downloads-in-2019-consumer-spend-of-120-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a record</a> 204 billion downloads and $120 billion in global consumer spend in 2019. Not including third-party Chinese app stores, iOS and Android users <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/app-stores-to-see-130-billion-downloads-in-2020-and-record-consumer-spend-of-112-billion/">downloaded</a> 130 billion apps in 2020. Consumer spend also hit a record $112 billion across iOS and Android alone. In 2019, people <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/content/average-us-time-spent-with-mobile-in-2019-has-increased" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spent</a> three hours and 40 minutes per day using apps, rivaling TV. Due to COVID-19, time spent in apps <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/app-stores-to-see-130-billion-downloads-in-2020-and-record-consumer-spend-of-112-billion/">jumped</a> 25% year-over-year on Android.</p>
<p>Apps aren’t just a way to pass idle hours — they’re also a big business. In 2019, mobile-first companies had a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/app-stores-saw-record-204-billion-app-downloads-in-2019-consumer-spend-of-120-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">combined</a> $544 billion valuation, 6.5x higher than those without a mobile focus.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h1>Top Stories</h1>
<h3>Apple defends its consumer privacy moves</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2086218" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086218" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2086218" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2048.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="445" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2048.jpeg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2048.jpeg?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2048.jpeg?resize=300,196 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2048.jpeg?resize=768,503 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2048.jpeg?resize=680,445 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2048.jpeg?resize=1536,1005 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/2048.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086218" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Apple SVP Craig Federighi <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/apple-takes-aim-at-adtech-hysteria-over-ios-app-tracking-change/">took aim at the adtech industry</a> in a speech to European lawmakers this week, where he downplayed and dismissed the industry backlash against the forthcoming app tracking changes as &#8220;outlandish&#8221; and even &#8220;false.&#8221; He said that online tracking is privacy’s biggest challenge and that Apple&#8217;s forthcoming App Tracking Transparency (ATT) is the front-line of defense.</p>
<p>&#8220;The mass centralization of data puts privacy at risk — no matter who’s collecting it and what their intentions might be,&#8221; Federighi said, reiterating that Apple aimed to have as little data on its customers as possible.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/08IC1AZTxls?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>This has been the company&#8217;s line to date, and it&#8217;s not necessarily the whole truth. Apple has so far characterized its decision to allow consumers to opt-out of being tracked as one that&#8217;s solely focused on consumer privacy. It positions Apple as consumers&#8217; savior and the only one fighting for our privacy. But the changes are also an example of Apple leveraging its platform power, potentially in an anticompetitive way, to give itself a seat at the table of a multi-billion-dollar market today dominated by its competitors <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Facebook.</p>
<p>In this case, Apple is inserting itself in the world of mobile advertising by forcing a shift from IDFA to its own SKAdNetwork, which limits the individualized data advertisers can access. This is good for consumers who don&#8217;t want to be targeted and tracked just because they&#8217;re using an app. Publishers, however, have argued they won&#8217;t be able to charge as much for ads where users opted out of tracking. This could have a snowball effect of hurting ad-supported businesses beyond the tech giants like Facebook.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Apple does get to collect a lot of consumer data which it uses to personalize ads. Its own App Store and Apple News apps <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074">personalize ads unless consumers opt out</a> in their iPhone&#8217;s Settings (and not through a scary pop-up warning like third-party apps have to display). Apple says <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-faces-antitrust-complaint-in-france-over-privacy-changes-in-iphones-11603893625?mod=business_lead_pos2">what it does in terms of personalization doesn&#8217;t count as &#8220;tracking</a>&#8221; because it doesn&#8217;t share the data with others or follow customers around websites and apps.</p>
<p>But as Apple moves into its own services businesses, the amount of data that can be used to personalize its own ads grows. Today, Apple&#8217;s ad targeting system includes users in segments based on the music, books, TV shows and apps they download, as well as in-app purchases and subscriptions. It also tracks users as they search the app search with keywords and tap to read App Store stories, and tracks location if permission has been granted to Apple News or the App Store.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WitfSziFqQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/apple-takes-aim-at-adtech-hysteria-over-ios-app-tracking-change/">Apple takes aim at adtech hysteria over iOS app tracking change</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple takes aim at adtech hysteria over iOS app tracking change&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/apple-takes-aim-at-adtech-hysteria-over-ios-app-tracking-change/embed/#?secret=WitfSziFqQ" data-secret="WitfSziFqQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In related news, Facebook-owned <a href="https://www.axios.com/whatsapp-apple-privacy-label-requirements-cc0d5edd-ab2f-4549-b9d7-ea3c97184056.html">WhatsApp criticized Apple&#8217;s forthcoming privacy label requirements</a> this week, <a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/general/unpacking-whatsapps-privacy-label-in-the-apple-app-store">saying that the labels are anti-competitive</a> because they won&#8217;t apply to first-party apps, like iMessage, that come pre-installed on iPhones. WhatsApp also argued that they don&#8217;t allow companies to share enough details about the measures they&#8217;re taking to protect consumer data.</p>
<p>Apple <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/12/09/apple-apps-will-show-privacy-labels/">responded</a> by saying labels for its own apps will be on its website for those apps not distributed through the App Store.</p>
<h2>Facebook antitrust lawsuits</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1956435" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1956435" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-1956435" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Facebook-Stories-Cross-Post-To-Instagram.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="368" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Facebook-Stories-Cross-Post-To-Instagram.png 2954w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Facebook-Stories-Cross-Post-To-Instagram.png?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Facebook-Stories-Cross-Post-To-Instagram.png?resize=300,162 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Facebook-Stories-Cross-Post-To-Instagram.png?resize=768,415 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Facebook-Stories-Cross-Post-To-Instagram.png?resize=680,368 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Facebook-Stories-Cross-Post-To-Instagram.png?resize=1536,830 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Facebook-Stories-Cross-Post-To-Instagram.png?resize=2048,1107 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Facebook-Stories-Cross-Post-To-Instagram.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1956435" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Forty-eight attorneys general across 46 states, the territory of Guam and the District of Columbia <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/">have filed an antitrust lawsuit that accuses Facebook</a> of suppressing its competition through monopolistic business practices. The states are asking the court to restrain Facebook from making further acquisitions in excess of $10 million without notifying the plaintiffs, and is asking for additional relief, including &#8220;the divestiture or restructuring of illegally acquired companies, or current Facebook assets or business lines.&#8221;</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/">FTC also voted to pursue</a> its own antitrust suit against Facebook at the federal level.</p>
<p>While the lawsuits are much larger than an app story alone, they do have the potential to impact the app ecosystem if the plaintiffs prevail, as they ask for the acquisitions of Instagram and WhatsApp, and maybe others, to be retroactively judged to be illegal and divested. This would allow for increased competition among the social app market, where Facebook leverages its power to maintain its dominant position. For instance, Facebook just integrated its messaging platform with Instagram&#8217;s, meaning <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/facebook-introduces-cross-app-communication-between-messenger-and-instagram-plus-other-features/">users can now message friends across two</a> of the largest social platforms via just one app &#8212; either Messenger or Instagram. WhatsApp could be integrated in the future, as well.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aZsvybVZgB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/">FTC seeks to break up Facebook, alleging illegal monopoly</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FTC seeks to break up Facebook, alleging illegal monopoly&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/embed/#?secret=aZsvybVZgB" data-secret="aZsvybVZgB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Twitter buys Squad</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2086110" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086110" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2086110" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_rEcHcBU_Fmu7PSbh6lwJkA.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="298" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_rEcHcBU_Fmu7PSbh6lwJkA.png 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_rEcHcBU_Fmu7PSbh6lwJkA.png?resize=150,66 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_rEcHcBU_Fmu7PSbh6lwJkA.png?resize=300,131 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_rEcHcBU_Fmu7PSbh6lwJkA.png?resize=768,336 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_rEcHcBU_Fmu7PSbh6lwJkA.png?resize=680,298 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_rEcHcBU_Fmu7PSbh6lwJkA.png?resize=1536,673 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_rEcHcBU_Fmu7PSbh6lwJkA.png?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086110" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>Twitter on Friday <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/twitter-acquires-screen-sharing-social-app-squad/">announced</a> the acquisition of the screen-sharing social app Squad. The startup&#8217;s co-founders, CEO Esther Crawford and CTO Ethan Sutin, along with the rest of Squad&#8217;s team will be joining Twitter&#8217;s design, engineering and product departments. The Squad app, which had heavily relied on Snap&#8217;s Snap Kit developer tools, will shut down.</p>
<p>Twitter may be <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/twitter-app-code-indicates-that-live-video-broadcasting-app-periscope-may-get-shut-down/">shuttering Periscope as well</a>, code reveals, which leaves some wondering what Twitter&#8217;s plans are in terms of streamlining its services. The company has more recently been experimenting with its own version of Stories, aka Fleets, and an audio-based networking product for group conversations.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GYDJEA66Rz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/twitter-app-code-indicates-that-live-video-broadcasting-app-periscope-may-get-shut-down/">Twitter app code indicates that live video broadcasting app Periscope may get shut down</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter app code indicates that live video broadcasting app Periscope may get shut down&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/twitter-app-code-indicates-that-live-video-broadcasting-app-periscope-may-get-shut-down/embed/#?secret=GYDJEA66Rz" data-secret="GYDJEA66Rz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h1>This Week in App News</h1>
<h3>Platforms: Apple</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reminder: Apple&#8217;s App Store Holiday shutdown is coming</strong>. The App Store will not accept new apps and app updates from December 23-27 (Pacific Time) for its annual holiday break.</li>
<li><strong>Reminder: App privacy questions requirement</strong> <a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=707raiff">starts</a> December 8.</li>
<li><strong>The iOS 14.3 Release Candidate<a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/12/08/ios-14-3-release-candidate-features/"> arrives</a></strong>, adding support for the new ProRAW photo format on iPhone 12 Pro and iPhone 12 Pro Max, a new Apple TV+ tab that makes it easier to find Apple&#8217;s Originals, readies the platform for Fitness+, and makes a change to bypass launching the Shortcuts app when using custom app icons, among other things.</li>
<li><strong>Apple Watch Family Setup</strong> <a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/20/12/09/apple-watch-family-setup-to-launch-in-canada-on-dec-14">arrives</a> in Canada on December 14.</li>
<li><strong>Apple Fitness+</strong> launches December 14.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nCPb9hqwsW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/apple-fitness-launches-on-december-14/">Apple Fitness+ launches on December 14</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple Fitness+ launches on December 14&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/apple-fitness-launches-on-december-14/embed/#?secret=nCPb9hqwsW" data-secret="nCPb9hqwsW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Platforms: Google</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2086126" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086126" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2086126" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.04.29-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="474" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.04.29-AM.jpg 1402w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.04.29-AM.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.04.29-AM.jpg?resize=300,209 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.04.29-AM.jpg?resize=768,536 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.04.29-AM.jpg?resize=680,474 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.04.29-AM.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086126" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Google is working on an ambitious project to improve GPS accuracy in apps</strong>. In dense urban areas, it&#8217;s often hard to get an accurate GPS reading &#8212; leading to issues like wrong-side-of-the-street and even wrong-city-block errors, which greatly impact ridesharing and navigation apps. Google&#8217;s new solution uses 3D mapping-aided corrections, comprised of 3D building models, raw GPS measurements and machine learning. <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2020/12/improving-urban-gps-accuracy-for-your.html">Its Pixel Feature Drop in December adds these corrections to Pixel 5 and Pixel 4a (5G)</a>, which Google says will reduce wrong-side-of-street occurrences by approximately 75%. Other Android phones (Android 8+) have version 1 implemented in the FLP (Fused Location Provider API), which reduces those occurrences by around 50%. Version 2 will be available to the entire Android ecosystem (Android 8 or later) in early 2021.</li>
<li><strong>Google Play Pass arrives in 7 new countries, including key Latin American markets.</strong> The subscription-based apps and games<a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/12/07/google-play-pass-brings-its-curated-selection-of-ad-free-apps-and-games-to-5-new-countries/"> service came to</a> Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Mexico, Peru, Russia and Saudi Arabia. This brings the total number of markets where the service is live to 42.</li>
<li><strong>Google&#8217;s <a href="https://www.blog.google/products/pixel/december-feature-drop">Pixel Feature Drop</a></strong> adds Adaptive Sound, Hold for Me (where Google Assistant waits on hold for you), Extreme Battery Saver Mode, screen sharing on Duo calls and more.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Gaming</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2086233" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086233" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2086233" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox-cloud-gaming.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="382" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox-cloud-gaming.jpg 990w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox-cloud-gaming.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox-cloud-gaming.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox-cloud-gaming.jpg?resize=768,431 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox-cloud-gaming.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox-cloud-gaming.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086233" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Microsoft</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li><strong style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Microsoft <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/xbox-cloud-gaming-coming-to-ios-and-pc-in-spring-2021/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">confirms</a> its Xbox cloud gaming service will launch on iOS in 2021</strong><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">. However, the company will route around the App Store rules by bringing the service to the iPhone and iPad in a web browser. This cuts Apple out of any revenues the game service can generate. Amazon&#8217;s Luna and Google&#8217;s Stadia are also planning to use the web browser on iOS to avoid the App Store.  </span></li>
<li><strong style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Google&#8217;s cloud gaming service <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-stadia-is-now-rolling-out-direct-you-tube-streaming-100047706.html">Stadia is rolling out YouTube live streaming</a>,</strong><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> allowing gamers to share their gameplay to YouTube. </span></li>
<li><strong>Apple asks for Epic Games&#8217; <a href="https://nz.news.yahoo.com/apple-wants-fortnite-court-case-thrown-023755574--spt.html">Fortnite lawsuit in Australia to be thrown out</a></strong> because Epic had promised to settle disputes and litigation in the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of California.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YYxLgAJ2HT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/xbox-cloud-gaming-coming-to-ios-and-pc-in-spring-2021/">Xbox cloud gaming coming to iOS and PC in spring 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Xbox cloud gaming coming to iOS and PC in spring 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/xbox-cloud-gaming-coming-to-ios-and-pc-in-spring-2021/embed/#?secret=YYxLgAJ2HT" data-secret="YYxLgAJ2HT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Government and policy</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The U.S. National Weather Service</strong> just saw a record year of weather-related disasters like the busiest Atlantic hurricane season on record and California&#8217;s wildfires. Now the agency <a href="https://www.weather.gov/media/notification/pdf2/pns20-85ncep_web_access.pdf">says</a> it&#8217;s running out of Internet bandwidth and<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/weather/2020/12/09/nws-data-limits-internet-bandwidth/"><strong> will need to throttle</strong></a><strong> the amount of data</strong> its clients and users can access. The move would impact weather consumers who <strong>get their weather from apps on their smartphones</strong>, as much of the forecasts and alerts they receive are based on Weather Service output and data.</li>
<li><strong>California&#8217;s CA Notify contact-tracing app</strong> for COVID-19 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/californias-ca-notify-app-to-offer-statewide-exposure-notification-using-apple-and-googles-framework/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">now reaches the full state</a>. The app uses Apple and Google&#8217;s exposure notification API.</li>
<li><strong>Cydia files anti-competition lawsuit against Apple</strong>. Third-party App Store maker Cydia, home to jailbreak apps that often added functionality beyond what Apple permitted through its terms, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/10/cydia-apple-lawsuit/">is suing Apple for using anticompetitive means</a> to destroy its rival app store. There are good examples of how denying third-party app stores a home on iOS may have been anticompetitive, but Cydia&#8217;s lawsuit may not be it. The store in its early days distributed pirated apps, not just those that fell outside Apple&#8217;s rules.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MbCpxqqazo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/californias-ca-notify-app-to-offer-statewide-exposure-notification-using-apple-and-googles-framework/">California&#8217;s CA Notify app to offer statewide exposure notification using Apple and Google&#8217;s framework</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;California&#8217;s CA Notify app to offer statewide exposure notification using Apple and Google&#8217;s framework&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/californias-ca-notify-app-to-offer-statewide-exposure-notification-using-apple-and-googles-framework/embed/#?secret=MbCpxqqazo" data-secret="MbCpxqqazo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Augmented reality</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2086132" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086132" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2086132" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/instagram-ar.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="489" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/instagram-ar.png 959w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/instagram-ar.png?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/instagram-ar.png?resize=300,216 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/instagram-ar.png?resize=768,552 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/instagram-ar.png?resize=680,489 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/instagram-ar.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086132" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Instagram</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Instagram <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-museum-exhibitis-augmented-reality-140008700.html">partnered with museums </a></strong>in the U.S. and France, including the Smithsonian, Palace of Versailles and Le Grand Palais, <strong>to bring AR versions of their exhibits</strong> to its camera&#8217;s AR effects lineup.</li>
<li><strong>Snap <a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/story/2020-12-08/lacma-snapchat-virtual-monuments">partnered with</a> the Los Angeles County Museum of Art</strong> on <strong>a multi-year augmented reality project,</strong> &#8220;LACMA x Snapchat: Monumental Perspectives.&#8221; The initiative will pair local artists chosen by the museum to create site-specific <strong>monuments and murals that can be viewed in AR</strong> in the Snapchat app.</li>
</ul>
<h3>E-commerce &amp; food delivery</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2072808" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2072808" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2072808" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Launch-Image-Home-Reels-Shop.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="434" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Launch-Image-Home-Reels-Shop.png 5355w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Launch-Image-Home-Reels-Shop.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Launch-Image-Home-Reels-Shop.png?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Launch-Image-Home-Reels-Shop.png?resize=768,490 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Launch-Image-Home-Reels-Shop.png?resize=680,434 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Launch-Image-Home-Reels-Shop.png?resize=1536,980 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Launch-Image-Home-Reels-Shop.png?resize=2048,1307 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Launch-Image-Home-Reels-Shop.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2072808" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Instagram</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Instagram <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/instagram-launches-shopping-in-reels-its-tiktok-rival/">launches</a> shopping in Reels, its TikTok rival</strong>. The feature is now one of many ways users can shop via video, including through video in Feed, Stories, Live and IGTV. Facebook Pay powers checkout for many sellers, allowing Instagram to generate revenue through transaction fees.</li>
<li><strong>WhatsApp adds carts to make shopping easier.</strong> Facebook-owned WhatsApp <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/facebook-adds-carts-to-whatsapp-to-make-shopping-easier/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">added a new shopping feature</a> that lets consumers buy multiple items from a business, and makes it easier for sellers to track orders.</li>
<li><strong>DoorDash shares popped 92%</strong> in their trading debut to reach as high as $195.50 after <strong style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">raising $3.37 billion during its IPO.</strong></li>
<li><strong>E-commerce app Wish <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/wish-wants-to-be-the-amazon-for-the-rest-of-us-will-retail-investors-buy-it/">to price IPO</a></strong> between $22-$24 per share at up to $14 billion valuation.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ho1R86ugyg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/wish-wants-to-be-the-amazon-for-the-rest-of-us-will-retail-investors-buy-it/">Wish wants to be the Amazon for the rest of us; will retail investors buy it?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wish wants to be the Amazon for the rest of us; will retail investors buy it?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/wish-wants-to-be-the-amazon-for-the-rest-of-us-will-retail-investors-buy-it/embed/#?secret=Ho1R86ugyg" data-secret="Ho1R86ugyg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Fintech</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Robinhood is losing thousands of day traders to China-owned Webull</strong><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-08/robinhood-is-losing-thousands-of-day-traders-to-china-owned-webull">reports Bloomberg</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">. Founded by Alibaba alum Wang Anquan, Webull has increased brokerage clients by 10x in 2020 to reach more than 2 million by offering free stock trades. Robinhood has 13 million, for comparison. Webull is expected to raise a round from private U.S. investors and expand into roboadvisor services.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3>Travel</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_1745335" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1745335" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-1745335" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1052001922.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1052001922.jpg 4669w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1052001922.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1052001922.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1052001922.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1052001922.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1052001922.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1052001922.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1052001922.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1745335" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image credits:</strong> Phillip Faraone/Getty Images for WIRED25</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Vacation rental app Airbnb</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">began trading this week</a> on public markets. After raising its range, the company opened at $146 per share on Thursday, more than double its $68 IPO price and valuing the company at over $100 billion. The stock closed at nearly $145.</li>
<li><strong>China&#8217;s Cyberspace Administration of China (CAC) <a href="http://www.cac.gov.cn/2020-12/08/c_1608994395220033.htm">announced</a> it was banning 105 mobile apps</strong> for violating Chinese regulations. The majority of the apps were made by Chinese developers but the U.S.-based travel booking and review site <strong>Tripadvisor</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/tripadvisor-china-banned/">was also on the ban list, causing its shares to drop</a>. Tripadvisor works in partnership with Nasdaq-listed Chinese travel firm <strong>Trip.com</strong> (previously called Ctrip).</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1fYUESsOkZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/">Airbnb&#8217;s first-day pop caps off a stellar week for tech IPOs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Airbnb&#8217;s first-day pop caps off a stellar week for tech IPOs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/embed/#?secret=1fYUESsOkZ" data-secret="1fYUESsOkZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Social &amp; Photos</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2085315" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085315" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2085315" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="258" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png 3531w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=150,57 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=300,114 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=768,291 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=680,258 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=1536,582 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=2048,777 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=50,19 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2085315" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li><strong style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Snap and Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/snap-launches-a-native-twitter-integration/">worked together</a> </strong><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">to make it possible for users to post their tweets to Snapchat through a </span><strong style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">native integration</strong><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> instead of screenshots. When Twitter users who are logged into Snapchat now share a tweet using the Snapchat icon from the share sheet in Twitter, they&#8217;ll be able to share, react or comment on the post, then send it to a Snapchat friend or post to their Story. The feature is live on iOS with Android in the works.</span></li>
<li><strong>Triller <a href="https://adage.com/article/digital/triller-ceo-mike-lu-takes-swipe-tiktok-app-tries-make-impression-wall-street/2299876">says it can reach 250 million users</a></strong> through partnerships with Samsung and others. The app, which hosted a Pay Per View boxing match between Mike Tyson and Roy Jones Jr. this year, is planning more events for 2021, including a concert with K-pop group <strong>Blackpink</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>A second federal judge <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/second-federal-judge-rules-against-trump-administrations-tiktok-ban/">rules against</a> the Trump administration&#8217;s TikTok ban</strong>, saying the government &#8220;likely exceeded IEEPA’s [the International Emergency Economic Powers Act] express limitations as part of an agency action that was arbitrary and capricious.&#8221;</li>
<li><strong>Instagram <a href="https://www.musicbusinessworldwide.com/genius-partners-with-instagram-to-launch-lyric-reels%e2%80%8b/">partnered</a> for the first time with lyrics site Genius on &#8220;Lyric Reels,</strong>&#8221; a sort of variation of Spotify&#8217;s &#8220;Behind the Lyrics&#8221; feature. The addition will see artists break down their songs&#8217; lyrics and meanings. Participants include Megan Thee Stallion​, ​24kGoldn and ​Tate McRae.</li>
<li><strong>Tinder makes it easier to report bad actors who use &#8220;unmatch&#8221; to hide from victims</strong>. Rival Bumble had just done the same. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/tinder-makes-it-easier-to-report-bad-actors-using-unmatch-to-hide-from-victims/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">But in Tinder&#8217;s implementation</a>, it&#8217;s only making it more obvious how to access its help documentation while Bumble had included a button for reporting users who had already unmatched you.</li>
<li><strong>Google&#8217;s Photos <a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/12/08/google-photos-can-now-sync-liked-images-with-apple-photos/">can now</a> sync your<a href="https://support.google.com/photos/answer/9845656?hl=en&amp;ref_topic=6128848"> &#8220;Liked&#8221; images</a> with Apple&#8217;s Photos</strong> service on iOS.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lqpdVa4eWS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/tinder-makes-it-easier-to-report-bad-actors-using-unmatch-to-hide-from-victims/">Tinder makes it easier to report bad actors using &#8216;unmatch&#8217; to hide from victims</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tinder makes it easier to report bad actors using &#8216;unmatch&#8217; to hide from victims&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/tinder-makes-it-easier-to-report-bad-actors-using-unmatch-to-hide-from-victims/embed/#?secret=lqpdVa4eWS" data-secret="lqpdVa4eWS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Streaming &amp; entertainment</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Netflix&#8217;s StreamFest,</strong> a free trial weekend in India, boosted installs by 200% week-over-week, reaching approximately 3.6 million global installs, <a href="https://sensortower.com/blog/netflix-streamfest-india-installs">reports Sensor Tower</a>.</li>
<li><strong style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Stitcher, </strong>recently <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/13/siriusxm-buys-stitcher-for-325-million-steps-up-its-march-into-podcasts/">acquired</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> by SiriusXM, </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/12/09/the-stitcher-app-finally-gets-the-makeover-it-needs-with-custom-show-groups-and-finer-speed-control/">revamped its app</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> for the first time in years. The new version offers a dedicated &#8220;My Podcasts&#8221; tab, better search filters, result sorting, user-curated groups of shows and more.</span></li>
<li><strong>HBO Max is fastest-growing SVOD in U.S</strong>. <a href="https://blog.apptopia.com/hbo-max-is-now-the-fastest-growing-major-svod-service-in-the-us">According to Apptopia</a>, the app hit a lifetime high for daily downloads three days after its debut, at 225,000. Since its May launch, DAUs have grown 242%.</li>
<li><strong>Spotify had to reset an undisclosed number of user passwords </strong>after a software vulnerability <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/spotify-resets-user-passwords-after-a-bug-exposed-private-account-information/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">exposed private account information</a> to its business partners, including things like &#8220;email address, your preferred display name, password, gender, and date of birth.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FVfTcw6LZ7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/spotify-resets-user-passwords-after-a-bug-exposed-private-account-information/">Spotify resets passwords after a security bug exposed users&#8217; private account information</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Spotify resets passwords after a security bug exposed users&#8217; private account information&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/spotify-resets-user-passwords-after-a-bug-exposed-private-account-information/embed/#?secret=FVfTcw6LZ7" data-secret="FVfTcw6LZ7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Health &amp; fitness</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Nike Run Club app</strong> <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/12/09/nike-run-club-app-updated-with-home-screen-widgets-for-ios-14/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+9To5Mac-MacAllDay+%289+to+5+Mac+-+Apple+Intelligence%29">adds</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> home screen </span><strong style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">widgets</strong><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> for iOS 14+. The widgets can show your Run Level, post-run progress and make it easier to start your next run.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3>Productivity</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Google Drive users on iOS and Android</strong><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2020/12/improved-search-google-drive-android-ios.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+GoogleAppsUpdates+%28Google+Workspace+Updates+Blog%29">will be able to see</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> and re-run desktop and mobile searches; view and select intelligent selections as they type, including suggestions for people, past searches, keywords and recently accessed files. </span></li>
</ul>
<h1>Funding and M&amp;A</h1>
<p><div id="attachment_2070089" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2070089" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2070089" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/calm-app-wide.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/calm-app-wide.jpeg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/calm-app-wide.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/calm-app-wide.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/calm-app-wide.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/calm-app-wide.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/calm-app-wide.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/calm-app-wide.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2070089" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Calm</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Meditation app Calm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/calm-raises-75m-more-at-2b-valuation/">raises $75 million</a></strong> more at $2 billion valuation, in a round led by prior investor Lightspeed Venture Partners.</li>
<li><strong>Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/ilyabr0wn/status/1337396880800509952?s=20">buys</a> video app Squad. (see above) </strong></li>
<li><strong>AI financial assistant Cleo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/cleo-series-b/">raises $44 million</a></strong> Series B, led by EQT Ventures. The app and chatbot aimed at Gen Z connects to bank accounts to give proactive advice and timely nudges.</li>
<li><strong>Mexican challenger banking app albo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/mexican-challenger-bank-albo-raises-45-million-to-expand/">raises $45 million</a> </strong>to expand into lending and insurance products.</li>
<li><strong>Sweden&#8217;s MTG <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/mtg-acquires-mobile-racing-game-studio-hutch-games-for-up-to-375-million/">acquires</a> mobile racing game studio Hutch Games</strong>, based in London, for up to $375 million. The studio produces titles like Rebel Racing, F1 Manager and Top Drives.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="m1KcbvWKZd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/mtg-acquires-mobile-racing-game-studio-hutch-games-for-up-to-375-million/">MTG acquires mobile racing game studio Hutch Games for up to $375 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MTG acquires mobile racing game studio Hutch Games for up to $375 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/mtg-acquires-mobile-racing-game-studio-hutch-games-for-up-to-375-million/embed/#?secret=m1KcbvWKZd" data-secret="m1KcbvWKZd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<ul>
<li><strong>Seattle&#8217;s Freespira <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2020/freespira-raises-10m-tech-platform-aims-ease-panic-attacks-ptsd/">raises $10 million</a></strong> for its therapeutic device for panic attacks PTSD that worked with a connected app and proprietary software.</li>
<li><strong>Banking app for teens GoHenry <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/gohenry-a-pre-paid-card-and-finance-app-for-6-18-year-olds-raises-40m/">raises $40 million</a></strong> to build out its business in the U.S. and U.K.</li>
<li><strong>Retail loyalty app Fetch Rewards <a href="https://pulse2.com/fetch-rewards-raises-80-million-funding/">raises $80 million</a></strong> Series C led by Iconiq Growth. The app offers rewards to users who scan their receipts after shopping.</li>
<li><strong>Pear Therapeutics <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-08/softbank-leads-80-million-round-in-digital-health-startup">raises $80 million</a></strong> in a round led by SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund 2. The company makes prescription apps aimed at treating substance use disorders, schizophrenia and multiple sclerosis. The FDA has already approved its treatments for substance abuse, opioid use and insomnia.</li>
<li><strong>Reface <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/reface-grabs-5-5m-seed-led-by-a16z-to-stoke-its-viral-face-swap-video-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">raises $5.5 million</a></strong> in seed funding led by a16z for its viral face-swapping video app.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IBpG9QYbyk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/gohenry-a-pre-paid-card-and-finance-app-for-6-18-year-olds-raises-40m/">GoHenry, a pre-paid card and finance app for 6-18 year olds, raises $40M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GoHenry, a pre-paid card and finance app for 6-18 year olds, raises $40M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/gohenry-a-pre-paid-card-and-finance-app-for-6-18-year-olds-raises-40m/embed/#?secret=IBpG9QYbyk" data-secret="IBpG9QYbyk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h1>Downloads</h1>
<p><strong>Google Health Studies</strong></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2086127" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086127" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2086127" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Health_Social_Static_4.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="355" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Health_Social_Static_4.max-1000x1000-1.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Health_Social_Static_4.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Health_Social_Static_4.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?resize=300,157 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Health_Social_Static_4.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?resize=768,401 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Health_Social_Static_4.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?resize=680,355 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Health_Social_Static_4.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086127" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Google takes on Apple&#8217;s Research app with <a href="https://blog.google/technology/health/google-health-studies-app/">an alternative for Android users</a>. The new <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.health.research.studies">Google Health Studies app</a> will work in partnership with leading research institutions, which will connect with study participants through the app. The first study is timely, as it focuses on respiratory illnesses, including the flu and COVID-19. The study will use <a href="https://ai.googleblog.com/2020/05/federated-analytics-collaborative-data.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-analytics-onclick="{&quot;event&quot;:&quot;page interaction&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;in-article links&quot;,&quot;action&quot;:&quot;link click&quot;,&quot;label&quot;:&quot;https://ai.googleblog.com/2020/05/federated-analytics-collaborative-data.html&quot;}">federated learning and analytics</a> — a privacy technology that keeps a person’s data stored on the device.</p>
<p><strong>Google Look to Speak</strong></p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/r6WVBSRe_ek?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Google <a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/accessibility/look-to-speak">launched</a> an accessibility-focused app,<a href="http://g.co/looktospeak"> Look to Speak</a>, that lets people use their eyes to choose pre-written phrases for their phone to say out loud. To use the app, people have to look left, right or up to select what they want to say from the phrase list and navigate the app. Look to Speak can also be personalized by letting users edit the words and phrases they want to say and adjust the gaze settings to their needs.</p>
<p><strong>Retro Widget</strong></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2086125" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086125" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2086125" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.49.28-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="484" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.49.28-AM.jpg 762w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.49.28-AM.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.49.28-AM.jpg?resize=300,213 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.49.28-AM.jpg?resize=680,484 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-11.49.28-AM.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086125" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Retro Widget 2</p></div></p>
<p>Gaming via a home screen widget? The fun <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/retro-widget/id1534337551?ign-itscg=30200&amp;ign-itsct=apps_box#?platform=iphone">Retro Widget 2</a> ($1.99) has <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/12/09/snake-game-iphone-widget-apple-watch/">been updated to bring</a> the classic Snake II game from old Nokia handsets to the iPhone&#8217;s home screen. The app includes five mazes and nine levels and lets you play Snake II using the 1, 3, 7 and 9 keys.</p>
<p><strong>Barter</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/barter-app-sales-widget/id1538533114">Barter</a> is an app designed for app developers alone. From the maker of the HomePass and HomeCam apps, Barter offers a way for <a href="https://www.imore.com/barter-puts-your-app-store-sales-your-iphone-home-screen-using-widgets">app developers to view their app sales</a> in a widget on iOS 14+ devices. The app includes no analytics or tracking beyond what Apple builds in to protect developer data. In the future, Pearce says he&#8217;ll expand the app to be able to show things like downloaded units, by product and more. The current version was an MVP to see if Apple would allow the app to pass App Review. Since it passed, it will soon be upgraded.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Introducing Barter, the best way to view your App Sales in a widget.<a href="https://t.co/SXh4G5Jeyf">https://t.co/SXh4G5Jeyf</a> <a href="https://t.co/iFqX0HEJSH">pic.twitter.com/iFqX0HEJSH</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Aaron Pearce (@aaron_pearce) <a href="https://twitter.com/aaron_pearce/status/1336020286219534336?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1952542" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="93" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png 2047w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=768,105 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=680,93 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=1536,210 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/12/this-week-in-apps-apple-scolds-adtech-facebook-hit-with-antitrust-suits-twitter-buys-squad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086032</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FDA grants emergency use authorization for Pfizer&#8217;s COVID-19 vaccine, distribution to begin within days</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/fda-grants-emergency-use-authorization-for-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-distribution-to-begin-within-days/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/fda-grants-emergency-use-authorization-for-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-distribution-to-begin-within-days/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 02:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BioNTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moderna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pfizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the wall street journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has granted an Emergency Use Authorization (EUA) for the COVID-19 vaccine developed by Pfizer and its partner BioNTech, the New York Times first reported on Friday night, and later supported by The Wall Street Journal. This EUA follows a recommendation by an independent panel of experts commissioned by the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/11/health/pfizer-vaccine-authorized.html?smtyp=cur&amp;smid=tw-nytimes">granted an Emergency Use Authorization (EUA) for the COVID-19 vaccine</a> developed by Pfizer and its partner BioNTech, the New York Times first reported on Friday night, and later <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/pfizer-biontech-covid-19-vaccine-is-authorized-in-the-u-s-11607740101?mod=e2tw">supported by The Wall Street Journal</a>. This EUA follows a recommendation by an independent panel of experts commissioned by the FDA to review Pfizer&#8217;s application and provide a recommendation, which the panel unanimously supported earlier this week.</p>
<p>Following this authorization, shipment of the vaccine are expected to begin immediately, with 2.9 million doses in the initial shipment order. Patients in the category of highly vulnerable individuals, which include healthcare workers and senior citizens in long-term care facilities, are expected to begin receiving doses within just a few days not was the EUA is granted.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mrj797kKDw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/fda-panel-recommends-approving-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-emergency-use-authorization/">FDA panel recommends approving Pfizer&#8217;s COVID-19 vaccine emergency use authorization</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FDA panel recommends approving Pfizer&#8217;s COVID-19 vaccine emergency use authorization&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/fda-panel-recommends-approving-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-emergency-use-authorization/embed/#?secret=mrj797kKDw" data-secret="mrj797kKDw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This approval isn&#8217;t a full certification by the U.S. therapeutics regulator, but it is an emergency measure that still requires a comprehensive review of the available information supplied by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/pfizer" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="pfizer">Pfizer <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> based on its Phase 3 clinical trial, which covered a group of 44,000 volunteer participants. Pfizer found that its vaccine, which is an mRNA-based treatment, was 95% effective in its final analysis of the data resulting form the trial to date – and also found that safety data indicated no significant safety issues in patients who received the vaccine.</p>
<p>On top of the initial 2.9 million dose order, the U.S. intends to distribute around 25 million doses by the end of 2020, which could result in far fewer people actually vaccinated since the Pfizer course requires two innoculations for maximum efficacy. Most American shouldn&#8217;t expect the vaccine to be available until at least late Q1 or Q2 2021, given the pace of Pfizer&#8217;s production and the U.S. order volume.</p>
<p>Still, this is a promising first step, and a monumental achievement in terms of vaccine development turnaround time, since it&#8217;s been roughly eight months since work began on the Pfizer vaccine candidate. Moderna has also submitted an EUA for its vaccine candidate, which is also an mRNA treatment (which provides instructions to a person&#8217;s cells to produce effective countermeasures to the virus). That could follow shortly, meaning two vaccines might be available under EUA within the U.S. before the end of the year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/fda-grants-emergency-use-authorization-for-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-distribution-to-begin-within-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086344</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Hyundai acquires 80% stake in Boston Robotics</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/daily-crunch-hyundai-acquires-80-stake-in-boston-robotics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/daily-crunch-hyundai-acquires-80-stake-in-boston-robotics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 23:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hyundai takes a controlling stake in an iconic robotics company, Twitter acquires a screen-sharing startup and we round up some security-themed gift ideas. This is your Daily Crunch for December 11, 2020. The big story: Hyundai acquires 80% stake in Boston Robotics Boston Robotics is behind a number of impressive robots, including the dog-like quadruped [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hyundai takes a controlling stake in an iconic robotics company, Twitter acquires a screen-sharing startup and we round up some security-themed gift ideas. This is your Daily Crunch for December 11, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Hyundai acquires 80% stake in Boston Robotics</strong></p>
<p>Boston Robotics is behind a number of impressive robots, including the dog-like quadruped Spot. Over the past decade, it&#8217;s changed ownership several times, with Google acquiring it in 2013, then selling it to Japanese investment giant SoftBank in 2017.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/hyundai-buys-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics/">today&#8217;s deal</a>, which values Boston Robotics at $1.1 billion and is subject to regulatory approval, SoftBank will still own a 20% stake.</p>
<p>&#8220;<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/boston-dynamics" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="boston-dynamics">Boston Dynamics <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> will benefit substantially from new capital, technology, affiliated customers, and Hyundai Motor Group’s global market reach enhancing commercialization opportunity for its robot products,&#8221; Hyundai said in a press release.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/twitter-acquires-screen-sharing-social-app-squad/">Twitter acquires screen-sharing social app Squad</a> — The entire Squad team is joining Twitter, while the Squad app will be shut down tomorrow.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/europe-urged-to-block-google-fitbit-ahead-of-major-digital-policy-overhaul/">Europe urged to block Google-Fitbit ahead of major digital policy overhaul</a> — Shoshana Zuboff, the Harvard professor who wrote the defining book on surveillance capitalism, has become the latest voice raised against the $2.1 billion deal.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/twitter-app-code-indicates-that-live-video-broadcasting-app-periscope-may-get-shut-down/">Twitter app code indicates that live video broadcasting app Periscope may get shut down</a> — If Periscope does get shut down, it would be the end of a five-year run.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/gorillas/">Gorillas, the on-demand grocery delivery startup taking Berlin by storm, has raised $44M Series A</a> — Gorillas delivers groceries within an average of 10 minutes.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/swedens-tink-raises-103m-as-its-open-banking-platform-grows-to-3400-banks-and-250m-customers/">Sweden’s Tink raises $103M as its open banking platform grows to 3,400 banks and 250M customers</a> — Tink aggregates a number of banks and financial services by way of an API.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/benchmark-fills-out-its-yes-bench-with-miles-grimshaw/">Benchmark fills out its, yes, bench, with Miles Grimshaw</a> — From his post as a general partner with New York-based Thrive, Grimshaw sourced deals in Lattice, Mapbox, Benchling and Airtable.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/cloud-gaming-platforms-were-2020s-most-overhyped-trend/">Cloud-gaming platforms were 2020’s most overhyped trend</a> — The future of the technology is bright, but much less sexy.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/general-catalysts-katherine-boyle-and-peter-boyce-are-looking-for-obsessive-founders/">General Catalyst’s Katherine Boyle and Peter Boyce are looking for ‘obsessive’ founders</a> — We sat down with Boyle and Boyce to discuss what they look for in founders, which sectors they’re most excited about and how business has changed in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/what-to-expect-while-fundraising-in-2021/">What to expect while fundraising in 2021</a> — DocSend CEO Russ Heddleston peers into a post-pandemic future.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/gift-guide-9-security-and-privacy-gifts-to-keep-your-friends-and-family-safe/">Gift Guide: 9 security and privacy gifts to keep your friends and family safe</a> — It&#8217;s a good time to evaluate how you’re keeping your data safe, and to help others in your life do the same.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-investor-day/">Disney+ has plans for 10 Marvel shows and 10 Star Wars shows in the next few years</a> — The company announced an ambitious slate of streaming originals.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/give-the-gift-of-extra-crunch-for-25-off/">Give the gift of Extra Crunch for 25% off</a> — Speaking of Extra Crunch, TechCrunch readers can send an annual membership as a gift to a friend, family member or co-worker for 25% off.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/daily-crunch-hyundai-acquires-80-stake-in-boston-robotics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086282</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oracle is headed to Texas now, too</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/oracle-is-headed-to-texas-now-too/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/oracle-is-headed-to-texas-now-too/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 22:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[austin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charles schwab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Blumberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hpe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Rabois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Austinites, watch out; another tech company is headed into town. Just days after Tesla CEO Elon Musk revealed during an interview that he has moved to Texas, and less than two weeks after HP Enterprise, a spin-out of the iconic Silicon Valley company Hewlett-Packard, announced that it is separately moving to Texas, yet another of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Austinites, watch out; another tech company is headed into town.</p>
<p>Just days after Tesla CEO Elon Musk revealed during an interview that he has <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/elon-musk-to-discuss-teslas-banner-year-despite-pandemic-silicon-valleys-future-11607449988">moved to Texas</a>, and less than two weeks after HP Enterprise, a spin-out of the iconic Silicon Valley company Hewlett-Packard, announced that it is separately <a href="https://apnews.com/article/houston-california-greg-abbott-texas-1ce5ef41c6e20e84b5954de11fa3c8a7">moving to Texas</a>, yet another of the Bay Area&#8217;s best-known brands &#8212; Oracle &#8212;  is pulling up stakes and headed east to Texas, too.</p>
<p>The news was first reported by <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-11/oracle-moves-headquarters-to-texas-joins-exodus-from-california?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=bd&amp;cmpId=google">Bloomberg</a>. Oracle confirmed the move in a statement sent to TechCrunch, saying that along with a &#8220;more flexible employee work location policy,&#8221; the company has changed its corporate headquarters from Redwood Shores, California, to Austin. &#8220;We believe these moves best position <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/oracle" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="oracle">Oracle <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> for growth and provide our personnel with more flexibility about where and how they work.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A spokeswoman declined to answer more questions related to the move, but Oracle says that &#8220;many&#8221; of its employees can choose their office location, as well as continue to work from home part time or full time.</p>
<p>HPE and Oracle aren&#8217;t the first major tech companies to plot such moves in recent times. Late last year, the brokerage giant <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/charles-schwab" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="charles-schwab">Charles Schwab <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said it was <a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/business/2019/11/30/schwab-is-the-latest-company-leaving-california-for-texas-and-it-wont-be-the-last-expert-says/">leaving the Bay Area for Texas </a>as it was announcing its $26 billion merger with TD Ameritrade, though it chose Dallas, about 200 miles away from Austin.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TJ64LZ6VF7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/elon-musk-has-made-the-move-to-texas/">Elon Musk moved to Texas</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Elon Musk moved to Texas&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/elon-musk-has-made-the-move-to-texas/embed/#?secret=TJ64LZ6VF7" data-secret="TJ64LZ6VF7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Tech giants <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="apple">Apple <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Google have also been expanding their presence in the state. Apple announced in 2018 that it was building a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/13/business/apple-austin-campus.html">$1 billion campus</a> in Austin. Meanwhile, Google, which opened its first Austin office 13 years ago, said last year that it was beginning to lease <a href="https://www.statesman.com/news/20190614/google-says-it-plans-significant-expansion-in-austin">far more space</a> in the city.</p>
<p>Taxes, a more affordable cost of living for employees, a lower cost of doing business and less competition for talent are among the top drivers for the companies&#8217; moves, though there is also a growing sense that culture is a factor, as well.</p>
<p>While California is led by Democrats, Texas is led by Republicans, and as the divide between the two parties grows, so does the divide between their respective supporters, with even self-described centrists saying they feel alienated.</p>
<p>Oracle co-founder and Chairman Larry Ellison has notably been one of few top tech execs to openly support President Donald Trump.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Joe Lonsdale, a co-founder of the venture firm 8VC and Palantir Technologies (which itself recently headed to Denver from Palo Alto), recently explained his own move this year to Texas from California <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/california-love-it-and-leave-it-11605472619">in the WSJ</a>, writing: &#8220;Politics in the state is in many ways closed off to different ideas. We grew weary of California’s intolerant far left, which would rather demonize opponents than discuss honest differences of opinion.&#8221;</p>
<p>In a similar vein this fall, in conversation with reporter Kara Swisher, Musk suggested he was also outside of Democratic circles, describing his political views as &#8220;socially very liberal and then economically right of center, maybe, or center? I don&#8217;t know. <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/28/opinion/sway-kara-swisher-elon-musk.html">Obviously I&#8217;m not a communist.</a>&#8221;</p>
<p>While Austin is becoming a go-to spot for many of California&#8217;s wealthiest contrarians, others are headed to Florida. Coincidentally or not, Florida is another Republican-controlled state that, like Texas, does not collect state tax.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/keith-rabois" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="keith-rabois">Keith Rabois, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> a Founders Fund investor who recently left the Bay Area for Miami, contributed to the <a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/outsidespending/contrib_all.php?cmte=C00610907&amp;type=A&amp;cycle=2016">NeverTrump PAC</a> in 2016 and said his first choice for U.S. president this year was Democratic contender Pete Buttigieg. But he has also worried openly about democratic socialism, of which the GOP has <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/08/25/905895428/republicans-blast-democrats-as-socialists-heres-what-socialism-is">long accused</a> Democrats of promoting.</p>
<p>Venture capitalist <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/david-blumberg" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="david-blumberg">David Blumberg, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> a Trump supporter, is also headed to Miami, he announced recently. Blumberg said he had it with &#8220;poor governance at the local level in San Francisco and statewide in California.&#8221; Yet he seemed to have grown frustrated with the Bay Area some time ago.</p>
<p>As Blumberg <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/9/17/20869679/donald-trump-silicon-valley-fundraiser-2020">told Vox last year, </a>he believes that tech platforms are biased against conservatives. He also told the outlet that the Valley was home to many more Trump supporters than might be imagined, and that &#8220;we generally keep our heads down” because “people who go out publicly for Republicans and for Trump can get business banned or get blackballed.”</p>
<p>Impetus notwithstanding, a longer-term question is whether these moves &#8212; particularly for those individuals and smaller outfits that are relocating &#8212; will prove permanent.</p>
<p>At least one tech exec, Twitter and Medium co-founder Ev Williams, has returned to the Bay Area after moving away &#8212; in his case, to New York. Williams, who was largely &#8220;looking for a change,&#8221; made the move with his family late last year after spending 20 years in the Bay Area, he <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/talking-techs-exodus-twitters-new-labels-and-mediums-future-with-founder-ev-williams/">recently told</a> TechCrunch. Then COVID struck.</p>
<p>&#8220;I had never lived in New York and thought, ‘Why not go? Now seems like a good time.’ Turns out I was wrong. [Laughs.] It was a very bad time to move to New York.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CkWSmfM0i3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/talking-techs-exodus-twitters-new-labels-and-mediums-future-with-founder-ev-williams/">Talking tech&#8217;s exodus, Twitter&#8217;s labels and Medium&#8217;s next moves with founder Ev Williams</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Talking tech&#8217;s exodus, Twitter&#8217;s labels and Medium&#8217;s next moves with founder Ev Williams&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/talking-techs-exodus-twitters-new-labels-and-mediums-future-with-founder-ev-williams/embed/#?secret=CkWSmfM0i3" data-secret="CkWSmfM0i3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/oracle-is-headed-to-texas-now-too/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086253</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here comes the Faraday fabric</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/here-comes-the-faraday-fabric/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/here-comes-the-faraday-fabric/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 20:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faraday cage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You don&#8217;t have to buy into 5G conspiracy theories to think that you could do with a little less radiation in your life. One way of blocking radiation is a Faraday cage, but this is usually a metal mesh of some kind, making everyday use difficult. Researchers at Drexel University have managed to create a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You don&#8217;t have to buy into 5G conspiracy theories to think that you could do with a little less radiation in your life. One way of blocking radiation is a Faraday cage, but this is usually a metal mesh of some kind, making everyday use difficult. Researchers at Drexel University have managed to create a Faraday fabric by infusing ordinary cotton with a compound called MXene — meaning your tinfoil hat is about to get a lot comfier.</p>
<p>Faraday cages work because radiation in radio frequencies is blocked by certain metals, but because of its wavelength, the metal doesn&#8217;t even have to be solid — it can be a solid cage or flexible mesh. Many facilities are lined with materials like this to prevent outside radiation from interfering with sensitive measurements, but recently companies like <a href="https://silent-pocket.com/">Silent Pocket</a> have integrated meshes into bags and cases that totally isolate devices from incoming signals.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s be frank here and say that this is definitely paranoia-adjacent. RF radiation is not harmful in the doses and frequencies we get it, and the FCC makes sure no device exceeds certain thresholds. But there&#8217;s also the possibility that your phone or laptop is naively connecting to public Wi-Fi, getting its MAC number skimmed by other devices, and otherwise interacting with the environment in a way you might not like. And honestly&#8230; with the amount of devices emitting radiation right now, who wouldn&#8217;t mind lowering their dose a little, just to be extra sure?</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That may be much easier to do in the near future, as Yury Gogotsi and his team at the Drexel Nanomaterials Institute, of which he is director, have come up with a way to coat ordinary textile fibers in a metallic compound that makes them effective Faraday cages — but also flexible, durable and washable.</p>
<p>The material, which they call MXene and is more of a category than a single compound, is useful in lots of ways, and <a href="https://nano.materials.drexel.edu/publications/">the subject of dozens of papers by the team</a> — this is just the most recent application.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have known for some time that MXene has the ability to block electromagnetic interference better than other materials, but this discovery shows that it can effectively adhere to fabrics and maintain its unique shielding capabilities,&#8221; <a href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2020-12/du-ff121120.php">said Gogotsi in a news release</a>. You can <a href="https://www.eurekalert.org/multimedia/pub/251432.php">see the fabric in action on video here</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2086223" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mxene-2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086223" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2086223" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mxene-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="663" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mxene-2.jpg 2438w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mxene-2.jpg?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mxene-2.jpg?resize=300,194 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mxene-2.jpg?resize=768,497 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mxene-2.jpg?resize=680,440 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mxene-2.jpg?resize=1536,994 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mxene-2.jpg?resize=2048,1326 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mxene-2.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2086223" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Drexel University</p></div></p>
<p>MXenes are conductive metal-carbon compounds that can be fabricated into all sorts of forms: solid, liquid, even sprays. In this case it&#8217;s a liquid — a solution of tiny MXene flakes that adhere to the fabric quite easily and produce a Faraday effect, blocking 99.9% of RF radiation in tests. After sitting around for a couple years (perhaps forgotten in a lab cupboard) it kept 90% of their effectiveness, and the treated fabric can also be washed and worn safely.</p>
<p>You wouldn&#8217;t necessarily want to wear a whole suit of the stuff, but this would make it easier for clothing to include an RF-blocking pocket in a jacket, jeans or laptop bag that doesn&#8217;t feel out of place with the other materials. A hat (or underwear) with a layer of this fabric would be a popular item among conspiracy theorists, of course.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s still a ways from showing up on the rack, but Gogotsi was optimistic about its prospects for commercialization, noting that Drexel has multiple patents on the material and its uses. Other ways of infusing fabric with MXenes could lead to clothes that generate and store energy as well.</p>
<p>You can read more about this particular application of MXenes <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0008622320311982?via%3Dihub#!">in the journal Carbon</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/here-comes-the-faraday-fabric/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086148</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>General Catalyst&#8217;s Katherine Boyle and Peter Boyce are looking for &#8216;obsessive&#8217; founders</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/general-catalysts-katherine-boyle-and-peter-boyce-are-looking-for-obsessive-founders/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/general-catalysts-katherine-boyle-and-peter-boyce-are-looking-for-obsessive-founders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 20:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[katherine boyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peter boyce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are definitely people who are working at companies that we start engaging before they even have an idea. So it's never too early]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/general-catalyst-partners" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="general-catalyst-partners">General Catalyst <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has made early bets on some of the biggest companies in tech today, including Airbnb, Lemonade and Warby Parker.</p>
<p>We sat down with <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/katherine-boyle" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="katherine-boyle">Katherine Boyle <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Peter Boyce, who co-lead the firm&#8217;s seed-stage investments, to discuss what they look for in founders, which sectors they&#8217;re most excited about and how business has changed in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>This conversation is part of our broader <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/announcing-the-extra-crunch-live-event-series/">Extra Crunch Live series</a>, where we sit down with VCs and founders to discuss startup core competencies and get advice. We&#8217;ve spoken to folks like Aileen Lee, Mark Cuban, Roelof Botha, Charles Hudson and many, others. You can browse the <a href="http://techcrunch.com/ecl">full library of episodes here</a>.</p>
<p>Check out our full conversation with Boyce and Boyle in the YouTube video below, or skim the text for the highlights.</p>
<h2>Which personality traits are most important in founders</h2>
<p><strong>Katherine Boyle:</strong> I look for what I would call this obsessive trait, where they are learning more about the regulatory complications, where they are constantly trying to figure out how to solve a problem.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d say that the common theme among the founders that I support are that they have this sort of obsessive gene or personality, where they will go deeper and deeper and deeper. When we invest in these companies, it becomes very clear that they often have sort of a contrarian view of the industry. Maybe they are not industry-native. They come at it from a different perspective of problem solving. They&#8217;ve had to defend that thesis for a very, very long time in front of a variety of different customers and different people. In some ways, that makes them much stronger in terms of the way they approach problems.</p>
<p><strong>Peter Boyce:</strong> I think the first would be being magnetic for talent. It ends up influencing the speed of learning and development. Really incredible founding teams that can be magnetic for talent and learning just kind of spirals out of control in really good ways over time. I really look for the speed and the sources of learning. And can folks be really intentional? Can they get the right set of advisors and teammates around them?</p>
<p>The second would be the personal connection to the problem space. It&#8217;s like there&#8217;s this kind of deep-seated source of energy and fuel that actually isn&#8217;t going to run out. Catherine and I&#8217;ve been lucky to work across a number of different particular thematic areas, but the thing they have in common is just this personal connection to how and why their business needs to exist. Because I just think that that fuel doesn&#8217;t run out, you know what I mean? Like, that&#8217;s renewable.</p>
<h2>On fundraising and building trust remotely</h2>
<p><strong>Boyle:</strong> If you&#8217;re someone who&#8217;s comfortable presenting on Zoom, making connections on Zoom, or using Signal and using Twitter and being very online, then I 100% think that you can make investments, build community and build connections through digital worlds and digital platforms. If you really like that in-person connectivity, then you might consider staying in a tech hub, or you might consider sort of these distanced walks until things go back to normal. <div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/general-catalysts-katherine-boyle-and-peter-boyce-are-looking-for-obsessive-founders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085545</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Give the gift of Extra Crunch for 25% off</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/give-the-gift-of-extra-crunch-for-25-off/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/give-the-gift-of-extra-crunch-for-25-off/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Travis Bernard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 19:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscriptions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This holiday season, TechCrunch readers can send an Extra Crunch annual membership as a gift to a friend, family member or co-worker for 25% off.  The gifting feature can be found here. Extra Crunch is our membership program that helps you spot technology trends and opportunities, build better startups and stay connected. It features thousands [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This holiday season, TechCrunch readers can send an Extra Crunch annual membership as a gift to a friend, family member or co-worker for 25% off. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The gifting feature can be found </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/ec-gifting/?tpcc=holidaygiftingarticle"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extra Crunch is our membership program that helps you spot technology trends and opportunities, build better startups and stay connected. It features thousands of articles, including weekly investor surveys, daily private market analysis and expert interviews on fundraising, growth, monetization and other work topics. Learn more about the types of articles in Extra Crunch </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/extracrunch/?tpcc=holidaygiftingarticle"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Membership also gets you access to our weekly video Q&amp;A series </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/extra-crunch-live/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extra Crunch Live</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, exclusive newsletters, and an experience on TechCrunch.com that’s free of banner ads. A 20% discount for any TechCrunch event is also available exclusively for members. More on our 2021 events schedule can be found <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/announcing-techcrunchs-2021-event-calendar/">here</a>.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The discounted rate will only be available until the end of 2020, so don’t miss out on the savings. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For questions about the deal, please contact our customer support team at extracrunch@techcrunch.com.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Give the gift of Extra Crunch </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/ec-gifting/?tpcc=holidaygiftingarticle"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>Not interested in gifting Extra Crunch? We have A TON of other ideas <a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/">here</a> in our holiday gift guide.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/give-the-gift-of-extra-crunch-for-25-off/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086198</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to expect while fundraising in 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/what-to-expect-while-fundraising-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/what-to-expect-while-fundraising-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 19:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommuting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[These predictions center around how we’ll fundraise post-pandemic, how the funding divide may widen for some, what fundraising activity could look like and sectors we think will fare well.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Russ Heddleston</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/rheddleston">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Russ is the co-founder and CEO of <a href="https://www.docsend.com/">DocSend</a>. He was previously a product manager at Facebook, where he arrived via the acquisition of his startup Pursuit.com, and has held roles at Dropbox, Greystripe and Trulia. Follow him here: <a href="https://twitter.com/rheddleston?lang=en">@rheddleston</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/docsend?lang=en">@docsend</a> 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/what-q2-fundraising-data-tells-us-about-the-rest-of-2020/">What Q2 fundraising data tells us about the rest of 2020</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/q3-2020-is-primed-to-be-an-intense-shopping-season-for-vcs/">Q3 2020 is primed to be an intense shopping season for VCs</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">At the end of 2019, no one would have predicted what an unpredictable and difficult year it has been for both startups and VCs in the fundraising world. Now we are staring down the end of 2020 and looking toward what we all hope is a better, safer 2021. What will this new year bring? With an end-of-year sprint to close deals, the anticipation of a new presidential administration and the hope of a COVID-19 vaccine on the horizon, startups and VCs know that change is on the horizon — but how much of that change will be positive?</p>
<p>As 2020 proved, no one can say for sure what 2021 will bring, but I’d like to put a few predictions on the table based on DocSend’s data and research, including the <a href="https://www.docsend.com/index/2020-docsend-startup-index/">DocSend Startup Index</a>, as well as some trends I’ve seen and my own experiences. These predictions center around how we’ll fundraise post-pandemic, how the funding divide may widen for some, what fundraising activity could look like into 2021, a few sectors we think will fare well and will incorporate some tips on how to succeed in the new year, no matter what comes our way.</p>
<h2>We’ll interact through a mix of the old and the new</h2>
<p>The pandemic forced all of us to drastically change how we work and interact with colleagues and clients. When the pandemic subsides and vaccines are widely available, in-person meetings and gathering back at the office will definitely resume, but it’s safe to say the old ways of networking and fundraising won’t shift back 100%. Founders and VCs alike have navigated the ups and downs of remote networking and fundraising interactions and will stick to what works and what doesn’t.</p>
<p>Is traveling to a conference the best way for a founder to have a chance at meeting the VC who is right to support their business? Will a VC want to drive an hour through Bay Area traffic for an in-person status update meeting on their latest investment? Zoom fatigue aside, video conference calls do have some benefits — efficiency, no travel time — although not all meetings are best conducted virtually.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			No matter what 2021 has in store, founders can still take proactive steps to help them succeed in their fundraising efforts.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The extent to which businesses go in-person or stick to virtual meetings could depend directly on what round of fundraising they are working toward or have completed. Businesses in the <a href="https://try.docsend.com/fundraising-report">pre-seed round</a> might stick with more Zoom meetings in order to conserve resources.</p>
<p>Founders in the seed round will likely split between video and in-person meetings as they are under pressure to show traction in this round, as we found in <a href="https://try.docsend.com/seed-report-webinar">our report on seed fundraising</a>, yet will also need to conserve resources and time. For <a href="https://try.docsend.com/series-a-fundraising-report-webinar">Series A</a>, they might have to meet less in person because they have established relationships with their investors. Series B might see more in-person meetings as their business has reached a level of complexity that is difficult to communicate via a deck or video conference.</p>
<h2>The funding divide may widen for those outside Silicon Valley<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/what-to-expect-while-fundraising-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083793</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Benchmark fills out its, yes, bench, with Miles Grimshaw</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/benchmark-fills-out-its-yes-bench-with-miles-grimshaw/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/benchmark-fills-out-its-yes-bench-with-miles-grimshaw/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 18:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benchmark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miles Grimshaw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086146</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Benchmark, the storied venture firm, has brought aboard a fifth general partner: 29-year-old Miles Grimshaw, a Yale graduate who joins the outfit from Thrive Capital, where he similarly joined a team of four other partners back in 2013, helping them raise the firm&#8217;s fourth and fifth funds (per Forbes). From his post as a general [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/benchmark" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="benchmark">Benchmark, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> the storied venture firm, has brought aboard a fifth general partner: 29-year-old Miles Grimshaw, a Yale graduate who joins the outfit from Thrive Capital, where he similarly joined a team of four other partners back in 2013, helping them raise the firm&#8217;s <a href="https://www.forbes.com/profile/miles-grimshaw/?sh=3622f9f3612c">fourth and fifth funds</a> (per Forbes).</p>
<p>From his post as a general partner with New York-based Thrive, Grimshaw had sourced deals in some of today&#8217;s buzziest startups and served on their boards, including Lattice, Mapbox, Benchling and Airtable, getting to know fellow investors at Benchmark in the process.</p>
<p>He represented Thrive on the board of <a href="https://www.benchling.com/">Benchling</a> &#8212; whose software helps lab scientists manage their biotech research &#8212; with Eric Vishria, a former entrepreneur and operator who joined Benchmark as a general partner in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/07/23/eric-vishria-benchmark/">2014</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Grimshaw also represented Thrive on the board of the cloud collaboration software company <a href="https://airtable.com/">Airtable</a> with Peter Fenton, who became the longest-serving general partner at Benchmark this year, as famed VC Bill Gurley began <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/22/report-bill-gurley-is-stepping-away/">transitioning out</a> of an active role at the firm. (Fenton was<a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2007/05/11/peter-fenton-prominent-vc-successful-triathlete/"> poached from Accel</a> back in 2006.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1jiZu67RlR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/22/report-bill-gurley-is-stepping-away/">Bill Gurley is stepping away from an active role at Benchmark, 21 years after joining the firm</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bill Gurley is stepping away from an active role at Benchmark, 21 years after joining the firm&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/22/report-bill-gurley-is-stepping-away/embed/#?secret=1jiZu67RlR" data-secret="1jiZu67RlR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>And Grimshaw has been serving on a board with Benchmark&#8217;s Sarah Tavel, who was herself <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/09/benchmark-just-hired-sarah-tavel-the-first-female-general-partner-in-the-firms-history/">poached by the firm</a> in 2017, from Greylock. That company is <a href="https://supergreat.com/">Supergreat</a>, a two-year-old, New York-based site for beauty enthusiasts that&#8217;s building a community of visitors who become reviewers, who then become shoppers.</p>
<p>Supergreat is among Benchmark&#8217;s newest bets. It was announced earlier this month that Benchmark led the startup&#8217;s $6.5 million Series A round.</p>
<p>Before hiring Grimshaw, Benchmark&#8217;s newest general partner was Chetan Puttagunta, who <a href="https://abovethecrowd.com/2018/07/09/benchmarks-newest-general-partner-chetan-puttagunta/">joined the firm in 2018</a> from New Enterprise Associates, where he spent more than seven years.</p>
<p>Benchmark has done better than some firms when it comes to succession, even while many of its general partners remain involved in startups long after they move on from the firm&#8217;s day-to-day operations.</p>
<p>Firm cofounder Bruce Dunlevie, for example, joined the board of WeWork back in 2012. He&#8217;s now part of a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/legal-us-otc-wework/amid-wework-board-strife-over-softbank-suit-dissident-directors-win-access-to-skadden-discovery-idUSKBN25K2C9">lawsuit</a> alleging fellow WeWork investor SoftBank of breach of contract and breach of fiduciary duty, after SoftBank abandoned a tender offer to buy out earlier shareholders following WeWork&#8217;s pulled IPO last year.</p>
<p>Reportedly, Matt Cohler &#8212; a former Facebook exec who was left an active role as a general partner with Benchmark <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/10/1/17924540/matt-cohler-benchmark-mitch-lasky">in 2018 </a>after a decade with the firm &#8212; also helped Benchmark <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/benchmark-wins-deal-for-live-shopping-app-popshop-at-100-million-valuation">secure its spot</a> in summer as the lead Series A investor in Popshop Live, a live-streaming e-commerce platform. According to The Information, Cohler agreed to join the startup&#8217;s board of directors to help seal the deal.</p>
<p>In addition to Cohler and Gurley, who&#8217;ve stepped back in recent years, Mitch Lasky, who joined the firm in 2007, also stepped away from its core team in 2018.</p>
<p>Benchmark made it known this summer that it was looking to bring aboard a fifth partner, one who likely completes the firm&#8217;s roster for now. As Fenton told us in September when he <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/benchmarks-peter-fenton-10-to-20-years-of-innovation-just-got-pulled-forward/">sat down</a> with us at our TechCrunch Disrupt event, Benchmark &#8220;can&#8217;t scale. When we&#8217;ve gotten above six partners, the firm doesn&#8217;t work so well.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fenton talked at some length about how Benchmark views the composition of its team. We also talked about that WeWork deal. If you&#8217;re curious to learn more, you can watch that interview below.</p>
<p>
		<div class="embed breakout" id="vidible_div_0" data-pid="56faf851e4b0d3dcac2e081a" data-bcid="564f313b67b6231408bc51ee" data-video="5f63c18353fd6e6a449b93cf"></div>
		<span><script type="text/javascript" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunch-2017/features/shortcodes/vidible-callback-js.php?id=0"></script></span>
		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/benchmark-fills-out-its-yes-bench-with-miles-grimshaw/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086146</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
