<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 11:56:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Shell invests in LanzaJet to speed up deliveries of its synthetic aviation fuel</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/shell-invests-in-lanzajet-to-speed-up-deliveries-of-its-synthetic-aviation-fuel/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/shell-invests-in-lanzajet-to-speed-up-deliveries-of-its-synthetic-aviation-fuel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 11:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[all nippon airways]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biofuels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british airways]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jet fuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LanzaJet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LanzaTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mitsui]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shell]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134414</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The energy giant Shell has joined a slew of strategic investors including All Nippon Airways, Suncor Energy, Mitsui, and British Airways in funding LanzaJet, the company commercializing a process to convert alcohol into jet fuel.  A spin-off from LanzaTech, one of the last surviving climate tech startups from the first cleantech boom that&#8217;s still privately [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The energy giant Shell has joined a slew of strategic investors including All Nippon Airways, Suncor Energy, Mitsui, and British Airways in funding LanzaJet, the company commercializing a process to convert alcohol into jet fuel. </span></p>
<p>A spin-off from LanzaTech, one of the last surviving climate tech startups from the first cleantech boom that&#8217;s still privately held, LanzaJet is taking a phased investment approach with its corporate backers, enabling them to invest additional capital as the company scales to larger production facilities.</p>
<p>Terms of the initial investment, or LanzaJet&#8217;s valuation after the commitment, were not disclosed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>LanzaJet claims that it can help the aviation industry reach net-zero emissions, something that would go a long way toward helping the world meet the emissions reductions targets set in the <a href="https://unfccc.int/process-and-meetings/the-paris-agreement/the-paris-agreement#:~:text=The%20Paris%20Agreement%20is%20a,compared%20to%20pre%2Dindustrial%20levels.">Paris Agreement</a>.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;LanzaJet&#8217;s technology opens up a new and exciting pathway to produce SAF using an AtJ process and will help address the aviation sector&#8217;s urgent need for SAF. It demonstrates that the industry can move faster and deliver more when we all work together,&#8221; said Anna Mascolo, President, Shell Aviation, in a statement. &#8220;Provided industry, government and society collaborate on appropriate policy mechanisms and regulations to drive both supply and demand, aviation can achieve net-zero carbon emissions. The strategic fit with LanzaJet is exciting.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>LanzaJet is currently building an alcohol-to-jet fuel facility in Soperton, Ga. Upon completion it would be the first commercial scale plant for sustainable synthetic jet fuel with a capacity of 10 million gallons per year.</p>
<p>The fuel is made by using an ethanol inputs &#8212; something that Shell is very familiar with. It&#8217;s also something that the oil giant has in ready supply. Through the Raízen joint venture in Brazil, Shell has been producing bio-ethanol for over ten years.</p>
<p>The company expects that its sustainable fuel will be mixed with conventional fossil jet fuel to power airplanes in a lower carbon intensity way. Roughly 90% of the company&#8217;s production output will be aviation fuel, while the remaining 10% will be renewable diesel, the company said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> LanzaJet’s SAF is approved to be blended up to 50% with fossil jet fuel, the maximum allowed  by ASTM, and is a drop-in fuel that requires no modifications to engines, aircraft, and infrastructure.  Additionally, LanzaJet’s SAF delivers more than a 70% reduction in greenhouse gas emissions on a  lifecycle basis, compared to conventional fossil jet fuel. The versatility in ethanol, and a focus on low carbon, waste-based, and non-food /non-feed sources, along with ethanol’s global availability, make  LanzaJet’s technology a relevant and enduring solution for SAF. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/shell-invests-in-lanzajet-to-speed-up-deliveries-of-its-synthetic-aviation-fuel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134414</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Empathy emerges from stealth with $13M for a digital assistant aimed at bereaved families</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/empathy-emerges-from-stealth-with-13m-for-a-digital-assistant-aimed-at-bereaved-families/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/empathy-emerges-from-stealth-with-13m-for-a-digital-assistant-aimed-at-bereaved-families/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 11:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[empathy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Death, despite being one of the most inevitable of life&#8217;s events, can also be one of the most complicated and problematic. Fraught with emotional and religious complexities, for many families it can also come with financial and organizational ones. Today, a startup called Empathy is coming out of stealth with the aim of taking some [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Death, despite being one of the most inevitable of life&#8217;s events, can also be one of the most complicated and problematic. Fraught with emotional and religious complexities, for many families it can also come with financial and organizational ones. Today, a startup called <a href="http://empathy.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Empathy</a> is coming out of stealth with the aim of taking some of the stigma out of working on some of those challenges head-on, with an AI-based platform for families to help organize affairs (and thus indirectly help assist in those families attending to themselves) after a death.</p>
<p>&#8220;On average, a family can spend 500 hours dealing with the different aspects related to the death of a loved one,&#8221; said CEO Ron Gura, who co-founded the company with Yonatan Bergman. &#8220;We provide a digital companion in the form of native apps that are built to empower bereaved families.&#8221; He said he likens Empathy to a &#8220;GPS for the recently bereaved.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Israeli startup is launching first in the U.S. market, and it&#8217;s doing so with $13 million in funding co-led by VCs General Catalyst and Aleph.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Some 3 million people on average die in the U.S. each year &#8212; a number that has seen <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/excess-mortality-p-scores" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some spikes more recently due to Covid-19</a>. And despite it being one of the more natural and predictable of things that we will all go through sooner or later, it&#8217;s not something that many people prepare for, whether it&#8217;s due to fear or religion or simply not wanting to dwell on morbid subjects. Ironically, that hasn&#8217;t been helped by the fact that it has in turn created a pretty significant stigma around building services to help people deal with it, either for themselves, or on behalf of others.</p>
<p>In very typical startup fashion, this spells opportunity, of course.</p>
<p>&#8220;I’ve been obsessed with this narrative for a few years,&#8221; said Gura, who previously worked with Berman at The Gifts Project and then later at eBay in Israel after it acquired the social gifting startup. &#8220;Death is one of the last consumer sectors that is untouched by innovation. It’s not because of technology or even a regulatory barrier. It seems it&#8217;s mainly because of the inherent optimism in us and our human nature that causes us to avoid talking about the inevitable truth of death and dying. So there is an unspoken sector that is not seeing transformation that pretty much every other sector is seeing these days.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also, I suspect, because death makes people incredibly vulnerable, and any enterprise based around vulnerability feels off.</p>
<p>Empathy&#8217;s approach is to make its help, and the building of a business around that idea, as transparent as possible. The company offers services for free for the first 30 days, and after that you pay a one-off fee of $65, which does not go up the longer you use the service, which could be five months or five years (or yes, longer).</p>
<p>After you fill in a few details about your particular circumstance, you are then guided through a step-by-step process of all of the different things one needs to deal with after a person dies.</p>
<p>These include things like the first, immediate arrangements you might need to make, how to inform others (and informing them), organising a funeral or other ceremony, procuring the right documents, dealing with the will, securing the deceased&#8217;s identity, dealing with his/her property, organising a probate, settling benefits and accounts, and bills, and other assets, taxes and perhaps bereavement counseling for ourselves. For many of us, not only are we upset, but we may have never had to go through these processes before, and it&#8217;s a surreal learning curve to be experiencing when you are already on a potential emotional rollercoaster.</p>
<p>The idea with Empathy is that while some of these will require some lifting from you, the platform will play the part of a &#8220;digital assistant&#8221; by helping prompt what you need to do next, and give you guidance for how to get through that. It doesn&#8217;t refer you to others; it doesn&#8217;t advertise other services and never plans to. The data that does go into the platform, Gura said, will not be used anywhere other than where you are channelling it for the purposes of settling affairs.</p>
<p>Empathy is not the first but the next in an interesting and slowly growing cluster of startups tackling this area. Others include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/08/uks-farewill-raises-25m-for-its-new-approach-online-will-writing-funerals-and-other-death-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Farewill</a> in the UK, helping people write wills for themselves; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/lantern-is-a-startup-looking-to-ignite-a-conversation-about-how-to-die-well/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lantern</a> to help open up the conversation about death and planning for it; and estate planning startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/trust-will-raises-15m-as-digital-estate-planning-hits-mainstream/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Trust &amp; Will</a>. Competition, perhaps, but at least for now showing that there can be helpful tech build even for the more difficult areas of life.</p>
<p>“The end-of-life industry is a large sector that has been untouched by the wave of digital transformation occurring in every other industry,” said Joel Cutler, MD and co-founder of General Catalyst, in a statement. “Empathy is unique in that it addresses both the emotional and logistical anguish of loss.  We believe this is the technology and experience that can greatly benefit every family.”</p>
<p>“The Empathy team is directing their vast experience in consumer software to significantly improve how people handle the burdens that come with death,” added Michael Eisenberg, partner and co-founder at Aleph. “When grieving, many families do not have the bandwidth to deal with tasks and bureaucracy. By combining financial technology and emotional understanding, Empathy has built a product for the next-of kin with compassion at its core.”</p>
<p>Longer term, Gura said that Empathy may look to tackle other aspects of the process, such as organizing affairs before the death of a loved one, or perhaps looking at other problematic life events, like divorce, that also spur a lot of obligations in their aftermath.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/empathy-emerges-from-stealth-with-13m-for-a-digital-assistant-aimed-at-bereaved-families/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134399</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revolution Ventures backs Casted in B2B-focused podcast play</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/casted-raises-7m-in-revolution-led-series-a-for-b2b-focused-podcast-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/casted-raises-7m-in-revolution-led-series-a-for-b2b-focused-podcast-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B2B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Casted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david golden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revolution ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Historically, podcasts have been aimed at consumers. The value to be gained in the B2B world is something that has been largely untapped. For Lindsay Tjepkema &#8212; who has been entrenched in the world of B2B marketing for more than 15 years &#8212; the opportunity was massive. So in 2019, she founded Casted, an audio [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Historically, podcasts have been aimed at consumers. The value to be gained in the B2B world is something that has been largely untapped.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindsaytjepkema/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lindsay Tjepkema</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; who has been entrenched in the world of B2B marketing for more than 15 years &#8212; the opportunity was massive. So in 2019, she founded </span><a href="https://casted.us/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Casted</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, an audio and video podcast product aimed at B2B marketers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And now Casted has raised $7 million in Series A funding led by </span><a href="https://revolution.com/entity/ventures/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Revolution Ventures</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Existing backers High Alpha Capital, Elevate Ventures and Tappan Hill Ventures also participated in the financing, which brings Indianapolis-based Casted’s total raised to about $9.3 million since its inception.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 was a good year for Casted. The startup quadrupled its revenue, tripled its customer base and doubled the size of its team during the course of the 12-month period. It has an impressive list of customers, including PayPal, HubSpot, Drift and ZoomInfo. Casted’s platform is also “the system of record” for Salesforce’s 25+ podcasting shows.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And to make things even more impressive, that revenue growth looks more like 8x year over year, according to Tjepkema.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She believes the company’s value prop goes beyond just giving companies a way to get their podcasts out there. Its ability to analyze data and turn that into intelligence for sales and marketing is what really sets it apart, she said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RVkBaQGBZg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/more-thoughts-on-growing-podcasts/">More thoughts on growing podcasts</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;More thoughts on growing podcasts&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/more-thoughts-on-growing-podcasts/embed/#?secret=RVkBaQGBZg" data-secret="RVkBaQGBZg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“If you&#8217;re a podcaster, and you&#8217;re doing it to grow a large audience, monetize and sell advertising, the number of downloads is important,” Tjepkema told TechCrunch. “But when you&#8217;re a B2B company or an enterprise company, the number of downloads doesn&#8217;t help. You need to know who&#8217;s engaged, how are people interacting with the content and then how is that going to impact revenue and pipeline, and customer loyalty and lifetime value.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For starters, Casted’s SaaS platform gives marketing teams a way to publish content. Once published, Casted provides access to a “fully searchable content archive” with transcription services and tagging. It then also helps the company amplify that content via cross-channel distribution. And finally &#8212; largely by integrating with digital marketing platforms such as HubSpot, WordPress and Marketo &#8212; Casted’s software provides analytics on what a specific user is paying attention to. Those data-driven analytics becomes valuable information for sales and marketing teams in terms of who to target and why.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Because everything that&#8217;s in the platform is transcribed, there are ways to clip it up and share it across other channels and get that into the hands of your sales team so they can use it to make their conversations with their customers even easier,” Tjepkema said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Revolution Ventures Managing Partner David Golden said that marketing technology has been a difficult sector for his firm to invest in, considering the volume of companies providing a variety of services such as email optimization and sales automation and business intelligence.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“But what Lindsay and her team was building out was clearly a new category in this space and the sort of slap-your-forehead category. Of course, podcasting for B2B marketing makes all the sense in the world when you look at the evolution of tools that have been available to business marketers, such as blogs, white papers and webinars,” Golden told TechCrunch. “It was just going to be a matter of time before audio and video would be important pieces of that toolbox, and there was nobody doing it.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jtSt056a44"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/24/infinite-dial-2020/">Survey shows growth in podcasts and voice assistants, little change in streaming</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Survey shows growth in podcasts and voice assistants, little change in streaming&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/24/infinite-dial-2020/embed/#?secret=jtSt056a44" data-secret="jtSt056a44" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Revolution estimates that B2B content makes up roughly just 15% of the podcasting content out there today.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Given the growth on the consumer side, we think this could be up to a $20 billion market by five years from now,” Golden said.</span></p>
<p>The company, he added, is just one of a growing number of martech companies <a href="https://flyoverfuture.com/stories/tracing-the-dna-of-indys-martech-startup-boom/">based in Indianapolis</a>, including ExactTarget (which was acquired by Salesforce for $2.5 billion).</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, Casted said the new capital will go toward expanding its 25-person team and scaling the platform with new integrations and partnerships. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/casted-raises-7m-in-revolution-led-series-a-for-b2b-focused-podcast-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134318</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After its first $54M fund, Algebra Ventures launches $90M fund for startups in Egypt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/after-its-first-54m-fund-algebra-ventures-launches-another-90m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/after-its-first-54m-fund-algebra-ventures-launches-another-90m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Algebra Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Novastar Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tlcom Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The venture capital scene in the North African tech ecosystem will be absolutely buzzing right now with the announcement of two large VC funds in the space of two days. Today, Algebra Ventures, an Egyptian VC firm, announced that it has launched its $90 million second fund. Four years ago, Algebra Ventures closed its first [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The venture capital scene in the North African tech ecosystem will be </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">absolutely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> buzzing right now with the announcement of two large VC funds in the space of two days</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, <a href="https://algebraventures.com/">Algebra Ventures</a>, an Egyptian VC firm, announced that it has launched its $90 million second fund</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Four years ago, Algebra Ventures closed its first fund of $54 million, and with this announcement, the firm hopes to have raised a total of $144 million when the second fund closes (with first close by Q3 2021).</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> If achieved,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Algebra will most likely have the largest indigenous fund from North Africa and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">arguably</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the managing partners &#8212; <a href="https://eg.linkedin.com/in/tassaad">Tarek Assaad</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/karimhussein">Karim Hussein</a>, the first fund was an Egyptian-focused fund. Still, the firm made some selective investments</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a few companies outside the country</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second fund will be similar &#8212; Egypt first, Egypt focused, but allocating investments in East and West Africa, North Africa and the Middle East</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assaad and Hussein launched the firm in 2016 as one of Egypt&#8217;s first independent venture capital funds</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It wasn&#8217;t easy to start one at the time, and it took the partners two years to close the first fund.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Raising a venture capital fund in Egypt in 2016, in all honesty, was a pain. There was no venture capital to speak of back then,&#8221; Assaad told TechCrunch. &#8220;The high-flying startups back then were raising between $1 million and $2 million. We decided to take the bull by the horn and raise from very established LPs.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These LPs include Cisco, the European Commission, Egyptian-American Enterprise Fund (EAEF), European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD), International Finance Corporation (IFC) and private family offices</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">From the first fund, Algebra backed 21 startups in Egypt and MENA, and according to the firm, six of its most established companies </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are valued</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at over $350 million and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">collectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> generate more than $150 million in annual revenue</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It hopes to back 31 startups from the second fund.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lIum5oZvTX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/rising-african-venture-investment-powers-fintech-cleantech-bets-in-2020/">Rising African venture investment powers fintech, clean tech bets in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rising African venture investment powers fintech, clean tech bets in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/rising-african-venture-investment-powers-fintech-cleantech-bets-in-2020/embed/#?secret=lIum5oZvTX" data-secret="lIum5oZvTX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Algebra says it&#8217;s sector-agnostic but has a focus on fintech, logistics, health tech and agritech</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although the firm has invested in startups in seed and Series B stages, Algebra </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is known</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to be an investor in startups looking to raise Series A investments</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another appealing proposition from Algebra lies in the fact that it owns an in-house team focused on talent acquisition &#8212; in operations, marketing, finance, engineering, etc., for portfolio companies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The firm&#8217;s ticket size remains unchanged from the first fund and will continue to cut checks ranging from $500,000 to $2 million</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, some aspects </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">as to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> how the firm handles operations might change according to the partners</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;One of the lessons learned in our first fund is that we see that there are more interesting opportunities and great entrepreneurs in the seed stage</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And given that we&#8217;re more on the ground in Egypt, sometimes we wait for them to mature to Series A. But going forward, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">we might</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> need to build relationships with those we find </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">exceptional</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at the seed level and also expand our participation on the Series B level, too,&#8221; Hussein said on how the firm will act going forward</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2134337" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2134337" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2134337" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Karim-Hussein.jpg?w=680" alt="Algebra Ventures" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Karim-Hussein.jpg 7360w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Karim-Hussein.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Karim-Hussein.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Karim-Hussein.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Karim-Hussein.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Karim-Hussein.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Karim-Hussein.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Karim-Hussein.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2134337" class="wp-caption-text">Karim Hussein (Managing partner, Algebra Ventures)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hussein adds that the company will also be doubling down on its talent acquisition network</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Algebra helps portfolio companies hire C-level executives, and while it plans to continue doing so, the firm might adopt a startup studio model &#8212; pairing some professionals to start a company that eventually gets Algebra&#8217;s backing and support</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The reason behind this stems from the next set of companies Algebra will be looking to invest in. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Hussein, the partners at Algebra have studied successful businesses in other emerging markets for some time and want to identify parallels in North Africa where the firm can invest</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;In cases where the firm can&#8217;t find those opportunities, we may spur some of those in the network to start building those businesses and capture those opportunities,&#8221; he remarked</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VyrWIztaOo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/novastar-ventures-becomes-200m-african-vc-fund-after-108m-raise/">Novastar Ventures becomes $200M African VC fund after $108M raise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Novastar Ventures becomes $200M African VC fund after $108M raise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/novastar-ventures-becomes-200m-african-vc-fund-after-108m-raise/embed/#?secret=VyrWIztaOo" data-secret="VyrWIztaOo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before Algebra, Hussein has </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been involved</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with building some successful tech companies in the U.S. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Primarily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> an engineer after bagging both bachelors and doctorate degrees from Carnegie Mellon University and MIT, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, he ventured into the world of startup investing and entrepreneurship after working for a consulting company in the dot-com era</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He would go on to start Riskclick, a software company known for its commercial insurance applications</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The founders sold the company </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to Skywire before Oracle acquired the company to become part of its suite of insurance services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">After some time at WebMD, Hussein returned to Egypt and began mentoring startups as an angel investor</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alongside other angel investors, he co-founded Cairo Angels, an angel investor network in Egypt, in 2013</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;There was a massive gap in the market. We were putting in a bit of small angel money to these businesses but there were no VCs to take them to the next level. So I met up with Tarek and Ziad Mokhtar, and the rest is Algebra,&#8221; he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assaad is also an engineer. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">He obtained his bachelors in Egypt before switching careers by going to Stanford Graduate School of Business</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He continued on that path working for some Bay Area companies before his return to Egypt. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">On his return, he became a managing partner at Ideavelopers, a VC firm operating a $50 million fund since 2009</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The firm has had a couple of good success stories, the most notable being fintech startup Fawry. Fawry is n</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ow a publicly traded</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> billion-dollar company and Assaad was responsible for the investment which realized a $100 million exit for Ideavelopers in 2015</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2134336" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2134336" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2134336" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tarek-Assad.jpg?w=680" alt="Algebra Ventures" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tarek-Assad.jpg 7360w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tarek-Assad.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tarek-Assad.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tarek-Assad.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tarek-Assad.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tarek-Assad.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tarek-Assad.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tarek-Assad.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2134336" class="wp-caption-text">Tarek Assaad (Managing partner, Algebra Ventures)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With Algebra, both partners are pioneering local investments in the region. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of its portfolio companies are the most well-known companies on the continent &#8212; health tech startup Yodawy; social commerce platform Brimore; logistics startup Trella; ride-hailing and super app Halan; food discovery and ordering platform Elmenus; fintech startup, Khazna; and others</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The firm&#8217;s latest raise and $144 million capital amount is one of the largest funds dedicated to African startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other large Africa-focused funds include the $71 million fund recently closed by another Egyptian firm, Sawari Ventures; Partech&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/31/partech-is-doubling-the-size-of-its-african-venture-fund-to-143-million/">$143 million fund</a>; Novastar Ventures&#8217; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/novastar-ventures-becomes-200m-african-vc-fund-after-108m-raise/">$200 million fund</a>; and the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/tlcom-capital-closes-71m-africa-fund-with-plans-to-back-12-startups/">$71 million Tide Africa Fund</a> by TLcom Capital</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These funds have been very pivotal to the growth of the African tech ecosystem </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in terms of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> funding. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year, African startups raised almost $1.5 billion from both local and international investors, according to varying reports</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This number was j</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ust</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/23/the-rise-of-silicon-savannah-and-africas-tech-movement/"> half a billion dollars</a> six years ago.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, regardless of the period &#8212; 2015 or 2021 &#8212; African VC investments have always been </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">largely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> dominated by foreign investors</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">But VC firms like Algebra Ventures are showing that local investors can cumulatively raise nine-figure funds or attempt to do so. Obviously, this will provide more startups with more funds and pave the way for indigenous and local VCs to at least increase their participation to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">nearly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> equal levels when compared to international investors.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yC0tLl1AeA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/">How African startups raised investments in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How African startups raised investments in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/embed/#?secret=yC0tLl1AeA" data-secret="yC0tLl1AeA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/after-its-first-54m-fund-algebra-ventures-launches-another-90m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134281</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India’s CRED valued at $2.2 billion in new $215 million fundraise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/indias-cred-valued-at-2-2-billion-in-new-215-million-fundraise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/indias-cred-valued-at-2-2-billion-in-new-215-million-fundraise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 09:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coatue Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cred]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dragoneer investment group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DST Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[falcon edge capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greenoaks Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kunal Shah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RTP Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sofina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two-year-old CRED has become the youngest Indian startup to be valued at $2 billion or higher. Bangalore-based CRED said on Tuesday it has raised $215 million in a new funding round &#8212; a Series D &#8212; that valued the Indian startup at $2.2 billion (post-money), up from about $800 million valuation in the $81 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Two-year-old CRED has become the youngest Indian startup to be valued at $2 billion or higher.</p>
<p>Bangalore-based <a href="https://www.cred.club/">CRED</a> said on Tuesday it has raised $215 million in a new funding round &#8212; a Series D &#8212; that valued the Indian startup at $2.2 billion (post-money), up from about $800 million valuation in the $81 million <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/india-cred-raises-81m-buys-back-1-2m-shares-from-employees/">Series C round in January this year</a>.</p>
<p>New investor Falcon Edge Capital and existing investor Coatue Management led the new round. Insight Partners and existing investors DST Global, RTP Global, Tiger Global, Greenoaks Capital, Dragoneer Investment Group, and Sofina also participated in Series D, which brings CRED&#8217;s total to-date raise to about $443 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/india-cred-in-talks-to-raise-200-million-at-2-billion-valuation/">reported</a> last month that CRED was in advanced stages of talks to raise about $200 million at a valuation of around $2 billion.</p>
<p>CRED operates an app that rewards customers for paying their credit card bills on time and gives them access to a range of additional services such as credit and a premium catalog of products from high-end brands.</p>
<p>An individual needs to have a credit score of at least 750 to be able to sign up for CRED. By keeping such a high bar, the startup says it is ensuring that people are incentivized to improve their financial behavior. (More on this later.)</p>
<p>CRED today serves more than 6 million customers, or about 22% of all credit card holders &#8212; and 35% of all premium credit card holders &#8212; in the world’s second largest internet market.</p>
<p>Kunal Shah, founder and chief executive of CRED, told TechCrunch in an interview that the startup intends to become the platform for affluent customers in India and also not limit its offerings to financial services.</p>
<p>He said the startup’s aforementioned e-commerce service, for instance, has been growing fast. He attributed the early success to customers enjoying the curation of items on CRED and merchants finding the platform appealing as the ticket size of each transaction on CRED tends to be higher.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Our focus on helping CRED members progress financially and have access to a high-trust environment has given us a massive opportunity to shape responsible behaviour, imagine new use cases, and create a rewarding platform for members.</p>
<p>&mdash; Kunal Shah (@kunalb11) <a href="https://twitter.com/kunalb11/status/1379373976493916160?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 6, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The startup plans to deploy the fresh funds to scale several of its revenue channels and engage in more experimentations, he said.</p>
<p>When asked whether CRED would like to serve all credit card users in India some day, Shah said the selection criteria limits the startup from doing so, but he was optimistic that more users will improve their scores in the future.</p>
<p>The startup, unlike most others in India, doesn’t focus on the usual TAM (addressable market) — hundreds of millions of users of the world’s second-most populated nation — and instead caters to some of the most premium audiences.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2124997" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2124997" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2124997 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/india-fintech-market.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="339" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/india-fintech-market.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/india-fintech-market.jpg?resize=150,50 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/india-fintech-market.jpg?resize=300,99 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/india-fintech-market.jpg?resize=768,254 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/india-fintech-market.jpg?resize=680,225 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/india-fintech-market.jpg?resize=50,17 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2124997" class="wp-caption-text">Consumer segmentation and addressable market for fintech firms in India (BofA Research)</p></div></p>
<p>“India has 57 million credit cards (vs 830 million debit cards) [that] largely serves the high-end market. The credit card industry is largely concentrated with the top 4 banks (HDFC, SBI, ICICI and Axis) controlling about 70% of the total market. This space is extremely profitable for these banks – as evident from the SBI Cards IPO,” analysts at Bank of America wrote in a recent report to clients.</p>
<p>“Very few startups like CRED are focusing on this high-end base and [have] taken a platform-based approach (acquire customers now and look for monetization later). Credit card in India remains an aspirational product. The under penetration would likely ensure continued strong growth in coming years. Overtime, the form-factor may evolve (i.e. move from plastic card to virtual card), but the inherent demand for credit is expected to grow,” they added.</p>
<p>CRED has become one of the most talked about startups in India, in part because of the pace at which it has raised money of late, its growing valuation, and the fact that it only caters to select customers.</p>
<p>Some users have also said that CRED doesn&#8217;t offer as appealing perks as it used to a year ago.</p>
<p>Shah, who is one of the most prolific angel investors in India and delivered one of the rare successful exits in the country with his previous venture, said CRED is already addressing these concerns. A recent feature, which allows customers to use CRED points at over a thousand merchants, for instance, has made the reward more appealing, he said, adding that the startup is slowly incorporating that into its own e-commerce store as well.</p>
<p>&#8220;What will soon happen is that customers will realize that these points are asset and not a liability. They will start to see benefits of the points in more places,&#8221; he said, adding that the pandemic derailed some of the things CRED had planned.</p>
<p>The startup, which bought back shares worth $1.2 million from employees in January this year, told them in an email today that it will soon be buying back stocks worth $5 million. &#8220;As the funding helps CRED invest in its future, hopefully the buyback will help some of you do that too,&#8221; the email said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/indias-cred-valued-at-2-2-billion-in-new-215-million-fundraise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134388</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brighton-based MPB snaps up $69M to build out its used camera equipment marketplace</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/brighton-based-mpb-snaps-up-69m-to-build-out-its-used-camera-equipment-marketplace/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/brighton-based-mpb-snaps-up-69m-to-build-out-its-used-camera-equipment-marketplace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 09:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cameras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circular economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketplaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[used goods]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Used-goods marketplaces, an online staple since the beginning of the internet as we know it, have really come into their own during the Covid-19 pandemic: they&#8217;ve been a place for people clearing out their domestic spaces to list items that they have that are still in good shape, making some money in the process; and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Used-goods marketplaces, an online staple since the beginning of the internet as we know it, have really come into their own during the Covid-19 pandemic: they&#8217;ve been a place for people clearing out their domestic spaces to list items that they have that are still in good shape, making some money in the process; and for buyers, they are a resource for finding items at a time when shopping in person and spending money in uncertain economic times have both fallen out of favor. Today, <a href="https://www.mpb.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MPB</a> &#8212; a popular marketplace that specializes in used cameras and photographic equipment &#8212; is announcing significant funding to double down on the opportunity after seeing its platform &#8220;recirculate&#8221; some 300,000 items of kit globally each year and pass £100 million ($139 million) in revenues this year.</p>
<p>The Brighton, England-based startup has snapped up £49.8 million (about $69 million at current exchange rates). It plans to use the money both to expand into more markets &#8212; it currently has offices in Brooklyn and Berlin &#8212; and into more product areas, specifically, extending the marketplace concept to serve content creators.</p>
<p>The Series D is being led by Vitruvian Partners, with significant participation from Acton Capital, and Mobeus Equity Partners, Beringea and FJ Labs also participating. Vitruvian is a new backer for MPB; the rest were already invested in the startup, which has raised around $91 million since 2011.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>MPB did not disclose its valuation in a statement on the fundraise; we have contacted the company to ask and will update if / when we learn more.</p>
<p>For some context, this is the biggest-ever round raised by a startup out of Brighton. Home to one university and right next to another, Brighton has had some tech world focus &#8212; Brandwatch made a splash in February when it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/brandwatch-is-acquired-by-cision-for-450m-creating-a-pr-marketing-and-social-listening-giant/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired by Cision for $450 million</a>; and it is well known for gaming companies and talent &#8212; but has largely been off the fundraising radar, perhaps in part because it is so close to London and its own gravitational pull for entrepreneurs and VCs. <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/133204-42/company/profile#insights" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PitchBook</a> put MPB&#8217;s valuation at $50.86 million in 2019; it&#8217;s likely to be significantly higher than this now.</p>
<p>“This funding round is a major milestone for MPB, culminating a decade of strong performance and a vision to make great kit accessible and affordable,&#8221; said Matt Barker, MPB&#8217;s founder and CEO, in a statement. &#8220;With the backing of Vitruvian Partners and those reinvesting in our business, we can accelerate our US and European growth strategy at scale, profitably. Photography and videography are intrinsic to societies and cultures all over the world, and at MPB we have created a circular model that offers everyone the chance to be visual storytellers and content creators in a way that’s good for the planet.”</p>
<p>Indeed, what&#8217;s interesting about MPB is how it touches on and addresses a number of themes that have been playing out across the world of e-commerce and wider digital society, and what&#8217;s probably made it successful has been its appeal to people on one or more of those fronts at the same time.</p>
<p>First, there is the platform it gives to people to sell and buy used camera equipment. The sale of used items gives owners an opportunity to make money off items they no longer need, and buyers a way to procure items at lower costs. And it has an obvious environmental angle to it, since circular economy operators encourage people to get more life out of electronics that might otherwise simply become part of landfill (or encourage more manufacturing of new goods in their place).</p>
<p>But on a more practical level, used-good sales also have often put people off in part because they are deprived of some of the guarantees that you would normally get on goods when buying from more established retailers.</p>
<p>MPB provides buying and seller security in its own way: by employing a team of people to vet and prepare items for sale, and providing a six-month guarantee on items sold over its platform. That has paid off for it even pre-pandemic: the company said that its compound growth rate over the last five years has been 53%.</p>
<p>(And more generally, used goods marketplaces are seeing some big attention from VCs at the moment in Europe: in February, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/spains-wallapop-raises-191m-at-an-840m-valuation-for-its-classifieds-marketplace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wallapop in Spain raised $191 million</a> for its more generalised used-goods marketplace, and in March <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/vestiaire-collective-raises-216-million-for-its-second-hand-fashion-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vestaire Collective raised $216 million</a>.)</p>
<p>Second, it touches on the bigger trend we&#8217;ve seen around the growth of communities focused on specific rather than general interests. It&#8217;s a clear way of conferring more authenticity, focus and signal in an otherwise very noisy world online, and in a specialized area like the sale of photography equipment, this can be especially critical and a unique selling point over more generic sales platforms like eBay: it means more attention paid by the platform to stock, as well as a more focused community of buyers and sellers.</p>
<p>Third, there is the focus of MPB in particular. We have most definitely seen the birth of a &#8220;creator economy&#8221; online, where people are making livings out of their own brands (ugh), or from their specific creative output, bypassing some of the more traditional middle-men in favor of newer ones (eg, network broadcasters no longer the sole gatekeepers for serialized video content and all of the work that goes into making it; YouTube conversely now makes a killing off it, and if Substack, Patreon and others like it play their cards right, they will soon, in their own areas of interest, too.)</p>
<p>What this might mean for companies like MPB is a surge of interest and attention on equipment for capturing those images, although it will be interesting to see how and if that can be leveraged on a wider scale, given how so much of that creation today is happening on smartphones, which themselves continue to get more sophisticated and eat into not just casual photographers&#8217; buying patterns, but more serious ones, too.</p>
<p>In the question of scaling, MPB will have an interesting partner in the form of Vitruvian Partners, which backs second-hand clothes marketplace Vestiaire Collective &#8212; which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/vestiaire-collective-raises-216-million-for-its-second-hand-fashion-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $216 million last month</a>, another sign of the times and how they have boosted the opportunities for used-good sales &#8212; alongside other marketplaces like Carwow, Just Eat, Farfetch, Skyscanner and Trustpilot.</p>
<p>“MPB has developed a unique tech-enabled platform to meet a market need, transforming access to photography kit to become a global leader in its field, whilst building a product that genuinely has a positive impact on the world,&#8221; said Tom Studd, partner at Vitruvian Partners, said in a statement. &#8220;Matt and the team have achieved strong and profitable growth through recent launches in the US and Germany, and we’re delighted to partner with them for the next step of the journey. Vitruvian looks to back exceptional teams with unique products in large markets, and we believe Matt and the team fit those criteria perfectly.”</p>
<p>Sebastian Wossagk, managing partner at Acton Capital, added: “It’s always a privilege to watch companies like MPB grow and excel in their field. Matt and his team have already taken the first steps into internationalisation by opening locations in Brooklyn and Berlin, and we’re excited to support them as they pursue further expansion in both the US and Europe.”</p>
<p>Something notable about MPB is that Barker <a href="https://spectrumphoto.co.uk/5-questions-mpb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">once said</a> that he founded it in part because he didn&#8217;t feel that the requirements of people in the photography community were being addressed well enough by more general sites like eBay or Gumtree. That may still be the case for those two sites (and countless other generic sales platforms), but it doesn&#8217;t mean that there are not a number of other players addressing the used-photography equipment market. They include the likes of <a href="https://www.worldwidecameraexchange.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Worldwide Camera Exchange</a>, <a href="https://www.parkcameras.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Park Cameras</a>, <a href="https://www.cameraworld.co.uk/used" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Camera World</a>, and many others with equally SEO-friendly names. That represents opportunities for consolidation, competitive threat, and hopefully innovation for better services, but also a sign that there is more to this market than might meet the eye.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/brighton-based-mpb-snaps-up-69m-to-build-out-its-used-camera-equipment-marketplace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134386</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bob W, the &#8216;tech-driven&#8217; hospitality provider, raises €10M in seed funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/bob-w/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/bob-w/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 09:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bob W]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[byFounders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finnish industry investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lodging]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2133903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bob W, the self-described &#8220;tech-driven&#8221; hospitality provider that offers an alternative to traditional hotels and short-stay rentals, is disclosing €10 million in seed funding. Leading the round, which included a first tranche of €4 million last year, is byFounders VC and private equity firm Finnish Industry Investment (Tesi). Other European real estate and venture capitalist [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://bobw.co">Bob W</a>, the self-described &#8220;tech-driven&#8221; hospitality provider that offers an alternative to traditional hotels and short-stay rentals, is disclosing €10 million in seed funding.</p>
<p>Leading the round, which included a first tranche of €4 million last year, is byFounders VC and private equity firm Finnish Industry Investment (Tesi). Other European real estate and venture capitalist investors participating include Kaamos, Superangel, United Angels and NREP (via its anchor investment into the 2150 venture capital fund, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/2150-launches-with-281m-fund-to-reduce-the-carbon-footprint-of-the-worlds-growing-cities/">promises to back</a> sustainable urban technologies).</p>
<p>Founded in 2018 by Niko Karstikko and Sebastian Emberger, Bob W &#8212; which is a play on the phrase &#8220;best of both worlds&#8221; &#8212; is described as offering tech-powered short-stay apartments that combine hotel-like quality with the authenticity of individual rentals.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Its &#8220;full-stack&#8221; model sees it source and manage properties and provide an accompanying app for guests, with support for chat-based customer service and contactless online check-in. It also claims to have made the majority of its operations autonomous. &#8220;[This] not only minimises human error but also allows the company to craft the entire guest experience, from booking to check-out, at scale,&#8221; says the company.</p>
<p>Launched in a number of Nordics markets, and on the verge of opening properties in London, the startup seems to be weathering the pandemic, reaching occupancy rates as high as 90% at its existing properties in Estonia and Finland. Revenue is also said to have grown by 80% in 2020, with the company putting a lot of marketing toward claims behind being more hygienic than many hotels.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pr6tGWKRqF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/">10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/embed/#?secret=pr6tGWKRqF" data-secret="pr6tGWKRqF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;A new generation of travellers have developed a refined taste when it comes to accommodation; they’re mixing business with pleasure and often staying for longer,&#8221; says Niko Karstikko co-founder and CEO of Bob W. &#8220;They want the reliable quality of a hotel and the authenticity and convenience of a private apartment. The problem is that many hotels feel generic and lack key amenities like kitchens, while booking a private rental feels like playing roulette&#8221;.</p>
<p>Despite this contradiction, Karstikko says the short-stay rental market has continued to grow over the past decade with millions of properties available, &#8220;demonstrating the demand for home-like settings where guests can live like a local&#8221;. And it&#8217;s this demand that was the inspiration behind Bob W.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2134197" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2134197" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2134197" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Helsinki_CityCentre_2.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="408" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Helsinki_CityCentre_2.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Helsinki_CityCentre_2.jpg?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Helsinki_CityCentre_2.jpg?resize=300,180 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Helsinki_CityCentre_2.jpg?resize=768,461 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Helsinki_CityCentre_2.jpg?resize=680,408 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Helsinki_CityCentre_2.jpg?resize=1536,922 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Helsinki_CityCentre_2.jpg?resize=2048,1229 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Helsinki_CityCentre_2.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2134197" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bob W</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Bob W guarantees the best short-stay apartment experience, which includes the amenities and local authenticity of a home combined with responsive host communication available 24/7, the best professional cleaning program in the industry, curated local service partners (gym, breakfast, etc.), dedicated business services and more&#8221;.</p>
<p>This means that guests can rely on &#8220;hotel-like consistency&#8221; across all of Bob W&#8217;s locations, without paying hotel prices and with &#8220;the flexibility to stay days, weeks or months&#8221;.</p>
<p>Karstikko says a typical Bob W guest is someone who &#8220;travels less but stays longer&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;They often mix business and pleasure and come for leisure, work, digital nomad-ery or just to get away and get a taste of living like a local,&#8221; he explains. &#8220;To do that, they seek out authentic places to stay which also have the amenities and consistent quality they expect, like a fully equipped kitchen and some elbow room. What they want is a home away from home&#8221;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7bhDz0y3dE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/cosi-raises-e20m/">Cosi raises €20M for its &#8216;full-stack&#8217; approach to short-term rentals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cosi raises €20M for its &#8216;full-stack&#8217; approach to short-term rentals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/cosi-raises-e20m/embed/#?secret=7bhDz0y3dE" data-secret="7bhDz0y3dE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Meanwhile, direct competitors include the likes of Sonder, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/cosi-raises-e20m/">Cosi Group</a>, Lime Home and, more broadly, the hotel and short-stay segments. To that end, Karstikko argues that Bob W is the &#8220;most local, authentic experience&#8221; on the market and offers the most consistent, yet customized experience. It also pitches itself on being more sustainable.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have put sustainability at the core of everything we do,&#8221; adds the Bob W CEO, &#8220;from powering our apartments with 100% renewable energy to recycling, minimising single-use plastic, sourcing furniture responsibly and [other] green initiatives throughout the business. We will also have massive news soon about how we’re taking sustainability to the next level, as all of us need to do more to combat the climate crisis&#8221;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/bob-w/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2133903</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Charles raises €6.4M seed to bring &#8216;conversational commerce&#8217; to WhatsApp</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/charles/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/charles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 07:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HV Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134209</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Charles, a Berlin-based startup that offers a &#8220;conversational-commerce&#8221; SaaS for businesses that want to sell on WhatsApp and other chat apps, has raised €6.4 million in funding. Led by Accel and HV Capital, the seed funding will be used by the company to scale and meet existing demand for its conversational commerce platform. Launched in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.hello-charles.com">Charles</a>, a Berlin-based startup that offers a &#8220;conversational-commerce&#8221; SaaS for businesses that want to sell on WhatsApp and other chat apps, has raised €6.4 million in funding.</p>
<p>Led by Accel and HV Capital, the seed funding will be used by the company to scale and meet existing demand for its conversational commerce platform.</p>
<p>Launched in 2020 by Artjem Weissbeck and Andreas Tussing after the pair had run a year-long experiment running a store in WhatsApp, Charles enables businesses to sell products and services via WhatsApp and other chat apps in order to &#8220;increase conversion rate, customer loyalty and ultimately revenue&#8221;.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The SaaS connects chat app APIs, such as WhatsApp and Messenger, with shop and CRM systems, like Shopify, SAP and HubSpot, all delivered through a user-friendly interface. The idea is to make it easier for businesses to meet their customers on the channels they already use and to bridge the gap between sales enquiries and support, and actual conversions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WfcG4BDsCN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/social-payments-why-fintechs-need-social-features/">Social+ payments: Why fintechs need social features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Social+ payments: Why fintechs need social features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/social-payments-why-fintechs-need-social-features/embed/#?secret=WfcG4BDsCN" data-secret="WfcG4BDsCN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8221; &#8216;Traffic&#8217; and with it &#8216;conversion&#8217; will exponentially move from the streets (retail) and the browser/native apps into chat apps,&#8221; says Weissbeck. &#8220;Thereby, conversational commerce will be the third big pillar of commerce, gluing together all channels and unlocking the full potential of personalization via the unique identification of customers via their phone number&#8221;.</p>
<p>This transition, argues the Charles founder, creates &#8220;tremendous challenges and opportunities&#8221; for companies in terms of customer journey design and the tech stack, which to date &#8212; Asia, aside &#8212; has been predominantly tailored around webshops and e-mail.</p>
<p>&#8220;Ultimately our technology provides the operating system for companies to master this challenge,&#8221; adds Tussing. &#8220;The core of our software integrates chat apps with shop/CRM backends in an intuitive interface that puts the human chat sales agent in the center, supported by chatbots and AI&#8221;.</p>
<p>Luca Bocchio, partner at Accel, says that conversational commerce is emerging as a &#8220;critical channel for brands,” and is a trend that will reshape the way brands interact with customers. [This is] paving the way for potential new category-defining tools to emerge,&#8221; he says, noting that Charles has the potential to be one of those tools.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GyIO6XIyka"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/messagebird-acquisitions/">MessageBird acquires 24sessions to bring video to its &#8216;omnichannel&#8217; platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MessageBird acquires 24sessions to bring video to its &#8216;omnichannel&#8217; platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/messagebird-acquisitions/embed/#?secret=GyIO6XIyka" data-secret="GyIO6XIyka" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;When we talk to potential clients it&#8217;s mostly existing customer service tools like Zendesk who are starting to add chat apps as an additional channel,&#8221; says Weissbeck, when asked to cite direct competitors. &#8220;These tools are usually built upon a &#8216;ticketing&#8217; logic, optimized to solve customer inquiries as quickly as possible and with a clear focus on service cases, not sales&#8221;.</p>
<p>In contrast, Weissbeck says Charles is built upon a &#8220;feed&#8221; logic, showing customer interaction as an ongoing conversation and end-to-end relationship &#8212; in the same way as the customer sees it.</p>
<p>&#8220;Further we deeply integrate into shop/CRM-backends to make it easy for agents to sell product and create carts or contracts &#8212; all in a very design-driven and intuitive interface, that is fun to use for the agent and puts her/him in the center,&#8221; says Tussing. &#8220;Supported by chatbots, not replaced&#8221;.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the revenue model is simple enough: Businesses pay a monthly base fee to cover Charles&#8217; fixed costs and on top of this the startup earns money on conversions. &#8220;We take a small share of the net sales, ensuring we are co-incentivised,&#8221; explains Weissbeck.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/charles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134209</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Egyptian VC firm Sawari Ventures finally closes $71M fund for North African startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/sawari-ventures-finally-closes-71m-fund-for-north-african-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/sawari-ventures-finally-closes-71m-fund-for-north-african-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 06:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morocco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sawari Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swvl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tunisia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2133892</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Egyptian-based VC firm Sawari Ventures has closed its $71 million fund for North Africa&#8217;s rapidly growing startup ecosystem. The firm first announced its fund in 2018, when it closed an initial $35 million (which subsequently increased to $41 million) in hopes to close at $70 million, per Menabytes. The investors in the first tranche included [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Egyptian-based VC firm <a href="https://sawariventures.com/">Sawari Ventures</a> has closed its $71 million fund for North Africa&#8217;s rapidly growing startup ecosystem</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The firm first <a href="https://www.menabytes.com/sawari-ventures-35-million-fund/">announced its fund</a> in 2018, when it closed an initial $35 million (which </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">subsequently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> increased to $41 million) in hopes to close at $70 million, per Menabytes</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The investors in the first tranche included CDC (which <a href="https://www.cdcgroup.com/en/our-impact/fund/sawari-ventures-fund-i/">forked over $12 million</a>), European Investment Bank, Proparco and the Dutch Good Growth Fund</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having closed an </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">additional</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> $30 million, Sawari Ventures&#8217; total raise is $1 million more than</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> its original target</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. And </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">it has added a range of new backers that includes Banque Misr, Banque du Caire, Ekuity, Misr Insurance Group, National Bank of Egypt and Suez Canal Bank</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://eg.linkedin.com/in/ahmed-el-alfi-622a204b">Ahmed El Alfi</a>, <a href="https://eg.linkedin.com/in/hany-al-sonbaty-12274322">Hany Al-Sonbaty</a> and <a href="https://www.itworx.com/company/board/wael-amin-board-director/">Wael Amin</a> launched Sawari Ventures in 2010. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before venturing into the world of venture capital, El Alfi and Al-Sonbaty were investment professionals in the Egyptian tech space for more than two decades</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amin, meanwhile, was a founder of a tech company called ITWorx that made notable acquisitions in the Egyptian tech ecosystem</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to Egypt, Sawari Ventures focuses on Morocco and Tunisia. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the firm, these three countries represent one of the best investment opportunities around given the mismatch between the capital available (amounts and variation at every stage) and the market opportunity</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They also share common traits such as language, culture, business, governance norms and market dynamics, making it easier for cross-border cooperation</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since launching the firm over 10 years ago, Sawari claims to have invested in more than 30 companies, mostly in Egypt</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of these companies include ride-hailing service SWVL, software startup Instabug, and AI chat-based personal assistant Elves, but its</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> sweet spots are the hardware, education, healthcare, cleantech and fintech sectors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We try to cast a wide net given that, in essence, this is a transformative moment in emerging markets tech with the rapid digitization of the underlying economy,&#8221; a company spokesperson told TechCrunch</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;So as expected, we’re seeing a great deal flow in the digitization of financial services, health care and education technologies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, given the engineering talent, there are unique opportunities in SaaS products, semiconductors and IoT</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sawari Ventures invests in growth-stage companies, in particular. But it also</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> operates <a href="https://flat6labs.com/">Flat6Labs</a>, a seed VC firm akin to an accelerator that has </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been used</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to perform its seed investments since establishing both Cairo and Tunis offices in 2011 and 2016</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2134335" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2134335" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2134335" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Sawari-Ventures-Closes-L.E.-1-Billion-Fund-to-Invest-in-Egyptian-Tech-driven-Companies.jpg?w=680" alt="Sawari Ventures" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Sawari-Ventures-Closes-L.E.-1-Billion-Fund-to-Invest-in-Egyptian-Tech-driven-Companies.jpg 2939w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Sawari-Ventures-Closes-L.E.-1-Billion-Fund-to-Invest-in-Egyptian-Tech-driven-Companies.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Sawari-Ventures-Closes-L.E.-1-Billion-Fund-to-Invest-in-Egyptian-Tech-driven-Companies.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Sawari-Ventures-Closes-L.E.-1-Billion-Fund-to-Invest-in-Egyptian-Tech-driven-Companies.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Sawari-Ventures-Closes-L.E.-1-Billion-Fund-to-Invest-in-Egyptian-Tech-driven-Companies.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Sawari-Ventures-Closes-L.E.-1-Billion-Fund-to-Invest-in-Egyptian-Tech-driven-Companies.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Sawari-Ventures-Closes-L.E.-1-Billion-Fund-to-Invest-in-Egyptian-Tech-driven-Companies.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Sawari-Ventures-Closes-L.E.-1-Billion-Fund-to-Invest-in-Egyptian-Tech-driven-Companies.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2134335" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sawari Ventures</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sawari says 10% of the now-closed investments will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be earmarked</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for seed-stage companies as investments through Flat6Labs Cairo and Tunis</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Flat6Labs Cairo will seed between 80 to 100 companies and offer follow-on investments to between 30 and 40</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Flat6Labs Tunisia will seed 60 to 70 companies and offer follow-on investments for 30 to 40. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The remaining 90% will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be used</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to invest in 20 to 25 growth-stage companies across Egypt, Tunisia and Morocco, with a median investment range of $2 million to $3 million</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The investment range is a continuation of how Sawari </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">typically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> cut checks for <a href="https://sawariventures.com/portfolio/">portfolio startups</a> since closing the first tranche three years ago</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The firm said it has invested between $1 million and $4 million in</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Elves</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brantu</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">ExpandCart</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Almentor, SWVL and MoneyFellows, among others</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The Egypt-based fund is a privately held fund regulated by the Financial Regulatory Authority of Egypt (FRA), which allowed us to attract capital from top-tier local financial institutions to co-invest with foreign capital from international development financial institutions, doubling our allocation to invest in Egyptian high-growth companies to $68 million,” El Alfi said in a statement</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our aim is to create exceptional returns through investing in knowledge-driven companies, which have the potential of bringing transformational changes to the Egyptian economy</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fund will support local companies with dedicated capital, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to quality expertise from our seasoned and specialized team, and the value-add of our investors</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/sawari-ventures-finally-closes-71m-fund-for-north-african-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2133892</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taiwan-based MLOps startup InfuseAI raises $4.3M Series A led by Wistron Corporation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/taiwan-based-mlops-startup-infuseai-raises-4-3m-series-a-led-by-wistron-corporation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/taiwan-based-mlops-startup-infuseai-raises-4-3m-series-a-led-by-wistron-corporation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 05:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[InfuseAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MLops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taiwan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AI models not only take time to build and train, but also to deploy in an organization’s workflow. That’s where MLOps (machine learning operations) companies come in, helping clients scale their AI technology. InfuseAI, a MLOps startup based in Taiwan, announced today it has raised a $4.3 million Series A, led by original design manufacturer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">AI models not only take time to build and train, but also to deploy in an organization’s workflow. That’s where MLOps (machine learning operations) companies come in, helping clients scale their AI technology. <a href="https://www.infuseai.io/">InfuseAI</a>, a MLOps startup based in Taiwan, announced today it has raised a $4.3 million Series A, led by original design manufacturer Wistron Corporation, with participation from Hive Ventures, Top Taiwan Venture Capital Group and Silicon Valley Taiwan Investments.</p>
<p>Founded in 2018, InfuseAI says the market for MLOps solutions is worth $30 million a year in Taiwan, with the global market expected to reach about $4 billion by 2025, <a href="https://www.cognilytica.com/2020/04/02/infographic-the-rapid-growth-of-mlops/">according to research firm Cognilytica</a>. Its clients include E.SUN, one of Taiwan’s largest banks, SinoPac Holdings and Chimei.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2uYqXhRFie"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/06/enterprise-companies-find-mlops-critical-for-reliability-and-performance/">Enterprise companies find MLOps critical for reliability and performance</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Enterprise companies find MLOps critical for reliability and performance&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/06/enterprise-companies-find-mlops-critical-for-reliability-and-performance/embed/#?secret=2uYqXhRFie" data-secret="2uYqXhRFie" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>InfuseAI helps companies deploy and manage machine learning models with turnkey solutions like PrimeHub, a platform that includes a model training environment, cloud or on-premise cluster computing (including container orchestration with Kubernetes) and collaboration tools for teams. Another product, called PrimeHub Deploy, lets clients train, deploy, update and monitor AI models.</p>
<p>In a press statement, Hive Ventures founder and managing partner Yan Lee said, &#8220;As enterprises from manufacturing, healthcare, finance and other sectors seek to scale their AI operations and model deployments, they will require a platform like InfuseAI to allow seamless collaboration between developers and data scientists. InfuseAI fits perfectly into our investment thesis which is focused on platforms and software in the enterprise adoption cycle.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e6TntCyPBx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/arrikto-raises-10m-for-its-mlops-platform/">Arrikto raises $10M for its MLOps platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Arrikto raises $10M for its MLOps platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/arrikto-raises-10m-for-its-mlops-platform/embed/#?secret=e6TntCyPBx" data-secret="e6TntCyPBx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/taiwan-based-mlops-startup-infuseai-raises-4-3m-series-a-led-by-wistron-corporation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134379</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Singapore-based career platform Glints gets $22.5M in Series C funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/singapore-based-career-platform-glints-gets-22-5m-in-series-c-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/singapore-based-career-platform-glints-gets-22-5m-in-series-c-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 04:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glints]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[job platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Glints, the Singapore-based career platform, announced today it has raised $22.5 million in Series C funding led by Japanese human resources management firm PERSOL Holdings. The new capital will be used on Glints’ expansion in Singapore, Indonesia, Vietnam and Taiwan and hiring for its product and engineering teams. Glints co-founder and chief executive officer Oswald [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://glints.com/">Glints</a>, the Singapore-based career platform, announced today it has raised $22.5 million in Series C funding led by Japanese human resources management firm PERSOL Holdings. The new capital will be used on Glints’ expansion in Singapore, Indonesia, Vietnam and Taiwan and hiring for its product and engineering teams.</p>
<p>Glints co-founder and chief executive officer Oswald Yeo said this is the largest funding round to date for a talent platform in Southeast Asia, and brings the startup’s total raised to $33 million. Other participants included returning investors Monk’s Hill Ventures, Fresco Capital, Mindworks Ventures, Wavemaker Partners, Flipkart co-founder Binny Bansal and former Goldman Sachs TMT China head and partner Xiaoyin Zhang.</p>
<p>Founded in 2013, Glints says it has been used by more than 1.5 million professionals and 30,000 organizations, including Gojek, Tokopedia, Starbucks and Mediacorp. Most of its current users are from the tech and financial services sectors, but Glints has a &#8220;broad horizontal focus on young to mid-level professionals,&#8221; and its long-term goal is to be sector agnostic, Yeo told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EnYzZIVtXV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/cakeresume-which-wants-to-become-asias-largest-tech-talent-pool-raises-900000-seed-round/">CakeResume, which wants to become Asia&#8217;s largest tech talent pool, raises $900,000 seed round</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;CakeResume, which wants to become Asia&#8217;s largest tech talent pool, raises $900,000 seed round&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/cakeresume-which-wants-to-become-asias-largest-tech-talent-pool-raises-900000-seed-round/embed/#?secret=EnYzZIVtXV" data-secret="EnYzZIVtXV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>One of the ways Glints differentiates from other job platforms active in its markets, like LinkedIn, JobStreet and CakeResume, is by building a &#8220;full-stack&#8221; of services for people who want to advance their careers. In addition to its job marketplace, which the company says has more than 7,000 active listings and 4 million visitors each month, Glints also offers community features and skills education, like online classes.</p>
<p>One of Glints’ value propositions is helping companies, especially in tech, cope with the regional talent shortage, a topic it recently covered in <a href="https://www.monkshill.com/content-hub/the-southeast-asia-tech-talent-report-mhv">a comprehensive report</a> with Monk’s Hill Ventures.</p>
<p>One of the solutions the report highlighted is hiring teams based in different Southeast Asian countries to address talent crunches in specific markets, like Singapore. Glints says its cross-border remote work hub, TalentHub, doubled its business in 2020 as the pandemic also made employers more open to hiring remotely.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kOJd9n7nNC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/monks-hill-ventures-and-glints-on-how-southeast-asian-startups-can-cope-with-the-regions-talent-crunch/">Monk&#8217;s Hill Ventures and Glints on how Southeast Asian startups can cope with the region&#8217;s talent crunch</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Monk&#8217;s Hill Ventures and Glints on how Southeast Asian startups can cope with the region&#8217;s talent crunch&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/monks-hill-ventures-and-glints-on-how-southeast-asian-startups-can-cope-with-the-regions-talent-crunch/embed/#?secret=kOJd9n7nNC" data-secret="kOJd9n7nNC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/singapore-based-career-platform-glints-gets-22-5m-in-series-c-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134372</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>KKR closes $15 billion fund targeting consumption and urbanization in Asia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/kkr-closes-15-billion-fund-targeting-consumption-and-urbanization-in-asia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/kkr-closes-15-billion-fund-targeting-consumption-and-urbanization-in-asia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 04:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asia pacific]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reliance jio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[KKR has just closed $15 billion for its Asia-focused private equity fund, exceeding its original target size after receiving &#8220;strong support&#8221; from new and existing global investors, including those in the Asia Pacific region. The new close came nearly four years after KKR raised its Asian Fund III of $9.3 billion and marks the New [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">KKR has just closed $15 billion for its Asia-focused private equity fund, exceeding its original target size after receiving &#8220;strong support&#8221; from new and existing global investors, including those in the Asia Pacific region.</p>
<p>The new close came nearly four years after KKR raised its <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20170601006750/en/KKR-Closes-US9.3-Billion-Asian-Fund-III">Asian Fund III of $9.3 billion</a> and marks the New York-based alternative asset management titan&#8217;s ongoing interest in Asia. It also makes KKR Asian Fund IV one of the largest private equity funds dedicated to the Asia Pacific region.</p>
<p>KKR itself will inject about $1.3 billion into Fund IV alongside investors through the firm and its employees&#8217; commitments. The new fund will be on the lookout for opportunities in consumption and urbanization trends, as well as corporate carve-outs, spin-offs, and consolidation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>KKR has been a prolific investor in Asia-Pacific since it entered the region 16 years ago with a multifaceted approach that spans private equity, infrastructure, real estate and credit. It currently has $30 billion in assets under management in the region.</p>
<p>The firm has been active during COVID-19 as well. On the one hand, the pandemic has accelerated the transition to online activities and singled out tech firms that proved resilient during the health crisis. Market disruption in the last year has also made valuations more attractive and pressured companies to seek new sources of capital. All in all, these forces provide &#8220;increasingly interesting opportunities for flexible capital providers like KKR,&#8221; the firm&#8217;s spokesperson Anita Davis told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Since the pandemic, KKR has deployed about $7 billion across multiple strategies in Asia.</p>
<p>While KKR looks for deals across Asia, each market provides different opportunities pertaining to the state of its economy. For deals in consumption upgrades, KKR seeks out companies in emerging markets like China, Southeast Asia and India, said Davis. In developed countries like Japan, Korea and Australia, KKR observed that continued governance reform, along with a focus on return on equity (ROE), has driven carve-outs from conglomerates and spin-offs from multinational corporations, Davis added.</p>
<p>Specifically, KKR&#8217;s private equity portfolio in Asia consists of about 60 companies across 11 countries. Some of its more notable deals include co-leading <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/26/chinas-bytedance-leapfrogs-uber-to-becomes-worlds-most-valuable-startup/">ByteDance&#8217;s $3 billion raise in 2018</a> amid the TikTok parent&#8217;s rapid growth and bankrolling Reliance Jio <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/21/kkr-invests-1-5-billion-in-indias-reliance-jio-platforms/">with $1.5 billion</a> in 2020.</p>
<p>&#8220;The opportunity for private equity investment across Asia-Pacific is phenomenal,&#8221; said Hiro Hirano, co-head of Asia Pacific Private Equity at KKR. &#8220;While each market is unique, the long-term fundamentals underpinning the region’s growth are consistent &#8212; the demand for consumption upgrades, a fast-growing middle class, rising urbanization, and technological disruption.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Asian Fund IV followed in the footsteps of KKR&#8217;s two other Asia-focused funds that closed in January, the <a href="https://media.kkr.com/news-details/?news_id=223def4b-2e42-4bea-ba85-c2cda7cbd79a">$3.9 billion Asia Pacific Infrastructure Investors Fund</a> and the<a href="https://media.kkr.com/news-details/?news_id=093ad462-7de2-4c5e-88e0-5d1f73f8aabc"> $1.7 billion Asia Real Estate Partners Fund</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tiMjHd9QSs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/06/sequoia-announces-1-35-billion-venture-and-growth-funds-for-india-and-southeast-asia/">Sequoia announces $1.35 billion venture and growth funds for India and Southeast Asia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sequoia announces $1.35 billion venture and growth funds for India and Southeast Asia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/06/sequoia-announces-1-35-billion-venture-and-growth-funds-for-india-and-southeast-asia/embed/#?secret=tiMjHd9QSs" data-secret="tiMjHd9QSs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/kkr-closes-15-billion-fund-targeting-consumption-and-urbanization-in-asia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134362</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hipmunk&#8217;s founders launch Flight Penguin to bring back Hipmunk-style flight search</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/flight-penguin/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/flight-penguin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adam goldstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flight search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hipmunk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hipmunk&#8217;s founders are building a successor to their now-defunct flight search service. The startup was acquired by SAP-owned travel and expense platform Concur in 2016, and its CEO Adam Goldstein departed in 2018. But Goldstein told me he and his co-founder Steve Huffman (also co-founder and CEO of Reddit) were still disappointed when Concur shut [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hipmunk&#8217;s founders are building a successor to their now-defunct flight search service.</p>
<p>The startup was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/13/concur-buys-hipmunk-to-add-search-to-its-travel-and-expense-management-platform/">acquired by SAP-owned travel and expense platform Concur</a> in 2016, and its CEO Adam Goldstein departed in 2018. But Goldstein told me he and his co-founder Steve Huffman (also co-founder and CEO of Reddit) were still disappointed when Concur <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/four-years-after-being-acquired-hipmunk-is-shutting-down/">shut the service down</a> at the beginning of last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;Over the years, there were millions and millions of people who used it and loved it,&#8221; Goldstein said. (I was one of those people — even before I knew what he was working on, I started out our call by telling Goldstein how much I miss Hipmunk.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>So the pair seed funded a project called <a href="https://flightpenguin.com">Flight Penguin</a>, with Goldstein serving as the new company&#8217;s chairman. And he said the actual product was built by former Hipmunk developer Sheri Zada.</p>
<p>The Flight Penguin interface will be very familiar to old Hipmunk users, with a visual layout that makes it easy to see the timing of flights and length of layovers. And just as Hipmunk allowed users to organize results by &#8220;agony&#8221; (so that the top results aren&#8217;t just cheap flights with inconvenient timing or ridiculous layovers), Flight Penguin allows them to sort their flights by &#8220;pain.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2134294" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2134294" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2134294" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/33t687fbfzy4vdol.jpg?w=680" alt="Flight Penguin screenshot" width="680" height="295" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/33t687fbfzy4vdol.jpg 1166w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/33t687fbfzy4vdol.jpg?resize=150,65 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/33t687fbfzy4vdol.jpg?resize=300,130 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/33t687fbfzy4vdol.jpg?resize=768,333 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/33t687fbfzy4vdol.jpg?resize=680,295 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/33t687fbfzy4vdol.jpg?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2134294" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Flight Penguin</p></div></p>
<p>But this isn&#8217;t just the old experience with a fresh coat of paint — it&#8217;s also meant to improve on Hipmunk in a few key ways. For one thing, it allows users to search by Chase Ultimate Rewards Points (as well as U.S. dollars, with the goal of adding more currencies and rewards programs in the future).</p>
<p>And the product itself is a Google Chrome extension, rather than a traditional flight search website. The extension actually presents a full, standalone web experience (rather than an overlay on another website), but Goldstein said this approach is still important, because it allows Flight Penguin to pull its data &#8220;through the frontend instead of the backend,&#8221; giving it the most up-to-date information. This helps to avoid situations where a flight or price shows up in search results but isn&#8217;t available on the airline&#8217;s or other seller&#8217;s website.</p>
<p>In addition, Goldstein said Flight Penguin will show &#8220;all the flights.&#8221; In other words, it won&#8217;t be making any deals with the airlines to hide certain flights or prices, and it will also show airlines that don&#8217;t normally make their flights available on other search platforms.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are actually many, many flights available but consumers don&#8217;t see them because travel search sites work out these deals,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We&#8217;re choosing not to play that game.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="udp1okaSPj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/aero-series-a/">Luxury air travel startup Aero raises $20M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Luxury air travel startup Aero raises $20M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/aero-series-a/embed/#?secret=udp1okaSPj" data-secret="udp1okaSPj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That has the obvious benefit of offering more comprehensive results, but also the disadvantage that Flight Penguin will not be able to collect affiliate fees for flight purchases. Instead, after a 30-day trial period, it will charge users $10 per month. (This is an introductory fee and will likely change in the future.)</p>
<p>Goldstein acknowledged that this is probably &#8220;not going to be a mainstream product that 50 million Americans use,&#8221; but he&#8217;s hoping that it can attract a significant subscriber base of frequent travelers who &#8220;value their time and care about the flight booking experience.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What we learned from Hipmunk was [&#8230;] the way business has traditionally been done in online travel worked for consumers in an era with lots of competition between airlines and travel agencies,&#8221; he added. &#8220;In a world where there&#8217;s much less competition, you&#8217;re basically becoming an agent for the people you&#8217;re working with, and it&#8217;s hard to build a business model around providing a great user experience. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re saying that we&#8217;re going to opt out of this game and play by our own rules.&#8221;</p>
<p>Flight Penguin is currently accepting signups for its waitlist, but Goldstein said the company is simply using this to bring users on-board in a controlled fashion, and that it plans to move people off the wait list pretty quickly.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MCS1Qo4QW1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/four-years-after-being-acquired-hipmunk-is-shutting-down/">Four years after being acquired, Hipmunk is shutting down</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Four years after being acquired, Hipmunk is shutting down&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/four-years-after-being-acquired-hipmunk-is-shutting-down/embed/#?secret=MCS1Qo4QW1" data-secret="MCS1Qo4QW1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/flight-penguin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134282</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clubhouse launches payments so creators can make money</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clubhouse-payments/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clubhouse-payments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 23:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paul davison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Clubhouse, a one-year-old social audio app reportedly valued at $1 billion, will now allow users to send money to their favorite creators &#8212; or speakers &#8212; on the platform. In a blog post, the startup announced the new monetization feature, Clubhouse Payments, as the “the first of many features that allow creators to get paid [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Clubhouse, a one-year-old social audio app <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/clubhouse-gets-investment-interest-at-1-billion-valuation?utm_source=ti_app">reportedly valued at $1 billion</a>, will now allow users to send money to their favorite creators &#8212; or speakers &#8212; on the platform. <a href="https://www.joinclubhouse.com/introducing-payments">In a blog post, </a>the startup announced the new monetization feature, Clubhouse Payments, as the “the first of many features that allow creators to get paid directly on Clubhouse.”</p>
<p>Clubhouse declined to comment. Paul Davison, the co-founder of Clubhouse, mentioned in the company’s latest town hall that the startup wants to focus on direct monetization on creators, instead of advertisements.</p>
<p>Here’s how it will work: A user can send a payment in Clubhouse by going to the profile of the creator to whom they want to give money. If the creator has the feature enabled, the user will be able to tap “Send Money” and enter an amount. It’s like a virtual tip jar, or a Clubhouse-branded version of Venmo (although the payments feature doesn&#8217;t currently let the user send a personalized message along with the money).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="und" dir="ltr">.<a href="https://twitter.com/joinClubhouse?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@joinClubhouse</a> <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f91d.png" alt="🤝" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/stripe?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@stripe</a> <a href="https://t.co/u7kXXdPXU7">pic.twitter.com/u7kXXdPXU7</a></p>
<p>&mdash; edwin (@edwinwee) <a href="https://twitter.com/edwinwee/status/1379201737353879555?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 5, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>“100% of the payment will go to the creator. The person sending the money will also be charged a small card processing fee, which will go directly to our payment processing partner, Stripe,” the post reads. “Clubhouse will take nothing.”</p>
<p>Stripe CEO Patrick Collison tweeted shortly after the blog post went up that “It&#8217;s cool to see a new social platform focus first on <em>participant</em> income rather than internalized monetization / advertising.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">It&#39;s cool to see a new social platform focus first on *participant* income rather than internalized monetization / advertising. Excited for the burgeoning creator economy and next era of internet business models.</p>
<p>&mdash; Patrick Collison (@patrickc) <a href="https://twitter.com/patrickc/status/1379191749550071811?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 5, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>When the startup raised a Series B led by Andreessen Horowitz in January, part of the reported $100 million funding was said to go to a creator grant program. The program would be used to “support emerging Clubhouse creators,” <a href="https://www.joinclubhouse.com/welcoming-more-voices">according to a blog post.</a> It’s unclear how they define emerging, but cultivating influencers (and rewarding them with money) is one way the startup is promoting high-quality content on its platform.</p>
<p>The synergies here are obvious. A Clubhouse creator can now get tips for a great show, or raise money for a great cause, while also being rewarded by the platform itself for being a recurring host.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uIYVsVbFpV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/clubhouse-ux-teardown-a-closer-look-at-homepage-curation-follow-hooks-and-other-features/">Clubhouse UX teardown: A closer look at homepage curation, follow hooks and other features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clubhouse UX teardown: A closer look at homepage curation, follow hooks and other features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/clubhouse-ux-teardown-a-closer-look-at-homepage-curation-follow-hooks-and-other-features/embed/#?secret=uIYVsVbFpV" data-secret="uIYVsVbFpV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The fact that Clubhouse’s first attempt at monetization includes no percentage cut of its own is certainly noteworthy. Monetization, or Clubhouse’s lack thereof, has been a topic of discussion about the buzzy startup since it took off in the early pandemic months. While it currently relies on venture capital to keep the wheels churning, it will need to make money eventually in order to be a self-sustaining business.</p>
<p>Creator monetization, with a cut for the platform, has led to the growth of large businesses. Cameo, a startup that sends personalized messages from creators and celebrities, takes about a 25% cut of each video sold on its platform. The startup reached unicorn status last week with a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/celebrity-video-request-site-cameo-reaches-unicorn-status-with-100m-raise/">$100 million raise. </a>OnlyFans, another platform that helps creators directly raise money from fans in exchange for paywalled contact, is <a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/2021/04/02/essex-born-onlyfans-founder-built-porn-empire-has-become-one/">projecting $1 billion in revenue for 2021. </a></p>
<p>Clubhouse’s payments feature will first be tested by a “small test group” starting today, but it is unclear who is in this group. Eventually, the payments feature will be rolled out to other users in waves.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rsUGOTP1yc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/celebrity-video-request-site-cameo-reaches-unicorn-status-with-100m-raise/">Celebrity video request site Cameo reaches unicorn status with $100M raise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Celebrity video request site Cameo reaches unicorn status with $100M raise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/celebrity-video-request-site-cameo-reaches-unicorn-status-with-100m-raise/embed/#?secret=rsUGOTP1yc" data-secret="rsUGOTP1yc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clubhouse-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134306</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: The Supreme Court sides with Google in Oracle suit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/daily-crunch-the-supreme-court-sides-with-google-in-oracle-suit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/daily-crunch-the-supreme-court-sides-with-google-in-oracle-suit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 22:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Supreme Court announces several tech-related rulings, LG will shut down its smartphone business and we take a deep dive into the story of StockX. This is your Daily Crunch for April 5, 2021. The big story: The Supreme Court sides with Google in Oracle suit The U.S. Supreme Court announced a couple of tech-related [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Supreme Court announces several tech-related rulings, LG will shut down its smartphone business and we take a deep dive into the story of StockX. This is your Daily Crunch for April 5, 2021.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: The Supreme Court sides with Google in Oracle suit</strong></p>
<p>The U.S. Supreme Court announced a couple of tech-related rulings today. In one, it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/supreme-court-google-oracle-ruling/">overturned Oracle&#8217;s victory in its copyright battle with Google</a>, which would have otherwise required Google to pay Oracle $8 billion for incorporating pieces of Oracle&#8217;s Java software language into the Android mobile operating system.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;In reviewing that decision, we assume, for argument’s sake, that the material was copyrightable,&#8221; wrote Justice Stephen Breyer. &#8220;But we hold that the copying here at issue nonetheless constituted a fair use. Hence, Google’s copying did not violate the copyright law.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition, the court <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/supreme-court-trump-clarence-thomas/">vacated a ruling</a> declaring that then-President Donald Trump had violated the First Amendment by clocking critics on Twitter. In his opinion on the case, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clarence-thomas-plays-a-poor-devils-advocate-in-floating-first-amendment-limits-for-tech-companies/">Justice Clarence Thomas argued </a> that companies like Facebook and Google are &#8220;at bottom communications networks, and they ‘carry’ information from one user to another&#8221; and can therefore be regulated in the same way as telecom carriers.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/04/lg-is-shutting-down-its-smartphone-business-worldwide/">LG is shutting down its smartphone business worldwide</a> — LG said it will focus its resources in “growth areas” such as electric vehicle components.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/labor-relations-board-sides-with-amazon-employees-over-firings/">Labor relations board sides with Amazon employees over firing</a> — Before being fired last year, Emily Cunningham and Maren Costa had been among the company’s most outspoken critics on staff.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/spotify-opens-a-second-personalized-playlist-to-sponsors-after-discover-weekly-in-2019/">Spotify opens a second personalized playlist to sponsors, after Discover Weekly in 2019</a> — On Repeat is now open to advertising sponsorships.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/indias-swiggy-nears-5-billion-valuation-in-new-800-million-fundraise/">India’s Swiggy nears $5B valuation in new $800M fundraise</a> — Swiggy is preparing to expand its business after cutting its workforce to navigate the pandemic.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/knotel-co-founder-leaves-company-describes-investor-newmark-as-a-stalking-horse/">Knotel co-founder leaves company, describes investor Newmark as ‘a stalking horse’</a> — The startup filed for bankruptcy earlier this year, its assets acquired by investor and commercial real estate brokerage Newmark.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/byjus-acquires-indian-tutor-aakash-for-nearly-1-billion/">Byju’s acquires Indian tutor Aakash for nearly $1B</a> — Akash is a 33-year-old chain of physical coaching centers.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/stockx-ec1/">The StockX EC-1</a> — Now valued at $2.8 billion, StockX has facilitated over 10 million transactions.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/plant-based-meat-startups-china/">Chinese startups rush to bring alternative protein to people’s plates</a> — 2020 could well have been the dawn of alternative protein in China.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/what-happens-to-your-nfts-and-crypto-assets-after-you-die/">What happens to your NFTs and crypto assets after you die?</a> — A new study finds that only one in four consumers have someone in their life who knows all of their passwords and account details.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/fueled-by-pandemic-contactless-mobile-payments-to-surpass-half-of-all-smartphone-users-in-u-s-by-2025/">Fueled by pandemic, contactless mobile payments to surpass half of all smartphone users in US by 2025</a> — According to a recent report by analyst firm eMarketer, in-store mobile payments usage grew 29% last year in the U.S.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/start-your-engines-techcrunch-is-virtually-headed-to-detroit/">Start your engines, TechCrunch is (virtually) headed to Detroit</a> — Mark April 15 on your calendars!</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/daily-crunch-the-supreme-court-sides-with-google-in-oracle-suit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134303</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LG&#8217;s exit from the smartphone market comes as no surprise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/lgs-exit-from-the-smartphone-market-comes-as-no-surprise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/lgs-exit-from-the-smartphone-market-comes-as-no-surprise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 21:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5g]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was time for LG to move on. Frankly, the only surprise was that it didn’t do so sooner.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For those who follow the space, LG will be remembered fondly as a smartphone trailblazer. For a decade-and-a-half, the company was a major player in the Android category and a driving force behind a number of innovations that have since become standard.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most notable story is that of the LG Prada. Announced a month before the first iPhone, the device helped pioneer the touchscreen form factor that has come to define virtually every smartphone since. At the time, the <a href="https://macdailynews.com/2007/02/13/lg_accuses_apple_iphone_of_being_a_copycat_of_prada_phone/">company openly accused</a> Apple of ripping off its design, noting, “We consider that Apple copycat Prada phone after the design was unveiled when it was presented in the iF Design Award and won the prize in September 2006.”</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			This July, the company will stop selling phones beyond what remains of its existing inventory.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>LG has continued pushing envelopes — albeit to mixed effect. In the end, however, the company just couldn’t keep up. This week, the South Korean electronics giant announced it will be getting out of the “incredibly competitive” category, choosing instead to focus on its myriad other departments.</p>
<p>The news comes as little surprise following months of rumors that the company was actively looking for a buyer for the smartphone unit. In the end, it seems, none were forthcoming. This July, the company will stop selling phones beyond what remains of its existing inventory.</p>
<p>The smartphone category is, indeed, a competitive one. And frankly, LG’s numbers have pretty consistently fallen into the “Others” category of global smartphone market share figures ruled by names like Samsung, Apple, Huawei and Xiaomi. The other names clustered beneath the top five have been, more often than not, other Chinese manufacturers like Vivo.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/lgs-exit-from-the-smartphone-market-comes-as-no-surprise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134250</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tim Cook drops hints about autonomous tech and the Apple car</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/tim-cook-drops-hints-about-autonomous-tech-and-the-apple-car/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/tim-cook-drops-hints-about-autonomous-tech-and-the-apple-car/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 20:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Titan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Cook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple CEO Tim Cook dropped a few hints in an interview released Monday about the direction of the much-anticipated Apple car, including that autonomous vehicle technology will likely be a key feature. &#8220;The autonomy itself is a core technology, in my view,&#8221; Cook told Kara Swisher in an interview on the &#8220;Sway&#8221; podcast. &#8220;If you [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple CEO Tim Cook dropped a few hints in an interview released Monday about the direction of the much-anticipated Apple car, including that autonomous vehicle technology will likely be a key feature.</p>
<p>&#8220;The autonomy itself is a core technology, in my view,&#8221; <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/05/opinion/apples-ceo-is-making-very-different-choices-from-mark-zuckerberg.html?">Cook told Kara Swisher in an interview on the &#8220;Sway&#8221; podcast</a>. &#8220;If you sort of step back, the car, in a lot of ways, is a robot. An autonomous car is a robot. And so there&#8217;s lots of things you can do with autonomy. And we&#8217;ll see what Apple does.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cook was careful not to reveal too much, declining to answer Swisher&#8217;s question outright if Apple is planning to produce a car itself or the tech within the car. What clues he did drop, suggests Project Titan is working on something in the middle.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We love to integrate hardware, software and services, and find the intersection points of those because we think that&#8217;s where the magic occurs,&#8221; said Cook. &#8220;And we love to own the primary technology that&#8217;s around that.&#8221;</p>
<p>To which Swisher responded: &#8220;I&#8217;m going to go with car for that, if you don&#8217;t mind. I&#8217;m just going to jump to car.&#8221;</p>
<p>We are, too.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="16P6i4WMzy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/the-apple-car-chatter-is-back-with-new-reports-pointing-to-a-2024-launch-date/">The &#8216;Apple car&#8217; chatter is back with new reports pointing to a 2024 launch date</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The &#8216;Apple car&#8217; chatter is back with new reports pointing to a 2024 launch date&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/the-apple-car-chatter-is-back-with-new-reports-pointing-to-a-2024-launch-date/embed/#?secret=16P6i4WMzy" data-secret="16P6i4WMzy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Many people in the micromobility industry like to say that e-scooters are basically iPhones on wheels, but it&#8217;s more likely that the Apple car will <em>actually</em> be the iPhone on wheels. Apple is generally known for owning all of its hardware and software, so it wouldn&#8217;t be surprising to see Apple engineers working closely with a manufacturer to produce an Apple car, with the potential to one day cut out the middle man and become the manufacturer.</p>
<p>The so-called Project Titan appeared at risk of failing before a car was ever seen by the public with mass layoffs in 2019. However, more recent reports suggest that the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/the-apple-car-chatter-is-back-with-new-reports-pointing-to-a-2024-launch-date/">project is alive</a> and well with plans to make a self-driving electric passenger vehicle by 2024.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/03/apple-and-hyundai-kia-driving-towards-deal-on-apple-car.html">Earlier this year, CNBC reported that Apple was close to finalizing a deal with Hyundai-Kia</a> to build an Apple-branded self-driving car at the Kia assembly plant in West Point, Georgia. Sources familiar with Apple&#8217;s interest in Hyundai say the company wants to work with an automaker that will let Apple hold the reins on the software and hardware that will go into the car.</p>
<p>The two companies never reached a deal and talks fell apart in February, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-08/hyundai-kia-say-they-aren-t-in-ev-discussions-with-apple">according to multiple reports</a>. That hasn&#8217;t stopped the flow of rumors and reports about Apple and its plans, which have previously been linked to other suppliers, automakers such as Nissan and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225026/apple-canoo-acquisition-investment-electric-car-goev">even startups</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s still unclear what the Apple car will look like, but as a passenger vehicle, rather than a robotaxi or delivery vehicle, it will be going up against the likes of Tesla.</p>
<p>&#8220;I’ve never spoken to Elon, although I have great admiration and respect for the company he’s built,&#8221; said Cook. &#8220;I think Tesla has done an unbelievable job of not only establishing the lead, but keeping the lead for such a long period of time in the EV space. So I have great appreciation for them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Project Titan is being led by Doug Field, who was formerly senior vice president of engineering at Tesla and one of the key players behind the Model 3 launch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FlD2HN9sMa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/automakers-suppliers-and-startups-see-growing-market-for-in-vehicle-ar-vr-applications/">Automakers, suppliers and startups see growing market for in-vehicle AR/VR applications</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Automakers, suppliers and startups see growing market for in-vehicle AR/VR applications&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/automakers-suppliers-and-startups-see-growing-market-for-in-vehicle-ar-vr-applications/embed/#?secret=FlD2HN9sMa" data-secret="FlD2HN9sMa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/tim-cook-drops-hints-about-autonomous-tech-and-the-apple-car/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134201</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clarence Thomas plays a poor devil&#8217;s advocate in floating First Amendment limits for tech companies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clarence-thomas-plays-a-poor-devils-advocate-in-floating-first-amendment-limits-for-tech-companies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clarence-thomas-plays-a-poor-devils-advocate-in-floating-first-amendment-limits-for-tech-companies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 19:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clarence thomas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[donald trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Amendment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Section 230]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supreme court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Supreme Court Justice Clarence Thomas flaunted a dangerous ignorance regarding matters digital in an opinion published today. In attempting to explain the legal difficulties of social media platforms, particularly those arising from Twitter&#8217;s ban of Trump, he makes an ill-informed, bordering on bizarre, argument as to why such companies may need their First Amendment rights [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Supreme Court Justice Clarence Thomas flaunted a dangerous ignorance regarding matters digital in an opinion published today. In attempting to explain the legal difficulties of social media platforms, particularly those arising from Twitter&#8217;s ban of Trump, he makes an ill-informed, bordering on bizarre, argument as to why such companies may need their First Amendment rights curtailed.</p>
<p>There are several points on which Thomas seems to willfully misconstrue or misunderstand the issues.</p>
<p>The first is in his characterization of Trump&#8217;s use of Twitter. You may remember that several people sued after being blocked by Trump, alleging that his use of the platform amounted to creating a &#8220;public forum&#8221; in a legal sense, meaning it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/23/its-unconstitutional-for-trump-to-block-people-on-twitter/">unlawful to exclude anyone from it for political reasons</a>. (The case, as it happens, was rendered moot after its appeal and dismissed by the court except as Thomas&#8217; temporary soapbox.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CqUw91dVcf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/supreme-court-trump-clarence-thomas/">Supreme Court tosses ruling that said Trump blocking Twitter critics was unconstitutional</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Supreme Court tosses ruling that said Trump blocking Twitter critics was unconstitutional&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/supreme-court-trump-clarence-thomas/embed/#?secret=CqUw91dVcf" data-secret="CqUw91dVcf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;But Mr. Trump, it turned out, had only limited control of the account; Twitter has permanently removed the account from the platform,&#8221; writes Thomas. &#8220;[I]t seems rather odd to say something is a government forum when a private company has unrestricted authority to do away with it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Does it? Does it seem odd? Because a few paragraphs later, he uses the example of a government agency using a conference room in a hotel to hold a public hearing. They can&#8217;t kick people out for voicing their political opinions, certainly, because the room is a <em>de facto</em> public forum. But if someone is loud and disruptive, they can ask hotel security to remove that person, because the room is <em>de jure</em> a privately owned space.</p>
<p>Yet the obvious third example, and the one clearly most relevant to the situation at hand, is skipped. What if it is the government representatives who are being loud and disruptive, to the point where the hotel must make the choice whether to remove them?</p>
<p>It says something that this scenario, so remarkably close a metaphor for what actually happened, is not considered. Perhaps it casts the ostensibly &#8220;odd&#8221; situation and actors in too clear a light, for Thomas&#8217; other arguments suggest he is not for clarity here but for muddying the waters ahead of a partisan knife fight over free speech.</p>
<p>In his best &#8220;I&#8217;m not saying, I&#8217;m just <em>saying</em>&#8221; tone, Thomas presents his reasoning why, if the problem is that these platforms have too much power over free speech, then historically there just happens to be some legal options to limit that power.</p>
<p>Thomas argues first, and worst, that platforms like Facebook and Google may amount to &#8220;common carriers,&#8221; a term that goes back centuries to actual carriers of cargo, but which is now a common legal concept that refers to services that act as simple distribution — &#8220;bound to serve all customers alike, without discrimination.&#8221; A telephone company is the most common example, in that it cannot and does not choose what connections it makes, nor what conversations happen over those connections — it moves electric signals from one phone to another.</p>
<p>But as he notes at the outset of his commentary, &#8220;applying old doctrines to new digital platforms is rarely straightforward.&#8221; And Thomas&#8217; method of doing so is spurious.</p>
<p>&#8220;Though digital instead of physical, they are at bottom communications networks, and they &#8216;carry&#8217; information from one user to another,&#8221; he says, and equates telephone companies laying cable with companies like Google laying &#8220;information infrastructure that can be controlled in much the same way.&#8221;</p>
<p>Now, this is certainly wrong. So wrong in so many ways that it&#8217;s hard to know where to start and when to stop.</p>
<p>The idea that companies like Facebook and Google are equivalent to telephone lines is such a reach that it seems almost like a joke. These are companies that have built entire business empires by adding enormous amounts of storage, processing, analysis and other services on top of the element of pure communication. One might as easily suggest that because computers are just a simple piece of hardware that moves data around, that Apple is a common carrier as well. It&#8217;s really not so far a logical leap!</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RBgY7UsnGo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/fcc-commissioner-disparages-trumps-social-media-order-the-decision-is-ours-alone/">FCC Commissioner disparages Trump&#8217;s social media order: &#8216;The decision is ours alone&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FCC Commissioner disparages Trump&#8217;s social media order: &#8216;The decision is ours alone&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/fcc-commissioner-disparages-trumps-social-media-order-the-decision-is-ours-alone/embed/#?secret=RBgY7UsnGo" data-secret="RBgY7UsnGo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>There&#8217;s no real need to get into the technical and legal reasons why this opinion is wrong, however, because <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/30/commission-impossible-how-and-why-the-fcc-created-net-neutrality/">these grounds have been covered so extensively over the years</a>, particularly by the FCC — which the Supreme Court has deferred to as an expert agency on this matter. If Facebook were a common carrier (or telecommunications service), it would fall under the FCC&#8217;s jurisdiction — but it doesn&#8217;t, because it isn&#8217;t, and really, no one thinks it is. This has been supported over and over, by multiple FCCs and administrations, and the deferral is itself a Supreme Court precedent that has become doctrine.</p>
<p>In fact, and this is really the cherry on top, Associate Justice Kavanaugh in a truly stupefying legal opinion a few years ago argued so far in the other direction that it became wrong in a totally different way! It was Kavanaugh&#8217;s considered opinion that the bar for qualifying as a common carrier was actually so high that even broadband providers don&#8217;t qualify for it. (This was all in service of taking down net neutrality, a saga we are in danger of resuming soon). As his erudite colleague Judge Srinivasan <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/11/supreme-court-nominee-brett-kavanaughs-brutal-education-in-net-neutrality/">explained to him at the time</a>, this approach too is embarrassingly wrong.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9ZNWuu2sUo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/11/supreme-court-nominee-brett-kavanaughs-brutal-education-in-net-neutrality/">Supreme Court nominee Brett Kavanaugh&#8217;s brutal education in net neutrality</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Supreme Court nominee Brett Kavanaugh&#8217;s brutal education in net neutrality&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/11/supreme-court-nominee-brett-kavanaughs-brutal-education-in-net-neutrality/embed/#?secret=9ZNWuu2sUo" data-secret="9ZNWuu2sUo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Looking at these two opinions, of two sitting conservative Supreme Court justices, you may find the arguments strangely at odds, yet they are wrong after a common fashion.</p>
<p>Kavanaugh claims that broadband providers, the plainest form of digital common carrier conceivable, are in fact providing all kinds sophisticated services over and above their functionality as a pipe (they aren&#8217;t). Thomas claims that companies actually providing all kinds of sophisticated services are nothing more than pipes.</p>
<p>Simply stated, these men have no regard for the facts but have chosen the definition that best suits their political purposes: For Kavanaugh, thwarting a Democrat-led push for strong net neutrality rules; for Thomas, asserting control over social media companies perceived as having an anti-conservative bias.</p>
<p>The case Thomas uses for his sounding board on these topics was rightly rendered moot — Trump is no longer president and the account no longer exists — but he makes it clear that he regrets this extremely.</p>
<p>&#8220;As Twitter made clear, the right to cut off speech lies most powerfully in the hands of private digital platforms,&#8221; he concludes. &#8220;The extent to which that power matters for purposes of the First Amendment and the extent to which that power could lawfully be modified raise interesting and important questions. This petition, unfortunately, affords us no opportunity to confront them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Between the common carrier argument and questioning the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/supreme-court-trump-clarence-thomas/">form of Section 230</a>, Thomas&#8217;s hypotheticals break the seals on several legal avenues to restrict First Amendment rights of digital platforms, as well as legitimizing those (largely on one side of the political spectrum) who claim a grievance along these lines. (Slate legal commentator Mark Joseph Stern, who spotted the opinion early, goes further, calling Thomas&#8217;s argument <a href="https://slate.com/technology/2021/04/clarence-thomas-social-media-first-amendment-censorship.html">a &#8220;paranoid Marxist delusion&#8221;</a> and providing some other interesting context.)</p>
<p>This is not to say that social media and tech do not deserve scrutiny on any number of fronts — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/who-regulates-social-media/">they exist in an alarming global vacuum of regulatory powers</a>, and hardly anyone would suggest they have been entirely responsible with this freedom. But the arguments of Thomas and Kavanaugh stink of cynical partisan sophistry. This endorsement by Thomas accomplishes nothing legally, but will provide valuable fuel for the bitter fires of contention — though they hardly needed it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wKNW1fNm3J"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/who-regulates-social-media/">Who regulates social media?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Who regulates social media?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/who-regulates-social-media/embed/#?secret=wKNW1fNm3J" data-secret="wKNW1fNm3J" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clarence-thomas-plays-a-poor-devils-advocate-in-floating-first-amendment-limits-for-tech-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134171</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Labor relations board sides with Amazon employees over firings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/labor-relations-board-sides-with-amazon-employees-over-firings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/labor-relations-board-sides-with-amazon-employees-over-firings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 19:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[union]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year, Amazon fired Emily Cunningham and Maren Costa. The pair of employees had been among the company’s most outspoken critics on staff, openly taking Amazon to task for environmental and labor issues. This week, the National Labor Relations Board determined that the pair’s firing was an illegal form of retaliation. Speaking with The New [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last year, Amazon fired Emily Cunningham and Maren Costa. The pair of employees had been among the company’s most outspoken critics on staff, openly taking Amazon to task for environmental and labor issues.</p>
<p>This week, the National Labor Relations Board determined that the pair’s firing was an illegal form of retaliation. Speaking with The New York Times, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/05/technology/amazon-nlrb-activist-workers.html">Cunningham noted</a> that the board would issue a more public criticism of Amazon’s action if the company does not take steps to address the issue.</p>
<p>Amazon tells TechCrunch that the decision was not a direct result of the pair’s criticism, but rather a product of other, unstated polices. “We support every employee’s right to criticize their employer’s working conditions, but that does not come with blanket immunity against any and all internal policies,&#8221; a spokesperson says. &#8220;We terminated these employees for repeatedly violating internal policies.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hnL7SI8Jfh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/14/amazon-fires-two-more-employees-who-were-openly-critical-of-working-conditions-during-pandemic/">Amazon fires two more employees who were openly critical of working conditions during pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon fires two more employees who were openly critical of working conditions during pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/14/amazon-fires-two-more-employees-who-were-openly-critical-of-working-conditions-during-pandemic/embed/#?secret=hnL7SI8Jfh" data-secret="hnL7SI8Jfh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Cunningham, meanwhile, called the decision a “moral victory.”</p>
<p>The news came amid widescale ramp-ups as Amazon was declared an essential service while COVID-19 bore down on the U.S. in April. Two weeks prior, the company opened a massive fulfillment center in Bessemer, Alabama, which has become the focal point of yet another labor battle for the online retail giant.</p>
<p>The warehouse is currently ground zero for the largest unionizing effort in the company’s history. The National Labor Relations Board is tasked with ballot counting, which kicked off on Tuesday of last week. In the final days of voting, the company made an aggressive social media push against union allies, though it has since walked it back some, including a soft apology for comments surrounding reports that employees regularly pee in bottles to meet stringent quotas.</p>
<p>In addition to its rulings on Cunningham and Costa, the NLRB has also found for Amazonians United co-founder, Jonathan Bailey.</p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> The company provided TechCrunch an additional statement, “We disagree with these preliminary findings. We support every employee’s right to criticize their employer’s working conditions, but that does not come with blanket immunity against our internal policies, all of which are lawful. We terminated these employees not for the reasons cited in the preliminary finding, but because they repeatedly violated internal policies.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4RhBUtqB9A"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/03/amazon-addresses-pee-bottle-denial-tweet/">Amazon addresses pee bottle denial tweet</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon addresses pee bottle denial tweet&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/03/amazon-addresses-pee-bottle-denial-tweet/embed/#?secret=4RhBUtqB9A" data-secret="4RhBUtqB9A" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="huV4ozXrPf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/22/where-is-the-e-commerce-app-ecosystem-headed-in-2021/">Where is the e-commerce app ecosystem headed in 2021?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Where is the e-commerce app ecosystem headed in 2021?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/22/where-is-the-e-commerce-app-ecosystem-headed-in-2021/embed/#?secret=huV4ozXrPf" data-secret="huV4ozXrPf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/labor-relations-board-sides-with-amazon-employees-over-firings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134180</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US indicts California man accused of stealing Shopify customer data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/shopify-breach-hacker-indicted/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/shopify-breach-hacker-indicted/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 19:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Bureau of Investigation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kylie Jenner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2134165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A grand jury has indicted a California resident accused of stealing Shopify customer data on over a hundred merchants, TechCrunch has learned. The indictment charges Tassilo Heinrich with aggravated identity theft and conspiracy to commit wire fraud by allegedly working with two Shopify customer support agents to steal merchant and customer data from Shopify customers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A grand jury has indicted a California resident accused of stealing Shopify customer data on over a hundred merchants, TechCrunch has learned.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/20580321-us-grand-jury-indictment-tassilo-heinrich">indictment</a> charges Tassilo Heinrich with aggravated identity theft and conspiracy to commit wire fraud by allegedly working with two Shopify customer support agents to steal merchant and customer data from Shopify customers to gain a competitive edge and &#8220;take business away from those merchants,&#8221; the indictment reads. The indictment also accuses Heinrich, believed to be around 18 years old at the time of the alleged scheme, of selling the data to other co-conspirators to commit fraud.</p>
<p>A person with direct knowledge of the security breach confirmed Shopify was the unnamed victim company referenced <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/20580321-us-grand-jury-indictment-tassilo-heinrich">in the indictment</a>.</p>
<p>Last September, Shopify, an online e-commerce platform for small businesses, revealed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/shopify-data-merchant-breach/">a data breach</a> perpetrated by two &#8220;rogue members&#8221; of its third-party customer support team that targeted &#8220;less than 200 merchants.&#8221; Shopify said it fired the two contractors for engaging &#8220;in a scheme to obtain customer transactional records of certain merchants.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="16hRfVvYNl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/how-to-respond-to-a-data-breach/">How to respond to a data breach</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to respond to a data breach&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/how-to-respond-to-a-data-breach/embed/#?secret=16hRfVvYNl" data-secret="16hRfVvYNl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Shopify said the contractors <a href="https://community.shopify.com/c/Shopify-Discussion/Incident-Update/m-p/888971/highlight/true#M197487">stole customer data</a>, including names, postal addresses and order details, like which products and services were purchased. One merchant who received the data breach notice from Shopify <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/shopify-data-merchant-breach/">said</a> the last four digits of affected customers&#8217; payment cards were also taken, which the indictment confirms.</p>
<p>Another one of the victims was Kylie Jenner&#8217;s cosmetics and make-up company, Kylie Cosmetics, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-54354526">the BBC reported</a>.</p>
<p>The indictment accuses Heinrich of paying an employee of a third-party customer support company in the Philippines to access parts of Shopify&#8217;s internal network by either taking screenshots or uploading the data to Google Drive in exchange for kickbacks. Heinrich paid the employee in thousands of dollars&#8217; worth of cryptocurrency, and also fake positive reviews claiming to be from merchants to whom the employee had provided customer service but had not left feedback. The indictment alleges that Heinrich received a year&#8217;s worth of some merchants&#8217; data.</p>
<p>Heinrich allegedly spent at least a year siphoning off incrementing amounts of data from Shopify&#8217;s internal network, at one point asking if he could &#8220;remotely access&#8221; the customer support employee&#8217;s computer while they were asleep.</p>
<p>In a brief statement, Shopify spokesperson Rebecca Feigelsohn said: &#8220;Shopify has cooperated with the FBI to investigate an incident involving the data of a small number of our merchants in September 2020. As previously stated, the perpetrators involved no longer work with Shopify. Because there is an active criminal investigation, we are unable to provide further comment at this time.&#8221;</p>
<p>Heinrich was arrested by the FBI at Los Angeles International Airport in February and is currently detained in federal custody pending trial, set to begin on September 7. Heinrich has pleaded not guilty.</p>
<p><em>Updated with comment from Shopify.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7kxR2vgAdR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/shopify-data-merchant-breach/">Shopify says two support staff stole customer data from sellers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Shopify says two support staff stole customer data from sellers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/shopify-data-merchant-breach/embed/#?secret=7kxR2vgAdR" data-secret="7kxR2vgAdR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/shopify-breach-hacker-indicted/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2134165</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
