<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 12:23:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Creadev seasons Salted with new funding for its QSR brands</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/creadev-seasons-salted-with-new-funding-for-its-qsr-brands/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/creadev-seasons-salted-with-new-funding-for-its-qsr-brands/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 12:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adrien Lejal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B. Riley Financial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creadev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Applebaum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Proof Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Restaurants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salted]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225919</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Salted created six brands so far, including moonbowls, Califlower Pizza and lulubowls, and serves food from Chinese takeout to pizza to salads.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.hellosalted.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Salted</a>, a Los Angeles-based startup creating digitally native quick-service restaurant brands, brought in a new round of $16 million in Series A funding to continue its nationwide expansion.</p>
<p>The company was founded seven years ago by CEO Jeff Applebaum, but a focus on providing healthy QSR brands and going after the <a href="https://www.morganstanley.com/ideas/food-delivery-app-profits" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$325 billion food delivery space</a> came about three years ago. Applebaum told TechCrunch that he aims to be “the Yum! Brands for the digital age.”</p>
<p>Salted has created six brands so far, including moonbowls, Califlower Pizza and lulubowls, and serves food from Chinese takeout to pizza to salads.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225919" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“Our technology and Salted Analytics product helps us grow at the rate we want to and still maintain customer experience,” Applebaum said. “We don’t consider ourselves a ghost kitchen, but a builder of budding brands that are going to be around for a hundred years. The great value is going to be in the brand layer, similar to Domino’s and Panda Express, which are scaling brands that people love.”</p>
<p>Creadev led the Series A that also included Proof Ventures and B. Riley Financial. The new investment joins with a $4 million seed round raised in May. At that time, Applebaum was using the funds for growth, and that strategy will continue with this new funding toward his goal of “building the next Chipotle,” he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company has over 200 employees, including kitchen staff, and recently opened its 19th location. It is serving food in seven states, including California, Illinois and Ohio, and each location operates four to six brands. Applebaum expects to have over 50 locations by next year.</p>
<p>The locations are already collectively showing profitably and are generating between $1 million and $2.5 million in annual sales, he added.</p>
<p>Adrien Lejal, investment director at Creadev, said he was attracted to Salted because the company “doesn’t take shortcuts in the healthier food options and stands true to its mission, which speaks to the values of the team.”</p>
<p>He has been following the company for about 18 months and decided to jump in when the company started raising its A round. The QSR space isn’t one Creadev typically invests in, but Lejal said it does invest across the food chain and in companies that have “huge scalability potential,” and Salted was an interesting example, he added.</p>
<p>“The company as it is now was founded in 2018 and is already operating in seven states and combines scalability with execution, quality and speed,” Lejal said. “We also definitely invest in people first and Jeff’s leadership and management style is very impressive in the way he is reaching milestones in a short period of time.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="55ly9l9O1Z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1-competition/">The voracious fight for your salad bowl</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The voracious fight for your salad bowl&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1-competition/embed/#?secret=55ly9l9O1Z" data-secret="55ly9l9O1Z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/creadev-seasons-salted-with-new-funding-for-its-qsr-brands/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225919</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Social Chat launches with $6M to bring brands closer to their customers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/social-chat-launches-with-6m-to-bring-brands-closer-to-their-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/social-chat-launches-with-6m-to-bring-brands-closer-to-their-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edith Yeung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frost Li]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gradient Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personalization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Race Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social chat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Social Chat was founded on the premise that social commerce should be the standard for every store, and it may very well be soon.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When brands sell through social media and other third-parties, they often spend millions of dollars to advertise on those platforms, yet have little or no knowledge of who their customers actually are. Social commerce startup <a href="https://onsocialchat.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Social Chat</a> is out to change that.</p>
<p>Frost Li, the former head of growth at Wish, founded the company in May to create software that leverages machine learning and artificial intelligence for personalization, recommendations and live customer service — all to enable brands to convert lost social engagement into revenue and customer acquisition without having to rely on a big engineering team.</p>
<p>“While at Wish, we learned that to offer the right shopping experience, you had to do absolute personalization,” Li told TechCrunch. “That was done with machine learning engineers, but when I left Wish and was advising brands, I found that what we had at Wish was rare. People were doing things manually and could not do personalization as much as a result.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225898" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>She aims to mimic the customer experience you might receive in-store working with a favorite salesperson, but in the digital world, and allow consumers to purchase and transact during the social events, she added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9vOP1dYkGG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/automattic-tc1-acquisitions/">Can social and e-commerce transform the future of the open web?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can social and e-commerce transform the future of the open web?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/automattic-tc1-acquisitions/embed/#?secret=9vOP1dYkGG" data-secret="9vOP1dYkGG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Li believes that social commerce should be the standard for every store, and it may very well be soon. Earlier this year, Grand View Research reported that the <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/social-commerce-market-size-worth-3-369-8-billion-by-2028--cagr-28-4-grand-view-research-inc-301207167.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">global social commerce market</a> was forecasted to reach $3.4 trillion by 2028 from growing annually by over 28% between now and then.</p>
<p>“Online shopping is very transactional right now, but we help construct, over time, a long-term relationship through social interaction with customers,” she added.</p>
<p>As it launches its e-commerce customer engagement and revenue software, Social Chat also announced a $6 million seed round co-led by Race Capital and Gradient Ventures and that included Kevin Lin, co-founder of Twitch; Tony Zhao, founder of Agora.io; Ran Makavy, former chief product officer at Lyft; Alanna Gregory, global head of engagement at AfterPay; and Jack Xie, vice president of engineering at Wish.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2225908" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225908" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2225908 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Social-Chat-Team.png?w=680" alt="Social Chat" width="680" height="396" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Social-Chat-Team.png 1178w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Social-Chat-Team.png?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Social-Chat-Team.png?resize=300,175 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Social-Chat-Team.png?resize=768,447 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Social-Chat-Team.png?resize=680,396 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Social-Chat-Team.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2225908" class="wp-caption-text">Social Chat team, from left, Richard Lin, Pearl Tsang, Frost Li and Michael Chen. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Social Chat</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Edith Yeung, partner at Race Capital, says the future of shopping will be social — children are watching less television and more TikTok, so brands need to take control of their data so they don’t lose their audience to another platform.</p>
<p>“What Frost is doing is giving power back to the brands so that they can shift customers back to their own websites to convert them to sales, that is why Shopify is doing so well,” she added. “Facebook is trying to get people to trust them again, but companies are still at their mercy to keep paying millions, but they don’t know who their customers are.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Social Chat previously raised $2 million for a total of $8 million and will use the funding to hire more AI and ML engineers to expand its product offerings.</p>
<p>Though it is a fairly new company and too early to see concrete growth metrics, Social Chat is already working with customers like HTC and 10 other brands and seeing some early traction.</p>
<p>As Li watches the social commerce market grow into a multitrillion-dollar market and the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/the-demise-of-browser-cookies-could-create-a-golden-age-of-digital-marketing/">technical part of tracking going away</a>, it will provide the company an opportunity to scale and solve problems for its users.</p>
<p>“We are differentiating ourselves with the AI play so that you can see value, but don’t have to keep paying Facebook to keep your users,” she said. “When Google gets rid of the cookies, it is going to be crazy: you will have to really own the first-party data to communicate with users, or you will lose visibility.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="i4SN1HIsGL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/the-demise-of-browser-cookies-could-create-a-golden-age-of-digital-marketing/">The demise of browser cookies could create a Golden Age of digital marketing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The demise of browser cookies could create a Golden Age of digital marketing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/the-demise-of-browser-cookies-could-create-a-golden-age-of-digital-marketing/embed/#?secret=i4SN1HIsGL" data-secret="i4SN1HIsGL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/social-chat-launches-with-6m-to-bring-brands-closer-to-their-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225898</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google and Jio’s smartphone with custom Android OS for India launches November 4 for $87</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/google-and-jios-smartphone-with-custom-android-os-for-india-launches-november-4-for-87/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/google-and-jios-smartphone-with-custom-android-os-for-india-launches-november-4-for-87/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 11:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jio Platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JioPhone Next]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reliance jio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google and top Indian telecom network Jio Platforms said on Friday that their much-anticipated budget smartphone, JioPhone Next, will go on sale in the world&#8217;s second largest smartphone market on November 4 (coinciding with the big Indian festival of Diwali.) The firms said the JioPhone Next will cost 6,499 Indian rupees ($87), and can also [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google and top Indian telecom network Jio Platforms said on Friday that their <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/google-and-jio-platforms-announce-worlds-cheapest-smartphone-jiophone-next/">much-anticipated budget smartphone, JioPhone Next,</a> will go on sale in the world&#8217;s second largest smartphone market on November 4 (coinciding with the big Indian festival of Diwali.) The firms said the JioPhone Next will cost 6,499 Indian rupees ($87), and can also be purchased in multiple instalments with an entry price as low as $27.</p>
<p>The smartphone runs Pragati OS, which is powered by an &#8220;extremely optimized&#8221; Android mobile operating system with a range of customized features such as Read Aloud and Translate Now that will work with any text on the phone screen, including web pages, apps, messages and even photos as well as support for 10 Indian languages.</p>
<p>&#8220;Among the many rich features of JioPhone Next, the one that has impressed me the most — and one that will empower common Indians the most and take their digital journeys to the next level — is its contribution to India’s linguistic integration. India’s unique strength is our linguistic diversity. Those Indians who might not be able to read content in English or in their language can get it translated, and even read out, in their own language on this smart device,&#8221; said Mukesh Ambani, Chairman and Managing Director of Reliance Industries, which operates Jio Platforms.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226279" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The two firms also revealed the specifications of the JioPhone Next. The smartphone features a 5.45-inch HD+ display with Corning Gorilla Glass 3 protection. It is powered by Qualcomm&#8217;s quad-core QM-215 chipset that clocks up to 1.3GHz, coupled with 2GB of RAM and 32GB internal storage, which is expandable. The dual-SIM capable JioPhone Next, which houses a 3,500 mAh battery, features a 13-megapixel rear camera with support for HDR and an 8-megapixel selfie sensor.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226303" style="width: 4298px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226303" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2226303 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-631026204.jpg" alt="" width="4288" height="2848" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-631026204.jpg 4288w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-631026204.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-631026204.jpg?resize=300,199 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-631026204.jpg?resize=768,510 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-631026204.jpg?resize=680,452 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-631026204.jpg?resize=1536,1020 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-631026204.jpg?resize=2048,1360 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-631026204.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4288px) 100vw, 4288px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2226303" class="wp-caption-text">Google CEO Sundar Pichai interacts with students at IIT Kharagpur campus on January 5, 2017 in Kharagpur, India. His firm has grown extremely bullish in India in recent years. Last year, the company announced it will invest $10 billion in India over the course of next five to seven years. (Image credits: Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<p>The JioPhone Next is Google&#8217;s latest attempt at reaching the masses in developing markets. The Android-maker has launched several programs over the past decade including Android One to deliver budget smartphones with improved user experience. At an event in India in 2017, Google chief executive Sundar Pichai noted that many markets such as India need phones at a price point of $30 for mass adoption.</p>
<p>&#8220;The JioPhone Next is an affordable smartphone designed for India, inspired by the belief that everyone in India should benefit from the opportunities the internet creates. To build it, our teams had to work together to solve complex engineering and design challenges, and I’m excited to see how millions of people will use these devices to better their lives and communities,&#8221; he said in a statement Friday.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Analysts have said in recent months that the JioPhone Next could disrupt the Indian smartphone market — the world’s second largest — and help the telecom network, which has amassed over 400 million subscribers and last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/google-invests-4-5-billion-in-indias-reliance-jio-platforms/">raised over $20 billion from a range of marquee investors including Google and Facebook</a>, further solidify its dominance in the country.</p>
<p>The JioPhone Next &#8212; which was originally scheduled to launch in the second week of September, but the two firms had to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/jiophone-next-launch-delayed-november-google-reliance-india/">delay the sale citing global chip shortage</a> &#8212; is aimed at helping roughly 300 million users in India who are still on a 2G network upgrade their gadget to access faster networks, Ambani said at an event earlier this year.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am delighted that Google and Jio teams have succeeded in bringing this breakthrough device to Indian consumers in time for the festival season, inspite of the current global supply chain challenges caused by the Covid pandemic. I have always been a firm believer in the power of the Digital Revolution to enrich, enable and empower the lives of 1.35 billion Indians. We have done it in the past with connectivity. Now we are enabling it again with a smartphone device,&#8221; he said in a statement Friday.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/google-and-jios-smartphone-with-custom-android-os-for-india-launches-november-4-for-87/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226279</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Leaked photo of Facebook&#8217;s Meta smartwatch shows camera notch</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/leaked-photo-of-facebooks-meta-smartwatch-shows-camera-notch/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/leaked-photo-of-facebooks-meta-smartwatch-shows-camera-notch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 11:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartwatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meta — that is, the company formerly known as Facebook — may be developing a smartwatch that can take photos and videos. A new leaked image shows a smartwatch with a notch with a front-facing camera.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mariella Moon</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mariella Moon is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/apple-will-require-unvaccinated-employees-to-test-for-covid-19-daily/">Apple will require unvaccinated employees to test for COVID-19 daily</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/netflix-says-142-million-households-watched-korean-series-squid-game/">Netflix says 142 million households watched Korean series &#8216;Squid Game&#8217;</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Meta — that is, the company <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-new-name-meta-182151399.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">formerly known</a> as Facebook — may be developing a smartwatch that can take photos and videos. <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-28/leaked-photo-shows-meta-s-planned-competitor-to-apple-watch" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1"><em>Bloomberg</em></a> has published an image showing a smartwatch with rounded corners similar to the Apple Watch, except it also has a notch with a front-facing camera. App developer Steve Moser found the image inside the company&#8217;s app used to control its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-ray-ban-stories-smart-glasses-ar-160006477.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1">Ray-Ban Stories</a> AR sunglasses, hinting that it could also be used to control the watch in the future.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226277" style="width: 684px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/dims.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226277" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2226277" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/dims.jpeg" alt="" width="674" height="411" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/dims.jpeg 674w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/dims.jpeg?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/dims.jpeg?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/dims.jpeg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 674px) 100vw, 674px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2226277" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Meta</p></div></p>
<p>In addition to having rounded corners and a camera, the smartwatch appears to have a stainless steel casing and detachable straps. Moser also says that the code inside the app indicates that the watch could be called Milan and that it could allow for the photos and videos you captured with it to be downloaded on a phone.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226276" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div id="max-player-injector" class="vmmi-si" data-maxi="0">
<div class="vdb_player"></div>
</div>
<p>According to <em>Bloomberg</em>, Meta is hoping to launch a smartwatch as early as 2022, but nothing has been finalized yet. Further, Facebook&#8217;s parent company is reportedly already working on three generations of product that will be released at different times. It&#8217;s not clear if the device shown in the image is one of those, or if it will even be released at all. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526266/facebook-smartwatch-two-cameras-heart-rate-monitor" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1"><em>The Verge</em></a> also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-smartwatch-camera-detachable-heart-rate-monitor-184825648.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">reported</a> earlier this year, though, that Facebook is working on a smartwatch with a front-facing and a 1080p rear camera with autofocus. It could have a heart rate monitor and LTE connectivity, as well, though those features could be distributed across the three different models.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on<a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-meta-smartwatch-camera-032354601.html"> Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/leaked-photo-of-facebooks-meta-smartwatch-shows-camera-notch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226276</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kurly, the Korean online grocery startup, says it plans IPO in June at estimated $5.9B valuation </title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/kurly-the-korean-online-grocery-startup-says-it-plans-ipo-in-june-at-estimated-5-9b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/kurly-the-korean-online-grocery-startup-says-it-plans-ipo-in-june-at-estimated-5-9b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kurly, a South Korea-based online grocery startup that provides next-day delivery services across the country, will go public by June next year.  The startup, which declined to comment on how much it plans to raise via IPO, said it estimates the company valuation approximately $5.9 billion after it goes public.   The announcement comes after its $200 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://www.kurly.com/shop/main/index.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kurly</a>, a South Korea-based online grocery startup that provides next-day delivery services across the country, will go public by June next year. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The startup, which declined to comment on how much it plans to raise via IPO, said it estimates the company valuation approximately $5.9 billion after it goes public.  </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The announcement comes after </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/kurly-the-korean-grocery-startup-raises-200m-on-a-2-2b-valuation-after-shifting-ipo-plans-away-from-the-nyse/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">its $200 million Series F at a $2.2 billion valuation</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> in July. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226241" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">A spokesperson at Kurly said the IPO is likely to be in June after it files an IPO application as early as December and expects to get approval in February by South Korean financial authorities. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Kurly has reviewed its listing in the U.S. but changed the plan to a Korean IPO. The company, which will continue to focus on its business in the home market, does not have an overseas expansion plan, and that’s one of the reasons why Kurly lists in South Korea, the spokesperson at Kurly told TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">South Korean authorities have eased IPO requirements for Korea-based startups to attract them to get listed on the domestic bourse after Korean e-commerce company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/coupang-follows-roblox-to-a-strong-first-day-of-trading/">Coupang listed</a> on the New York Stock Exchange early this year.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Korea Exchange announced in March it will allow companies with an expected market capitalization of $855 million (1 trillion WON) or more to get listed even if they do not meet financial requirements.  </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cV3ZB2kcPk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/kurly-the-korean-grocery-startup-raises-200m-on-a-2-2b-valuation-after-shifting-ipo-plans-away-from-the-nyse/">Kurly, the Korean grocery startup, raises $200M on a $2.2B valuation after shifting IPO plans away from the NYSE</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kurly, the Korean grocery startup, raises $200M on a $2.2B valuation after shifting IPO plans away from the NYSE&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/kurly-the-korean-grocery-startup-raises-200m-on-a-2-2b-valuation-after-shifting-ipo-plans-away-from-the-nyse/embed/#?secret=cV3ZB2kcPk" data-secret="cV3ZB2kcPk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Kurly was founded in 2015 by Sophie Kim, a former investment banker-turned-entrepreneur. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The Seoul-based online grocery company said its IPO proceeds will be used to advance its research and development, enhance its order process, and improve its payment system. It also plans to expand its headcount. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The company claims that it has now about 9 million users. It posted $853 million (1trillion WON) transactions in 2020 and aims to generate $1.7 billion of transactions by the end of this year, according to the spokesperson. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Competition in the online grocery delivery industry has been heating up, spurred by the pandemic. Kurly’s domestic competitors, including </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://pulsenews.co.kr/view.php?sc=30800028&amp;year=2021&amp;no=773355" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">SSG.com</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">, an E-commerce platform arm owned by Korean </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/004170.KS/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Shinsegae Group,</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> and </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://pulsenews.co.kr/view.php?sc=30800028&amp;year=2021&amp;no=1026026" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Oasis Market</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">, which recently closed fundraising, are also set to go public in 2022. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="19bdH9Xjls"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/whos-building-the-grocery-store-of-the-future/">Who&#8217;s building the grocery store of the future?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Who&#8217;s building the grocery store of the future?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/whos-building-the-grocery-store-of-the-future/embed/#?secret=19bdH9Xjls" data-secret="19bdH9Xjls" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RTB0x3VGHu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/korean-grocery-startup-kurly-raises-150m/">Korean grocery startup Kurly raises $150M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Korean grocery startup Kurly raises $150M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/korean-grocery-startup-kurly-raises-150m/embed/#?secret=RTB0x3VGHu" data-secret="RTB0x3VGHu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/kurly-the-korean-online-grocery-startup-says-it-plans-ipo-in-june-at-estimated-5-9b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226241</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beta Finance, which offers one-click option to short crypto assets, raises from Sequoia Capital India and others</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/beta-finance-which-offers-one-click-option-to-short-crypto-assets-raises-from-sequoia-capital-india-and-others/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/beta-finance-which-offers-one-click-option-to-short-crypto-assets-raises-from-sequoia-capital-india-and-others/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 10:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Beta Finance, a decentralized finance protocol that has developed a one-click solution for lending, borrowing and shorting of any crypto asset, said on Friday it has raised $5.75 million across its private and public launchpad investments rounds. The private investment round was led by Sequoia Capital India. ParaFi Capital, DeFiance Capital, Spartan Group, GSR, Delphi [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Beta Finance, a decentralized finance protocol that has developed a one-click solution for lending, borrowing and shorting of any crypto asset, said on Friday it has raised $5.75 million across its private and public launchpad investments rounds.</p>
<p>The private investment round was led by Sequoia Capital India. ParaFi Capital, DeFiance Capital, Spartan Group, GSR, Delphi Digital, and Multicoin Capital also participated in it.</p>
<p>The startup, founded by Allen Lee, is attempting to make it easier for users to short a crypto coin to fight the price volatility and also give them another avenue to hedge their risk.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226238" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Existing DeFi protocols only support the borrowing and shorting of a very limited selection of mature crypto assets &#8212; leaving the vast majority of such tokens inaccessible from users.</p>
<p><a href="https:/www.betafinance.org">Beta Finance</a>, which is built atop the Etherium blockchain, says it is filling this inefficiency by creating what it calls the first user-friendly protocol that offers a wider choice and functionality.</p>
<p>Its one-click solution enables traders without technical know-how to manage and update their short positions on any token with all relevant token information directly available on the interface to guide their decision. &#8220;Users can short many of the most volatile assets neglected by existing money markets, which helps offset volatility, hedge risk and gain healthier returns,&#8221; the startup said.</p>
<p>“We see short selling as a critical piece of financial infrastructure that has been missing from the DeFi protocol,” said Lee in an interview with TechCrunch. “For DeFi to replace traditional finance, we believe that it’s necessary to build tools such as short selling.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Beta Finance, whose coin BETA trades on Binance, &#8220;has the potential to be a category-defining protocol,&#8221; said Pieter Kemps, Principal at Sequoia India, in a statement.</p>
<p>The startup says within the first month of its platform&#8217;s launch, it had processed over 10,000 deposits, 1,000 borrows, and 500 short positions for over 10,000 unique addresses. The protocol had an average total value locked of over $195 million, the startup said.</p>
<p>&#8220;In addition to being the pioneer for one-click shorting, Beta has already proven its ability to accommodate a diverse range of assets (including volatile ones) while remaining secure by becoming the very first protocol to short an NFT when it enabled short-selling for the $NFD token, just a week after launching the protocol. We are very optimistic that Beta will become a key stakeholder for the DeFi ecosystem going forward,&#8221; said Kemps.</p>
<p>Beta FInance will deploy the fresh capital to broaden its product offerings and hire more talent, Lee said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/beta-finance-which-offers-one-click-option-to-short-crypto-assets-raises-from-sequoia-capital-india-and-others/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226238</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bosch to invest another $467 million to boost chipmaking capacity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/bosch-boosts-investment-semiconductor-chip-capacity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/bosch-boosts-investment-semiconductor-chip-capacity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 03:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bosch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robert Bosch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semiconductors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[German technology and parts supplier Robert Bosch GmbH will invest another 400 million euros ($467 million) to expand its chip manufacturing facilities in response to the ongoing semiconductor shortage that has wreaked havoc on the production of everything from vehicles and appliances to personal computers and power tools. The boosted expenditure, which is earmarked for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">German technology and parts supplier Robert Bosch GmbH will invest another 400 million euros ($467 million) to expand its chip manufacturing facilities in response to the ongoing semiconductor shortage that has wreaked havoc on the production of everything from vehicles and appliances to personal computers and power tools.</p>
<p>The boosted expenditure, which is earmarked for 2022, will go toward expanding operations at the company’s wafer fabrication plants in Dresden and Reutlingen, Germany, and its semiconductor component facility in Penang, Malaysia. The majority of the funds will be used to increase manufacturing capacity at the Dresden site, which the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/bosch-opens-1-2-billion-chip-plant-in-germany/">opened in June</a> at a cost of €1 billion ($1.2 billion), the single largest investment in its history. That facility produces 300-millimeter wafers, a larger size that yields more individual chips per wafer.</p>
<p>Around 50 million euros will be spent in Reutlingen in both 2022 and 2023, where the company has been making semiconductor components since 1970. There, Bosch will expand its &#8220;cleanroom&#8221; – a specially engineered environment where the silicon wafers are made into semiconductor chips – by more than 4,000 square meters (about 43,000 square feet), to a total of 14,500 square meters (156,000 sq feet). The expansion will also create 150 new jobs, according to Bosch.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225855" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In Penang, Bosch will construct a new semiconductor test center, which will enter operations in 2023. The test center will take up around 14,000 square meters (150,696 sq feet) initially. However, the company has the space — more than 100,000 square meters — on the Penang strip, and plans to eventually develop all of it.</p>
<p>The huge investment comes during a protracted semiconductor shortage that automotive executives and industry analysts forecast will extend into next year. Executives from both Ford Motor Company and General Motors told investors in their respective third quarter earnings calls this week that they foresee the shortages persisting into 2022, and possibly even 2023.</p>
<p>It’s a sensible move for the company, which not only supplies automakers and other companies, but also uses its chips in-house for products such as Bosch power tools. It’s also good news for the European Union, which aims to increase domestic supply chain resilience by boosting the production of semiconductors in the EU to <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/europe-fit-digital-age/europes-digital-decade-digital-targets-2030_en">one-fifth of the world’s supply</a> by 2030.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/bosch-boosts-investment-semiconductor-chip-capacity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225855</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Project Cambria&#8217; is a high-end VR headset designed for Facebook&#8217;s metaverse</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/project-cambria-is-a-high-end-vr-headset-designed-for-facebooks-metaverse/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/project-cambria-is-a-high-end-vr-headset-designed-for-facebooks-metaverse/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Henry Pickavet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 23:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Cambria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VR]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook is working on a new high-end VR headset codenamed Project Cambria. The company teased the device during its recent Connect conference on Thursday. It plans to release the headset sometime next year. Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg said it will be a separate "high-end" product from the company's $299 Quest 2 headset. It will also cost more than that device.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Igor Bonifacic</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Igor Bonifacic is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/sony-buys-remake-and-remaster-studio-bluepoint-games/">Sony buys remake and remaster studio Bluepoint Games</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/1password-can-now-randomly-generate-email-addresses-for-logins/">1Password can now randomly generate email addresses for logins</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Facebook is working on a new high-end VR headset codenamed Project Cambria. The company teased the device during its recent Connect conference on Thursday. It plans to release the headset sometime next year. Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg said it will be a separate &#8220;high-end&#8221; product from the company&#8217;s $299 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/oculus-quest-2-review-vr-facebook-headset-173026291.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1">Quest 2 headset</a>. It will also cost more than that device.</p>
<p>Cambria will include capabilities that currently aren&#8217;t possible on other VR headsets. New sensors in the device will allow your virtual avatar to maintain eye contact and reflect your facial expressions. The company says that&#8217;s something that will allow people you&#8217;re interacting with virtually to get a better sense of how you&#8217;re feeling. Another focus of the headset will be mixed-reality experiences. With the help of new sensors and reconstruction algorithms, Facebook claims Cambria will have the capability to represent objects in the physical world with a sense of depth and perspective.</p>
<p>Cambria will also feature new optics that the company said will increase visual fidelity. Facebook promised to share more details about the headset next year. In the meantime, it mentioned that third-party developers are already working on experiences for the device.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226147" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-project-cambria-vr-headset-181249160.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/project-cambria-is-a-high-end-vr-headset-designed-for-facebooks-metaverse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226147</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mercedes cars will have optional Dolby Atmos audio starting in 2022</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/mercedes-cars-will-have-optional-dolby-atmos-audio-starting-in-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/mercedes-cars-will-have-optional-dolby-atmos-audio-starting-in-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Henry Pickavet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 22:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dolby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercedes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226100</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You won't have to buy a Lucid Air if you want a car with more immersive Dolby Atmos. Mercedes will equip its cars with Atmos audio on all models that use both its latest MBUX interface (introduced with the latest S-Class) and an optional Burmester 3D or 4D sound system. Whether or not you'll driving, you'll hear compatible music in a vertically enhanced sound field — it might not sound like a "live concert" as Mercedes claims, but it should be a step up from the usual stereo playback.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jon Fingas</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jon Fingas is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/uber-will-rent-up-to-50000-tesla-evs-to-drivers/">Uber will rent up to 50,000 Tesla EVs to drivers</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/verizon-partners-with-amazon-to-offer-satellite-internet-in-rural-areas/">Verizon partners with Amazon to offer satellite internet in rural areas</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">You won&#8217;t have to buy a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lucid-air-ev-dolby-atmos-160018074.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">Lucid Air</a> if you want a car with more immersive Dolby Atmos. Mercedes <a href="https://media.daimler.com/marsMediaSite/en/instance/ko.xhtml?oid=51745258" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1">will equip</a> its cars with Atmos audio on all models that use both its latest MBUX interface (introduced with the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mercedes-benz-s-class-first-drive-video-130059002.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1">latest S-Class</a>) and an optional Burmester 3D or 4D sound system. Whether or not you&#8217;ll driving, you&#8217;ll hear compatible music in a vertically enhanced sound field — it might not sound like a &#8220;live concert&#8221; as Mercedes claims, but it should be a step up from the usual stereo playback.</p>
<p>The 4D system includes 31 speakers, six of which create the 3D effect from above. Another four &#8220;near-ear&#8221; speakers sit in the front seats, and all four seats have two sound transducers (aka exciters) each. Throw in 1750W of total power (including an 18.5-liter subwoofer) and you&#8217;ll likely be happy regardless of the audio processing.</p>
<p>Just don&#8217;t plan on buying an Atmos-equipped car right away. The format will first be available in the Mercedes-Maybach in summer 2022, and the S-Class soon after. Other models will follow, but you might not want to count on buying an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-10-2019-mercedes-benz-a-class-a220-review.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">A-Class</a> with Atmos any time soon.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226100" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CCxB_IGyPI4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mercedes-benz-dolby-atmos-music-204555703.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/mercedes-cars-will-have-optional-dolby-atmos-audio-starting-in-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226100</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: After renaming Facebook &#8216;Meta,&#8217; Zuckerberg says &#8216;mission remains the same&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/daily-crunch-84/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/daily-crunch-84/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 22:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for October 28, 2021. With our SaaS event now behind us — a big thanks to the TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/about-techcrunch/">events and sales teams</a> who keep crushing it for the publication — we can pivot our focus back to, well, the metaverse? — <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-changes-its-corporate-branding-to-meta/"><strong>Facebook goes Meta</strong></a><strong>: </strong>By creating a brand above its preceding corporate domicile, Facebook has created a meta-entity to include its various projects. And one of those is the metaverse. Thus, the new name for the company — Meta — makes pretty good sense. Most folks don’t seem to like it much, but it’s hard to weed the General Facebook Snark from the Actually About The Name Snark, if that makes sense. More in our Big Tech section down below.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/nerdwallets-ipo-proves-you-can-write-your-way-to-a-unicorn-valuation/"><strong>NerdWallet writes its way to unicorn valuation:</strong></a><strong> </strong>As online finance content empire NerdWallet approaches the public markets, the writing-centric company will garner a valuation north of $1 billion, per its latest IPO filings. TechCrunch, a words-first publication, had thoughts on the matter.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/mark-zuckerberg-takes-thinly-veiled-shots-at-apple-for-stifling-innovation-via-its-platform-policies/"><strong>Facebook is cross with Apple:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Facebook — Meta, I suppose — took a few potshots at Apple during its big event today. They are worth considering apart from the larger branding and VR efforts that the company announced. Apple’s changing privacy rules have taken a toll on Facebook, and the social giant is not pleased about it.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Before we get into the startup news, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/allbirds-flotation-should-help-the-market-sort-the-value-of-tech-enabled-ipos/">former startup Allbirds is going public, and TechCrunch has the details on just what it is worth</a>. And, in the wake of Rent the Runway, we are starting to see a valuation band created for tech-enabled IPOs.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226002" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/atlys-raises-4-25m-to-make-visa-applications-faster-and-easier/"><strong>Atlys wants to make visa applications quicker:</strong></a><strong> </strong>And it just raised $4.25 million for its work. Sure, fewer of us than normal are flying overseas, but eventually we’ll get back on planes and go places. And when we do, well, the paperwork will beckon. Perhaps Atlys can take some of the sting out of stapling photos of yourself to a packet that you then mail to the black hole of an embassy.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/cover-a-modular-home-builder-thats-modeled-in-ways-after-tesla-has-raised-a-60-million-series-b/"><strong>Soon we shall all live in pods:</strong></a> Prefab pods, if Cover gets its way. The startup creates walls and other similar home components in its factory. Those bits are then shipped to building sites and set up sans a crane. Frankly, let’s hope this works? We have a housing crisis in the United States, and any movement toward alleviating it is welcome. The company also just raised $60 million.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tim-berners-lee-startup-inrupt-funding/"><strong>Inrupt’s plans to reclaim internet privacy raising capital:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The deal isn’t done yet, but TechCrunch broke news today that Tim Berners-Lee’s Inrupt startup, a company that wants to build “a platform that gives users control of their data” online, is looking to raise between $30 million and $40 million.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/oneroof-raises-1-25m-to-build-a-hyper-localized-nextdoor/"><strong>What if Nextdoor was even more insular?</strong></a><strong> </strong>Well, that’s what OneRoof is building, an even more hyperlocal Nextdoor, the social network known to bring neighbors together so that they can argue and throw racist invective at one another. Now you will be able to do so in even tighter-knit circles. The company just raised $1.25 million.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tiger-coatue-double-down-on-hinge-health-with-new-400m-infusion/"><strong>Healthcare remains a lucrative market:</strong></a><strong> </strong>That’s our takeaway from Hinge Health raising $400 million in a new round. The company is focused on chronic musculoskeletal (MSK) conditions, which encompass things like aching backs and knees. Given how large the American healthcare market is, the company’s $6.2 billion valuation may make a mote more sense than you are mentally giving it credit for.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/aws-for-blockchain-alchemy-boost-valuation-to-3-5b-with-250m-raise/"><strong>Alchemy raises $250M in competitive round:</strong></a> Every venture investor is in awe of Amazon’s AWS group, because it eats growth and shits operating profit. It’s worth a zillion dollars. So it’s perhaps not surprising that the competition to put capital into Alchemy was more than hot. The firm provides basic infra to other crypto companies, and a grip of crypto companies that you know of are already Alchemy customers.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/yugabyte-stores-up-188m-more-for-its-open-source-distributed-sql-database-model-now-valued-at-1-3b/"><strong>Yugabyte raises yuge venture round at yuger valuation:</strong></a> Yugabyte is now a unicorn, which feels like a very 2021 sentence. The database company just added $188 million to its own financial database at a valuation of $1.3 billion.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/dragos-series-d-unicorn/"><strong>Dragos raises $200M, soars to $1.7B valuation, sadly isn’t about dragons:</strong></a> Dragos works in industrial cybersecurity, which matters. Keeping IRL infra safe is a pretty big deal. But when I read the company&#8217;s name I was frankly hoping for mythical beasts. Alas.</li>
<li>And to close out our startup notes, <a href="https://twitter.com/NeeshaTambe">TechCrunch’s Neesha Tambe</a> has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/sequoia-provides-founders-with-key-insights-on-launching-building-and-fundraising/">notes from a chat with Sequoia</a> concerning fundraising tips for today’s startups.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Credit card and payments companies compete for a slice of the growing BNPL market</h2>
<p>Giving consumers the convenience of deferring payment for a product is not a new idea, but now that upstarts like Klarna, Afterpay and Affirm have taken the concept to the next level, legacy credit card companies and payment firms are taking notice.</p>
<p>Mary Ann Azevedo and Ryan Lawler have identified a &#8220;slow emergence&#8221; in the BNPL space &#8220;of a symbiotic relationship between traditional financial institutions, payments upstarts and leading companies.&#8221;</p>
<p>Visa announced yesterday that many companies are using its technology to power point-of-sale BNPL solutions; last month, its rival rolled out Mastercard Installments, its bespoke offering.</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s not really a surprise that these credit card companies are stepping it up when it comes to BNPL,&#8221; reported Ryan and Mary Ann. &#8220;If anything, it’s a wonder that it took them this long.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rUSHa3M6sD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/everyone-loves-bnpl/">Credit card and payments companies compete for a slice of the growing BNPL market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Credit card and payments companies compete for a slice of the growing BNPL market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/everyone-loves-bnpl/embed/#?secret=rUSHa3M6sD" data-secret="rUSHa3M6sD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Before we get to our Facebook News Roundup, Twitter also made a bit of noise today. Users <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/twitter-launches-spaces-recording-feature-to-testers-on-ios-global-launch-to-follow/">will now be able to record Spaces</a>, its audio chat rooms. And its subscription “Blue” service <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/twitter-blue-introduces-labs-to-give-users-early-access-to-new-features/">will include early feature access</a>.</p>
<h3>The rest of what Facebook announced:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-teases-polar-a-mobile-app-for-creating-ar-filters/">Facebook teases Polar, a mobile app for creating AR filters</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-messenger-audio-calls-are-coming-to-oculus-quest/">Facebook Messenger audio calls are coming to Oculus Quest</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-opens-oculus-store-to-2d-progressive-web-apps/">Facebook opens Oculus Store to 2D progressive web apps</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/slack-is-coming-to-the-oculus-quest/">Slack is coming to the Oculus Quest</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-errr-meta-unceremoniously-kills-off-oculus-brand/">Company formerly known as Facebook unceremoniously kills off ‘Oculus’ brand</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>And from the rest of Big Tech:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/everyone-loves-bnpl/"><strong>Digging into majors attacking the BNPL market:</strong></a> While Affirm is best known as an early BNPL startup that made it to the public markets, Big Finance is not going to let tech have all the fun. Mary Ann and Ryan investigate.</li>
<li>And in news that is sure to make other companies as happy as the privacy changes, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/apples-app-privacy-report-launches-into-beta-to-show-you-what-your-apps-are-up-to/">Apple’s “App Privacy Report” is now in beta</a>. Do note, please, that the more Apple pisses off other companies regarding data privacy, the better off consumers may be — but also that Apple is only doing this for its own results, not because it likes us.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants to help startups find the right expert for their needs. To do this, we’re building a shortlist of the top growth marketers. We’ve received great recommendations for growth marketers in the startup industry since we launched our survey.</p>
<p>We’re excited to read more responses as they come in!<a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03"> Fill out the survey here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/daily-crunch-84/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226002</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Satellite manufacturer Terran Orbital to go public in $1.58B SPAC merger</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/satellite-manufacturer-terran-orbital-to-go-public-in-1-58b-spac-merger/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/satellite-manufacturer-terran-orbital-to-go-public-in-1-58b-spac-merger/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 21:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite imagery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satellites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spac merger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terran orbital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226090</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Terran Orbital, a leading manufacturer of small satellites, is going public in a merger with special purpose acquisition company (SPAC) Tailwind Two Acquisition Corp. The deal has a post-transaction enterprise value of $1.58 billion and will furnish the company with around $470 million. Of those funds, $345 million will come from Tailwind Two’s contribution, plus [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Terran Orbital, a leading manufacturer of small satellites, is going public in a merger with special purpose acquisition company (SPAC) Tailwind Two Acquisition Corp. The deal has a post-transaction enterprise value of $1.58 billion and will furnish the company with around $470 million.</p>
<p>Of those funds, $345 million will come from Tailwind Two’s contribution, plus $50 million PIPE provided by AE Industrial Partners, Beach Point Capital, Daniel Staton, Lockheed Martin and Fuel Venture Capital. An additional $75 million has been committed by Francisco Partners and Beach Point Capital, and the company may have access to up to $125 million in debt commitments from Francisco Partners and Lockheed Martin at the close of the transaction.</p>
<p>Terran’s announcement is a reflection that space startups are still looking to SPAC mergers as a way to raise cash and go public. Deals with blank-check firms have become a popular route to the public markets in the space industry; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/virgin-orbit-to-go-public-via-3-2b-spac-deal/">Virgin Orbit</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/satellite-operator-planet-to-go-public-in-2-8b-spac-merger/">Planet</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/acquisition-happy-space-infrastructure-company-redwire-set-to-go-public-via-spac/">Redwire</a>, BlackSky, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/satellite-constellation-operator-spire-global-to-go-public-via-1-6-billion-spac/">Spire Global</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/satellite-imagery-startup-satellogic-to-go-public-via-spac-valuing-the-company-at-850m/">Satellogic</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/rocket-lab-to-go-public-via-spac-at-valuation-of-4-1-billion/">Rocket Lab</a>, Momentus and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/rocket-startup-astra-is-going-public-vis-spac/">Astra</a> are among the space companies that have raised billions through this financial vehicle.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226090" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Terran Orbital is a contract manufacturer, designing, building and engineering satellites primarily for the U.S. government. Around 95% of Terran’s work is related to NASA and the Department of Defense, CEO Marc Bell told TechCrunch in an interview earlier this year.</p>
<p>The company will be opening <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/terran-orbital-to-open-a-300m-satellite-manufacturing-and-component-facility-on-floridas-space-coast/">the world’s largest space vehicle manufacturing facility</a> on Florida’s Space Coast at an investment of $300 million, it announced in September. The 660,000-square-foot facility will have the capacity to manufacture 1,000 complete satellites and over 1 million satellite components per year — a volume unheard of in the space industry.</p>
<p>In addition to manufacturing satellites, Terran Orbital also aims to operate its own earth observation constellation and deliver satellite imagery as a service. In a statement, Bell called it the new SaaS: “satellites as a service.”</p>
<p>The transaction, which has already received unanimous approval by both Terran Orbital and and Tailwind Two’s boards of directors, is expected to close in the first quarter of 2022.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/satellite-manufacturer-terran-orbital-to-go-public-in-1-58b-spac-merger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226090</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon stock falls on revenue miss, rising costs due to macroeconomic conditions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/amazon-stock-falls-on-revenue-miss-rising-costs-due-to-macroeconomic-conditions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/amazon-stock-falls-on-revenue-miss-rising-costs-due-to-macroeconomic-conditions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 21:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s very hard to feel poorly for a company worth around $1.75 trillion, so we won&#8217;t. But shareholders of Amazon stock are taking on a bit of water in after-hours trading this afternoon. Amazon reported its Q3 2021 results today after the bell, detailing its recent performance that included a top-and-bottom miss on revenues and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s very hard to feel poorly for a company worth around $1.75 trillion, so we won&#8217;t. But shareholders of Amazon stock are taking on a bit of water in after-hours trading this afternoon. Amazon reported its <a href="https://ir.aboutamazon.com/news-release/news-release-details/2021/Amazon.com-Announces-Third-Quarter-Results/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Q3 2021 results</a> today after the bell, detailing its recent performance that included a top-and-bottom miss on revenues and profits.</p>
<p>In the three months concluding September 30, 2021, the e-commerce and cloud computing giant reported $110.8 billion in revenues, up 15% compared to the year-ago period. Amazon also reported net income of $3.2 billion in the period, or $6.12 per share.</p>
<p>Analysts <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/AMZN/analysis?p=AMZN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">had expected</a> the company to post revenues of $111.6 billion, and per-share earnings of $8.92. The company&#8217;s net income dipped by some 49% on a year-over-year basis.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226030" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Shares of Amazon are off just over 5% as we write to you this afternoon.</p>
<p>But while Amazon&#8217;s Q3 performance missed the mark &#8212; the company&#8217;s AWS unit did report accelerating revenue growth on a year-over-year basis, providing something for the company&#8217;s fans to crow about &#8212; its Q4 notes may overshadow its trailing results. The company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/">new CEO, Andrew Jassy</a>, said the following in the company&#8217;s earnings digest:</p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">In the fourth quarter, we expect to incur several billion dollars of additional costs in our Consumer business as we manage through labor supply shortages, increased wage costs, global supply chain issues, and increased freight and shipping costs—all while doing whatever it takes to minimize the impact on customers and selling partners this holiday season. </span></p></blockquote>
<p>The executive framed the impending costs as customer-forward, arguing that taking near-term hits for longer-term results is reasonable. Investors were not sufficiently content with the promise of future cash flows to avoid reducing the company&#8217;s market cap by a few dozen billion.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But, as we noted, it&#8217;s hard to feel that bad for the firm given that Amazon reported net income north of $1 billion per month in Q3.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Vw9nahu68o"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/">3 analysts weigh in: What are Andy Jassy&#8217;s top priorities as Amazon&#8217;s new CEO?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 analysts weigh in: What are Andy Jassy&#8217;s top priorities as Amazon&#8217;s new CEO?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/embed/#?secret=Vw9nahu68o" data-secret="Vw9nahu68o" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Cloud revenues are the element of Amazon earnings that we at TechCrunch pay the most attention to, so let&#8217;s peek at the data. First, here&#8217;s how the company&#8217;s AWS division performed in revenue and operating income terms:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2226046 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.41.14-PM.png" alt="" width="559" height="69" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.41.14-PM.png 559w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.41.14-PM.png?resize=150,19 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.41.14-PM.png?resize=300,37 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.41.14-PM.png?resize=50,6 50w" sizes="(max-width: 559px) 100vw, 559px" /></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226045" style="width: 566px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226045" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2226045 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.39.59-PM.png" alt="" width="556" height="72" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.39.59-PM.png 556w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.39.59-PM.png?resize=150,19 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.39.59-PM.png?resize=300,39 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.39.59-PM.png?resize=50,6 50w" sizes="(max-width: 556px) 100vw, 556px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2226045" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p>
<p>So about $4.5 billion in new year-over-year revenues, and around $1.5 billion in new operating income. For those of you curious, both AWS and revenue and operating expenses grew by around 39% in the year-over-year window. Now let&#8217;s take a closer peek at pure growth metrics:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2226046 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.41.14-PM.png" alt="" width="559" height="69" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.41.14-PM.png 559w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.41.14-PM.png?resize=150,19 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.41.14-PM.png?resize=300,37 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.41.14-PM.png?resize=50,6 50w" sizes="(max-width: 559px) 100vw, 559px" /></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226044" style="width: 567px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226044" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2226044 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.40.21-PM.png" alt="" width="557" height="201" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.40.21-PM.png 557w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.40.21-PM.png?resize=150,54 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.40.21-PM.png?resize=300,108 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-4.40.21-PM.png?resize=50,18 50w" sizes="(max-width: 557px) 100vw, 557px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2226044" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p>
<p>This set of data is notable because AWS is the fastest growing segment at Amazon. While the company is mostly in the headlines thanks to its e-commerce operations it is now being growth-led by its quieter cloud group. How long until investors demand that the company be split in two to unlock value?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/amazon-stock-falls-on-revenue-miss-rising-costs-due-to-macroeconomic-conditions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226030</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Audi turns to software to add more range to its older e-tron EVs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/audi-software-adds-range-to-older-e-tron-evs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/audi-software-adds-range-to-older-e-tron-evs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 20:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225986</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Audi has rolled out a new software update to its 2019 model year e-tron electric SUV that will add up to 12 miles of range to the battery. While the improvement might not seem significant — it is, after all, only 12 miles — it does show how automakers are using software to improve older [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Audi has rolled out a new software update to its 2019 model year e-tron electric SUV that will add up to 12 miles of range to the battery.</p>
<p>While the improvement might not seem significant — it is, after all, only 12 miles — it does show how automakers are using software to improve older electric vehicles. In this case, Audi used software to unlock more capacity in the existing battery, essentially improving its efficiency. The automaker also said the software updates have improved the efficiency of the front electric motor and the battery&#8217;s thermal management system.</p>
<p>The 2019 Audi e-tron 55 quattro is equipped with a 95 kilowatt-hour battery and will now use 86 kWh of capacity. That will push its range from the original 411 kilometers to about 441 km (274 miles) under the WLTP standard. (EPA standard is considered more conservative; the original EPA estimates for the 2019 was 204 miles.)</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225986" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The software update is available to all Audi e-tron 55 quattro production vehicles built between mid-September 2018 (model year 2019) and the end of November 2019 (model year 2020). Unlike Tesla, which lets owners launch software updates over-the-air, meaning anywhere they can access Wi-Fi, Audi requires a visit to one of its service centers.</p>
<p>This will help the older model keep apace of the newer 2020 and 2021 Sportback and e-tron SUV, which have improved software and hardware.</p>
<p>One might wonder why Audi didn&#8217;t just use that capacity to begin with. Audi and other automakers entering into the EV game initially limited the usable capacity of its battery out of an abundance of caution to avoid any degradation.</p>
<p>Other automakers are beginning to use over-the-air software updates, following Tesla&#8217;s lead, to improve or add features. In February, Volvo launched its first OTA software update on its all-electric XC40 Recharge in Europe. Volvo released an OTA this month that increased driving range through improvements to the battery management system and pre-conditioning timer. The company also launched a <a href="https://www.media.volvocars.com/us/en-us/media/pressreleases/289321/optimise-the-range-of-your-fully-electric-volvo-with-new-range-assistant-app-in-latest-over-the-air" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Range Assistant app</a> to help drivers get the most range out of their batteries.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/audi-software-adds-range-to-older-e-tron-evs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225986</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Predicting the next wave of Southeast Asia tech giants</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/predicting-the-next-wave-of-southeast-asia-tech-giants/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/predicting-the-next-wave-of-southeast-asia-tech-giants/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 20:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Southeast Asia & Oceania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jungle ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite the impressive growth and stellar companies grabbing headlines and tons of capital, Southeast Asia is only just entering the next phase of development.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Amit Anand</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/amitvedand">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Amit Anand is a founding partner of <a href="https://www.jungle.vc/">Jungle Ventures</a> and an early pioneer and leader in the development of Southeast Asia’s venture capital industry.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/investors-are-doubling-down-on-southeast-asias-digital-economy/">Investors are doubling down on Southeast Asia&#8217;s digital economy</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">With Grab’s announcement of its imminent <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Startups/Grab-says-on-track-to-close-SPAC-deal-by-end-of-2021">Nasdaq listing</a> and GoJek merging with Tokopedia to form tech giant <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/indonesias-goto-set-wrap-up-2-bln-funding-round-eyes-ipo-2022-sources-2021-08-19/">GoTo</a>, casual international observers could be forgiven for believing that Southeast Asia’s tech universe only comprises similar companies. However, these companies only represent the highlights of what is a blossoming startup ecosystem.</p>
<p>Southeast Asia is hitting a sweet spot. It remains at a relatively nascent phase expansion in the technology industry but is at the same time developed enough to have a 400-million-strong internet user base. By late 2021, approximately 80% of the Southeast Asian population (aged 15 and above) will be digital consumers, according to a report by <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/news/southeast-asia-the-home-for-digital-transformation">Facebook and Bain &amp; Company</a>.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, tech startup growth is booming as well. More than 35 tech startups across e-commerce, fintech and SaaS have achieved unicorn status in Southeast Asia, which has over 200 significant startups. As per Jungle Ventures’ calculations, the total value of the region’s digital companies is around $340 billion today and is estimated to grow to $1 trillion by 2025.</p>
<p>Further, Southeast Asian companies are breaking IPO records. Both Grab and GoTo’s valuations hover around the $35 billion to $40 billion mark. Sea is the 65<sup>th</sup> most valuable company in the world with a market cap of $187 billion, while Bukalapak was Indonesia’s largest-ever IPO at $1.5 billion at a market cap of $8 billion. There are many more waiting in the pipeline hoping to join this illustrious club of Southeast Asian tech decacorns.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Despite strong e-wallet adoption, over 70% of adults in Southeast Asia remain either underbanked or unbanked due to various cost and geographical limitations.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<h2>Vertical e-commerce is climbing the vine</h2>
<p>E-commerce will continue to accelerate in Southeast Asia — the sector is projected to grow 80% year on year and double in five years to $254 billion from $132 billion in 2021, according to the Facebook and Bain report. Shopee, Lazada, GoTo and Bukalapak are testament to the phenomenal growth opportunities available, and they are still growing.</p>
<p>While initial e-commerce success came from retail-focused companies such as Shopee and Lazada, the next value creation wave is emerging through vertical e-commerce.</p>
<p>Carro, which achieved unicorn status this year, offers an automotive marketplace in addition to supplementary products such as financing and insurance. Others like Livspace, Pomelo, Zalora and Sociolla are serving the home goods, fashion and personal care industries, respectively, and raising millions of dollars in funding. Their success is underpinned by the fact that at a product category level, Southeast Asia is still in the early stages of online retail penetration.</p>
<p>Based on the chart below, just &#8220;catching up&#8221; to the same level of penetration as China in verticalized segments increases the e-commerce opportunity by four to five times across the region.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/predicting-the-next-wave-of-southeast-asia-tech-giants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224901</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok is testing a new direct tipping feature with select creators</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tiktok-is-testing-a-new-direct-tipping-feature-with-select-creators/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tiktok-is-testing-a-new-direct-tipping-feature-with-select-creators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 20:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Navarra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media consultant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streamlabs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok is testing a new in-app tipping feature on its platform that would allow creators to accept money from fans outside of TikTok LIVE streams, where gifting is already supported. The company confirmed the feature is part of a limited test for the time being and is not yet broadly available. TikTok creator Jera Bean [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok is testing a new in-app tipping feature on its platform that would allow creators to accept money from fans outside of TikTok LIVE streams, where gifting is already supported. The company confirmed the feature is part of a limited test for the time being and is not yet broadly available.</p>
<p>TikTok creator <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@jera.bean/video/7023876662139866415?is_copy_url=1&amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;lang=en">Jera Bean</a> first spotted the feature and posted a video showcasing the new option, which was then highlighted by social media consultant <a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1453506329872670722">Matt Navarra</a> on Twitter.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">TikTok is rolling out a Tips feature to some creators </p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226023" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>h/t jera.bean <a href="https://t.co/fmrfuxdkrG">https://t.co/fmrfuxdkrG</a> <a href="https://t.co/hufl2qopk2">pic.twitter.com/hufl2qopk2</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Matt Navarra (@MattNavarra) <a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1453506329872670722?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 27, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Her video shows the new feature in her TikTok account&#8217;s settings and the screen where TikTok details the requirements.</p>
<p>Creators who are part of the limited test can apply for the feature if they have at least 100,000 followers and are in good standing, the screen explains. Once creators submit an application to activate the feature, they’ll be notified when their account is approved. Creators that have been approved will be given a Tips button on their profiles, which their followers will be able to use to send them direct payments.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Tips page also notes that the money received by creators will go directly to them and that TikTok will not be taking a cut. It’s unknown if TikTok plans to take a cut from creator Tips in the future if the feature progresses past the testing stage, but that seems likely.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re always thinking about new ways to bring value to our community and enrich the TikTok experience,&#8221; a TikTok spokesperson told TechCrunch, when reached for comment.</p>
<p>The feature is TikTok’s latest push toward monetization and helping creators earn a living through its platform. Last year, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/tiktok-creator-fund-200-million-us/">introduced</a> a $200 million fund aimed at helping creators in the U.S. supplement their earnings. TikTok also helps creators sign brand partnerships and sponsorship deals and also provides monetization for livestreams. Considering TikTok&#8217;s focus on monetization efforts, it’s no surprise that the company is experimenting with a way for creators to directly receive money from their followers.</p>
<p>TikTok also isn’t the only social media platform looking to offer creators more ways to make money, as the new Tips option is similar to Twitter’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/twitter-tip-jar-lets-you-pay-people-for-good-tweetin/">&#8220;Tip Jar&#8221;</a> feature that launched earlier this year. Similar to TikTok’s approach, Tip Jar is available to a select group of users including nonprofits, journalists, experts and creators.</p>
<p>TikTok and Twitter&#8217;s direct tipping features appear to be a way for the companies to compete with other digital platforms like Instagram and YouTube, which offer lucrative ways for creators to make money.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tiktok-is-testing-a-new-direct-tipping-feature-with-select-creators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226023</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Company formerly known as Facebook unceremoniously kills off &#8216;Oculus&#8217; brand</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-errr-meta-unceremoniously-kills-off-oculus-brand/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-errr-meta-unceremoniously-kills-off-oculus-brand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 20:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Bosworth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Display technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixed reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus Rift S]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus VR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palmer Luckey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearable devices]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the company&#8217;s AR/VR-focused Connect event this morning, Mark Zuckerberg announced that despite a name change, Facebook Meta&#8217;s mission will remain the same and that its existing brands wouldn&#8217;t be changing. “To reflect who we are and what we hope to build, I am proud to announce that starting today, our company is now Meta. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At the company&#8217;s AR/VR-focused Connect event this morning, Mark Zuckerberg announced that despite a name change, <del>Facebook</del> Meta&#8217;s mission will remain the same and that its existing brands wouldn&#8217;t be changing.</p>
<p>“To reflect who we are and what we hope to build, I am proud to announce that starting today, our company is now Meta. Our mission remains the same — it’s still about bringing people together. Our apps and our brands — they’re not changing either,” Zuckerberg said.</p>
<p>Well, it turns out that&#8217;s not so true. In a lengthy <a href="https://www.facebook.com/boz/posts/10114026973983491">Facebook post</a>, CTO-in-waiting Andrew Bosworth detailed about 15 minutes later following the completion of the keynote that as part of the new rebrand, they will be killing off the Oculus brand.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225989" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Oculus phrasing was conspicuously absent from the presentations today and features like the Oculus Store were consistently referred to as the Quest Store. In his post, Bosworth details that starting early next year the process to rename the Oculus app to the Meta app and the Oculus Quest to the Meta Quest will begin.</p>
<p>&#8220;We all have a strong attachment to the Oculus brand, and this was a very difficult decision to make. While we’re retiring the name, I can assure you that the original Oculus vision remains deeply embedded in how Meta will continue to drive mass adoption for VR today,&#8221; Bosworth wrote.</p>
<p>Facebook bought Oculus VR back in 2014.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sure looks like Zuckerberg made it about 15 seconds into his company rebrand before his first lie as Meta CEO</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&quot;Our mission remains the same — it’s still about bringing people together. Our apps and our brands — they’re not changing either.&quot; <a href="https://t.co/yPlYBGUZbB">https://t.co/yPlYBGUZbB</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Lucas Matney (@lucasmtny) <a href="https://twitter.com/lucasmtny/status/1453810993163759619?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 28, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-errr-meta-unceremoniously-kills-off-oculus-brand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225989</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiger Global leads $25M investment into Swap, which aims to be &#8216;LatAm&#8217;s fintech factory&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tiger-global-leads-25m-investment-into-swap-which-aims-to-be-latams-fintech-factory/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tiger-global-leads-25m-investment-into-swap-which-aims-to-be-latams-fintech-factory/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 19:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banking-as-a-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LATAM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Swap, a São Paulo-based BaaS startup, announced today it has raised $25 million in a Series A led by Tiger Global Management. The financing was “heavily oversubscribed,” according to the company, which has now raised $28 million since its October 2018 inception. Endeavor, Tinder co-founder Justin Mateen, partners of DST Global, ONEVC, Global Founders Capital [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.swap.financial/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Swap</a>, a São Paulo-based BaaS startup, announced today it has raised $25 million in a Series A led by Tiger Global Management.</p>
<p>The financing was “heavily oversubscribed,” according to the company, which has now raised $28 million since its October 2018 inception. Endeavor, Tinder co-founder Justin Mateen, partners of DST Global, ONEVC, Global Founders Capital and Flourish Ventures all participated in the latest round. Previous backers include Canary and other angels such as Ariel Lambrecht, co-founder of 99 — the first Brazilian unicorn and Guilherme Bonifácio, iFood’s co-founder.</p>
<p>Founded by Douglas Storf, Ury Rappaport and Alexandre Takinami, Swap aims to empower companies to transform their financial operations via its APIs, which it says offers users “the infrastructure for various financial solutions, allowing them to monetize their platforms.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225980" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The inspiration behind Swap came from Storf and Rappaport&#8217;s own experience at 99 (formerly known as 99Taxis), where the two sought to create a series of financial products for the transport app&#8217;s partner drivers. It was there that the pair recognized the opportunity for an infrastructure service that would help any company provide financial products for their customers.</p>
<p>Swap’s growth as of late has been impressive. Over the past year, it has seen its customer base expand by 300%. During that same timeframe, it has been consistently growing 30% per month and 7,500% year over year with profitable results in the third quarter, according to Swap CEO Douglas Storf. (Of course, we don’t know the base from which it grew, but the multiples are noteworthy).</p>
<p>“We’ve demonstrated product-market fit and are helping more and more companies embed finance offerings into their products,” Storf said.</p>
<p>Swap operates in its home country of Brazil and is looking to use its capital to expand the use cases it serves there. The company aims to specialize by segment from a market and a technological perspective.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We have always sought to be a fully integrated solution that truly allows companies to launch their fintechs quickly and efficiently,” said Storf. “Rather than being just a card processor, we specialized in providing the full solution to specific segments, being at the same time their bin sponsor, their card processor, their partner bank and providing all the core infrastructure to make them operational.”</p>
<p>The CEO says that full-service approach sets Swap apart from other BaaS companies in the market. The company also has a strategy around solving the pains of specific segments. For example, it launched Multiflex in early 2021, an offering aimed at flexible benefits companies and in September 2021, the Swap Credit platform, aimed at companies in that segment. In short, the company aims to be “LatAm’s fintech factory.”</p>
<p>It is currently working with 15 customers such as Swile, Portão 3, Z1, BMP Money Plus and A55.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Storf notes that its customers are expanding to other Latin American countries so it will be a natural evolution to grow into new markets outside of Brazil.</p>
<p>Swap started 2021 with 27 employees and today it has 60 employees. It expects to double that number in 2022 with its new capital hiring across product development, operations and sales.</p>
<p>Tiger Global Partner Alex Cook notes that the number of fintech companies and use cases in Latin America has “increased dramatically, lowering costs and improving experiences for consumers and businesses.”</p>
<p>“We are thrilled to partner with Doug, Ury, and the Swap team as they build a modern card issuing and banking infrastructure platform for the next generation of financial services companies in Brazil,” he wrote via email.</p>
<p>The latest financing marks Global Founder Capital’s third time investing in Swap. Says Partner Fabricio Pettená: “Swap has completely reinvented banking as a service in Brazil, going beyond card acceptance and into credit and vertical solutions.”</p>
<p>Bruno Yoshimura, general partner and co-founder of ONEVC points out that Swap today has two major products: card as a service and infrastructure for credit.</p>
<p>“Now, they plan to listen to their customers&#8217; needs to develop the other building blocks,” he said. “With three former CTOs in the core team, I believe they have the right DNA to build AWS for fintechs in Latam.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tiger-global-leads-25m-investment-into-swap-which-aims-to-be-latams-fintech-factory/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mark Zuckerberg takes thinly veiled shots at Apple for &#8216;stifling innovation&#8217; via its platform policies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/mark-zuckerberg-takes-thinly-veiled-shots-at-apple-for-stifling-innovation-via-its-platform-policies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/mark-zuckerberg-takes-thinly-veiled-shots-at-apple-for-stifling-innovation-via-its-platform-policies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook-connect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook (aka &#8220;Meta&#8221;) CEO Mark Zuckerberg today took several thinly veiled shots at Apple and the overall app ecosystem when detailing his plans for the metaverse during today&#8217;s keynote speech at the company&#8217;s Facebook Connect 2021 event. Specifically, he called out app platforms and their associated fees for &#8220;stifling innovation,&#8221; while simultaneously justifying Facebook&#8217;s plans [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-changes-its-corporate-branding-to-meta/">aka &#8220;Meta&#8221;</a>) CEO Mark Zuckerberg today took several thinly veiled shots at Apple and the overall app ecosystem when detailing his plans for the metaverse during today&#8217;s keynote speech at the company&#8217;s Facebook Connect 2021 event. Specifically, he called out app platforms and their associated fees for &#8220;stifling innovation,&#8221; while simultaneously justifying Facebook&#8217;s plans to keep some of its own fees higher as it further invests in its burgeoning VR ecosystem and its Oculus Quest Store.</p>
<p>His statements follow Apple&#8217;s recent app privacy changes that have <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/facebook-q-3-earnings-investors-eye-fallout-from-whistleblower-apple-privacy-changes-175203219.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">taken a toll on</a> Facebook&#8217;s ads business. With the release of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/apples-app-tracking-transparency-feature-has-arrived-heres-what-you-need-to-know/">App Tracking Transparency</a>, Apple now allows consumers to stop apps from tracking them across other apps and websites. But this change has dragged down Facebook&#8217;s revenue, the company has admitted.</p>
<p>Now, Facebook sees the potential in building out its own app platform with Oculus to create a new stream of revenue &#8212; one where it becomes the platform that profits, instead of the developer having to pay the commissions. And one where its business can&#8217;t be destroyed at the whims of another company&#8217;s shift in strategy.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225882" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Zuckerberg acknowledged that it&#8217;s time to make this change, saying that he&#8217;s learned in recent years that &#8220;building products isn&#8217;t enough.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We also need to help build ecosystems so that millions of people can have a stake in the future and can be rewarded for their work and benefit as the tide rises &#8212; not just as consumers, but as creators and developers,&#8221; he said. &#8220;This period has also been humbling, because as big of a company as we are, we&#8217;ve also learned what it is like to build for other platforms. And living under their rules has profoundly shaped my views on the tech industry,&#8221; Zuckerberg continued.</p>
<p>&#8220;Most of all, I&#8217;ve come to believe that the lack of choice and high fees are stifling innovation, stopping people from building new things and holding back the entire internet economy,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>These comments seem directly pointed at Apple and Google, on whose platforms Facebook&#8217;s core products largely reside. Facebook has to pay fees on in-app purchases to the app stores &#8212; including when users subscribe to creators, buy badges or tip streamers directly, for example. While both Apple and Google have been bringing their commissions down for smaller businesses, media providers and subscription apps, the standard split is still 70/30 (platform/developer).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>App Store rules have also prevented Facebook from building out other products where it could have increased revenues &#8212; as with its newer gaming service.</p>
<p>The company <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/7/21358355/facebook-apple-app-store-policies-comments-facebook-gaming-ios" target="_blank" rel="noopener">slammed Apple&#8217;s policies last year</a> as it launched Facebook Gaming on iOS without games, for example. Apple doesn&#8217;t allow apps that contain other apps or games, as that would cut into its own ability to generate revenues from third-party developers. So instead of being able to play mini-games as on Android, Facebook Gaming iOS users could only watch streams.</p>
<p>However, the real concern for Facebook&#8217;s future is one where its ad revenues are threatened by platform policy changes out of its control.</p>
<p>Those revenues over the years have allowed Facebook to invest in other sectors, in addition to keeping its apps free, Zuckerberg noted.</p>
<p>&#8220;We offer our creator and commerce tools either at cost or with modest fees to enable as much creation and commerce as possible. And it&#8217;s worked. Billions of people love our products,&#8221; he touted. &#8220;We have hundreds of millions of businesses on our platform.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company now plans to take the same approach to build its metaverse ecosystem &#8212; by either subsidizing devices or selling them at cost, to make them more broadly available to consumers, Zuckerberg said. And unlike with Apple&#8217;s App Store, Facebook says it plans to support sideloading and linking to PCs to provide consumers and developers with choice, instead of locking them into its platform. (Of course, many developers will choose to launch on the Quest Store for discovery&#8217;s sake, which is why Facebook knows it can make this promise.)</p>
<p>He also said that Facebook would keep developer and creator service fees low, when possible. However, Zuckerberg &#8212; sketching out the company&#8217;s next business model &#8212; warned that won&#8217;t always be the case. Given the size of its investment in this new ecosystem, some fees would remain higher, he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;To keep investing in this future, we&#8217;ll need to keep some fees higher for some period to make sure that we don&#8217;t lose too much money on this program overall,&#8221; Zuckerberg explained. &#8220;After all, while a growing number of developers are already profitable, we expect to invest many billions of dollars for years to come before the metaverse reaches scale. Our hope, though, is that if we all work at it that within the next decade, the metaverse will reach a billion people, host hundreds of billions of dollars of digital commerce, and support jobs for millions of creators and developers.&#8221;</p>
<p>In other words, Facebook&#8217;s plan is to become more like Apple by tapping into developer revenues at scale and making its own rules.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/mark-zuckerberg-takes-thinly-veiled-shots-at-apple-for-stifling-innovation-via-its-platform-policies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225882</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequoia provides founders with key insights on launching, building and fundraising</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/sequoia-provides-founders-with-key-insights-on-launching-building-and-fundraising/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/sequoia-provides-founders-with-key-insights-on-launching-building-and-fundraising/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neesha A. Tambe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:45:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sequoia hosted a private, sponsored AMA for founders in Startup Battlefield and Startup Alley at the virtual Disrupt SF last month. Stephanie Zhan, Konstantine Buhler, George Robson and Josephine Chen shared some key insights and best practices. It was good stuff, so we wanted to share. We took some highlights from the session and chatted [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sequoia hosted a private, sponsored AMA for founders in Startup Battlefield and Startup Alley at the virtual Disrupt SF last month. Stephanie Zhan, Konstantine Buhler, George Robson and Josephine Chen shared some key insights and best practices. It was good stuff, so we wanted to share. We took some highlights from the session and chatted with a couple more partners to dive deeper into what founders need to know &#8212; how to ask for help, fundraising principles, how to build company culture and more.</span></p>
<p><b>Fundraising requires the stars to align</b></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’ve sat on both the founder side and investor side, what is one thing you wish you could have told your founder self</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">?</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225808" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shaun Maguire: I think most founders don’t appreciate how random fundraising is. Having sat in the room for five years now, it really requires the stars to align for an investment to happen. It requires finding a champion &#8212; in order to find a champion you have to find them at the right time. Maybe they have done two other investments this year. They feel too busy. They take on board seats and don’t have the bandwidth when you meet with them. Or you’re catching them on a bad day. Or it’s an industry they had invested in previously with a company that didn’t work. There is a lot of randomness.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The firm can feel like their investment pace is too high because they invested in three companies the week prior. So now the week you’re pitching them, they feel like the pace is too high, so the bar is now higher than it was a week ago. Ninety percent of the time it’s randomness and it’s not you. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What are things a founder can do to prepare for when the stars align?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shaun Maguire: If someone is going to join the board of your company, it’s a long-term partnership. It’s a 10+ year commitment. A lot of founders think they should only meet VCs in the fundraising process. They want to hold the meetings when they have the deck ready. Of the 15 boards I’ve been on, I’ve only invested in one founder, where I met them within the month of the investment process. All of the others, I met them three months before they came to raise. Personally, if I’m entering into a long-term relationship, I want to know them as a person and get longitudinal data. I want to see how they have been performing over time. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What would you say to founders who are not “typical founders”? How do you break through the pattern-matching framework some VCs have in their head?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shaun Maguire: Identify your high-level ambition to start a company, and then work backwards. If that’s my goal, what are the stepping stones I need to get there? I personally had a 1.0 GPA in high school and had to recover from that. I thought a lot about stepping stone paths. I wanted to go to a good college&#8230;so I went to community college first. I thought about: How am I going to stand out? I need to go do something crazy and stand out. I need to do something different. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reverse engineer it. Are there any immediate things I, as a founder, can do that are stepping stones to the bigger goals. Second piece, be really persistent. And it’s not what people want to hear. With Escape Dynamics [Shaun Maguire’s first company], we had to pitch 100 investors and eventually found one that would work with us. </span></p>
<p><b>Tactics to prepare for fundraising</b></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s a challenge to raise. What do you do when you don’t have a lead and you need a lead? How do you cross that bridge?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stephanie Zhan: Treat fundraising as you would recruiting critical team members. It’s invaluable to find the right partner, especially at the very beginning of the company. I like to think of it as a compass: A small degree change in the direction of your company in month one has an outsized impact on where you will be 10 years out. If it&#8217;s a challenge to raise and you don&#8217;t have a lead investor, I would evaluate whether additional capital is absolutely necessary, and if so, how much the company truly needs. The earliest rounds are the most expensive dilution for a founder — and will only compound over the years — so it’s important to raise as much as the company requires to grow and strive for a lead investor that can have a transformative impact over the long term. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">When should a founder turn down an investment even if they are running out of runway?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stephanie Zhan: The value of having the right partners — a strong brand and network, a team who rolls up their sleeves alongside you, and someone who cares about you as a person and founder — compounds over time and provides incredible signaling for your company. The reverse is also true. There are lots of options for capital these days; it&#8217;s up to founders to recognize the ones who offer real value, not valuation. Always ask yourself: Can this partner truly add value and help me bend the arc of my company? Cut through the marketing noise by talking to founders who have worked with that partner over years. Ask about the good and bad times, as well as the successful and less successful outcomes  — this will help you truly discern the differences among investors. Think about which partner you want by your side for the next 10-20 years and who you want to turn to during the highs and lows of your company-building journey. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What recommendations do you have for founders who are on the cutting edge of things that investors may not know how to invest in or may not understand the space of?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shaun Maguire: It’s really important to understand the [min rule decision making] psychology and that’s what you’re dealing with as a founder because it can change the tactics that you use. It’s hard when you are doing something cutting edge because there is less pattern matching for everyone in the partnership. First you need to find a champion and then you need to find the most negative person in the firm and try to win them over. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">How does a previous startup failure factor into your decision to invest in a new company?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">George Robson: A startup can fail for a variety of reasons, so we check any bias at the door by decoupling the success or failure of a business from the quality of the team. When we partner with a second-time founder, we talk a lot about their former experience to gauge their ability to reflect and carry those learnings into a new chapter. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What are other success markers outside revenue that you look for in early-stage startups?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stephanie Zhan: We look for founders who are building companies that will become generational and shape history. The most important thing we look for is a special team: one that deeply understands the problem they are solving, has a unique and compelling insight that’s shaped their way of going about the problem, has grit and ambition to take them through the long haul, and has commercial instincts to understand how a compelling product can be over time to become an enduring, independent business.</span></p>
<p><b>Running a successful startup</b></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What&#8217;s one of the hardest parts for founders building companies in the early stage?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">George Robson: Early-stage startups have an abundance of choice, yet they also have finite resources. It’s important for founders to prioritize in a thoughtful way. For example, when looking to expand internationally, focus on the key questions that matter, such as: ‘who are your customers?’ and ‘where can you build a repeatable GTM function?</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">When should a founder talk to an investor about issues/red flags/problems?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">George Robson: Similar to other relationships in life, the connection between an investor and founder is built on trust. Founders should be transparent with their investors and feel safe flagging issues early so they can help troubleshoot. If we&#8217;ve done our job well, nothing we discuss at a board meeting should ever be a surprise, as we&#8217;re supporting our founders to build their businesses everyday.  </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">At what point does someone deserve a co-founder title?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jess Lee: There’s no ‘one path’ to finding or becoming a co-founder. I was retroactively made a co-founder of Polyvore as the founders felt I deserved it based on my contributions — and that’s always meant a lot to me. I was technically the first hire and not there from day one, but I acted like an owner, poured my heart and soul into the work and helped shape the culture. In the end, I was also just lucky that Pasha, Guangwei and Jianing were generous people who went out of their way to give me the title and even some of their own shares. I&#8217;ll always be grateful for that.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Culture comes up a lot. Thoughts? What are the two main tactical steps companies can take to build a strong culture in the beginning?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">George Robson: Don&#8217;t compromise on people. Put culture first at your company and codify your culture early.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jess Lee: It’s never too early to define your culture. In fact, in our Company Design Program — which gives early-stage founders the learnings and community to build an enduring company — we provide founders with a framework for culture: values → behaviors → stories. Values are the fundamental beliefs and guiding principles of the company, ideally stated in a pithy, memorable way. Behaviors are how you want to see people act, based on those values. Stories are the real-life anecdotes of when your company lived those values. The stories are especially important, since that&#8217;s what people remember. They help make the company culture tangible and easier to operationalize. As an example, people know the story of the Airbnb founders selling cereal to make ends meet or of Jeff Bezos using doors for desks, which embody their values of entrepreneurship and frugality, respectively.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/sequoia-provides-founders-with-key-insights-on-launching-building-and-fundraising/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225808</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atlys raises $4.25M to make visa applications faster and easier</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/atlys-raises-4-25m-to-make-visa-applications-faster-and-easier/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/atlys-raises-4-25m-to-make-visa-applications-faster-and-easier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlys]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[International travel is slowly opening up again, but that also means business and leisure travelers alike will once again have to think about visa restrictions as they take to the air. Nobody has ever enjoyed the process of applying for a visa, but Atlys promises to take the hassle out of the process. The company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">International travel is slowly opening up again, but that also means business and leisure travelers alike will once again have to think about visa restrictions as they take to the air. Nobody has ever enjoyed the process of applying for a visa, but <a href="https://www.atlys.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atlys</a> promises to take the hassle out of the process. The company today announced that it has raised a $4.25 million seed funding round led by Andreessen Horowitz. Pinterest co-founders Ben Silbermann and Evan Sharp also participated in this round, together with The Chainsmokers’ Mantis VC (yes, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Io0fBr1XBUA">those Chainsmokers</a>), Long Journey Ventures, South Park Commons Fund and Ari Emanuel’s Endeavor.</p>
<p>Atlys argues that it can take travelers up to 13 hours to work through the visa process for various countries &#8212; and that&#8217;s without trying to figure out the ever-changing COVID testing and vaccination requirements. While most business travelers work with agencies that speed up this process by quite a bit, especially for repeat applications, Atlys promises to bring the process down to five minutes.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2225848" style="width: 210px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225848" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-medium wp-image-2225848" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?w=200" alt="Mohak Nahta, Founder of Atlys" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg 3268w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=768,1151 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=454,680 454w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=1025,1536 1025w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=1367,2048 1367w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2225848" class="wp-caption-text">Atlys founder Mohak Nahta. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Atlys</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225750" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Using the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/atlys-simplify-travel/id1514036839" target="_blank" rel="noopener">company&#8217;s iPhone app</a>, travelers answer a few questions about their travels (where you are, where you are going, why you are traveling, etc.) and scan their documents. There are some smart integrations here, too, with the ability to take passport photos and then pick them up at Walgreens (or get delivery) or to ask your manager for a letter of employment signed through DocuSign.</p>
<p>Pricing depends on where you are and where you are going, but it tops out at about $50.</p>
<p>The company was founded by Mohak Nahta, who came to the U.S. as an immigrant himself. &#8220;I am thrilled to have such an incredible group of investors supporting <span class="il">Atlys</span> and our mission,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It is with their invaluable experience and guidance that will propel us further in our quest to simplify travel and create a seamless process for all.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company plans to use the new funding to build out its team and expand its coverage across more country pairs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;One of the things we look for in founders is &#8216;founder-product fit&#8217;, meaning does the founder have a unique insight into the market or problem they are trying to solve? As an immigrant myself, I immediately appreciated how deeply and personally Mohak also understood the cumbersome visa process, and how he was leveraging his insights to build Atlys,&#8221; said Sriram Krishnan, general partner at Andreessen Horowitz. &#8220;The magic of Atlys lies in its ability to connect many disparate systems behind the scenes, while offering a simple, streamlined end-customer experience.&#8221;</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u7LPtGjiOMQ?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MEi3P6xCyy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/the-chainsmokers-just-closed-their-debut-venture-fund-mantis-with-35-million/">The Chainsmokers just closed their debut venture fund, Mantis, with $35 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Chainsmokers just closed their debut venture fund, Mantis, with $35 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/the-chainsmokers-just-closed-their-debut-venture-fund-mantis-with-35-million/embed/#?secret=MEi3P6xCyy" data-secret="MEi3P6xCyy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/atlys-raises-4-25m-to-make-visa-applications-faster-and-easier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225750</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
