<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:24:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Visier raises $125M at a $1B valuation for its big-data approach to HR analytics and planning</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/visier-raises-125m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-its-big-data-approach-to-hr-analytics-and-planning/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/visier-raises-125m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-its-big-data-approach-to-hr-analytics-and-planning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The world of work has changed massively in the last year, and with it a rush of startups have emerged with new technology and approaches to improve how it is shaped, and specifically how human resources departments do their jobs. In the latest chapter, Visier, a Canadian startup that has built a big-data engine to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The world of work has changed massively in the last year, and with it a rush of startups have emerged with new technology and approaches to improve how it is shaped, and specifically how human resources departments do their jobs. In the latest chapter, <a href="https://www.visier.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Visier</a>, a Canadian startup that has built a big-data engine to ingest and analyze information from disparate human resources and related applications to develop more accurate profiles of people and departments &#8212; useful when considering remuneration, promotions, and wider hiring budgets &#8212; has raised $125 million (USD), a Series E that the company confirms now values it at $1 billion.</p>
<p>The funding comes on the heels of the company seeing massive growth in particular in the last year, with companies scrambling more than ever before, in a new world of more hybrid and remote work, to get a better grip on how and what teams and individuals are doing. Visier said it now processes employee records for 8,000 customers, large and high-profile enterprises like Adobe, BASF, Bridgestone, Electronic Arts, McKesson, Merck KGaA and Uber that collectively represent some 12 million individual users across 75 countries.</p>
<p>New backer Goldman Sachs Asset Management is leading the round, with previous investors Sorenson Capital, Foundation Capital, Summit Partners, and Adams Street Partners also participating. Visier &#8212; pronounced &#8220;busier,&#8221; which co-founder and chairman John Schwarz joked you are <em>not</em> supposed to be when using its product &#8212; has now raised just under $220 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As Schwarz described it to me, the challenge that Visier is addressing is that while everyone uses HR management tools like Workday, Success Factors, any number of payroll applications and more &#8212; on average 20 applications per department, he said &#8212; to chart a lot of basics of how an employee works day to day or month to month, a lot of that data remains in silos and so it&#8217;s hard to get a &#8220;360&#8221; view based on all of it, and that&#8217;s before considering how to take that information and benchmark it against other information outside the business.</p>
<p>The solution that Visier provides to address that is a big-data engine that it has built that can connect to any and all of those apps, ingest the data contained in it, match it up to provide visualizations of the current state of things, and increasingly also predictive insights. Today, this is done typically for HR departments, but this has applicability to managers, finance departments and really the employees themselves.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the future we want to help everyone understand the policy today, which impacts the outcome tomorrow,&#8221; he said in an interview.</p>
<p class="p1">The move to build big data analytics targeting particular areas of an organization has been an interesting trend that has played out in other departments too such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/dooly-raises-80m-more-for-its-ai-tools-to-help-salespeople-manage-their-busywork/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sales</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/11/12/tidemarks-latest-release-uses-big-data-to-help-finance-look-forward-instead-of-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">finance</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/quantexa-raises-64-7m-to-bring-big-data-intelligence-to-risk-analysis-and-investigations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">risk analysis</a> and other areas. The idea here is not unlike what data scientists have been working on for years with wider analytics questions: tapping troves of data from disparate sources to order it better, match it up with each other, to provide insight into wider trends and activities within an organization.</p>
<p class="p1">As data science becomes more democratized &#8212; and thanks to advances in no-code and low-code tooling, turned into tools that even non-technical people can implement and use &#8212; we will likely see many more use cases where this idea gets applied. After all, data is the new oil, but unlike actual oil, we seem to be supplied with an endless amount of it these days.</p>
<p class="p1">And yes, we&#8217;ve seen a real rush of HR tools come to the market in recent years &#8212; and see a lot of funding in the current climate as their businesses see customer interest rise &#8212; they include HR platforms like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/hibob-raises-70m-on-a-500m-valuation-for-its-new-take-on-hr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hibob</a>, HR aimed at particular verticals like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/personio-raises-125m-on-a-1-7b-valuation-for-an-hr-platform-targeting-smes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Personio</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/factorial-raises-16m-to-take-on-the-hr-world-with-a-platform-for-smbs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Factorial</a>, or for distributed workforces like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/oyster-an-hr-platform-for-distributed-workforces-snaps-up-50m-on-a-475m-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Oyster</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/remote-raises-35m-to-help-orgs-with-global-workforce-payroll-benefits-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Remote</a>, or those that are building supercharged org-charts like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/charthop-raises-35m-for-its-internal-org-chart-and-people-analytics-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ChartHop</a>.</p>
<p class="p1">But Visier believes that there are no big-data players looking not to be primary-source repositories of information but big data integrators from other platforms. Schwarz notes that in most cases, the &#8220;competition&#8221; will be custom-made implementations built by systems integrators using Tableau or something similar but not the same as what it provides in terms of real-time analytics.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s all about using data from other sources,&#8221; he said, pointing out that it&#8217;s telling that Workday tried to build something like what Visier provides, but that more than half of Visier&#8217;s customers also use Workday (meaning whatever is there is not quite doing the trick).</p>
<p>“Access to information about employees and the health of an organization has never been more critical,” said Holger Staude, managing director within Goldman Sachs Asset Management. “We’re excited to partner with Visier at this pivotal moment and support the company’s continued growth.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/visier-raises-125m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-its-big-data-approach-to-hr-analytics-and-planning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171330</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gympass, the corporate wellness unicorn, raises a $220M series E</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gympass-the-corporate-wellness-unicorn-raises-a-220m-series-e/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gympass-the-corporate-wellness-unicorn-raises-a-220m-series-e/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marcella McCarthy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argentina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[classpass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harvard Business School]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaszek Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[McKinsey & Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pricewaterhousecoopers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2170357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gympass, the exercise and corporate wellness unicorn that originated in Brazil, today announced a $220 million Series E. The company has seen tremendous growth in the last few months, as more and more people are vaccinated and flocking back to the gym. Gympass is like ClassPass, but on steroids. However, unlike ClassPass’ BTC model, Gympass [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gympass, the exercise and corporate wellness unicorn that originated in Brazil, today announced a $220 million Series E. The company has seen tremendous growth in the last few months, as more and more people are vaccinated and flocking back to the gym.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://site.gympass.com/web/us">Gympass</a> is like ClassPass, but on steroids. However, unlike ClassPass’ BTC model, Gympass partners with employers who then pay a flat fee for the platform (an app) which then allows their employees to choose from several wellbeing plans that give them access to myriad in-person gyms and studios, and a directory of health apps, such as Calm. The offerings are broken up into the following categories: physical health, emotional health, nutrition and sleep.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the company, in May, Gympass saw a record 4 million monthly check-ins across its network of more than 50,000 global partners. In fact, for some of the partners, usage hit above pre-COVID levels. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Between increased anxiety rates and documented weight gain during the pandemic, it’s clear that people are eager to get active again with the hopes of improving their mental health and their waistlines.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GymPass is the brainchild of Cesar Carvalho, a former McKinsey &amp; Company consultant in Brazil who was always on the road and yearned for a corporate wellness product that would comply with his hectic work schedule.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6ZiSW1GSFD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1/">The Tonal EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Tonal EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1/embed/#?secret=6ZiSW1GSFD" data-secret="6ZiSW1GSFD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Some days I worked from home, other days I worked from the office, and then there was the time I was traveling. I could never go to the gym in one place,” Carvalho told TechCrunch. “I realized that my needs were the same as others,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He decided to pursue his business idea while he was at Harvard Business School.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I’m one of those crazy entrepreneurs that drops out of their MBA to start a company, but looking back now, it worked out okay,” he said, later telling TechCrunch that Gympass is now in Brazil, Mexico, Chile, Argentina, the U.S., Germany, Spain, Italy, Ireland, and the U.K. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since its launch in São Paulo in 2012, the company achieved product-market fit fairly quickly, and its growth and expansion have been largely organic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Originally, Gympass was a BTC concept, and one of its first clients was an executive at PricewaterhouseCoopers in Brazil. He liked the product so much that he eventually said to Carvalho, “Can’t I communicate this to my 5000 employees in all the cities where we have offices in Brazil?” With that question &#8211; and offer &#8211; Carvalho saw the need to pivot and build a B2B company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After only three years in Brazil, one of his biggest Brazilian clients asked Carvalho to expand to Mexico, because his company had a large presence there and he wanted to offer Gympass to its employees. And so follows most of the expansion stories. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We expanded to Spain, because we worked with a Spanish bank in Mexico, and they wanted their employees in Spain to have access to our product,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This round, which doubles the company’s valuation to $2.2 billion, includes participation from SoftBank, General Atlantic, More Strategic Ventures, Kaszek Ventures and Valor. Carvalho plans to use the money to grow the company in the U.S., expand its offerings, and work on making the tech smarter. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We want [the app] to be able to recommend the best partners for your complete well-being journey based on your workout patterns, for example: ‘This is the best meditation app for you to use with your workout profile,’” Carvalho said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5XKoCEGyTH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-origin/">How a homegrown experiment became one of the fastest-growing companies in fitness tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How a homegrown experiment became one of the fastest-growing companies in fitness tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-origin/embed/#?secret=5XKoCEGyTH" data-secret="5XKoCEGyTH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gympass-the-corporate-wellness-unicorn-raises-a-220m-series-e/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2170357</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>4G Clinical&#8217;s clinical trial management software attracts over $200M in new funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/4g-clinicals-clinical-trial-management-software-attracts-over-200m-in-new-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/4g-clinicals-clinical-trial-management-software-attracts-over-200m-in-new-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clinical trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic significantly changed how we do medical research, and now companies are trying to figure out what trends will stay and which ones will go. One that 4G Clinical is hoping will survive the pandemic is a need for speed and flexibility in therapeutics trials.  4G Clinical creates software to run the back-end of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic significantly changed how we do medical research, and now companies are trying to figure out what trends will stay and which ones will go. One that 4G Clinical is hoping will survive the pandemic is a need for speed and flexibility in therapeutics trials. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">4G Clinical creates software to run the back-end of a clinical trial. That means randomizing patients into treatment and placebo groups, locating medicines and placebos, keeping the supply of those medicines stocked, and, at least during the pandemic, delivering those medicines to patients. All of these tasks fall under the umbrella of Randomized Trial Supply Management, or RTSM for short. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Specifically, 4G Clinical&#8217;s software, called Prancer, uses natural language processing to take specific requirements needed to manage a clinical trial, which are often written in long, complex documents, and configures them into a platform.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fastest the company has been able to move from a phone call to the first dose in a clinical trial was 6 days – a sprint that created the software needed for a COVID-19 study during the pandemic. That was an exceptionally fast case, but in general, 4G Clinical says it can beat standard timelines by considerable margins.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Most vendors in the world would say that they are probably, you know, between 10 and 16 weeks from, you know, from the kicking off a study until they can dose a patient,” says Dave Kelleher, a company co-founder. “Our typical timeline is generally four to six weeks post spec signature.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Generally, large pharmaceutical companies are capable of creating these trial management systems internally. Small companies, however, may not have the capability to do so. 4G Clinical goal is to provide a service that can be of use to both. 4G Clinical has currently designed systems for over 230 companies – though the company would not disclose the specific trials in which its systems are being used. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Y1OUCuhR4C"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/4-strategies-for-building-a-digital-health-unicorn/">4 strategies for building a digital health unicorn</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 strategies for building a digital health unicorn&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/4-strategies-for-building-a-digital-health-unicorn/embed/#?secret=Y1OUCuhR4C" data-secret="Y1OUCuhR4C" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">4G clinical is also announcing over $200 million in a growth equity round led by Goldman Sachs. Before Goldman, the primary investment came from Boston-based Schooner Capital and First Analysis, a VC firm out of Chicago. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kelleher declined to say what the plans for the round were, other than company has plans to pursue more go-to-market strategies and R&amp;D, and ultimately aims to “take up as much air” in the eClinical and RTSM space as possible. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The eClinical market is expected to reach about </span><a href="https://www.gminsights.com/pressrelease/eclinical-solutions-market"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$14.7 billion by 2027</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. RTSM made up about 17 percent of market share in 2020. With the complexity of clinical trials increasing, and the number of trials growing – even after COVID-19 related issues shut many trials down in 2020 – there may be room for more growth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before COVID-19, there was evidence that the amount of clinical trials had </span><a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/resources/trends"><span style="font-weight: 400;">steadily been increasing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. In 2000, there were 2,119 clinical trials registered at Clinicaltrials.gov. By 2010, 100,208, and by 2020, 362,532 registered by the end of the year (that includes massive slowdowns created by the pandemic for non-COVID research). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Within that landscape, there is some evidence that sponsors of clinical trials are using more external applications to manage those clinical trials. Of 500 clinical operations professionals respondents </span><a href="https://www.veeva.com/eu/resources/clinical-operations-survey-report-2020/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">surveyed</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by Veeva (another eClinical company, keep in mind) found that 63 percent were using an RTSM system, up from about 43 percent in 2017. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">4G Clinical, generally, is looking to benefit from the increased public attention to the clinical trials process, and the flexibility that the pandemic has created for sponsors to get creative with clinical trial designs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic did encourage some innovation in this regard. Take, for example, the World Health Organization’s SOLIDARITY trial, which used an adaptive trial design in which multiple drugs could be tested at once. Drugs that showed no promise mid-way through the trial could be dropped (as hydroxychloroquine was in June 2020). The adaptive part, in short, allows for mid-trial tweaks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s not the traditional design of the gold-standard randomized controlled clinical trial, but it did glean a significant amount of knowledge in a short period of time. </span><a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMe2034294"><span style="font-weight: 400;">After seven months</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, three of four drugs tested showed no effect on mortality, whereas the fifth remdesivir, showed some limited promise. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9o43Rd0WAf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/the-health-data-transparency-movement-is-birthing-a-new-generation-of-startups/">The health data transparency movement is birthing a new generation of startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The health data transparency movement is birthing a new generation of startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/the-health-data-transparency-movement-is-birthing-a-new-generation-of-startups/embed/#?secret=9o43Rd0WAf" data-secret="9o43Rd0WAf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adaptive trial designs weren’t unheard of before the pandemic – the FDA had actually released guidance on adaptive clinical trials </span><a href="https://www.fda.gov/media/78495/download"><span style="font-weight: 400;">in 2019</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But the post-pandemic landscape might encourage more flexibility in this regard, and with it, increase a need for software that can be tweaked to accommodate such changes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think that we saw some regulatory hurdles reduced as part of this process that allows for more creativity in study design,” says Kelleher. “Probably the most important thing for us is our flexibility, we can make changes to studies very rapidly – to live studies.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">4G Clinical and other RTSM software like it, are looking to hone tools that already exist within clinical trials – specifically software used to actually run them. It’s an area of research that the team itself has both a personal stake in, and strong industry knowledge. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kelleher was diagnosed with Multiple Sclerosis at the age of 23 (a disease to which there is still no definitive cure), and previously founded the Portland-based ACME business consulting. His co-founder Ed Tourtellotte, lost his wife to breast cancer around the same time. Neither have a background in pharmacology, but rather, the team is tackling drug development through streamlining clinical trial software. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By contrast, other companies aim to streamline clinical trial processes through A.I-based drug target identification, an especially hype-induced area of the space in which investment quadrupled to </span><a href="https://aiindex.stanford.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/2021-AI-Index-Report_Master.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$13.9 billion between 2019 and 2020</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Clinical trial management software may seem more mundane, but it’s still an essential part of running Phase III and most Phase II studies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tourtellotte has designed bespoke software systems for major drug developers, including Pfizer’s Impala system (used in 80 percent of Pfizer’s clinical trials for the past 20 years, says Kelleher) and another system Trident, which was sold </span><a href="https://www.outsourcing-pharma.com/Article/2010/10/20/BioClinica-to-launch-game-changing-IVR-IWR-platform"><span style="font-weight: 400;">to Bioclinica in 2009</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (along with Tourtoulette’s company, Tourtellotte Solutions). Trident was </span><a href="https://www.genengnews.com/topics/drug-discovery/gsk-to-use-bioclinica-tool-to-manage-clinical-trials/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">utilized by GlaxoSmithKlein</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for clinical trials in 2010. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At this point, the company has declined to confirm a total amount of funding, but in 2020, revenue grew 110 percent with just ten percent of its portfolio focused on COVID-19 related projects. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8MCKO4ME4t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/does-early-stage-health-tech-need-more-patient-capital/">Does early-stage health tech need more &#8216;patient&#8217; capital?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Does early-stage health tech need more &#8216;patient&#8217; capital?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/does-early-stage-health-tech-need-more-patient-capital/embed/#?secret=8MCKO4ME4t" data-secret="8MCKO4ME4t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/4g-clinicals-clinical-trial-management-software-attracts-over-200m-in-new-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171334</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alphabet’s Wing launches OpenSky drone airspace authorization app in US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/alphabets-wing-launches-opensky-drone-airspace-authorization-app-in-us/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/alphabets-wing-launches-opensky-drone-airspace-authorization-app-in-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FAA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I love testing drones. It’s a lot of fun, and a nice way to mix up my standard review cycle. But I’ve altogether given up on testing them around here. Granted, living in Queens, NY presents a unique combination of obstacles, including population density, two major international airports and a prison – but restrictions have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I love testing drones. It’s a lot of fun, and a nice way to mix up my standard review cycle. But I’ve altogether given up on testing them around here. Granted, living in Queens, NY presents a unique combination of obstacles, including population density, two major international airports and a prison – but restrictions have made it next to impossible to fly around here.</p>
<p>Knowing precisely where the nearest open airspace is can get tricky, particularly in large cities like New York. Today, Alphabet’s drone-delivery subsidiary Wing announced that it’s launching its OpenSky app in the U.S. on Google Play and the iOS App Store.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171186" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171186" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2171186" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/opensky.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="576" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171186" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Wing</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The app was launched in Australia back in 2019 for both hobbyist and commercial drone pilots, with help from the Civil Aviation Safety Authority (CASA). The U.S. version was created with input from the FAA for operation in Low Altitude Authorization and Notification Capability (LAANC) airspaces.</p>
<p>Using the app, drone operators can request approval to operate in spaces like those around areas, expediting a process that would traditionally take days or weeks to go through.</p>
<p>“Why is a drone delivery company investing in an operator app?” Wing asks rhetorically in a blog post. “Because with nearly two million registered drones in the U.S. already, regulatory compliance of all drones will allow them to share the sky safely. Moreover, compliance will ultimately expand the uses and benefits of drones &#8212; among them emergency response, commercial inspections and contactless delivery &#8212; to more people.”</p>
<p>The app is available for users in the U.S. starting today.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="y2ATBJL9ZX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/05/alphabets-wing-launches-opensky-a-safety-app-for-australian-drone-operators/">Alphabet&#8217;s Wing launches OpenSky, a safety app for Australian drone operators</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Alphabet&#8217;s Wing launches OpenSky, a safety app for Australian drone operators&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/05/alphabets-wing-launches-opensky-a-safety-app-for-australian-drone-operators/embed/#?secret=y2ATBJL9ZX" data-secret="y2ATBJL9ZX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/alphabets-wing-launches-opensky-drone-airspace-authorization-app-in-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171183</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Artisan home decor retailer The Citizenry raises $20M in Series B funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/artisan-home-decor-retailer-the-citizenry-raises-20m-in-series-b-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/artisan-home-decor-retailer-the-citizenry-raises-20m-in-series-b-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business model]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fair trade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[furniture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ikea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Williams-Sonoma]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2170401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Citizenry announced today that it raised $20 million in Series B funding in partnership with NextWorld Evergreen. A direct-to-consumer home decor retailer, The Citizenry works with artisans from around the world to produce limited-edition runs of handcrafted, hand-numbered home goods. In October, The Citizenry opened its first brick-and-mortar store in New York City, and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Citizenry announced today that it raised $20 million in Series B funding in partnership with NextWorld Evergreen. A direct-to-consumer home decor retailer, <a href="https://www.the-citizenry.com/">The Citizenry</a> works with artisans from around the world to produce limited-edition runs of handcrafted, hand-numbered home goods. In October, The Citizenry opened its first brick-and-mortar store in New York City, and with this round of funding, The Citizenry hopes to accelerate its development into a whole-home brand.</p>
<p>Co-Founder Rachel Bentley got her start at Bain &amp; Company, where she worked in strategy consulting in global supply chains.</p>
<p>&#8220;I saw a lot of the challenges that were coming as a result of that, tied to income inequality, human rights, and the environment,&#8221; Bentley told TechCrunch. &#8220;But I also saw the tremendous opportunity that connections of global supply chains can create to hopefully move communities forward.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Bentley and fellow co-founder Carly Nance, a brand strategist, noticed that there was a gap in the market for premium, thoughtfully crafted home goods. They took the leap to leave their corporate jobs to start The Citizenry with the aim to make a positive global impact and set more socially conscious standards for the home decor industry.</p>
<p>These are lofty goals, but Bentley&#8217;s experience in global supply chain strategy helped her develop a business model that prioritizes the fair treatment of workers.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2170637" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2170637" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2170637" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/4X6A9543-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/4X6A9543-1.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/4X6A9543-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/4X6A9543-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/4X6A9543-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/4X6A9543-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/4X6A9543-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/4X6A9543-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2170637" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> The Citizenry</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;One of the biggest challenges in working with artisan communities is that companies are there for one season, they place a large order, and their goal is to get a really high volume at a very low price,&#8221; Bentley says. &#8220;We came in and took the opposite approach. We tried to identify groups we saw a long term potential with, that we could partner with for the next ten, twenty, fifty years, to really help grow their businesses. Having sustainable income day in and day out, not just seasonally, is where you really start to see change happen.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Citizenry is a member of the World Fair Trade Organization (WFTO), and for over eighteen months, they&#8217;ve been going through the process to become fully verified through the WFTO&#8217;s Guarantee System. This means that the WFTO reviews every partner and conducts several day, in-person examinations of the artisans&#8217; working conditions. On average, The Citizenry pays its artisans double the local minimum wage.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2170638" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2170638" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2170638" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Citizenry_Headshots1764.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="463" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Citizenry_Headshots1764.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Citizenry_Headshots1764.jpg?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Citizenry_Headshots1764.jpg?resize=300,204 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Citizenry_Headshots1764.jpg?resize=768,523 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Citizenry_Headshots1764.jpg?resize=680,463 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Citizenry_Headshots1764.jpg?resize=1536,1046 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Citizenry_Headshots1764.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2170638" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> The Citizenry</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Social responsibility is much more important to our generation than previous generations,&#8221; Bentley said. &#8220;We want to feel good about the way a product was made, because we know we&#8217;re going to be living with the ramifications of how it was made, whether that&#8217;s environmentally or in terms of human rights.&#8221;</p>
<p>Bentley says that the rise in farm-to-table food shopping is indicative of consumers&#8217; transition in values. But spending an extra few dollars on organic produce isn&#8217;t quite the same as shelling out $695 for a Portuguese leather headboard. So, The Citizenry may not undercut retailers like IKEA, but their price points are often cheaper than luxury home competitors like Williams-Sonoma, for example. The fact that The Citizenry can even compete with larger retailers while paying livable wages to artisans is a testament to their business model.</p>
<p>Since closing its Series A in 2019, The Citizenry has grown sales over 200%, with repeat customers driving 45% of sales. Over the same period, the company has supported 3,000 global artisan jobs. With its Series B funding, The Citizenry hopes to expand its furniture section &#8212; the most shopped category on its website &#8212; and invest in expanding its brick-and-mortar business after its SoHo store&#8217;s successful launch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eZj5cOTcua"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/03/ethical-fashion-is-on-the-rise/">Ethical fashion is on the rise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ethical fashion is on the rise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/03/ethical-fashion-is-on-the-rise/embed/#?secret=eZj5cOTcua" data-secret="eZj5cOTcua" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/artisan-home-decor-retailer-the-citizenry-raises-20m-in-series-b-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2170401</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpaceX plans to use its Starlink internet on Starship orbital launch to demonstrate connection quality</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/spacex-plans-to-use-its-starlink-internet-on-starship-orbital-launch-to-demonstrate-connection-quality/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/spacex-plans-to-use-its-starlink-internet-on-starship-orbital-launch-to-demonstrate-connection-quality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 11:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starlink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX&#8217;s upcoming Starship orbital test flight could end up being a veritable smorgasbord of its technological capabilities, as the company has filed with the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to request approval to fly Starlink terminals on the spacecraft in order to &#8220;demonstrate high data rate communications&#8221; between the new launch system and the ground throughout [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SpaceX&#8217;s upcoming Starship orbital test flight could end up being a veritable smorgasbord of its technological capabilities, as the company has filed with the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to request approval to fly Starlink terminals on the spacecraft in order to &#8220;demonstrate high data rate communications&#8221; between the new launch system and the ground throughout the course of the trip to space and back.</p>
<p>SpaceX plans to show that its network of Starlink low-Earth orbit satellites can provide &#8220;unprecedented volumes of telemetry and enable communications during atmospheric reentry&#8221; even during the parts of the launch where communications signals are typically lost due to the presence of &#8220;ionized plasma&#8221; in the atmosphere during the re-entry phase (via <a href="https://twitter.com/nextspaceflight/status/1409743521964126213">Michael Baylor on Twitter</a>). If it works, it could provide better than ever live data for SpaceX during its test flight, which should help with the Starship and Super Heavy launch system&#8217;s development — and it could mean better, more spectacular views for those of us just watching from home via livestream, too.</p>
<p>Including Starlink as the communications method for telemetry and other communications during the launch is definitely a functional improvement for SpaceX if it works as described, but it&#8217;s even more of a flex for the company in terms of showing off Starlink&#8217;s capabilities. The FCC filing ones that the terminals to be installed on the spacecraft are basically just its existing consumer terminals with new exterior housings, so if it performs well that could attract the attention of more consumer broadband customers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Plus, SpaceX is also talking a lot about the capabilities of Starlink as a system to replace older, more distant geostationary satellites networks to provide things like connectivity on airplanes, on ships and in other in other transportation modals. Showing that it offers solid performance during a rocket launch is definitely going to encourage partners in those areas.</p>
<p>The filing does specific that its license to operate Starlink on Starship begin on August 1, which means either it&#8217;s planned for a launch after the one <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/spacex-aiming-for-first-orbital-test-launch-of-starship-in-july/">SpaceX President Gwynne Shotwell said the company is hoping to fly sometime in July</a>, or the date has already likely slipped to the following month.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nfhavgovjA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/spacex-aiming-for-first-orbital-test-launch-of-starship-in-july/">SpaceX aiming for first orbital test launch of Starship in July</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX aiming for first orbital test launch of Starship in July&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/spacex-aiming-for-first-orbital-test-launch-of-starship-in-july/embed/#?secret=nfhavgovjA" data-secret="nfhavgovjA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/spacex-plans-to-use-its-starlink-internet-on-starship-orbital-launch-to-demonstrate-connection-quality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171347</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Connected vehicle data startup Wejo partners with Microsoft, Palantir, Sompo</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/connected-vehicle-data-startup-wejo-partners-with-microsoft-palantir-sompo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/connected-vehicle-data-startup-wejo-partners-with-microsoft-palantir-sompo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 11:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connected vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palantir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SOMPO Holdings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wejo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171274</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Connected vehicle data startup Wejo has announced partnerships with Microsoft, Palantir and Sompo Holdings to improve its ability to collect, store and analyze data from millions of connected vehicles around the world.  This follows the GM-backed startup’s announcement that it would be going public by merging with a special purpose acquisition company, Virtuoso Acquisition Corp., [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Connected vehicle data startup Wejo has announced partnerships with Microsoft, Palantir and Sompo Holdings to improve its ability to collect, store and analyze data from millions of connected vehicles around the world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This follows the GM-backed startup’s </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/28/gm-palantir-backed-wejo-to-go-public-via-spac/?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAB15j4_LLIgYipyT2vQvTXTKPis2yUVqj62qrz6u4mz0arn1auKNqwFb52kxhKtezYBd8s3W18C1p8Oia9zphszONZf9ao4dOKumFAkS1vehge_TMlAvQ6y9ibvaFaAYvFniAQ5QAs3Xh1MUF9IBavxqZsDlr4sCtErDV6xv6vzo"><span style="font-weight: 400;">announcement that it would be going public by merging with a special purpose acquisition company</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Virtuoso Acquisition Corp., which is expected to close later this year. A $25 million commitment from Microsoft and Sompo, combined with already-committed investors GM and Palantir, bring Wejo’s total PIPE financing to $125 million. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palantir has been a previous strategic investor in Wejo. In 2019, the software developer launched a Japanese joint venture with insurance provider Sompo. Now this venture’s partnership with Wejo will give the startup the chance to collect connected vehicle data in Japan, and perhaps the greater Asia-Pacific region. The company already has some live vehicles in Korea, but 95% of its data comes from the U.S., according to Richard Barlow, Wejo’s founder and CEO. Sompo will analyze Wejo’s connected vehicle data using the </span><a href="https://www.palantir.com/palantir-foundry/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palantir Foundry data and analytics platform</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, according to the company.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><i></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The vast majority of cars now sold globally have this ability to be connected, so there’s a huge opportunity,” Barlow told TechCruch. “We have 11 million live cars on our platform out of a supply base of about 50 million vehicles. We have over 17 OEM partners live on the platform, and we’re processing 16 billion data points a day, a peak of about 40,000 per second, which explains why we’re also excited to be backed by Microsoft and to be migrating to their Azure cloud platform.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Barlow says Wejo can see 7% of all vehicles moving around New York, 6% around California and 20% around Detroit from partnerships with automakers like GM, Daimler and Hyundai. The company can either hand off raw, anonymized data — collected from vehicles with the consent of the owner — to businesses, developers or governments, or it can perform data analytics for them, which is also where the partnership with Microsoft can come in handy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Microsoft came up with a really compelling solution about how we can leverage their machine learning and AI capabilities to actually provide even more incredible products back to OEMs and key industries that want to use connected vehicle data,” said Barlow. “So Microsoft’s Azure doing that heavy lifting is really going to speed up our business.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Wejo, initial applications might include traffic solutions, as well as remote diagnostics, integrated payments, advertising, retail and logistics. The two companies are also discussing the potential of using Wejo for Microsoft’s mapping solutions. Barlow says mapping companies are often typical buyers of Wejo’s data and expects to see more insurance providers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We&#8217;ve seen 11 million instances of two vehicles coming together, and in real time, we&#8217;re getting data from both those vehicles,” said Barlow. “So we&#8217;re starting to preempt and understand the characteristics or behaviours of before and after that collision or that interaction of vehicles.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wejo collects data that can recreate a car crash, from how each driver stomped on the brakes to which airbags were deployed to the speed of impact and which sensors were destroyed. It can then share this kind of data back to the insurer to help speed up the claims and recovery process and make repairs be more accurate, said Barlow.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All of this data demonstrating human driving behaviors in a range of circumstances has been collected over the last seven years, making Wejo an attractive partner for companies developing autonomous technology.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NUs4GXHwJe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/">The battle for voice recognition inside vehicles is heating up</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The battle for voice recognition inside vehicles is heating up&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/embed/#?secret=NUs4GXHwJe" data-secret="NUs4GXHwJe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/connected-vehicle-data-startup-wejo-partners-with-microsoft-palantir-sompo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171274</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DevOps platform JFrog acquires AI-based IoT and connected device security specialist Vdoo for $300M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/devops-platform-jfrog-acquires-ai-based-iot-and-connected-device-security-specialist-vdoo-for-300m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/devops-platform-jfrog-acquires-ai-based-iot-and-connected-device-security-specialist-vdoo-for-300m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 11:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IoT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jfrog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vdoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[JFrog, the company best known for a platform that helps developers continuously manage software delivery and updates, is making a deal to help it expand its presence and expertise in an area that has become increasingly connected to DevOps: security. The company is acquiring Vdoo, which has built an AI-based platform that can be used [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://jfrog.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JFrog</a>, the company best known for a platform that helps developers continuously manage software delivery and updates, is making a deal to help it expand its presence and expertise in an area that has become increasingly connected to DevOps: security. The company is acquiring <a href="https://www.vdoo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vdoo</a>, which has built an AI-based platform that can be used to detect and fix vulnerabilities in the software systems that work with and sit on IoT and connected devices. The deal &#8212; in a mix of cash and stock &#8212; is valued at approximately $300 million, JFrog confirmed to me.</p>
<p>Sunnyvale-based, Israeli-founded JFrog is publicly traded on Nasdaq, where it went public last September, and currently it has a market cap of <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/FROG?p=FROG&amp;.tsrc=fin-srch" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$4.65 billion</a>. Vdoo, meanwhile, had raised about $70 million from investors that include NTT, Dell, GGV and Verizon (disclaimer: Verizon owns TechCrunch), and when we covered its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/vdoo-raises-25m-more-to-develop-its-ai-based-security-for-iot-and-connected-devices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most recent funding round</a>, we estimated that the valuation was somewhere between $100 million and $200 million, making this a decent return.</p>
<p>Shlomi Ben Haim, JFrog&#8217;s co-founder and CEO, said that his company&#8217;s turn to focusing deeper on security, and making this acquisition in particular to fill out that strategy, are a natural progression in its aim to built out an end-to-end platform for the DevOps team.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;When we started JFrog, the main challenge was to educate the market on what we saw as most important priorities when it comes to building, testing and deploying software,&#8221; he said. Then sometime around 2015-2016 he said they started to realize there was a &#8220;crack&#8221; in the system, &#8220;a crack called security.&#8221; InfoSec engineers and developers sometimes work at cross purposes, as &#8220;developers became too fast&#8221; the work they were doing was inadvertently led to a lot of security vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>JFrog has been building a number of tools since then to address that and to bring the collective priorities together, such as its XRay product. And indeed, Vdoo is not JFrog&#8217;s first foray into security, but it represents a significant step deeper into the hardware and systems that are being run on software. &#8220;It&#8217;s a very important leap forward,&#8221; Ben Haim said.</p>
<p>For its part, Vdoo was born out of a realization as well as a challenging mission: IoT and other connected devices &#8212; a universe of some 50 billion pieces of hardware as of last year &#8212; represents a massive security headache, and not just because of the volume of devices: each object uses and interacts with software in the cloud and so each instance represents a potential vulnerability, with zero-day vulnerabilities, CVEs, configuration and hardening issues, and standard incompliances among some of the most common.</p>
<p>While connected-device security up to now has typically focused on monitoring activity on the hardware, how data is moving in and out of it, Vdoo’s approach has been to build a platform that monitors the behavior of the devices themselves on top of that, using AI to compare that behavior to identify when something is not working as it should. Interestingly, this mirrors the kind of binary analysis that JFrog provides in its DevOps platform, making the two complementary to each other.</p>
<p>But what&#8217;s notable is that this will give JFrog a bigger play at the edge, since part of Vdoo&#8217;s platform works on devices themselves, &#8220;micro agents&#8221; as the company has described them to me previously, to detect and repair vulnerabilities on endpoints.</p>
<p>While JFrog has built a lot of its own business from the ground up, it has made a number of acquisitions to bolt on technology (one example: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/21/jfrog-acquires-shippable-adding-continuous-integration-and-delivery-to-its-devops-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shippable</a>, which it used to bring continuous integration and delivery into its DevOps platform). In this case, Netanel Davidi, the co-founder and CEO of Vdoo (who previously co-founded and sold another security startup, Cyvera, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/03/24/palo-alto-networks-buys-cyber-security-company-cyvera-for-200m/">to Palo Alto Networks</a>) said that this was a good fit because the two companies are fundamentally taking the same approaches in their work (another synergy and justification for DevOps and InfoSec being more closely knitted together too I might add).</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;In terms of the fit between the companies, it&#8217;s about our approach to binaries,&#8221; Davidi said in an interview, noting that the two being on the same page with this approach was fundamental to the deal. &#8220;That&#8217;s only the way to cover the entire pipeline from the very beginning, when they go you develop something, all the way to the device or to the server or to the application or to the mobile phone. That&#8217;s the only way to truly understand the context and contextual risk.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>He also made a note not just of the tech but of the talent that is coming on with the acquisition: 100 people joining JFrog&#8217;s 800.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> &#8220;If JFrog chose to build something like this themselves, they could have done it,&#8221; he said. &#8220;But the uniqueness here is that we have built the best security team, the best security researchers, the best vulnerability researchers, the best reverse engineers, which focus not only on embedded systems, and IoT, which is considered to be the hardest thing to learn and to analyze, but also in software artifacts. We are bringing this knowledge along with us.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>JFrog said that Vdoo will continue to operate as a standalone SaaS product for the time being. Updates that are made will be in aid of supporting the JFrog platform and the two aim to have a fully integrated, &#8220;holistic&#8221; product by 2022.</p>
<p>Along with the deal, JFrog reiterated financial guidance for the next quarter that will end June 30, 2021. It expects revenues of $47.6 million to $48.6 million, with non-GAAP operating income of $0.5 million to $1.5 million and non-GAAP EPS of $0.00 to $0.01, assuming approximately 104 million weighted average diluted shares outstanding. For Full Year 2021, revenues are expected to be $198 million to $204 million, with non-GAAP operating income between $5 million and $7 million and an approximately 3% increase in weighted average diluted shares. JFrog anticipates consolidated operating expenses to increase by approximately $9-10 million for the remainder of 2021, subject to the acquisition closing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/devops-platform-jfrog-acquires-ai-based-iot-and-connected-device-security-specialist-vdoo-for-300m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171317</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2U set to acquire non-profit edX for deal north of $600M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/2u-set-to-acquire-non-profit-edx-for-deal-north-of-600m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/2u-set-to-acquire-non-profit-edx-for-deal-north-of-600m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 10:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2U]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harvard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2U, a SaaS platform that helps non-profits and colleges run online universities, plans to acquire all the assets of Harvard and MIT-founded edX for a deal north of $600 million, according to multiple sources. 2U did not immediately respond to requests for comment, and its unclear if this is an all-cash deal. The combined forces [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">2U, a SaaS platform that helps non-profits and colleges run online universities, plans to acquire all the assets of Harvard and MIT-founded edX for a deal north of $600 million, according to multiple sources. 2U did not immediately respond to requests for comment, and its unclear if this is an all-cash deal. The combined forces of edX and 2U could reach over 50 million learners.</p>
<p><em>Update: 2U confirmed the deal, expected to close within 120 days subject to regulatory and governmental approvals, in a press release post-publication. It also confirmed that the price of the acquisition which will be an $800 million all-cash deal. </em></p>
<p>The deal gives 2U, <a href=" https://techcrunch.com/2014/02/25/2u-files-for-100m-ipo-adds-ex-citigroup-chief-to-board-but-is-it-really-poised-to-be-the-next-big-education-technology-company/ ">a company that filed to go public in 2014 </a>and continues to be one of the rare U.S. edtech companies listed on the stock market, a new wave of collaboratively-built content to its software. Plus, 2U just acquired with stronger name recognition thanks to its Ivy League backers, which some see as a branding move that could help the public company with its own chunk of the market. The company&#8217;s last big acquisition was in 2019, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/08/2u-trilogy/">when it paid $750 million to acquire Trilogy education,</a> a company that builds in-person and online bootcamps in collaboration with universities.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href=" https://techcrunch.com/2012/05/02/harvard-mit-will-bring-classes-to-the-masses-with-their-edx-online-learning-initiative/ ">EdX was founded in 2012</a> amid a crop of massive open online course (MOOC) offerings, including Udacity and Coursera. The company, set up as a non-profit, had an alluring promise upon launch: it would help anyone in the world take a Harvard or MIT class, for free. The institutions, of course, have thrown in a cumulative $80 million in donations into edX to keep the operation free. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/05/02/harvard-mit-will-bring-classes-to-the-masses-with-their-edx-online-learning-initiative/">Its own launch</a> came weeks after Coursera announced that Princeton, Stanford, UPenn, and the University of Michigan would host courses on its own online learning platform. Now, edX&#8217;s acquisition comes months after Coursera went public.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="O4B1vzyR2k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/a-first-look-at-courseras-s-1-filing/">A first look at Coursera’s S-1 filing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A first look at Coursera’s S-1 filing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/a-first-look-at-courseras-s-1-filing/embed/#?secret=O4B1vzyR2k" data-secret="O4B1vzyR2k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Today, edX, led by president and professor Anant Agarwal, hosts over 3,000 courses led by 15,000 instructors and used by 35 million users. Open edX, the platform’s open source platform, is used by 2,400 learning sites worldwide,</span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.edx.org/about-us"> according to the organization’s website.</a></p>
<p>EdX will turn into a public benefit corporation as part of this transaction. Per sources, proceeds from the transaction will go into another non-profit managed by Harvard and MIT, and the institutions will not profit off of the transaction. That said, an MIT statement reveals. that edX took a line of credit from MIT and Harvard, and those funds will be returned to both institutions.</p>
<p>&#8220;Because edX is a public charity, the proceeds from its sale can only be distributed for a purpose consistent with edX’s mission, not to compensate those who contributed to the nonprofit,&#8221;<a href="https://news.mit.edu/2021/mit-harvard-transfer-edx-2u-faq-0629"> the statement reads. </a></p>
<p>Part of this transaction, which has been in the works since February 2021, is colored by the fact that edX has been transparent with its own financial woes and journey to becoming a self-sustaining business. Then MIT Provost Rafael Reif, now the president of the school, had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/05/02/harvard-mit-will-bring-classes-to-the-masses-with-their-edx-online-learning-initiative/">hinted at eventual revenue generation the program first launched</a>, saying in 2012 that “the drive is not to make money..that said, we intend to find a way to support those activities. There are several approaches we are considering, and we don’t want this project to become a drain on the budgets of MIT or Harvard.”</p>
<p>In 2018, the same fiscal year it <a href="https://www.classcentral.com/report/edx-2020-review/">had $37 million in revenue</a>, edX introduced<a href="https://blog.edx.org/furthering-the-edx-mission?track=blog"> a support fee, </a>alongside its ongoing offering that asks students to pay for a verified certification upon course completion. In announcement, the company wrote that &#8220;we believe that we need to move toward a financial model that allows edX and our partners to achieve sustainability and we acknowledge that means moving away from our current model of offering virtually everything for free.&#8221; The edX board also considered other options, MIT. said, <a href="https://news.mit.edu/2021/mit-harvard-transfer-edx-2u-faq-0629">but decided those were</a> &#8220;not as beneficial to edX, its learners, or its partner institutions as the transaction with 2U.&#8221;</p>
<p>The new transaction and edX’s choice to turn into a public benefit corporation might become the financial model that it itself was looking for, indicating just how. hard it may be to monetize a MOOC. While 2U has committed to continuing edX’s free coursework for at least five years, as well as seeding a new non-profit, edX as it currently stands &#8211; a massive education non-profit &#8211; will no longer function as it currently does in the future.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FgH0FlmSmN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/">Edtech valuations aren&#8217;t skyrocketing, but investors see more exit opportunities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Edtech valuations aren&#8217;t skyrocketing, but investors see more exit opportunities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/embed/#?secret=FgH0FlmSmN" data-secret="FgH0FlmSmN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/2u-set-to-acquire-non-profit-edx-for-deal-north-of-600m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171331</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google debuts a new website and set of resources for Americans experiencing food insecurity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/google-debuts-a-new-website-and-set-of-resources-for-americans-experiencing-food-insecurity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/google-debuts-a-new-website-and-set-of-resources-for-americans-experiencing-food-insecurity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food for good]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hunger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google today is launching a new suite of resources for people struggling with food insecurity across the U.S. The project includes the launch of a new website, &#8220;Find Food Support,&#8221; that connects people to food support resources, including hotlines, SNAP information, and a Google Maps locator tool that points people to their local food banks, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google today is launching a new suite of resources for people struggling with food insecurity across the U.S. The project includes the launch of a new website, &#8220;<a href="http://g.co/findfoodsupport">Find Food Support</a>,&#8221; that connects people to food support resources, including hotlines, SNAP information, and a Google Maps locator tool that points people to their local food banks, food pantries and school meal program pickup locations, among other things.</p>
<p>In an <a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/connecting-people-to-food-support">announcement</a>, Google explains how the Covid-19 pandemic fueled a worsening food crisis in the U.S., which led to some 45 million people &#8212; or 1 in 7 Americans &#8212; experiencing food insecurity at some point during 2020. That figure was up 30% over 2019, the company noted. And of those 45 million people, 15 million were children.</p>
<p>While the pandemic&#8217;s impacts are starting subside as businesses are reopening and in-person activities are resuming, many children will still go hungry during the summer months when school lunch programs become unavailable.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To help address this need and others related to food insecurity, Google&#8217;s new website available at <a href="http://g.co/findfoodsupport">g.co/findfoodsupport</a> offers a combination of food support resources, YouTube videos about the problem of food insecurity in the U.S., and a Google Maps locator tool that will direct people to their nearby food bank or other food support locations.</p>
<p>Google says it worked with organizations including No Kid Hungry, FoodFinder, and the U.S. Department of Agriculture to capture 90,000 places offering free food support across the 50 U.S. states. Using the online tool, website visitors can type in their location to see school meal program pickup sites, food banks and food pantries in their area.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171188" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171188" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2171188" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Untitled-1.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171188" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>The tool will display the location&#8217;s address, phone number and other details &#8212; like which days it&#8217;s open or business hours.</p>
<p>Although you can find this information in Google Maps directly, it can be more difficult if you don&#8217;t know the right keywords to use. For example, a search &#8220;food support&#8221; returned a combination of charities, food banks and public services alongside businesses with matching keywords, like &#8220;Food Lion&#8221; and &#8220;Lowe&#8217;s Foods.&#8221; A search for &#8220;food assistance&#8221; was more complete, but also returned unrelated results, like the &#8220;US Food &amp; Drug Administration.&#8221; The online tool&#8217;s search results will be more precise and accurate.</p>
<p>The new website also highlights other food support information, including SNAP benefit information; support for specific groups, like seniors, children, and families; state-by-state benefit guidelines; and food support hotlines. For those not facing food support issues, it offers information on how to donate money, time or food to those in need.</p>
<p>The site additionally features a handful of YouTube videos published by organizations across the country who are working to address food insecurity issues in their own communities. The videos aim to destigmatize food insecurity by showing how all types of people use food support &#8212; including military families, children, and seniors. Google says 1 in 9 active-duty military families experience food insecurity, as do 1 in 6 children, 1 in 3 college students, and over 5 million seniors, for example.</p>
<p>The new site is the result of an effort by Google&#8217;s &#8220;Food for Good,&#8221; headed by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/emilyjma/">Emily Ma</a>. Food for Good originally began as an early stage moonshot project (from Alphabet&#8217;s X, formerly Google[x]) <a href="https://blog.x.company/a-new-home-for-project-delta-a39f8286b6d7">known as Project Delta</a>, which focused on creating a smarter food system. The team wanted to find ways to keep food waste out of landfills by better directing food to those who need it most. In December 2020, Ma <a href="https://blog.x.company/a-new-home-for-project-delta-a39f8286b6d7">announced</a> Project Delta would be moving to Google to scale up its work. The core team then joined Google as &#8220;Food for Good,&#8221; while the food traceability team remained at X to work on broader issues.</p>
<p>Google says it will continue to add more food support locations to the food locator tool going forward, beyond the 90,000 it offers today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/google-debuts-a-new-website-and-set-of-resources-for-americans-experiencing-food-insecurity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171117</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Accel closes on $3B across three funds as it ramps up global investing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/accel-closes-on-3b-across-three-funds/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/accel-closes-on-3b-across-three-funds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Accel announced Tuesday the close of three new funds totaling $3.05 billion, money that it will be using to back early-stage startups, as well as growth rounds for more mature companies. Notably, the 38-year-old Silicon Valley-based venture firm is doubling down on global investing. The announcement underscores both the robust confidence investors continue to have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="http://www.accel.com">Accel</a> announced Tuesday the close of three new funds totaling $3.05 billion, money that it will be using to back early-stage startups, as well as growth rounds for more mature companies. Notably, the 38-year-old Silicon Valley-based venture firm is doubling down on global investing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The announcement underscores both the robust confidence investors continue to have for backing startups in the tech sector and the amount of money available to startups these days.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Specifically, today Accel is announcing its fifteenth early-stage U.S. fund at $650 million; its seventh early-stage European and Israeli fund also at $650 million and its sixth global growth stage fund at $1.75 billion. The latter fund is in addition, and designed to complement, a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">previously unannounced </span><a href="https://www.accel.com/noteworthy/accels-latest-fund"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$2.3 billion global &#8220;Leaders&#8221; fund</span></a> that is focused on later-stage investing<span style="font-weight: 400;"> that Accel closed in December.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Accel expects to invest in about 20 to 30 companies per fund on average, according to Partner Rich Wong. Its average investment in its growth fund will be in the $50 million to $75 million range, and $75 million and $100 million out of its global Leaders fund.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the firm is also still eager and “excited” to incubate companies, Wong said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’ll still write $500,000 to $1 million seed checks,” he told TechCrunch. “It’s important to us to work with companies from the very beginning and support them through their entire journey.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Indeed, as TechCrunch recently reported, Accel has a history of backing companies that were previously bootstrapped (and often profitable) -– the latest example being <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/23/lower-raises-100m-series-a-from-accel/">Lower</a>, a Columbus, Ohio-based fintech, which just raised a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/23/lower-raises-100m-series-a-from-accel/"> $100 million Series A</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interestingly, Accel is often referred to some of these companies by existing portfolio companies (also in the case of Lower, whose CEO was referred to Accel by Galileo Clay Wilkes). More often than not, companies that Accel backs out of its early-stage and growth funds are bootstrapped and located outside of Silicon Valley.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The venture firm has long looked outside of Silicon Valley for opportunities, and has had offices not only in the Bay Area, but in London and Bangalore for years. Part of its investment thesis is to “invest early and locally,” according to Wong. Examples of this philosophy include investments in companies based all over the world &#8212; from Mexico to Stockholm to Tel Aviv to Munich.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the time of its last fund closure in 2019, the firm has seen 10 portfolio companies go public, including </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Slack, Austin-based Bumble, Bucharest-based UiPath, CrowdStrike, PagerDuty, Deliveroo and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/squarespace-files-for-a-direct-listing-on-the-nyse/">Squarespace</a>, among others.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9F2tBahW8M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/uipaths-ipo-filing-suggests-robotic-process-automation-is-booming/">UiPath&#8217;s IPO filing suggests robotic process automation is booming</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UiPath&#8217;s IPO filing suggests robotic process automation is booming&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/uipaths-ipo-filing-suggests-robotic-process-automation-is-booming/embed/#?secret=9F2tBahW8M" data-secret="9F2tBahW8M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also had 40 companies experience an M&amp;A, including Utah-based Qualtrics&#8217;s $8 billion acquisition by SAP and Segment&#8217;s $3.2 billion acquisition by Twilio. Also, just last week, Rockwell Automation announced it was</span><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210625005162/en/Rockwell-Automation-to-Expand-Industrial-Cloud-Software-Offering-with-Acquisition-of-Plex-Systems"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> buying Michigan-based Plex Systems </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">for</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> $2.22 billion in cash. Accel first invested in Plex, which has developed a subscription-based smart manufacturing platform, in 2012.</span></p>
<p>Recent investments include a number of fintech companies such as LatAm&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/accel-backs-mexican-startup-flinks-effort-to-bring-investing-to-latin-america/">Flink</a>, Berlin-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/berlins-trade-republic-nabs-900m-led-by-sequoia-at-a-5b-valuation-to-take-its-neo-broker-app-across-europe/">Trade Republic</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/unit-raises-51m-in-accel-led-series-b-to-grow-its-banking-as-a-service-platform/">Unit</a> and Robinhood rival <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/as-expected-stock-trading-service-public-raises-220m-at-unicorn-valuation/">Public</a>. Accel has also backed as existing portfolio companies such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/webflow-raises-140m-pushing-its-valuation-to-2-1-billion/">Webflow, </a>a software company that helps businesses build no-code websites and events startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/">Hopin</a>.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wong says Accel is “open-minded but thematic” in its investment approach.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Accel Partner Sonali de Rycker, who is based out of London, agrees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“For example, we’ll look at automation companies, consumer businesses and security companies, but at a global scale. Our goal is to find the best entrepreneurs regardless of where they are,” she said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That has only been intensified by the recent rise of the smartphone and cloud, Wong said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Before, companies were mostly selling to the consumer in their own country,” he added. “But now the size of the market is so dramatically bigger, allowing them to become even larger, which is one of the reasons why I believe we’re seeing investment pace at this speed.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To support this, it’s notable that Accel’s global Leaders fund is “dramatically” larger than the $500 million Leaders fund the firm closed in 2019.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, de Rycker points out, companies are staying private longer so the opportunity to invest in them until they sell or go public is greater.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Accel is also patient. In some cases, the firm’s investors will develop “years-long” relationships with companies they are courting.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“1Password is an example of this approach,” Wong said. “Arun [Mathew] had that relationship for at least six years before that investment was made. Finally, 1Password called and said ‘We’re ready, and we want you to do it.’ ”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And so Accel led the Australian company&#8217;s first external round of funding in its 14-year history &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/14/fourteen-years-after-launching-1password-takes-first-funding-a-200m-series-a/">a $200 million Series A</a> &#8212; in 2019. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the firm is open-minded, there are still some industries it has not yet embraced as much as others. For example, Wong said, “We’re not announcing a $2.2 billion crypto fund, but we have done crypto investments, and see some very interesting trends there. We’ll look at where crypto takes us.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="t7nNvMWL4K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/14/fourteen-years-after-launching-1password-takes-first-funding-a-200m-series-a/">Fourteen years after launching, 1Password takes a $200M Series A</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fourteen years after launching, 1Password takes a $200M Series A&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/14/fourteen-years-after-launching-1password-takes-first-funding-a-200m-series-a/embed/#?secret=t7nNvMWL4K" data-secret="t7nNvMWL4K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/accel-closes-on-3b-across-three-funds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171271</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>10club raises $40 million seed funding to build Thrasio of India</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/10club-raises-40-million-seed-funding-to-replicate-thrasio-model-in-india/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/10club-raises-40-million-seed-funding-to-replicate-thrasio-model-in-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 09:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fireside Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thrasio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[10club, a six-month-old Indian startup that is building a Thrasio-like venture, said on Tuesday it has raised $40 million in what is one of the largest seed financing rounds in the South Asian market. The round was co-led by Fireside Ventures (a prominent Indian investor in consumer and hardware tech space) and an unnamed global [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">10club, a six-month-old Indian startup that is building a Thrasio-like venture, said on Tuesday it has raised $40 million in what is one of the largest seed financing rounds in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>The round was co-led by Fireside Ventures (a prominent Indian investor in consumer and hardware tech space) and an unnamed global investor, the Indian startup said, without revealing the other firm’s name. HeyDay, PDS International, Class 5 Global, Secocha Ventures, and founders of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/indian-electronics-and-lifestyle-brand-boat-raises-100-million-from-warburg-pincus/">hardware startup boAt</a> (Aman Gupta and Sameer Mehta) also participated in the round. It&#8217;s not clear whether the round also includes debt &#8212; as is popular among Thrasio-like ventures &#8212; and if the entire financing is being wired in one tranche.</p>
<p><a href="https://10club.team">10club</a> acquires small brands that sell their products on e-commerce platforms and scales those businesses.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Great businesses are growing on the backs of e-commerce giants like Amazon, Flipkart, Nykaa and more. They get their foundational years right but find it difficult to scale, and understand that competition is hard to curb.That&#8217;s where we step in, allowing you &#8211; the entrepreneurs &#8211; to enjoy an exit and benefit from years of hard work,” the startup describes on its LinkedIn page.</p>
<p>10club is one of a few dozen firms that is <a href="https://the-captable.com/2021/06/india-thrasio-amazon-flipkart-acquire-brands-mensa/">attempting to replicate</a> what is popularly known as the Thrasio-model in India. Mensa Brands, a similar venture by former fashion e-commerce Myntra chief executive, recently raised $50 million in equity and debt. TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/investors-race-to-win-early-stage-startup-deals-in-india/">reported</a> earlier this month that UpScale, another prominent player in this space, is in advanced talks with Germany’s Razor Group to raise capital.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Pity the folks at Thrasio that must be scratching their heads wondering why they&#39;re getting so many hits/mentions from India. <a href="https://t.co/N9r2JYWCyp">https://t.co/N9r2JYWCyp</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Osborne Saldanha (@os7borne) <a href="https://twitter.com/os7borne/status/1405143112763150343?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 16, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Like Thrasio, several of these firms are trying to acquire brands that sell mid-range to high-end products in categories where competition is limited. In fact, some of the categories that are common among these brands are so under-appreciated that even Amazon and other e-commerce firms have not explored them through their private label ecosystems.</p>
<p>New York-headquartered Thrasio, which has raised over $1.3 billion in equity and debt since December last year, had acquired or otherwise <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/thrasio-raises-100m-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play-appoints-retail-cfo-heavyweight-for-its-next-steps/">consolidated about 6,000 third party sellers</a> on Amazon as of earlier this year.</p>
<p>“India and online-first brands are at the cusp of the next revolution. We, at Fireside, believe that both VC and acquisition driven model will co-exist going forward and can turbocharge the growth of early-stage brands. Together with the team at 10Club, we will be able to drive this change and enable e-commerce entrepreneurs to realize the full potential of their brands,&#8221; said Vinay Singh, Partner at Fireside Ventures, in a statement. As part of the deal, Singh is also joining 10club&#8217;s board.</p>
<p>Bhavna Suresh, co-founder of 10club and former chief executive of real-estate marketplace Lamudi, said the startup has already built its foundational pillars of the centralized platform and signed letters of intent worth $15 million from several firms and will deploy the fresh capital to operate the new businesses.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">&quot;Thrasio for India&quot; has the opportunity to be a feature not a product<br />Insurgent, well funded consumer brands can expand mkt + sub-cats by acquiring emerging brands<br />Marketplaces needn&#39;t launch Pvt labels- they can invest in their partner brands instead<br />Co-founders of&#8230;</p>
<p>&mdash; Suchita (@suchitasalwan) <a href="https://twitter.com/suchitasalwan/status/1407637921260208136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 23, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/10club-raises-40-million-seed-funding-to-replicate-thrasio-model-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171319</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ShipBob nabs $200M at a $1B+ valuation to help e-commerce companies run logistics like Amazon&#8217;s</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/shipbob-nabs-200m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-help-e-commerce-companies-run-logistics-like-amazons/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/shipbob-nabs-200m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-help-e-commerce-companies-run-logistics-like-amazons/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 09:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ShipBob]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shipping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[E-commerce saw a massive surge of activity and growth in 2020; and while we may hear a lot about how big companies like Amazon got even bigger during the Covid-19 pandemic, that rising tide also lifted a lot of smaller boats. And that, in turn, has had a big impact on the wider e-commerce ecosystem. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">E-commerce saw a massive surge of activity and growth in 2020; and while we may hear a lot about how big companies like Amazon got even bigger during the Covid-19 pandemic, that rising tide also lifted a lot of smaller boats. And that, in turn, has had a big impact on the wider e-commerce ecosystem.</p>
<p>In the latest development, <a href="https://www.shipbob.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ShipBob</a>, which has built an operation and tech platform that today works with some 5,000 e-commerce businesses to run shipping and logistics like their bigger rivals, has raised $200 million. ShipBob is already profitable, but it will be using this money to double down on newer areas of business: both in terms of expanding geographically, and technically, with more R&amp;D around software, robotics, and autonomous systems.</p>
<p>&#8220;We constantly evaluate the needs of our merchants today, where we believe their needs will evolve in the future, and prioritize what can drive the most impact to help make them successful and differentiate from their competitors,&#8221; said Dhruv Saxena, the company&#8217;s CEO, in an interview.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Chicago-based ShipBob has confirmed that the round pushes its valuation to over $1 billion, doubling its valuation compared to its last round, a Series D that it closed in <a href="https://www.shipbob.com/blog/series-d-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">September 2020</a>.</p>
<p>Bain Capital Ventures is leading this Series E round, with SoftBank, Menlo Ventures, Hyde Park Venture Partners, Hyde Park Angels and Silicon Valley Bank also participating. Several of these are repeat investors in the company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="t47BU1anNG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/06/shipbob-raises-40-million-series-c-to-help-small-e-commerce-businesses-compete-with-amazon/">ShipBob brings in $40M to help e-commerce businesses compete with Amazon</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ShipBob brings in $40M to help e-commerce businesses compete with Amazon&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/06/shipbob-raises-40-million-series-c-to-help-small-e-commerce-businesses-compete-with-amazon/embed/#?secret=t47BU1anNG" data-secret="t47BU1anNG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>ShipBob&#8217;s business is part infrastructure play, and part tech play, in what Saxena, who co-founded the company with Divey Gulati, described to us as a &#8220;full-stack approach.&#8221; On the infrastructure front, the company operates warehouses across around 20 locations in the U.S., Canada, Europe and Australia (with plans to use some of this hefty round to expand that list to 10 more centers), from which its customers can store and distribute the goods that they are selling online.</p>
<p>The company then provides a merchant application to its customers to help track that inventory and to help liaise with the warehouses to select items to pick and send to fill orders.</p>
<p>Thirdly, it integrates with a number of shipping companies to then actually send out those orders to customers. Altogether it says it integrates with some 40 partners, ranging from the likes Walmart (to power two-day delivery) and Pachama (to carbon off-set deliveries), plus Amazon, Walmart, Shopify, BigCommerce, Wix, Square and Squarespace so that people setting up sites or selling through those platforms can use ShipBob to handle the orders once a customer has clicked on &#8220;buy.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fulfillment and logistics are not the most obvious &#8220;face&#8221; of e-commerce, but to companies that are selling items online (or indeed, offline) that need to be delivered to someone after purchasing, they can be a make or break part of the business model, nearly as important as having a good storefront that works quickly, gets people where they want to be, and offering them things they want to buy. In logistics, the many, various items that are calculated as part of that operation &#8212; setting, intake and storage, pick and pack, shipping, and return fees are just some of those items &#8212; potentially rack up to a significant cost for the sellers, which they either pass on to the buyers or stomach to compete on price against much bigger players like Amazon. On top of that, it&#8217;s almost inevitable that shipping and logistics are not &#8220;core competencies&#8221; of the companies that heavily rely on them.</p>
<p>And as many have pointed out, Amazon&#8217;s success is built in large part on economies of scale, by making a better return because of how much it&#8217;s passing through the same system, distributing the cost of operation across more goods.</p>
<p>Companies like ShipBob &#8212; and it is not the only one in this space, with others including Amazon, ShipHero, Byrd, OceanX, Shippo, and many more &#8212; have essentially built a logistics operation that lets those companies outsource the work of doing that themselves, much as they would use a payments provider like Stripe rather than building a payments flow from the ground up. ShipBob also, by virtue of working with many businesses, creates that economy of scale by bringing their orders and work all together, mimicking essentially what Amazon does for itself.</p>
<p>Saxena says that ShipBob already has a &#8220;Prime&#8221; style offering for customers &#8212; by which he means, a way to provide low-cost or even &#8220;free&#8221; faster shipping for orders over a certain amount of money &#8212; but it will be interesting to see how and if it ever looks to move up the stack and see how it can leverage its logistics control and command to move up the stack and work on loyalty or membership programs for the most dedicated customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our customers are the brands and we built ShipBob to support their business growth,&#8221; he said. &#8220;A requisite to supporting their growth is offering fast and affordable shipping across any channel that they want to sell, so we do offer a &#8216;Prime&#8217; style offering to the brands that we support today. For example, ShipBob merchants can offer affordable 2-day shipping directly through their website and through the marketplaces where they sell, like Amazon, Walmart, Facebook, and Google.&#8221;</p>
<p>What will also be interesting to see is how and if the growth we&#8217;ve seen in e-commerce in the last year &#8212; fueled by a very particular set of circumstances that either closed stores, or kept people away from them, or both &#8212; will be sustained, and how that will impact ShipBob. As we pointed out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/etsy-acquires-elo7-known-as-the-etsy-of-brazil-for-217m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">yesterday</a>, there was a<a href="https://www.digitalcommerce360.com/article/us-ecommerce-" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> 44% bump in COVID-19 online spending in 2020</a>, but in the year before that the U.S. has had e-commerce growth of around 15% as it&#8217;s a pretty penetrated market already.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Due to Covid, e-commerce penetration in the US got pulled forward by 5-7 years and while some of it will revert back as the economy opens up, it is still higher than the pre-COVID levels </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">across nearly all verticals</span>,&#8221; Saxena said, citing the company&#8217;s own stats that appear to <a href="https://trends.shipbob.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">bear this out</a>. &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">Many consumers who were forced to adapt to online buying are continuing to buy things online. For example, older demographics bought online for the first time and will continue to do so, while younger demographics who bought a considerable percentage of their goods online already, increased that percentage while the size of their buying power increased as well.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>It&#8217;s for this reason, and the fact that ShipBob is profitable, that investors are happy to make a bullish investment now.</p>
<p>“The fastest growing ecommerce brands recognize that world-class fulfillment increases revenue and builds customer loyalty,” said Ajay Agarwal, partner at Bain Capital Ventures and a board member, said in a statement.. “These leading brands are partnering with ShipBob as the one-stop cloud logistics platform to manage and deliver their merchandise</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/shipbob-nabs-200m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-help-e-commerce-companies-run-logistics-like-amazons/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171309</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ghana&#8217;s Jetstream lands $3M to build the digital infrastructure for Africa&#8217;s trade corridors</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/ghanas-jetstream-lands-3m-to-build-the-digital-infrastructure-for-africas-trade-corridors/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/ghanas-jetstream-lands-3m-to-build-the-digital-infrastructure-for-africas-trade-corridors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 07:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cargo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jetstream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[port]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[west africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The share of exports from Africa to the rest of the world ranged from 80% to 90% between 2000 and 2017. This has created a growing demand for Africa to be less dependent on commodity exports and focus on regional commerce. Not only does this decrease export dependence, but it also forms new markets for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The share of exports from Africa to the rest of the world ranged from 80% to 90% between 2000 and 2017. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This has created a growing demand for Africa to be less dependent on commodity exports and focus on regional commerce</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not only does this decrease export dependence, but it also forms new markets for value-added goods to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be exchanged</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yet, Africa is home to the slowest and costliest ports in the world. Reports say that sometimes it is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">logistically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> cheaper and faster for African businesses to trade goods with distant overseas partners than via Africa’s intracontinental trade corridors. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">That&#8217;s a big problem and <a href="https://jetstreamafrica.com/">Jetstream</a>, a Ghanaian-based company proposing to change that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> closed a $3 million seed round</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Local and international investors participated in the round. They include Alitheia IDF, Golden Palm Investments, 4DX Ventures, Lightspeed Venture Partners, Asia Pacific Land, Breyer Labs, and MSA Capital.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was founded by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://gh.linkedin.com/in/miishe"> Miishe Addy</a> and <a href="https://gh.linkedin.com/in/solomon-torgbor-25169b18">Solomon Torgbor</a> in 2018. The founders started Jetstream to enable African businesses to see and control their own cross-border supply chains. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It aggregates private sector logistics providers at African ports and borders, and brings them online</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Initially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the founders&#8217; insight was around fragmentation problems and lack of coordination at African ports; an experience Torgbor was all too familiar with. He had worked at Maersk’s freight forwarding subsidiary Damco for eight years. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">There, he saw cargoes sitting for weeks at container terminals without moving forward in the supply chain</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The delays were due to errors and incorrect paperwork at customs, importers, and exporters not having working capital at the right time to pay their logistics bills and poor coordination on the ground. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For exports, the cargo volumes were sometimes too small to ship </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">cost-effectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by sea freight</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171257" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171257" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2171257" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jetstream-photo.jpg?w=680" alt="Jetstream" width="680" height="562" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jetstream-photo.jpg 3232w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jetstream-photo.jpg?resize=150,124 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jetstream-photo.jpg?resize=300,248 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jetstream-photo.jpg?resize=768,634 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jetstream-photo.jpg?resize=680,562 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jetstream-photo.jpg?resize=1536,1269 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jetstream-photo.jpg?resize=2048,1692 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jetstream-photo.jpg?resize=50,41 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171257" class="wp-caption-text">L-R: Miishe Addy (CEO) and Solomon Torgbor (COO)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, Addy taught business at Meltwater Entrepreneurial School of Technology (MEST), a Pan-African incubator and entrepreneur training program. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before MEST, the law graduate from Stanford worked for management consulting company Bain &amp; Company</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Torgbor spoke with Addy about the challenges he noticed at Damco, she immediately thought they were worth tackling</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“As he was talking, a light bulb went off and I thought. &#8216;These are exactly the types of problems that technology solves,&#8217;” the CEO said to TechCrunch</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. “We discussed and tried lots of different solutions for about a year and discovered that cargo aggregation generated strong traction almost immediately.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jetstream started operations in Ghana in March 2019 with a Less Than Container Load (LCL) aggregation service</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The service allowed agricultural exporters to group their shipments into shared sea freight containers. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then in November of that year, Jetstream added trade finance for customers who found it difficult to fill large </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">purchase</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> orders</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, Jetstream is white labeling the systems built internally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to manage shipments and financing for customers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We are different from a more siloed freight management system because we are leveraging financing to integrate the customs brokers, freight forwarders, shipping lines, airlines, and container terminals all onto the Jetstream platform so that shipments can </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be managed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and tracked every step of the way. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are bringing many of the local providers online for the first time,&#8221; Addy said of the changes Jetstream has had to make along the way</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jetstream&#8217;s business model is straightforward. It charges for the freight, clearance, and financial services offered. For freight, it charges a per-container or per-kilogram fee. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For customs clearance, it charges a flat fee that varies depending on the tax category and location of the shipment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And for financing and insurance services, it charges a commission on the value of the goods </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">being shipped</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the pandemic, inefficiencies and a lack of coordination between providers around the ports </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">were made more evident </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">and created stronger growth for Jetstream as its logistics service revenue </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">significantly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> grew 512% from March 2020 to March 2021. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Addy believes that the pandemic further intensified Jetstream&#8217;s vision to bring cross-border trade corridors online and drive toward an inflection point in the speed and growth of commerce on the continent. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We see a future where trade running on Jetstream’s digital rails has a powerful competitive edge on logistics</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Jetstream is to cross-border logistics what Flutterwave is to fintech in Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">,” she continued</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_951217" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-951217" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-951217" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shutterstock_174080105.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="448" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shutterstock_174080105.jpg 4272w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shutterstock_174080105.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shutterstock_174080105.jpg?resize=300,197 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shutterstock_174080105.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shutterstock_174080105.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shutterstock_174080105.jpg?resize=1536,1011 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shutterstock_174080105.jpg?resize=2048,1348 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shutterstock_174080105.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-951217" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://www.shutterstock.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shutterstock <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reports estimate that the market for cross-border logistics services in Africa is about $32 billion in revenue</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is predicted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to double in size over the next decade. For Jetstream, starting with Ghana is the perfect place to capture as much value and expand vis-a-vis the continent&#8217;s growth. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a Ghanaian native, COO Torgbor hammers home this point. In a statement, he calls Ghana a springboard to intracontinental trade and intercontinental trade with other fast-growing emerging markets. The</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> West African nation currently sits at the helm of Africa&#8217;s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">newly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> enacted, continent-wide free trade zone <a href="https://au.int/en/cfta">AfCFTA</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ghana is also home to Port Tema, the <a href="https://www.freightnews.co.za/article/largest-port-west-and-central-africa-named#:~:text=It's%20official.,(GPHA)%2C%20Michael%20Luguje.">largest container terminal in West and Central Africa</a> that plans to handle one million containers a year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to Port Tema, Jetstream counts an unnamed Asia-based global shipping line as a major early adopter and customer of its technology</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This has seen Jetstream&#8217;s business generate seven-figure revenue and Addy claims the startup grows more than 100% year on year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Per <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/">reports</a>, women-led startups in Africa attract less than 15% of the total VC investments that flow into the continent. However, many female-targeted funds have launched in the last couple of years to fill this gap and one of such participated in this round. <a href="https://www.alitheiaidf.com/">Alitheia IDF</a>, a VC firm focused on gender-diverse startups, usually invests five- to seven-figure sums and is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/these-investors-want-to-back-ridiculously-early-female-led-african-startups/">one of the few venture capital firms in Africa</a> tackling the low access to funding for women-led teams. Thus, Jetstream&#8217;s funding presents a rare win for this demographic (investors and founders alike) especially for the latter who are based in Ghana where few female tech CEOs exist.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Addy tells me she looks forward to when more <a href="https://qz.com/africa/1969926/investors-are-finally-taking-africas-female-founders-seriously/">African female-led teams are well funded</a>, wishing Jetstream could help set off the trend. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;I especially hope that our business growth encourages the investor side of the tech ecosystem to take a second look at </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">all of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the women leaders who aren&#8217;t</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">being </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">adequately</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> funded,&#8221; she commented.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That aside, Jetstream also has operations in Nigeria with agents present in South Africa, China, the U.S., the U.K., and Europe. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This talent placement is one of Jetstream&#8217;s moves geared towards 2028 when the CEO says the company hopes to have a presence at ports and borders in Africa comprising 80% of the continent’s total global trade</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VsD26oNaUX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/these-investors-want-to-back-ridiculously-early-female-led-african-startups/">These investors want to back &#8216;ridiculously early&#8217; female-led African startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;These investors want to back &#8216;ridiculously early&#8217; female-led African startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/these-investors-want-to-back-ridiculously-early-female-led-african-startups/embed/#?secret=VsD26oNaUX" data-secret="VsD26oNaUX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oHx9YFoVjq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/summer-sale-save-10-on-extra-crunch-membership/">Summer Sale: Save 10% on Extra Crunch membership</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Summer Sale: Save 10% on Extra Crunch membership&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/summer-sale-save-10-on-extra-crunch-membership/embed/#?secret=oHx9YFoVjq" data-secret="oHx9YFoVjq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/ghanas-jetstream-lands-3m-to-build-the-digital-infrastructure-for-africas-trade-corridors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harness Wealth raises $15 million to democratize the power of family offices</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/harness-wealth-raises-15-million-to-democratize-the-power-of-family-offices/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/harness-wealth-raises-15-million-to-democratize-the-power-of-family-offices/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 23:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Activant Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bain Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[estate planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harness Wealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jackson Square Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Torch Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2170022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Family offices have existed since the 1800s, but they&#8217;ve never been so manifold as in recent years. According to a 2019 Global Family Office Report by UBS and Campden Wealth, 68% of the 360 family offices surveyed were founded in 2000 or later. Their rise owes to numerous factors, including the tech startups that mint [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Family offices have existed since the 1800s, but they&#8217;ve never been so manifold as in recent years. According to a <a href="https://www.ubs.com/global/en/wealth-management/uhnw/global-family-office-report/global-family-office-report-2019.html">2019 Global Family Office Report</a> by UBS and Campden Wealth, 68% of the 360 family offices surveyed were founded in 2000 or later.</p>
<p>Their rise owes to numerous factors, including the tech startups that mint new centi-millionaires and billionaires each year, along with the increasingly complex choices that people with so much moolah encounter. Think household administration, legal matters, trust and estate management, personal investments, charitable ventures.</p>
<p>Still, family offices tend to cater to people with investable assets of <a href="https://home.kpmg/xx/en/home/insights/2019/11/the-emergence-of-the-family-office.html">$1 billion or more</a>, according to KPMG. Even multi-family offices, where resources are shared with other families, are more typically targeting people with at least $20 million to invest. That high bar means there are still a lot of people with a lot of resources who need hand-holding.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Enter <a href="https://www.harnesswealth.com/">Harness Wealth</a>, a three-year-old, New York-based outfit that was founded by David Snider and Katie Prentke English to cater to individuals with increasingly complex financial pictures, including following liquidity events. The two understand as well as anyone how one&#8217;s vested interests can abruptly change &#8212; and how hard these can be to manage when working full-time.</p>
<p>Snider got his start out of school as an associate with Bain &amp; Company and later as an associate with Bain Capital before becoming the first business hire at Compass and getting promoted to COO and CFO after the real estate company&#8217;s $25 million Series A raise in 2013. Compass grew, of course, and now, less than four months after its late-March IPO, it boasts a market cap of nearly $27 billion.</p>
<p>Indeed, over the years, Snider, who rejoined Bain as an executive-in-residence after 4.5 years with Compass, spied an opportunity to bring together often siloed businesses like tax and estate and investment planning, including it because &#8220;it resonated with me personally. Despite all these great things on my resume, every six months I found something I could or should have been doing differently with my equity.&#8221;</p>
<p>Prentke English also has much in common with the clients Harness Wealth is targeting. After spending more than six years at American Express, she spent two years as the CMO of London-based online investment manager Nutmeg. She left the role to start Harness after being introduced to Snider through a mutual friend; in the meantime, Nutmeg was just <a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://pitchbook.com/newsletter/jp-morgan-buys-digital-wealth-manager-nutmeg">acquired</a> by JPMorgan Chase.</p>
<p>While there is no shortage of wealth managers to whom such individuals can turn, Harness says it does far more than pair people with the right independent registered investment advisors &#8212; which <em>is</em> a key part of its business. It also helps its customers, depending on their needs, connect with a team of pros across an array of verticals &#8212; not unlike the access an individual might have if they were to have a family office.</p>
<p>As for how Harness makes money, it collects part of the fee that advisers on the platform charge for their services. Snider says the percentage varies, though it&#8217;s an &#8220;ongoing revenue share to ensure alignment with our clients.&#8221; In other words, he adds, &#8220;We only do well if they find long-term success with the advisers on our platform,&#8221; versus if Harness merely collected a lead generation fee at the outset.</p>
<p>Ultimately, the company thinks it can replace a lot of the do-it-yourself services available in the market, like Personal Capital and Mint, and it suggests it is making headway, with a ballooning base of customers that include employees of Coinbase, UiPath, Paypal, Snowflake, Doordash, and Amazon, as well as partners at venture firms.</p>
<p>That confidence is rooted in part in Snider&#8217;s experience with Compass, which, in its earlier days, thought it could navigate around real estate agents but &#8220;found that while people wanted better data insights and a better UX, they also wanted that coupled with someone who&#8217;d had many clients who looked like them,&#8221; says Snider. Prentke English joined forces with him after discovering that Nutmeg, too, was &#8220;running into the limitations of a non-human-powered solution,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>Investors think the thesis makes sense, evidently. Harness just closed on $15 million in Series A funding led by Jackson Square Ventures, a round that brings the company&#8217;s total funding to $19 million.</p>
<p>As for what Harness Wealth does with that fresh capital, part of it, interestingly, will be used to develop its own captive business line called Harness Tax. As Snider explains it, more of its clients are finding that tax planning is among their biggest concerns, given all that is happening on the IPO front, with SPACs, with remote work, and also with cryptocurrencies, into which more people are pouring money but around which the tax code has been playing catch-up.</p>
<p>It makes sense, given that tax planning can be time-sensitive and often dictate the overall financial planning strategy. At the same time, it&#8217;s fair to wonder whether some of Harness Wealth&#8217;s adviser partners will be turned off from working with the outfit if it thinks its partner is evolving into a rival.</p>
<p>Snider insists that Harness Wealth &#8212; which currently employs 22 people and is not-yet profitable &#8212; has no such designs. &#8220;Our goal is only to help people where we can add value, and we saw an opportunity to lean in on tax side.&#8221; Harness has a &#8220;a very large population of people who may not understand their tax liabilities&#8221; because of the crypto boom in particular, he explains, adding, &#8220;We want to make sure we&#8217;re front and center&#8221; and ready to help as needed.</p>
<p>Others of Harness Wealth&#8217;s new and existing investors include Bain Capital; Torch Capital; Activant; GingerBread Capital; FJ Labs; i2BF Ventures; First Minute Capital; Liquid2 Ventures; Alleycorp, Marc Benioff; Compass founder Ori Allon; and Paul Edgerley, who is the former co-head of Bain Capital Private Equity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/harness-wealth-raises-15-million-to-democratize-the-power-of-family-offices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2170022</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Duolingo filed to go public</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/duolingo-s-1/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/duolingo-s-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 22:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duolingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Duolingo, a Pittsburgh-based language learning business last valued at $2.4 billion, has officially filed to go public. The 400-person company, which we explored in great detail in our EC-1, was co-founded by Luis von Ahn, the inventor of CAPTCHA and reCAPTCHA, and Severin Hacker. One of the most revealing bits of its story? It&#8217;s a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.duolingo.com/">Duolingo</a>, a Pittsburgh-based language learning business last valued at $2.4 billion, <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1562088/000162828021013065/duolingos-1.htm">has officially filed to go public.</a></p>
<p>The 400-person company, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1/">which we explored in great detail in our EC-1</a>, was co-founded by Luis von Ahn, the inventor of CAPTCHA and reCAPTCHA, and Severin Hacker. One of the most revealing bits of its story? It&#8217;s a route to monetization as a then rare edtech consumer business based outside of Silicon Valley. The company has had a somewhat circuitous journey &#8212; full of trial and error &#8212; on finding the perfect business model. It eventually landed on subscriptions, despite an original distaste for it thanks to its mission to provide free education.</p>
<p>Luckily, the S-1 <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1562088/000162828021013065/duolingos-1.htm#i0bdeca0cb60e438aaa7fdfbd87a2dfd7_38">reveals that its earlier decisions led to sharp revenue growth at the company</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The vast majority of Duolingo’s revenue comes from subscriptions. In the most recent calendar year, for example, the edtech giant generated 73% of its total top line from subscription incomes. That revenue was followed by advertising incomes and the Duolingo English Test (DET), which represented 17% and 10% of its top line in 2020. (Notably, von Ahn hoped that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1-monetization/">the DET would be 20% of Duolingo’s revenue by 2019</a>, a figure that it failed to reach by some margin.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tHyEW1H1jR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1-product/">The product-led growth behind edtech’s most downloaded app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The product-led growth behind edtech’s most downloaded app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1-product/embed/#?secret=tHyEW1H1jR" data-secret="tHyEW1H1jR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Its multi-part business model appears to be paying off. The company’s revenue grew from $70.8 million in 2019 to $161.7 million in 2020, a 129% increase. Of course some of that growth would have happened sans the recent global pandemic, but it’s not hard to see some COVID-related acceleration in the figures. Duolingo also reported $55.4 million in revenue during the first quarter of 2021, representing a 97% growth from the year-ago period.</p>
<p>The company recently turned profitable on an adjusted basis.</p>
<p>But in more strict accounting terms, net losses have grown for Duolingo. In the three months ended March 31, 2021, for example, the company had net losses of 13.5 million, a sharp increase compared to the same period last year when it had net losses of $2.2 million. And from 2019 to 2020, the company’s GAAP net losses expanded from $13.6 million to $15.8 million.</p>
<p>It should be noted that the company’s net margin improved in 2020, as its revenue more than doubled and its losses barely crept higher. The company’s profitability or lack thereof should not prove to be a problem during its impending listing.</p>
<p>In its S-1 filing, Duolingo provided a placeholder $100 million figure for the funds it expects to raise; we’ll get a better idea of how much capital the edtech unicorn may onboard during its IPO when it sets an IPO price range after its roadshow.</p>
<p>The former startup is effectively the kick-off to the Q3 2021 IPO season, one that several inventors have told TechCrunch will be more than active.</p>
<p>Duolingo has raised $183.3 million in venture capital to date. Investors that have meaningful stakes in the company include NewView Capital, Union Square Ventures, CapitalG, Kleiner Perkins, and General Atlantic, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/understanding-duolingos-quiet-10m-raise/">recently got a spot on the cap table through a secondary transaction</a>.</p>
<p>At a run rate of around $220 million today and growth of more than 100%, Duolingo should not have a problem clearing its privately set $2.4 billion price tag. Unless public-market investors are concerned that the edtech market’s growth is mostly behind it. That Duolingo grew by nearly 100% in the first quarter could temper such concerns.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YddCV4tvpg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1-monetization/">How Duolingo became fluent in monetization</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Duolingo became fluent in monetization&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1-monetization/embed/#?secret=YddCV4tvpg" data-secret="YddCV4tvpg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Factoids and other joy</h2>
<p>TechCrunch is still digging its way through Duolingo’s IPO filing, but we’ve found a number of details that add more than a little color to its recent growth and business results. Here are some standouts:</p>
<ul>
<li>A “record low” attrition rate in 2020 in which only four employees, or 2% of its workforce left the company.</li>
<li>The company eventually plans to launch a “Duolingo Proficiency Score” across its offered languages, with the hopes of creating a “widely accepted indicator of language proficiency level and make Duolingo a global proficiency standard.”</li>
<li>It cited Apple’s “Translate” tool, an iOS app launched in 2020 that allows users to translate text sentences or speech between several languages, as a competitor in the ‘risk factors’ section.</li>
<li>And finally, <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_/status/1407034043376574469">it confirmed</a> that it is seeking potential acquisition candidates to add complementary services to its startup.</li>
</ul>
<p>Duolingo plans to list on the NASDAQ stock exchange using the ticker symbol DUOL.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/duolingo-s-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171239</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: SpaceX announces tentative plans to launch first orbital flight next month</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/daily-crunch-spacex-announces-tentative-plans-to-launch-first-orbital-flight-next-month/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/daily-crunch-spacex-announces-tentative-plans-to-launch-first-orbital-flight-next-month/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 22:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for Monday, June 28. How much time did you spend on your phone this weekend? Too much? Not a lot? According to recent data on consumer app spending, you probably spent a pretty fair amount. Consumer spending on apps <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/consumer-spending-on-apps-hit-record-64-9b-in-first-half-of-2021-but-install-growth-slowed-to-1-7/">hit a new record</a> in the first half of the year, though the pace of growth is slowing.</p>
<p>Before we begin, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/summer-sale-save-10-on-extra-crunch-membership/">Extra Crunch is on sale this week</a>. Check it out here and support <a href="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/71FxJIhq4rL._AC_SL1500_.jpg">The Good Ship TechCrunch</a>. &#8212; Alex</p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/surgical-robotics-company-cmr-raises-600m/"><strong>Surgical robots are big business:</strong></a><strong> </strong>News broke today that U.K.-based surgical robotics startup CMR has put together a $600 million round led by SoftBank’s second Vision Fund and Ally Bridge Group. CMR is now worth $3 billion.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/etsy-acquires-elo7-known-as-the-etsy-of-brazil-for-217m/"><strong>Etsy acquires Brazilian rival:</strong></a> Also out today was news that Etsy, the consumer crafts marketplace popular in the United States, purchased its Brazilian cognate for $217 million. The deal for Elo7 follows <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/etsy-is-acquiring-social-selling-site-depop-for-1-625b-in-a-mostly-cash-deal/">Etsy’s recent purchase of Depop</a>. It appears that Etsy views at least a good portion of its growth through an inorganic lens.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/spacex-aiming-for-first-orbital-test-launch-of-starship-in-july/"><strong>SpaceX wants to send Starship to (near) space:</strong></a><strong> </strong>SpaceX’s Starship is <em>nearly</em> going to space next month, the company reported. Yep, Starship, the thing you probably most remember for blowing up during trials, could be headed to orbit in July. Don’t think that we’re knocking SpaceX for having some failed trials. The company used to crash rocket stages in reentry all the time. Now it lands them on drone ships with regularity. In space tech, perhaps you have to blow up before you can properly take flight.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>To kick off today, we’re talking about Pittsburgh, a fascinating startup market <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/calling-all-yinzers-techcrunch-is-virtually-headed-to-pittsburgh/">that TechCrunch is visiting in short order</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/pittsburghs-mayor-on-the-citys-startup-community-and-the-difficulty-of-attracting-venture-capital/">Pittsburgh’s mayor on the city’s startup community and the difficulty of attracting venture capital:</a> </strong>How do you reinvent a city that was left behind by deindustrialization and wants to shake off its old reputation? TechCrunch got in the weeds with Bill Peduto, the mayor of Pittsburgh since 2014.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/vcs-discuss-the-opportunities-and-challenges-of-the-pittsburgh-startup-ecosystem/"><strong>VCs discuss the opportunities — and challenges — in Pittsburgh’s startup ecosystem:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Of course, city government is only one piece of the larger puzzle of building a startup hub. The monied classes also have a part to play when it comes to creating a flywheel for startup creation, investment and re-investment.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/how-cmu-is-helping-build-its-own-startups-and-keeping-them-in-pittsburgh/"><strong>How Carnegie Mellon is helping build its own startups and keeping them in Pittsburgh:</strong></a> And speaking of flywheels, another key component of any startup market that wants to be self-sustaining is helping keep its newly educated minds local, where they can build, scale, exit, and then put their capital and knowledge back to work.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/pittsburgh-city-spotlight/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2164781 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Moving to our regular fare, here’s more from today’s digest of startup happenings:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/tapcart-a-shopify-for-mobile-apps-raises-a-50-million-series-b/">$50M to build the Shopify of mobile commerce:</a></strong> Tapcart wants to bring Shopify’s desktop shopping magic to the mobile world, and today it announced an eight-figure round led by Left Lane Capital. (To a degree, it reminds us of <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/24/why-you-have-to-pay-attention-to-the-indian-startup-scene/">recent YC grad Bikayi</a></strong>.)</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/robotic-beverage-maker-botrista-raises-10m/"><strong>$10M for chilled robotic drinks:</strong></a><strong> </strong>No, not drinks for robots. Robot-prepared drinks. We’ve seen startups building auto-baristas before, but Botrista’s machine could be something special. It looks slick, and we’d frankly drink most of its offered combinations. Let’s see how far 10 million bucks can take it.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/sentinelones-upgraded-ipo-pricing-is-good-news-for-tiger-public-markets-and-your-local-vc/"><strong>Yet another hot software IPO:</strong></a><strong> </strong>SentinelOne’s IPO is looking spicy after raising its price range. The company’s valuation is creeping higher ahead of its debut, and should value the cybersecurity unicorn at a multiple of its final private price.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/27/paymaya-owner-voyager-innovation-raises-167m-from-kkr-tencent-and-ifc-will-launch-digital-bank-in-the-philippines/"><strong>$167M for a leading Philippines-based fintech:</strong></a><strong> </strong>PayMaya’s parent company is a lot richer today after closing $121 million in new capital along with $46 million from prior investments this week. Per TechCrunch, the funds will be used to “launch more financial services, including a digital bank.”</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/equity-monday-big-ipads-and-ballmer-era-google/">Today’s episode of the Equity Podcast</a></strong> features a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/thursday-snags-3-5m-for-a-dating-app-thats-live-once-a-week/">new spin on dating apps</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Closing, two from the personnel department:</strong> First, Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong is coming to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/coinbase-ceo-brian-armstrong-is-coming-to-disrupt/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a>. And Foursquare’s Dennis Crowley is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/foursquare-founder-dennis-crowley-steps-back-from-the-company/">stepping back from the company</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>3 data strategies for selling to developers</h2>
<p>Many consumers are open to a slick sales pitch, but software developers generally know better.</p>
<p>Successful dev-focused marketing efforts steer these users toward free tools, but unless you know exactly what data to look for and how to measure it, your efforts will have limited impact.</p>
<p>Software companies hoping to connect with developers should treat end users like the &#8220;go-to-market side of the team,&#8221; advises Sam Richard, senior director of growth at OpenView, which has invested in companies like Datadog, Expensify and Calendly.</p>
<p>For example: Instead of simply pulling analytics from your production database, what if your GTM team polled stakeholders who touch revenue about the data points they use to make decisions? If you assigned a product manager to address their needs, draft a roadmap and develop an MVP, how much could you learn?</p>
<p>&#8220;Don&#8217;t overthink it,&#8221; says Richard. &#8220;Selling to developers isn’t impossible — it’s just difficult.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hxUnyBhIhU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/3-data-strategies-for-selling-to-developers/">3 data strategies for selling to developers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 data strategies for selling to developers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/3-data-strategies-for-selling-to-developers/embed/#?secret=hxUnyBhIhU" data-secret="hxUnyBhIhU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li>Did you know that both Microsoft <em>and</em> Apple are worth $2 trillion apiece? It was just a few years ago that the five largest American tech firms <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/techs-5-biggest-players-now-worth-3-trillion/">were worth a mere $3 trillion</a>, though at the time that number felt <em>huge. </em>Today, however, Microsoft started to help chart its path to the $3 trillion mark on its own with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/the-first-preview-of-windows-11-is-now-available/">the release of the first official Windows 11 preview</a>. Sure, there have been some builds floating around, but this time the source code is from the code’s source.</li>
<li>Facebook has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/facebook-to-target-nigerian-learners-with-educational-app-sabee-created-by-its-rd-team/">a new product out in Nigeria</a> &#8212; where it has an office &#8212; called Sabee. TechCrunch reports that it “aims to connect learners and educators in online communities to make educational opportunities more accessible.” Facebook wants to reach all internet users, and Africa is a <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1176668/internet-penetration-rate-in-africa-by-region/">growth market for internet penetration</a>, so the move makes sense.</li>
<li>For those of you out there invested in the Android wearable ecosystem, good news: Samsung and Google have a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/samsung-and-google-detail-wearable-platform-ahead-of-next-galaxy-watch-launch/">lot of new stuff that you are probably going to like</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch is building a shortlist of the top growth marketers in tech. We’d love to hear who you’ve worked with, so <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">fill out the survey here</a>! Here’s one of the many great recommendations we’ve received:</p>
<p><strong>Name of marketer: </strong><a href="https://diptiparmar.com">Dipti Parmar</a></p>
<p><strong>Name of recommender: </strong>Brody Dorland, co-founder, <a href="https://divvyhq.com">DivvyHQ</a></p>
<p><strong>Recommendation:</strong> “She gave me an easy-to-implement plan to start with clear outcomes and timeline. She delivered it within one month and I was able to see the results in a couple of months. This encouraged me to hand over bigger parts of our content strategy and publishing to her.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/daily-crunch-spacex-announces-tentative-plans-to-launch-first-orbital-flight-next-month/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171163</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Korean court sides against Netflix, opening door for streaming bandwidth fees from ISPs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/korean-court-sides-against-netflix-opening-door-for-streaming-bandwidth-fees-from-isps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/korean-court-sides-against-netflix-opening-door-for-streaming-bandwidth-fees-from-isps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 21:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SK Broadband]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2170985</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A court case in South Korea has ended in a loss for Netflix and a victory for ISPs in the country, which may now be empowered to levy bandwidth usage fees on traffic-gobbling streaming platforms. The decision is likely to be challenged, as it essentially saddles the new wave of streaming services with ISP-negotiated rents [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A court case in South Korea has ended in a loss for Netflix and a victory for ISPs in the country, which may now be empowered to levy bandwidth usage fees on traffic-gobbling streaming platforms. The decision is likely to be challenged, as it essentially saddles the new wave of streaming services with ISP-negotiated rents just as the market is exploding.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.kedglobal.com/newsView/ked202106250013">As reported by the Korean Economic Daily</a>, the court&#8217;s decision is less prescriptive than an official &#8220;figure it out amongst yourselves.&#8221; But it fails to protect streamers from a class of bandwidth fees they have fought for years.</p>
<p>Netflix filed suit in 2020 alleging that the ISP SK Broadband had no right to demand payment for the bandwidth the platform uses, similar to a legal conflict that flared up around 2014.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Back then, ISPs complained that streaming services consumed an inordinate amount of bandwidth and the companies should pay something to offset the cost of providing it. Streaming sites countered that they were simply fulfilling the requests of users who had already paid for the bandwidth in question, and that ISPs were trying to &#8220;double dip&#8221; and charge for the same bits twice.</p>
<p>The technical reality is a bit more complicated than that, though, and Netflix ended up paying what are called interconnect fees to facilitate the infrastructure necessary for the quick, consistent delivery of huge amounts of data. Netflix has said that this is basically a &#8220;fast lane&#8221; tax, but from the lack of chatter since the matter was settled back then, they seem to have chalked it up as the cost of doing business.</p>
<p>In a statement offered by its Korean subsidiary (reported in the same Korean Economic Daily story), Netflix said it &#8220;has not been paying network usage fees, or something equivalent to the fees claimed by SK Broadband, to any one of the ISPs in the world.&#8221; It&#8217;s not clear whether it classifies interconnect and caching as &#8220;equivalent&#8221; or whether these arrangements have changed; I&#8217;ve asked the company for clarification and will add it to the story if they respond.</p>
<p>In Korea, however, the issue is not so settled, and with huge growth there, the streaming sites would probably prefer not to have to pay fees proportionate to their success — hence the lawsuit. But the court&#8217;s recent decision put the ball back in their court, saying that &#8220;it needs to be determined by negotiations between the parties involved whether or not some fees will be paid.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s welcome news for the broadband providers, since any fee they negotiate will be higher than zero, which is what they were working with before. What sort of money they can possibly demand is a complete mystery, since the space is changing so quickly. And the court case, since it&#8217;s so unfavorable to some of the biggest companies in the world (which stand to make a mint in the voracious South Korean market), will almost certainly be taken up again. In the meantime consumers in the country may well see streaming prices go up — a tried and true method of whipping up a froth of consumer outrage.</p>
<p>The issue is far from settled in the U.S. and elsewhere, as with a new Democrat-led FCC there may also be a new push for strong net neutrality rules. Netflix had pushed for this sort of fee to be outlawed during the original net neutrality push, but ultimately the idea was abandoned (and would later be mooted anyway when the rules were rescinded). The argument over what ISPs can and can&#8217;t charge for, and who should pay, is an ongoing and global one.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="x9QraVbpFD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/streaming-services-face-their-real-test-in-2021/">Streaming services face their real test in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Streaming services face their real test in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/streaming-services-face-their-real-test-in-2021/embed/#?secret=x9QraVbpFD" data-secret="x9QraVbpFD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/korean-court-sides-against-netflix-opening-door-for-streaming-bandwidth-fees-from-isps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2170985</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MWC 2021 day one wrap-up</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/mwc-2021-day-one-wrap-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/mwc-2021-day-one-wrap-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 21:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lenovo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile World Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mwc 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“It is great that MWC is back,” Samsung UK’s James Kitto said, opening up this year’s presser. “And behalf of everyone at Samsung, it’s great to be back at MWC.” What, precisely, it means to be “back” in 2021 is another question entirely. Samsung was, of course, one of a number of major industry players [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">“It is great that MWC is back,” Samsung UK’s James Kitto said, opening up this year’s presser. “And behalf of everyone at Samsung, it’s great to be back at MWC.”</p>
<p>What, precisely, it means to be “back” in 2021 is another question entirely. Samsung was, of course, one of a number of major industry players who announced that they would not be exhibiting at this year’s Mobile World Congress in Barcelona. It was hard not to see an echo of last year’s event, when key players pulled out, one by one, forcing the GSMA to cancel the event altogether.</p>
<p>This year’s event is different for myriad reasons. For one thing, MWC’s traditional timeframe of late-February/early-March put the event directly in the crosshairs of COVID-19’s arrival in the EU. For another, this time out, the organizing body had another year to prepare.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">A look at Hall 3 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MWC21?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MWC21</a> for <a href="https://twitter.com/saschasegan?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@saschasegan</a> <a href="https://t.co/Z5V6MHqT4A">pic.twitter.com/Z5V6MHqT4A</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Sean Kinney (@seankinneyRCR) <a href="https://twitter.com/seankinneyRCR/status/1409417144681574400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 28, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The simplest route would have been to do what the CTA did with CES and go all-virtual. The first all-virtual CES had plenty of issues of course, but attempting an in-person element ahead of a widespread vaccine rollout in the U.S. would have, at best, complicated things by orders of magnitude.</p>
<p>COVID-19 <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/world/spain-covid-cases.html">continues to be a concern in Spain</a> – as with much of the world. The GSMA opted to go ahead with the event this year, however, after pushing MWC back several months from its standard dates. The company has implemented all sorts of safety measures, but judging from early videos taken at the event, social distancing ought not to prove an issue on the show floor this year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2170931" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2170931" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2170931" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/New-Unified-Platform-One-UI-Watch-App-Ecosystem.2021-06-28-11_55_13.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="576" /><p id="caption-attachment-2170931" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Samsung/Google</p></div></p>
<p>It seems safe to assume that most who are “attending” the event are doing so virtually – a list that includes the vendors themselves.</p>
<p>Samsung is among those high profile companies that presented a pre-recorded virtual press conference. Perhaps companies still see value in being attached to this sort of event even if it’s virtual, or maybe the on-going partnership with the organization is worth nurturing. The cynical part of me wonders how many of the sponsored sessions just couldn’t be reversed.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ECsupzeQmK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/samsung-and-google-detail-wearable-platform-ahead-of-next-galaxy-watch-launch/">Samsung and Google preview wearable platform ahead of next Galaxy Watch launch</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Samsung and Google preview wearable platform ahead of next Galaxy Watch launch&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/samsung-and-google-detail-wearable-platform-ahead-of-next-galaxy-watch-launch/embed/#?secret=ECsupzeQmK" data-secret="ECsupzeQmK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Samsung’s event was arguably the biggest of the day, but the presser felt like little more than a placeholder. The biggest news of the press conference was an expansion of a partnership Google announced at I/O last month, while much of the rest of the stream was pointing toward an Unpacked event happening later this summer.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171080" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171080" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2171080" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-1.48.31-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="536" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-1.48.31-PM.jpg 2318w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-1.48.31-PM.jpg?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-1.48.31-PM.jpg?resize=300,157 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-1.48.31-PM.jpg?resize=768,402 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-1.48.31-PM.jpg?resize=680,356 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-1.48.31-PM.jpg?resize=1536,804 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-1.48.31-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1073 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-1.48.31-PM.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171080" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Samsung</p></div></p>
<p>In fact, the event closed with a black and white slide reading “See you soon at the next Unpacked,” in case you didn’t get the hint. Bottom line: no hardware.</p>
<p>Lenovo, on the other hand, didn’t hold back. That’s due, in part, to the fact that the company releases a tremendous amount of hardware, so why not tie it to MWC, right?</p>
<p>The list of announcements inluces a new version of the Smart Clock Google Assistant alarm clock with a built-in wireless charging pads for phones and several tablets, including the Yoga Tab 11 and 13, which sport combination hanger/kickstand. The 13-inch system also doubles as an external monitor, which is when the kickstand really comes in handy.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171083" style="width: 735px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171083" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2171083" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/lenovo-clock-smart-clock-gen-2-subseries-hero.jpg" alt="" width="725" height="515" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/lenovo-clock-smart-clock-gen-2-subseries-hero.jpg 725w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/lenovo-clock-smart-clock-gen-2-subseries-hero.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/lenovo-clock-smart-clock-gen-2-subseries-hero.jpg?resize=300,213 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/lenovo-clock-smart-clock-gen-2-subseries-hero.jpg?resize=680,483 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/lenovo-clock-smart-clock-gen-2-subseries-hero.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 725px) 100vw, 725px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171083" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Lenovo</p></div></p>
<p>TCL got out ahead of the event early, with the announcement of <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/tcl-nxtwear-g-smart-glasses-and-multi-screen-collaboration-feature-announced-at-mwc-2021-301319326.html">NXTWEAR G</a> – a wearable OLED cinema display. The headmounted device approximates a 140-inch display with a 16:9 aspect ratio. The company also offered a better look at the 20 Pro 5G, which is coming to the States at just a dollar short of $500, featuring a snapdragon 750G processor and a headphone jack to boot.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171085" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171085" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171085 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/TCL_NEXTWEAR_G-e1624915903438.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="365" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/TCL_NEXTWEAR_G-e1624915903438.jpeg 1378w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/TCL_NEXTWEAR_G-e1624915903438.jpeg?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/TCL_NEXTWEAR_G-e1624915903438.jpeg?resize=300,161 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/TCL_NEXTWEAR_G-e1624915903438.jpeg?resize=768,412 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/TCL_NEXTWEAR_G-e1624915903438.jpeg?resize=680,365 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/TCL_NEXTWEAR_G-e1624915903438.jpeg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171085" class="wp-caption-text">TCL NEXTWEAR G</p></div></p>
<p>Those are your top line headlines for the show so far. The event runs through July 1st, so still plenty of show left, whether or not anyone will be there to see it in person.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/mwc-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/mwc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about Mobile World Congress 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/mwc-2021-day-one-wrap-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171077</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Demand Curve: Email marketing tactics that convert subscribers into customers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/demand-curve-email-marketing-tactics-that-convert-subscribers-into-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/demand-curve-email-marketing-tactics-that-convert-subscribers-into-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 21:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing tactics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2170787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Email has the highest return on investment than any other marketing channel because you have a captive audience who has opted-in to you communicating with them. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Stewart Hillhouse</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/stew_hillhouse">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Stewart Hillhouse writes actionable growth marketing insights as senior content lead at<a href="http://demandcurve.com/"> Demand Curve</a>. By night, he interviews marketers and creatives on his podcast,<a href="https://stewarthillhouse.com/tag/podcast/"> Top Of Mind</a>. Before getting into marketing, Stewart was a semi-professional lumberjack. He also writes at<a href="http://stewarthillhouse.com/"> stewarthillhouse.com</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Email has the highest return on investment of any other marketing channel. On average, email earns you $40 for every $1 spent. And the best part is that email is an owned channel, which means you can reach your subscriber directly instead of relying on social media algorithms to surface your content.</p>
<p>At <a href="http://demandcurve.com">Demand Curve</a>, we’ve worked with over 500 startups, meticulously documenting growth tactics for all growth channels. We also incorporate what we&#8217;ve learned from our agency, <a href="http://bellcurve.com">Bell Curve</a>, which works with Outschool, Imperfect Produce and Microsoft to name a few.</p>
<p>To understand how to use email marketing effectively, we interviewed email marketers at this year&#8217;s fastest-growing startups. This post covers the most profitable tactics they use that capture 80% of the value using 20% of the effort.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>If people don&#8217;t open it, nothing else matters</h2>
<p>The subject line of your email is the most important, yet most marketers neglect it until after crafting the body of the email.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			The subject line of your email is the most important, yet most marketers neglect it until after crafting the body of the email.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Increase the open-rate of your subject lines by making them self-evident. You don&#8217;t want people guessing why you want them to pay attention to your email. If the subject line is unclear or vague, your subscribers will ignore it.</p>
<p>One trick is to write like you speak. Try using subject lines that use informal language and contractions (it&#8217;s, they&#8217;re, you&#8217;ll). Not only will this save character count, it will also make your copy more friendly and quick to read.</p>
<p>Subject lines should be relevant to your subaudiences. Marketers generate 760% more revenue from segmented email campaigns than from untargeted emails.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2170792" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2170792" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2170792 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/1.png" alt="A good subject line will increase the chances of your email being read" width="1200" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/1.png 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/1.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/1.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/1.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/1.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/1.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2170792" class="wp-caption-text">A good subject line will increase the chances of your email being read. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re collecting emails from multiple areas on your website, chances are the context will be slightly different for each. For example, people who subscribe after reading an article on ketogenic diets should receive emails that further educate them on keto and seeds products relevant to that lifestyle. Sending them information and product recommendations for vegetarians would not be relevant and could lead to them unsubscribing.</p>
<p>To ensure you&#8217;re sending relevant emails to the right audiences, segment your audience using tags and filters within your email marketing platform. Each platform will do this slightly differently, but all modern platforms should allow you to do this. When crafting your email subject line, ask yourself: &#8220;Would this email make sense to receive for this segment of subscriber?&#8221;</p>
<p>Your subject lines should be short and concise. About 46% of all emails are opened on mobile devices, which means the subject line must be short enough to fit on a smaller screen while getting your point across. Fifty characters is approximately the maximum length a subject line can be before it gets cut off on a mobile screen.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Founders, help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Keeping your subject lines short also makes them easier to scan when your subscriber is looking through their inbox. Including emojis in your subject line can cut down your character count and emulates how friends send text messages to each other. Including emojis in your subject lines will make your email feel less corporate and more friendly.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2s2TZW5IWG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/klaviyo-ec1/">The Klaviyo EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Klaviyo EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/klaviyo-ec1/embed/#?secret=2s2TZW5IWG" data-secret="2s2TZW5IWG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Designing emails that get read</h2>
<p>Once your subscriber opens your email, there are three outcomes that can follow: read, skim or bounce.</p>
<p>Subscribers that read your emails are the most valuable, because they will consume the full contents of your email. Skimmers will only read the headlines and look at the images you include. Subscribers who bounce will open your email, but if nothing catches their attention right away, they will simply delete or close your email.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re going to want to design your emails to minimize the number of bouncers, satisfy readers and provide enough high-level information that skimmers still understand your message.</p>
<p>To minimize the number of bounces, choose an email design that catches the eye and is relevant to your brand. Take the Casper email below for example. The starry night background and moon illustration is directly relevant to the mattresses they sell. Visually branded email designs will help elevate your brand perception.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2170793" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2170793" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2170793 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/2.png" alt="Design your emails to appeal to all kinds of readers" width="1200" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/2.png 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/2.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/2.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/2.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/2.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/2.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2170793" class="wp-caption-text">Design your emails to appeal to all kinds of readers. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<p>To optimize for skimmers, write action-focused headlines. Use designs that draw the eye of your reader to key elements. As you can see in the Headspace example, the image of the rising sun pushes your gaze upward to the headline and the call-to-action button. Skimmers should be able to understand the context of the entire email and take action without needing to read the body.</p>
<p>To convert more readers, fulfill the expectation set by the subject line. Readers will be looking for any promises or hints you gave them in your subject line. Be sure to deliver on this promise in the body. Do so in an aggressively concise way — just because they&#8217;re reading doesn&#8217;t mean they don&#8217;t value their time.</p>
<h2>Call to actions that convert</h2>
<p>The goal of your body copy is to drive people to your call-to-action button (CTA). Your CTA is crucial, because it&#8217;s how you convert an email subscriber into a paying customer. To increase the conversion of your CTA, make a valuable promise in your body copy and headers that&#8217;s only delivered through your CTA.</p>
<p>Good CTA copy typically begins with a verb that teases what the reader will encounter next:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Get</strong> your free sample.</li>
<li><strong>Redeem</strong> discount now.</li>
<li><strong>Browse</strong> the full inventory.</li>
</ul>
<p>Low-converting CTA copy is vague or nonactive:</p>
<ul>
<li>Learn more.</li>
<li>See inventory.</li>
<li>Download.</li>
</ul>
<p>Your email should only have one CTA. Any more and your conversion will decrease due to unnecessary decision-making. Ensure that the page on your site that your CTA leads to fulfills the promise you made in your body and CTA button.</p>
<h2>Recap</h2>
<p>Once the focus of the subject line is clear and the desired outcome is chosen, everything else should be crafted to carry the reader step by step through the email, eventually taking them to the desired action.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a good idea to work backward from the desired outcome you want the reader to perform. If the desired outcome is for them to click on a CTA button, frame your subject line, headers and body copy as a valuable promise that can only be achieved by clicking the button.</p>
<p>Consider the experience of your email through the eyes of all three types of subscribers: readers, skimmers and bouncers. Use visual and written prompts that make the purpose of your email clear to all three categories. Failing to do so could lead to unsubscribes and lost revenue.</p>
<p>Email has the highest return on investment than any other marketing channel because you have a captive audience who has opted-in to you communicating with them. Email can drive six times more conversions that a Twitter post and is 40 times more likely to get noticed than a Facebook post.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EjhSvCtA6h"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-email-marketers-for-startups/">Help TechCrunch find the best email marketers for startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Help TechCrunch find the best email marketers for startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-email-marketers-for-startups/embed/#?secret=EjhSvCtA6h" data-secret="EjhSvCtA6h" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/demand-curve-email-marketing-tactics-that-convert-subscribers-into-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2170787</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
