<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:19:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Concreit closes on $6M to allow more people to invest in the global private real estate market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/concreit-closes-on-6m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/concreit-closes-on-6m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 12:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Concreit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dana Stalder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matrix Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Concreit, a company that wants to open real estate investing to a broader group of people, announced today that it has closed $6 million in a seed funding round led by Matrix Partners.  Hyphen Capital also participated in the round, in addition to individual investors such as Betterment founder and CEO Jon Stein; Andy Liu, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://concreit.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Concreit</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a company that wants to open real estate investing to a broader group of people, announced today that it has closed $6 million in a seed funding round led by Matrix Partners. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hyphen Capital also participated in the round, in addition to individual investors such as Betterment founder and CEO Jon Stein; Andy Liu, partner at Unlock Venture Partners; and investor and advisor Ben Elowitz. Concreit raised the capital at a</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> $22.5 million post-money valuation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Seattle-based startup also today launched its app, which it claims allows “anyone” to invest in the global private real estate market for as little as $1. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s a lofty claim. But first let’s start with some background.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Concreit is not the first time that co-founders Sean Hsieh and Jordan Levy have worked together. The pair previously founded and bootstrapped VoIP communications platform Flowroute before </span><a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2018/cloud-based-telecommunications-company-flowroute-acquired-west-corporation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">selling it to West Corp.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2018. Upon the sale of that company, Hsieh and Levy set out to build a company that, in their words, “could help everyday people become more financially secure.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hsieh, a second-generation immigrant, worked in his family’s restaurant where they shared the dream of achieving financial freedom through real estate. Similarly, Levy says he grew up watching his parents build a small construction business from scratch. He was intrigued by the idea of passive income through single-family rental homes but became disillusioned with the overhead, risk and hassle of managing one’s own single-family rental investments. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So the duo worked together to design a mobile-first offering that could enable small investors to benefit from real estate “without the burden of making repairs at 2 a.m. on a Saturday.” Enter Concreit. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="o8uvfJcjLp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/">10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/embed/#?secret=o8uvfJcjLp" data-secret="o8uvfJcjLp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, most investors can open a Concreit account and make their first investment in just minutes on their mobile device, the company claims. The company’s free mobile app allows consumers to invest as little as $1 into a fund managed by a team of investment professionals. Withdrawals can be requested at any time through the app and sent upon approval.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform facilitates weekly earned payouts, automated investments and on-demand withdrawals while compounding earned payouts weekly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After selling Flowroute, Hsieh says he “saw the opportunity to earn a great APR through private real estate investing while gaining less correlation with traditional public stocks or bonds markets,” Hsieh said. “But they were only for the already wealthy or required multiyear commitments of capital. Concreit gives everyone access to a real estate portfolio and the ability to have access to withdrawals when they need them.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Put simply, the startup wants to make it easy for anyone &#8212; not just the wealthy &#8212; to invest in real estate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Concreit, Hsieh said, offers “regular people” the ability to access real estate strategies typically used by large hedge funds and private equity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re seeing a surge of retail demand for alternatives and other ways to invest outside of the public markets and the crypto space for those that value diversification,” Hsieh told TechCrunch.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most other competitors are focused on marketing and selling securities, but we knew in order to be an innovator in this space we had to produce a truly unique experience for our investors.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Concreit’s platform is designed to be a more connected investment experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We knew early on that digital natives deserved a whole new real estate investing experience and that it had to be 100x better than just taking traditional real estate investment opportunities and offering them digitally,” Hsieh said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So on the platform side, Concreit has built a cloud-based proprietary securities accounting engine that allows the company to process fractional calculations and pull in a lot of mutual fund practices, applying them toward the “more labor-intensive” private equity markets, with a focus on real estate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We&#8217;ve taken a lot of the cloud-architectural work that we&#8217;ve pioneered in the telecommunications space and applied it towards a back-office accounting solution that gives us a competitive edge around what we offer to our investors,” Hsieh said. “This affords the ability to run accounting at a higher frequency, which is how we are able to run weekly dividends, process fractional redemptions and ultimately a more real-time experience for our users.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Concreit’s first private REIT fund, focused on passive income, consists of lower-risk fixed-income </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">private market residential and commercial real estate first-lien mortgages. The fund, which the</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> company says has an annualized return of 5.47%, is managed by a team of industry professionals. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup has added over 18,000 customers to its platform since it was qualified by the SEC (slightly over a year ago), and doubled its user base in the month of August.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“O</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ur current users can invest with any dollar amount, no lock-ups, weekly payouts, and an experience that’s as easy &amp; familiar as a savings account,” Hsieh said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Matrix’s </span><a href="https://matrixpartners.com/team/dana-stalder/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dana Stalder</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, who joined Concreit’s board as part of the financing, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> believes </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Concreit has leveled the playing field for real estate investing by making it more accessible. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What Concreit has built is incredibly hard to do from both a technology and regulatory standpoint,”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> he told TechCrunch. “Alternative asset classes, in particular, have been notoriously closed off to the average consumer, leaving high yield returns exclusively to wealthy investors. “</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XvH6YIZVbT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/hustle-fund-backs-fintor-which-wants-to-make-it-easier-to-invest-in-real-estate/">Hustle Fund backs Fintor, which wants to make it easier to invest in real estate</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hustle Fund backs Fintor, which wants to make it easier to invest in real estate&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/hustle-fund-backs-fintor-which-wants-to-make-it-easier-to-invest-in-real-estate/embed/#?secret=XvH6YIZVbT" data-secret="XvH6YIZVbT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/concreit-closes-on-6m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203461</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Zealand startup HeartLab raises $2.45M to bring heart scanning software to the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/new-zealand-startup-heartlab-raises-2-45m-to-bring-heart-scanning-software-to-the-u-s/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/new-zealand-startup-heartlab-raises-2-45m-to-bring-heart-scanning-software-to-the-u-s/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 12:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HealthTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heartlab]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Zealand-based medtech startup HeartLab has raised $2.45 million in seed funding that it says will help the company expand its AI-powered heart scanning and reporting platform to cardiologists in the United States by early next year. HeartLab provides an end-to-end solution for echocardiograms, the ultrasound tests that doctors use to examine a patient&#8217;s heart [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">New Zealand-based medtech startup HeartLab has raised $2.45 million in seed funding that it says will help the company expand its AI-powered heart scanning and reporting platform to cardiologists in the United States by early next year.</p>
<p dir="ltr">HeartLab provides an end-to-end solution for echocardiograms, the ultrasound tests that doctors use to examine a patient&#8217;s heart structure and function. Not only does the software help sort and analyze ultrasound images to help doctors diagnose cardiovascular disease, but it also streamlines the workflow by generating patient reports for doctors that can then be added to a patient&#8217;s health record.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Will Hewitt, 21, started HeartLab when he was 18 years old studying applied mathematics and statistics at the University of Auckland and working as a researcher at the Auckland Bioengineering Institute. The idea for the startup came to him as he listened to cardiologist, and now co-founder, Patrick Gladding explain how time-consuming and potentially inaccurate it is for doctors to have to review multiple scans manually everyday.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="A2aZQWeqV2"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/ai-is-ready-to-take-on-a-massive-healthcare-challenge/">AI is ready to take on a massive healthcare challenge</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AI is ready to take on a massive healthcare challenge&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/ai-is-ready-to-take-on-a-massive-healthcare-challenge/embed/#?secret=A2aZQWeqV2" data-secret="A2aZQWeqV2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;You&#8217;ve got a really repetitive manual task done by a highly trained professional,&#8221; Hewitt told TechCrunch. &#8220;To start with, we just decided to train the AI to do one really small part of the doctor&#8217;s job, which was to look at these scans and generate a couple of different measurements that normally the doctor would have to do themselves,&#8221; said Hewitt.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In order to replicate the tedious process that doctors were doing, HeartLab built its own in-house labeling tool with sonographers that includes step-by-step guides and prompts to collect data on a range of different measurements. Hewitt said this initiative was one of the most valuable efforts of engineering the company has invested in to date because it has lead to cross validation, which is used to test the ability of the machine learning model to predict new data, as well as flag problems like selection bias and overfitting.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Once HeartLab was able to successfully replicate the scanning process, the company worked to expand its services in a way that would relieve doctors of further admin minutiae so they could spend more time actually treating their patients. Usually, doctors use a software tool that analyzes the images, another that visualizes patterns and another that actually writes up the report, says Hewitt. HeartLab&#8217;s platform, called Pulse, can now condense those processes into one software.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">Cardiologists and sonographers at four different sites in New Zealand are trialing HeartLab&#8217;s tech now, which is also awaiting regulatory approval from the U.S.&#8217;s Food and Drug Administration. HeartLab anticipates FDA approval of Pulse by the first quarter of 2022, which is when the startup can begin selling the SaaS product.</p>
<p>&#8220;To begin with we want to talk to small and medium clinics over in the U.S.,&#8221; said Hewitt. &#8220;We&#8217;ve actually found that our products are most popular at those clinics because it replaces more software than at a larger clinic. At a larger clinic some of these bits of software they&#8217;ve already had to purchase, versus a smaller clinic, it&#8217;s stuff that they couldn&#8217;t access anyway. So when we get to the states, we want to start shipping mostly to those sorts of users while we work out how to best pitch our value proposition to the larger clinics.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hewitt says the funds from this round will also help the startup hire 10 more staff members to join the existing 13-member team based in Auckland. Having more tech talent on board will help HeartLab advance its product offering. At the moment, Pulse is at the point where it sees so many scans and takes so many measurements that it can get through the process quicker than a doctor could on their own and actually pick out patterns that a doctor wouldn&#8217;t see, according to Hewitt. The next step, which a good chunk of the seed funding is going toward, is how to be diagnostic about disease rather than just being able to indicate it.</p>
<p>&#8220;How do we actually provide something that normally doctors would have to order another scan for?&#8221; said Hewitt. &#8220;One of the key ideas with AI is you can create mappings from low-resolution images like ultrasounds. How can we try to learn a pattern from an ultrasound that&#8217;s similar to what you might see from an MRI, for example?&#8221;</p>
<p>If HeartLab can figure out how to glean advanced information from an echocardiogram instead of an MRI, it would be able to save hospitals, clinics and patients a lot of money. Each cardiac MRI can cost about <a href="https://www.acc.org/latest-in-cardiology/articles/2019/01/07/12/42/for-the-fits-the-future-of-cardiovascular-imaging-considerations-for-fits#:~:text=Each%20cardiac%20MRI%20scan%20can,times%20the%20cost%20of%20echocardiography.">$1,000 to $5,000</a>, which is about five times the price of an echocardiogram.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;d say the biggest challenge for us is, how can we transform from a company that at the moment can deliver products to a few local clinics successfully to actually building a product that scales and delivers a really good experience to lots of users and different hospitals?&#8221; said Hewitt.</p>
<p>Advancements in early diagnostics and imaging tech like HeartLabs&#8217; is causing an increased demand for such tools. As a result, the global <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/en/news-release/2020/12/09/2142533/0/en/AI-Enabled-Medical-Imaging-Solutions-Market-Size-To-Be-Worth-USD-4-720-6-Million-by-2027-Emergen-Research.html">AI-enabled medical imaging solutions market is expected to reach $4.7 billion by 2027</a>. By extending its reach to the U.S., where heart disease is the leading cause of death, HeartLab is poised to take a big piece of that pie.</p>
<p>In total, HeartLab has publicly raised about $3.2 million in funding, which includes a <a href="https://www.hinz.org.nz/news/531115/Health-AI-start-up-raises-1.1m.htm">pre-seed last October</a> of about $800,000 led by Icehouse Ventures with support from Founders Fund, the San Francisco-based VC firm that led the round announced on Thursday. Icehouse Ventures also contributed to the oversubscribed seed round, along with another New Zealand firm Outset Ventures and private investor and CEO of design platform Figma, Dylan Field.</p>
<p>“The use of AI in medicine is reducing pressures on health systems and ultimately saving lives,&#8221; said Founders Fund partner Scott Nolan, who has led investment rounds for three other New Zealand startups, in a statement. &#8220;The HeartLab team has built a really compelling AI-powered platform that doctors love to use.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/new-zealand-startup-heartlab-raises-2-45m-to-bring-heart-scanning-software-to-the-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203423</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SoftBank deepens commitment to LatAm with two new partners focused on early-stage investing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/softbank-deepens-commitment-to-latam-with-two-new-partners-focused-on-early-stage-investing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/softbank-deepens-commitment-to-latam-with-two-new-partners-focused-on-early-stage-investing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Remove From TC River]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marcelo Claure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In March 2019, SoftBank Group International made headlines when it announced the SoftBank Innovation Fund, which started out with a $2 billion commitment to invest in tech startups in Latin America. A lot has changed since then. SoftBank changed the name of the fund to the SoftBank Latin America Fund, or LatAm Fund for short. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In March 2019, SoftBank Group International made headlines when it announced </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the SoftBank Innovation Fund, which started out with </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/07/softbank-launches-the-innovation-fund-committing-2b-to-invest-in-latin-america/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a $2 billion commitment</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to invest in tech startups in Latin America.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A lot has changed since then. SoftBank changed the name of the fund to the SoftBank Latin America Fund, or LatAm Fund for short. The Japanese investment conglomerate has dramatically ramped up its investing in the region, and so have a number of other global investors. In fact, venture capitalists poured an estimated $6.2 billion into Latin American startups in the first half of 2021.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As evidence of its continued commitment to the region, SoftBank Group announced today that it has added two new managing partners to its LatAm Fund team: Rodrigo Baer and Marco Camhaji. The two will focus on “identifying and supporting” early-stage companies across the Latin American region, SoftBank told TechCrunch exclusively.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Baer and Camhaji will report to SoftBank Executive President &amp; COO Marcelo Claure, who points out that the firm’s LatAm fund has invested in more than two-thirds of the nearly two dozen </span><a href="https://lavca.org/latin-america-unicorn-leaderboard/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">unicorns</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> currently operating in the region. He said that SoftBank is today “one of the largest and most active” technology investors in the region.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0Ioft2N78r"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/why-global-investors-are-flocking-to-back-latin-american-startups/">Why global investors are flocking to back Latin American startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why global investors are flocking to back Latin American startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/why-global-investors-are-flocking-to-back-latin-american-startups/embed/#?secret=0Ioft2N78r" data-secret="0Ioft2N78r" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The move is significant in that the hires represent </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">an expansion of SoftBank LatAm Fund’s mandate and means that the firm is now backing companies at all stages in the region.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By bringing Baer and Camhaji on board, Claure said in a statement, SoftBank will “be better able to identify high-growth companies and support them at every step of their lifecycle.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SoftBank describes Baer as one of the pioneers of Brazil’s venture capital industry. He has invested in more than 20 companies since 2010. According to Crunchbase, he co-founded Warehouse Investimentos in 2010, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">where he led deal-sourcing efforts. He joined the investment team of Redpoint eVentures, a LatAm-based early-stage VC fund, in June 2014. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">He also was previously an engagement manager at McKinsey and worked at Aurora Funds, a healthcare-services focused fund based in the US. He is also active with Endeavor and multiple angel groups. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prior to joining SoftBank, Camhaji was a business development principal at Amazon, establishing strategic partnerships with fintechs in Latin America. He also served as the CEO of Adianta, a Brazilian B2B invoice financing company. Previously, Camahji was a founder and partner at Yellow Ventures, making seed investments in technology startups. He was also a partner and CFO of Redpoint eVentures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In August, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shu Nyatta, a managing partner at SoftBank who co-leads its $5 billion Latin America Fund, pointed out a dynamic that might seem obvious but is rarely articulated: Technology in LatAm is often more about </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">inclusion</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> rather than </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">disruption</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>“The vast majority of the population is underserved in almost every category of consumption. Similarly, most businesses are underserved by modern software solutions,” Nyatta told TechCrunch. “There’s so much to build for so many people and businesses. In San Francisco, the venture ecosystem makes life a little better for individuals and businesses who are already living in the future. In LatAm, tech entrepreneurs are building the future for everyone else.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some recent </span><a href="https://www.latinamericafund.com/portfolio"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SoftBank investments in the region</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/mexican-unicorn-kavak-raises-a-485m-series-d-at-a-4b-valuation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kavak</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a used car marketplace born in Mexico but now also operating in Brazil and Argentina. “Think of Carvana, but for emerging markets.”</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/colombian-on-demand-delivery-startup-rappi-raises-over-500m-at-a-5-25b-valuation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rappi</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, where “DoorDash-meets-Instacart,” operating across Latin America.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/20/sao-paulos-quintoandar-real-estate-platform-raises-120m-now-valued-at-5-1b/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">QuintoAndar</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a Brazilian real estate marketplace.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/brazilian-lending-company-creditas-raises-255-million-as-latin-americas-fintech-explosion-continues/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Creditas</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> unlocks the equity trapped in homes and cars and other important assets for Brazilians.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gympass-the-corporate-wellness-unicorn-raises-a-220m-series-e/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gympass</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a marketplace for fitness and wellness, provided through the enterprise to employees.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>As global investors continue to flood the region with capital, it&#8217;s clear that SoftBank is getting even more aggressive about backing startups in Latin America. Earlier this week, the firm also announced the launch of the SoftBank Latin America Fund II, its second dedicated private investment fund focused on tech companies located in LatAm, with an initial $3 billion commitment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MMpJvtIALL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/softbank-commits-3b-more-to-investing-in-latin-american-tech-companies/">SoftBank commits $3B more to investing in Latin American tech companies</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SoftBank commits $3B more to investing in Latin American tech companies&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/softbank-commits-3b-more-to-investing-in-latin-american-tech-companies/embed/#?secret=MMpJvtIALL" data-secret="MMpJvtIALL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/softbank-deepens-commitment-to-latam-with-two-new-partners-focused-on-early-stage-investing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197181</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alphabet&#8217;s Project Taara is beaming high-speed internet across the Congo River</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/alphabets-project-taara-is-beaming-high-speed-internet-across-the-congo-river/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/alphabets-project-taara-is-beaming-high-speed-internet-across-the-congo-river/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The high speed wireless optical link technology Alphabet originally developed for its shuttered Loon balloon company is currently being used for another moonshot called Project Taara.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mariella Moon</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mariella Moon is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/xiaomi-launches-its-own-smart-glasses-of-course/">Xiaomi launches its own smart glasses, of course</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/tesla-ordered-to-share-autopilot-data-with-the-us-traffic-safety-agency/">Tesla ordered to share Autopilot data with the US traffic safety agency</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Alphabet <a href="https://www.engadget.com/loon-shutdown-014334705.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">ended</a> Project Loon earlier this year, but the things it learned from the internet-broadcasting balloon initiative haven&#8217;t gone to waste. The high speed wireless optical link technology originally developed for Loon is currently being used for another moonshot called <a href="https://www.engadget.com/project-taara-fsoc-internet-alphabet-econet-liquid-telecom-africa-103541990.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">Project Taara</a>. In a new <a href="https://x.company/blog/posts/taara-beaming-broadband-across-congo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1">blog post</a>, Taara&#8217;s Director of Engineering, Baris Erkmen, has revealed that the initiative&#8217;s wireless optical communications (WOC) links are now beaming high-speed connectivity across the Congo River.</p>
<p>The idea for Taara started when the Loon team successfully used WOC to beam data between Loon balloons that were more than 100 kilometers apart. The team wanted to explore how the technology can be used on the ground. As part of the team&#8217;s exploration on WOC&#8217;s potential applications, they worked on bridging the connectivity gap between Brazzaville in the Republic of the Congo and Kinshasa in the Democratic Republic of Congo.</p>
<p>The two locations are separated by the Congo River and are only 4.8 kilometers apart. However, internet connectivity costs much, much more in Kinshasa, because providers will have to lay down enough fiber connection to cover 400 kilometers of ground around the river. What Project Taara did was install links that can beam high-speed connectivity from Brazzaville to Kinshasa across the river instead. Within 20 days and with 99.9 percent availability, the links served served nearly 700 TB of data.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203651" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/unnamed.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203651" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203651" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/unnamed.gif" alt="How Project Taara's optical beaming connectivity works" width="1024" height="819" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2203651" class="wp-caption-text">How Project Taara&#8217;s optical beaming connectivity works.</p></div></p>
<p>Taara&#8217;s WOC links work by seeking each other out and linking their beams of light together to create a high-speed internet connection. It&#8217;s not ideal for use in foggy locations, but Project Taara has developed network planning tools that can estimate WOC availability based on various factors like weather. In the future, the team will be able to use those tools to plan for the locations where Taara&#8217;s technology will work best.</p>
<p>Baris Erkmen, Director of Engineering for Taara, wrote in the post:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Better tracking accuracy, automated environmental responses and better planning tools are helping Taara&#8217;s links deliver reliable high-speed bandwidth to places that fiber can&#8217;t reach, and helping us connect communities that are cut off from traditional ways of delivering connectivity. We&#8217;re really excited about these advances, and are looking forward to building on them as we continue developing and refining Taara&#8217;s capabilities.&#8221;</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/alphabet-project-taara-high-speed-internet-congo-river-105835108.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/alphabets-project-taara-is-beaming-high-speed-internet-across-the-congo-river/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203650</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Byju&#8217;s acquires coding platform Tynker for $200 million in US expansion push</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/byjus-acquires-coding-platform-tynker-for-200-million-in-us-expansion-push/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/byjus-acquires-coding-platform-tynker-for-200-million-in-us-expansion-push/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 10:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[byju's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tynker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203622</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Byju’s said on Thursday it has acquired California-headquartered Tynker, a leading coding platform for K-12 students, the latest in a series of major purchases as the Indian edtech giant attempts to aggressively expand to international markets. The companies didn’t disclose the terms of the deal, but a person familiar with the matter told TechCrunch that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Byju’s said on Thursday it has acquired California-headquartered Tynker, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/05/31/tynker-raises-7-1m-to-expand-its-code-teaching-programs-to-new-schools-and-regions/">leading coding platform for K-12 students</a>, the latest in a series of major purchases as the Indian edtech giant attempts to aggressively expand to international markets.</p>
<p>The companies didn’t disclose the terms of the deal, but a person familiar with the matter told TechCrunch that the Indian firm is spending about $200 million on the acquisition.</p>
<p>Tynker, which counts BBC Learning, Google, Microsoft, Mattel and NASA among its partners, operates an eponymous coding platform. It has amassed over 60 million kids on its platform, Tynker founders told TechCrunch in an interview.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/05/15/tynker-a-startup-that-teaches-kids-to-code-now-works-with-robots-drones-and-more/">eight-year-old startup</a> gamifies the learning experience &#8212; using robots and drones, for instance, to help kids visualise complex concepts &#8212; to make it more exciting for them to participate. The startup has partnerships &#8212; and presence in &#8212; over 100,000 schools across 150 nations, said Srinivas Mandyam.</p>
<p>Mandyam, as well as Tynker&#8217;s other co-founders &#8212; Krishna Vedati and Kelvin Chong &#8212; will continue with the firm after the acquisition, they said. Vedati said in an interview that the startups began exploring ways to collaborate earlier this year.</p>
<p>“At Tynker, we believe that kids of all ages should develop the critical thinking skills needed to become the ‘makers of tomorrow’,” said Vedati, who serves as the startup&#8217;s chief executive.</p>
<p>“Our focus is on understanding what kids are passionate about – whether that’s building games, making animations or modding Minecraft – and we then create specific experiences, apps and personalized learning paths to empower them to create with code. We wholeheartedly believe that joining the BYJU’S family can help children on a global level develop the fundamental STEM skills that will serve them well as they progress in school and ultimately help prepare them for careers in both technical and non-technical fields.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Byju Raveendran, founder and chief executive of Byju&#8217;s, told TechCrunch in an interview that Tynker&#8217;s asynchronous offering fits perfectly in Byju&#8217;s current portfolio. India&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/ubs-investment-makes-byjus-the-most-valuable-startup-in-india/">most valuable startup</a> acquired WhiteHat Jr, a coding platform that offers synchronous classes, last year in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/indias-byjus-acquires-whitehat-jr-for-300-million/">a $300 million deal</a>. &#8220;Tynker&#8217;s offering is complimentary to WhiteHat Jr&#8217;s,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Tynker is the latest firm to be acquired by Byju&#8217;s, which has amassed over 100 million registered users &#8212; about 6.5 million of whom are paid customers &#8212; across the globe. The Bangalore-headquartered startup has this year also acquired Scholr, Aakash Institute, Hashlearn, Epic, and Great Learning for over $2 billion in cash and equity deals. Just last week it revealed that it had also purchased Times Internet-backed Gradeup for an undisclosed amount.</p>
<p>Raveendran said that Byju&#8217;s is continuing to explore more merger and acquisition opportunities. These acquisitions are helping Byju&#8217;s aggressively broaden its offerings and tap international markets in more meaningful ways, he said.</p>
<p>On the other side of the business, the Indian edtech giant &#8212; which has raised over $1.5 billion since the pandemic broke last year &#8212; is also beginning to explore an initial public offering. The startup has begun conversations with bankers, some of whom have given the firm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/bankers-chase-byjus-for-ipo-valuation-pegged-up-to-50-billion/">a proposed valuation of up to $50 billion</a>, TechCrunch reported first last month.</p>
<p>Raveendran confirmed that the &#8220;IPO is on the cards,&#8221; but said it&#8217;s too early to comment on a precise timeline.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/byjus-acquires-coding-platform-tynker-for-200-million-in-us-expansion-push/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203622</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Asian merchant commerce platform Pine Labs raises $100 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/asian-merchant-commerce-platform-pine-labs-raises-100-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/asian-merchant-commerce-platform-pine-labs-raises-100-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 10:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pine labs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pine Labs said on Thursday it has raised an additional $100 million, just weeks after securing $600 million in a financing round, as the Asian merchant commerce platform begins to explore the public markets. The U.S.-based investment management company Invesco Developing Markets Fund made the $100 million investment, the startup said in a statement. Pine [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Pine Labs said on Thursday it has raised an additional $100 million, just weeks after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/merchant-commerce-asian-giant-pine-labs-raises-600-million/">securing $600 million in a financing round</a>, as the Asian merchant commerce platform begins to explore the public markets.</p>
<p>The U.S.-based investment management company Invesco Developing Markets Fund made the $100 million investment, the startup said in a statement. Pine Labs, which started its journey in India, was valued at $3 billion in its July financing round.</p>
<p>Pine Labs, which counts Sequoia Capital India, Temasek, PayPal and Mastercard among its early backers, offers hundreds of thousands of merchants payments terminals, invoicing tools and working capital.</p>
<p>Its payments terminal — also known as point-of-sale machines — are connected to the cloud, and offer a range of additional services such as working capital — to the merchants. Pine Labs’s payments terminal has integration with over two dozen banks and financial and technology partners.</p>
<p>This differentiates Pine Labs from the competition, whose terminals typically have integration with just one bank. Each time a rival firm strikes a new partnership with a bank, they need to deploy new machines into the market. This makes the whole deployment expensive for both the fintech and the bank. (This is why you also often see a restaurant has multiple terminals at the check out.) The startup says it processes tens of billions of payment transactions.</p>
<p>“Over the last 18 months we have scaled our Prepaid Issuing stack, Online Payments, and also the Buy Now Pay Later (BNPL) offering. We continue to make progress in the larger Asian markets with our BNPL platform. Very excited to have a marquee investor like Invesco join us in the journey,” said B. Amrish Rau (pictured above), chief executive of Pine Labs, in a statement.</p>
<p>The startup is looking to file for an initial public offering within two years, Rau said in July. Indian newspaper Economic Times reported on Thursday that the company had hired Morgan Stanley and Goldman Sachs to advise the firm on the IPO.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The Invesco Developing Markets Fund is pleased to invest in Pine Labs, a leading fintech services company in India that fits our strategy of seeking high quality companies that have durable long-term growth potential,” said Justin Leverenz, CIO of Developing Markets Equities at Invesco, in a statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/asian-merchant-commerce-platform-pine-labs-raises-100-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203613</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Org nabs $20M led by Tiger Global to expand its platform based on public organizational charts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/the-org-nabs-20m-led-by-tiger-global-to-expand-its-platform-based-on-public-organizational-charts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/the-org-nabs-20m-led-by-tiger-global-to-expand-its-platform-based-on-public-organizational-charts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 09:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LinkedIn normalized the idea of making people&#8217;s resume&#8217;s visible to anyone who wanted to look at them, and today a startup that&#8217;s hoping to do the same for companies and how they are organized and run is announcing some funding. The Org, which wants to build a global, publicly-viewable database of company organizational charts &#8212; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">LinkedIn normalized the idea of making people&#8217;s resume&#8217;s visible to anyone who wanted to look at them, and today a startup that&#8217;s hoping to do the same for companies and how they are organized and run is announcing some funding. <a href="http://theorg.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Org</a>, which wants to build a global, publicly-viewable database of company organizational charts &#8212; and then utilize that database as a platform to power a host of other services &#8212; has raised $20 million, money that it will be using to hire more people, add on more org charts, and launch new features, with a recruitment toolkit being first on the list.</p>
<p>The Series B is led by Tiger Global, with previous backers Sequoia, Founders Fund, and Balderton Capital also participating alongside new investors Thursday Ventures, Lars Fjeldsoe-Nielsen (a former Balderton partner), Neeraj Arora (formative early WhatsApp exec), investor Gavin Baker, and more.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> From what we understand, the investment values The Org at $100 million.</span></p>
<p>Founders Fund led the company&#8217;s last round, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/the-org-nabs-8-5m-led-by-founders-fund-to-build-a-global-database-of-company-org-charts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Series A in February 2020</a>, and the whole world of work has really changed a lot in the interim because of Covid-19: companies have become more distributed (a result of offices shutting down); the make-up of businesses has changed because of new demands; many of us have had our sense of connection to our jobs tested in ways that we never thought it would.</p>
<p>All of that has had a massive impact on The Org, and has definitely played into its theory of why org charts are useful, and most useful as a tool for transparency.</p>
<p>&#8220;In many ways the pandemic has forced us to reevaluate the norms of how work happens. One of the misconceptions was the idea that you are only working when you are at the office, 9-5. But the future of work is a hybrid set up but you get a lot of issues that arise out of that, communication being one of them. Now it&#8217;s much more important to create alignment, a sense of connection, and really feeling a sense of belonging in your company,&#8221; Christian Wylonis, the CEO who co-founded the company with Andreas Jarbøl, said in an interview. &#8220;We think that a lot of these issues are rooted around transparency and that is what The Org is about. Who is doing what, and why?&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2203611" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/20210304-DSC00001.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/20210304-DSC00001.jpg 9021w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/20210304-DSC00001.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/20210304-DSC00001.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/20210304-DSC00001.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/20210304-DSC00001.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/20210304-DSC00001.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/20210304-DSC00001.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/20210304-DSC00001.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>He said that when the coronavirus suddenly ramped up a global issue &#8212; and it really was sudden; our conversation in February 2020 had nothing whatsoever to do with it, yet it was only weeks later that everything shut down &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t obvious that The Org would have a place in the so-called &#8220;new normal.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We were as nervous as anyone else, but the idea of what work would look like and how we enable people around that has gotten a lot higher on the agenda,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The appetite for new tools has improved dramatically, and we can see that in our traffic.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Org has indeed seen some very impressive growth. The company now hosts some 130,000 public org charts, sees 30,000 daily visitors, and has more than 120,000 registered users. And more casual usage has boomed, too. Wylonis notes that The Org now has close to 1 million visitors each month versus just 100,000 in February 2020, when it only had 16,000 org charts on its platform.</p>
<p>Monetization is coming slowly for the startup. Building, editing and officially &#8220;claiming&#8221; a profile on the platform are all still free, but in the meantime The Org is working on its platform play and using the database that it is building to power other services. Job hunting is the first area that it will tackle. Posting jobs will be free, and it&#8217;s integrating with Greenhouse to feed information into its system, but recruiters and HR pro&#8217;s are given an option to manage the sourcing and screening process through The Org, a kind of executive recruitment tool, which will come at a charge. Down the line there are plans for more communications and HR tools, Wylonis said. Some of this will be built by way of integrations and APIs with other services, and some tools &#8212; such as communications features &#8212; will be built in-house, from the ground up.</p>
<p>When I covered the company&#8217;s last round, I&#8217;d noted that there were some obvious hurdles for The Org, as well as others building business models on providing more transparency and information around hiring and how companies are run. Sometimes the companies in question don&#8217;t actually <em>want</em> to have more transparency. And any database that is based around self-reporting runs the risk of being only as good as the data that is put into it &#8212; meaning it may be incomplete, or simply wrong, or just presented to the contributors&#8217; best advantage, not that of the company itself. (This is one of the issues with LinkedIn, too: even with people&#8217;s resumes being public, it&#8217;s still very easy to lie about what you actually do, or have done.)</p>
<p>So far, the theory is that some of this will be resolved by way of who The Org is targeting and how it is growing. Today the company&#8217;s &#8220;sweet spot&#8221; is early-stage startups with about 50-200 employees, and generally org charts are created for these businesses in part by The Org itself, and then largely by way of wiki-style user-edited content (anyone with a company email can get involved).</p>
<p>The plan is both to continue working with those smaller startups as they scale up, but also target bigger and bigger businesses. These however can be trickier to snag &#8212; not least because they will stretch into the realm of public companies, but also because their charts will be more complicated to map and manage consistently. For that reason, The Org is also adding in more features around how companies can &#8220;claim&#8221; their profiles, including managing permissions for who can edit profiles.</p>
<p>This might mean more managed public profiles, but the idea is that it will be a start, and once more companies post more information, we will see more transparency overall, not unlike how LinkedIn evolved, Wylonis said.</p>
<p>The LinkedIn analogy is interesting for another reason. It seems a no-brainer that LinkedIn, which is at its heart a massive database of information about the world of professional work, and the people and companies involved in it, would have wanted to build its own version of org charts at some point. And yet it hasn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>Some of this might be down to how LinkedIn has fundamentally built and organised its own database and knowledge graph, but Wylonis believes it might also be a conceptual difference.</p>
<p>&#8220;We think that this might be the fundamental difference between us and them,&#8221; Wylonis said of LinkedIn. &#8220;They are a database of resumes. &#8216;I can say whatever I want.&#8217; But for us, the atomic unit is the organization itself. That is an important distinction because it’s a one to many relationship. It can’t be only me editing my profile. And allows us to build structures.&#8221;</p>
<p>He added that this was one of the reasons that Rabois &#8212; who was an early exec at LinkedIn &#8212; became an early investor in The Org: &#8220;LinkedIn has been looking at this forever, but they haven’t been able to build it, and so that is how we caught his attention.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/the-org-nabs-20m-led-by-tiger-global-to-expand-its-platform-based-on-public-organizational-charts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203603</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Volta Trucks raises €37 million to bring electric delivery trucks to the streets of London and Paris</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/volta-trucks-raises-e37-million-to-bring-16-ton-electric-truck-to-the-streets-of-london-and-paris/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/volta-trucks-raises-e37-million-to-bring-16-ton-electric-truck-to-the-streets-of-london-and-paris/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 09:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric trucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proterra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volta trucks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trucking tends to be associated with highways, but it’s not uncommon to find large delivery vehicles trundling down the tightly packed streets of the world’s most populated cities. According to EV startup Volta Trucks, that’s far from ideal: in London, large commercial vehicles cause around 26% of pedestrian fatalities and around 80% of cyclist fatalities, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Trucking tends to be associated with highways, but it’s not uncommon to find large delivery vehicles trundling down the tightly packed streets of the world’s most populated cities. According to EV startup Volta Trucks, that’s far from ideal: in London, large commercial vehicles cause around 26% of pedestrian fatalities and around 80% of cyclist fatalities, and account for an outsized portion of carbon emissions.</p>
<p>Volta’s solution is to electrify and redesign the large cargo vehicle &#8212; called Heavy Goods Vehicles (HGVs) in Europe &#8212; for middle- and last-mile delivery in urban centers. “The traditional design of trucks and city centers really don&#8217;t work together, but you can&#8217;t just ban trucks from city centers,” a company spokesperson told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Volta Trucks has raised a €37 million ($44 million) funding round to accelerate its plans, starting with a fleet of pilot vehicles in London and Paris.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="k99YUWlb5N"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/the-debut-of-electric-pickups-signals-a-new-ev-era/">The debut of electric pickups signals a new EV era</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The debut of electric pickups signals a new EV era&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/the-debut-of-electric-pickups-signals-a-new-ev-era/embed/#?secret=k99YUWlb5N" data-secret="k99YUWlb5N" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The round was led by New York-based Luxor Capital Group and returning investor Byggmästare Anders J Ahlström Holding of Stockholm. New investors included U.S. electric truck and battery manufacturer Proterra and supply chain management company Agility.</p>
<p>The idea for the company came to Volta co-founder and Swedish serial entrepreneur Carl-Magnus Norden when Elon Musk revealed the Tesla Model 3. Norden realized that there was very little equivalent movement to electrify the world of commercial vehicles, despite the fact that they produce a large share of carbon emissions.</p>
<p>Four years later, Volta (not to be confused with Volta Charging, the European EV charging station company) has come up with a truck that gives the driver a 220-degree view, similar to what one might see on a city bus. The driver’s seat is also in the center of the cab. On the inside of the 16-ton truck, called Volta Zero, will sit a single unit containing an electric motor, transmission and rear axle supplied by OEM supplier Meritor. This unit, called an eAxle, leaves more space between the chassis rails for the battery.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l0N6FgmPODk" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Those batteries will have a 95- to 120-mile range and will be designed by Proterra, a supplier (and now investor) that Volta says will be able to furnish batteries into the longer term and at higher production levels. Volta is imagining that it will produce up to 5,000 trucks by the end of 2023, 14,000 to 15,000 by 2024, and 27,000 trucks by 2025.</p>
<p>Volta plans to also offer a “truck as a service” model, which is a leasing agreement including insurance, charging infrastructure, service repair and maintenance. While Volta also plans on selling trucks outright, the spokesperson said the company anticipates the leasing model will make up 50%, and as high as 80%, of its business.</p>
<p>Volta is gearing up to launch a fleet of six R&amp;D vehicles in London and Paris at the beginning of the year. These trucks will be used for internal validation. The company plans to start about a 33-vehicle pilot program with customers in two major European cities by the middle of next year.</p>
<p>The plan is that this will allow Volta to start full-scale production by the end of 2022. All of the vehicles, with the exception of the six beta trucks, will be manufactured by Steyr Automotive in Austria. The two announced the manufacturing agreement last week.</p>
<p>Volta says it has letters of intent for 2,500 trucks. The goal is to convert these to binding deposit-led orders as Volta moves closer to series production. This round now brings its total funding to date to around €60 million ($71 million).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/volta-trucks-raises-e37-million-to-bring-16-ton-electric-truck-to-the-streets-of-london-and-paris/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203367</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gogoro will go public on Nasdaq after $2.35B SPAC deal</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/gogoro-will-go-public-on-nasdaq-after-2-35b-spac-deal/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/gogoro-will-go-public-on-nasdaq-after-2-35b-spac-deal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 08:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gogoro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poema Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taiwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gogoro is going public. The company, which is best known for its electric Smartscooters and swappable battery infrastructure, announced today it will list on Nasdaq through a merger with Poema Global, a SPAC affiliated with Princeville Capital. The deal sets Gogoro’s enterprise valuation at $2.35 billion and is targeted to close in the first quarter [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.gogoro.com/">Gogoro</a> is going public. The company, which is best known for its electric Smartscooters and swappable battery infrastructure, announced today it will list on Nasdaq through a merger with <a href="https://www.poema-global.com/">Poema Global</a>, a SPAC affiliated with Princeville Capital. The deal sets Gogoro’s enterprise valuation at $2.35 billion and is targeted to close in the first quarter of 2022. The combined company will be known as Gogoro Inc and trade under the symbol GGR.</p>
<p>Assuming no redemptions, Gogoro anticipates making $550 million in proceeds, including an oversubscribed PIPE (private investment in public equity) of over $250 million and $345 million held in trust by Poema Global. Investors in the PIPE include strategic partners like Hon Hai (Foxconn) Technology Group and GoTo, the Indonesian tech giant created through the merger of Gojek and Tokopedia, and new and existing investors like Generation Investment Management, Taiwan’s National Development Fund, Temasek and Dr. Samuel Yin of Ruentex Group, Gogoro’s founding investor.</p>
<p>The capital will be used on Gogoro’s expansion in China, India and Southeast Asia and further development of its tech ecosystem.</p>
<p>Founded ten years ago in Taiwan, Gogoro’s technology includes smart swappable batteries and their charging infrastructure and cloud software that monitors the condition and performance of vehicles and batteries. Apart from its own brands, including Smartscooters and Eeyo electric bikes, Gogoro also makes its platform available through its Powered by Gogoro Network (PBGN) program, which enables partners to create vehicles that use Gogoro’s batteries and swapping stations.</p>
<p>Gogoro’s SPAC deal comes a few months after it announced major partnerships in China and India. In China, it is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/gogoros-electric-vehicle-technology-will-make-its-china-debut-through-a-deal-with-yadea-and-dcj/">working with Yadea and DCJ to build a battery-swapping network</a>, and in India, Hero MotoCorp, one of the world’s largest two-wheel vehicle makers,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/gogoro-partners-with-indias-hero-motocorp-one-of-the-worlds-largest-two-wheel-vehicle-makers/"> will launch scooters based on Gogoro’s tech</a>. It also has deals with manufacturers like Yamaha, Suzuki, AeonMotor, PGO and CMC eMOVING.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QRoLKQ4YWU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/gogoros-electric-vehicle-technology-will-make-its-china-debut-through-a-deal-with-yadea-and-dcj/">Gogoro strikes deal with Yadea and DCJ to build a battery-swapping network in China</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gogoro strikes deal with Yadea and DCJ to build a battery-swapping network in China&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/gogoros-electric-vehicle-technology-will-make-its-china-debut-through-a-deal-with-yadea-and-dcj/embed/#?secret=QRoLKQ4YWU" data-secret="QRoLKQ4YWU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>With these partnerships in place, “we really now need to take our company to the next level,” founder and chief executive officer Horace Luke told TechCrunch. Gogoro decided to go the SPAC route because “you can talk a lot deeper about what the business opportunity is, what the structure is, what the partnerships are, so you can properly value a company rather than a quick roadshow. Given our business plans, it gives us a great opportunity to focus on the expansion,” he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>One of the reasons Gogoro decided to work with Poema is because “their thesis is quite aligned with ours,” said Bruce Aitken, Gogoro’s chief financial officer. “They have, for example, a sustainability fund, so our passion for green and sustainability merges well with that.”</p>
<p>Gogoro says that in less than five years, it has accumulated more than $1 billion in revenue and more than 400,000 subscribers for its battery swapping infrastructure. The company will launch its China pilot program in Hangzhou in the fourth-quarter of this year, followed by about six more cities next year. In India, Hero MotoCorp is currently developing its first Gogoro-powered vehicle and will begin deploying its battery-swapping infrastructure in New Delhi in 2022.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="V1NOeXUkTP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/gogoro-partners-with-indias-hero-motocorp-one-of-the-worlds-largest-two-wheel-vehicle-makers/">Gogoro partners with India&#8217;s Hero MotoCorp, one of the world&#8217;s largest two-wheel vehicle makers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gogoro partners with India&#8217;s Hero MotoCorp, one of the world&#8217;s largest two-wheel vehicle makers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/gogoro-partners-with-indias-hero-motocorp-one-of-the-worlds-largest-two-wheel-vehicle-makers/embed/#?secret=V1NOeXUkTP" data-secret="V1NOeXUkTP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We see the demand in China as a lot bigger than we first anticipated, so that’s all good news for us, and that’s one of the fundamental reasons why we need to go public because we need to raise the capital and resources needed for us to actually contribute in a big way to these markets,” said Luke.</p>
<p>When asked if Gogoro is planning to strike a similar partnership with GoTo to expand into Southeast Asia, Luke said the “important thing is to recognize that Southeast Asia is the third-largest market outside of China and India for two-wheelers. Gogoro has always had the vision to go after these big markets. GoTo, being a great success in Indonesia, their investment in Gogoro will start conversations, but there isn’t anything to announce at this point other than that they’re joining the PIPE.”</p>
<p>In a press statement, Poema Global CEO Homer Sun said, “We believe the technology differentiation Gogoro has developed in combination with the world-class partnerships it has forged will drive significant growth opportunities in the two largest two-wheeler markets in the world. We are committed with working alongside Gogoro’s outstanding management team to support its geographic expansion plans and its transition to a Nasdaq-listed company.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HrYpD87cr0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/almost-everything-you-need-to-know-about-spacs/">Almost everything you need to know about SPACs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Almost everything you need to know about SPACs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/almost-everything-you-need-to-know-about-spacs/embed/#?secret=HrYpD87cr0" data-secret="HrYpD87cr0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/gogoro-will-go-public-on-nasdaq-after-2-35b-spac-deal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203580</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>African genomics startup 54gene raises $25M to expand precision medicine capabilities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/african-genomics-startup-54gene-raises-25m-to-expand-precision-medicine-capabilities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/african-genomics-startup-54gene-raises-25m-to-expand-precision-medicine-capabilities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 08:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[54gene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genomics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[precision medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole-genome sequencing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Less than 3% of genetic material used in global pharmaceutical research is from Africa. The staggering gap is quite surprising because Africans and people of African descent are reported to be more genetically diverse than any other population. Since launching in 2019, African genomics startup 54gene has been at the forefront of bridging this divide [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Less than 3% of genetic material used in global pharmaceutical research is from Africa. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The staggering gap is quite surprising because Africans and people of African descent </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are reported </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to be more </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">genetically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> diverse than any other population</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since launching in 2019, African genomics startup <a href="https://54gene.com/">54gene</a> has been at the forefront of bridging this divide in the global genomics market</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Today, the company has secured $25 million in Series B funding to bolster its efforts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This round comes a year after the company, founded by Dr Abasi Ene-Obong, raised $15 million in Series A and two years after closing a $4.5 million seed round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In total, 54gene has raised more than $45 million since its </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">inception</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the world&#8217;s analyzed genomes coming mostly from anywhere that isn&#8217;t Africa, the continent remains a valuable source of new genetic information for health and drug discovery research</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is where 54gene&#8217;s work is relevant. The company conducts and leverages this research to ensure Africans are recipients of upcoming drug and medical discoveries</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year when we covered the company last year, CEO Ene-Obong disclosed that for 54gene to conduct this research, it recruits voluntary participants who donate genetic samples via swab or blood tests</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It still very much works this way. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, instead of depending on third-party health centres like hospitals and sending the samples abroad for analysis, 54gene <a href="https://www.illumina.com/company/news-center/feature-articles/54gene-Uses-Illumina-Sequencing-to-Create-World-Class-Facility.html">launched its own genetics sequencing and microarray lab</a> in Lagos last September</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The company did this in partnership with U.S.-based biotech company Illumina.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speaking with TechCrunch, Ene-Obong says </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to the genotyping capabilities offered, the lab also provides whole-genome sequencing (WGS) and whole-exome sequencing (WES)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not to bore you with the jargon but here&#8217;s why this is important. Genotyping tends to show only 0.02% of an individual&#8217;s DNA; however</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, WGS can show almost 100% of the same person&#8217;s DNA.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For WES, although it represents only 1.5% of the human genome, it shows approximately 85% of known disease-related variants.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With these three in place, the company can advance genomics research and expand its ability to help scientists and researchers in Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike fintech and other fast-moving sectors like e-commerce, innovation in healthtech takes some time to take shape finally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. 54gene is one of the few startups in the sector and even in Africa to have moved from seed stage to Series B in under two years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s this sort of frightening speed that makes one wonder what the company is doing right. So I ask the CEO whether the company </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is indeed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> seeing significant progress in advancing African genomics; he answers in the affirmative.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Though the arc of conducting early research through drug approval can be long in biotech, we have taken the approach to building the backbone that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is needed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for short-term successes to long-term gains that provide better healthcare delivery and treatment outcomes from diseases,&#8221; he added</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to setting its first lab, the CEO says the company increasing its biobanking capacity by 5x and is counts that as a major success.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During its last raise, 54gene had a biobank capacity for 60,000 samples. If Ene-Obong comments are anything to go by, the two-year-old company currently has a biobank capacity for 300,000 samples, close to its longer-term aim to manage up to 500,000.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another one is the recruitment and training of talent to generate and process data needed to produce insights for the company&#8217;s drug discovery efforts</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nigeria has </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">a dearth of experienced clinicians and with the remaining few leaving in droves, it is not hard to see why it is a win for the company. Knowing this, 54gene plans to use part of the new funding to recruit and train more professionals</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other use of funding will be to expand</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> its capabilities in sequencing, target identification and validation, and precision medicine clinical trials</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Also of great importance is its expansion across the African continent.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">54gene will have to sign off partnerships to aid this expansion. A recent partnership was made between the company and the Tanzania Human Genetics Organization and Ene-Obong says </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">54gene is in varying stages of conversations with more partners. However, he was tight-lipped on who they might be.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are excited</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about our Africa-first approach which will see us expand to countries within East and West Africa in the coming year,&#8221; he added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">54gene made some hires to this end: Michelle Ephraim, Colm O&#8217;Dushlaine, Peter Fekkes, Teresia Bost, Jude Uzonwanne &#8212; </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">all of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> who have decades of experience working with companies like Leica Biosystems, Regeneron Genetic Center, Novartis, Celgene, and the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pan-African venture capital firm Cathay AfricInvest Innovation Fund led this round. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lead investor from the company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/14/african-genomics-startup-54gene-raises-15m-led-by-adjuvant-capital/">Series A funding</a>, Adjuvant Capital invested once again with participation from other VCs including KdT Ventures, Plexo Capital, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Endeavor</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Catalyst, and Ingressive Capital</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6fFAEF25Gz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/14/african-genomics-startup-54gene-raises-15m-led-by-adjuvant-capital/">African genomics startup 54gene raises $15M led by Adjuvant Capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;African genomics startup 54gene raises $15M led by Adjuvant Capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/14/african-genomics-startup-54gene-raises-15m-led-by-adjuvant-capital/embed/#?secret=6fFAEF25Gz" data-secret="6fFAEF25Gz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/african-genomics-startup-54gene-raises-25m-to-expand-precision-medicine-capabilities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203564</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tanso nabs $1.9M pre-seed to help industrial manufacturers do sustainability reporting</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/tanso-nabs-1-9m-pre-seed-to-help-industrial-manufacturers-do-sustainability-reporting/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/tanso-nabs-1-9m-pre-seed-to-help-industrial-manufacturers-do-sustainability-reporting/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 08:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon offset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early-stage startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[munich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Picus Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability reporting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tanso]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UVC Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203033</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The climate crisis is creating massive demand for data capture as industries grapple with how to decarbonize. Put simply, you can&#8217;t cut your carbon emissions if don&#8217;t know what they are in the first place. This need to gather data is a big opportunity for startups &#8212; and a wave of early companies have already [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The climate crisis is creating massive demand for data capture as industries grapple with how to decarbonize. Put simply, you can&#8217;t cut your carbon emissions if don&#8217;t know what they are in the first place.</p>
<p>This need to gather data is a big opportunity for startups &#8212; and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/a-growing-number-of-startups-are-creating-apis-to-assess-and-offset-corporate-carbon-emissions/">a wave of early companies</a> have already been founded to try to plug the sustainability data gap, through things like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/a-growing-number-of-startups-are-creating-apis-to-assess-and-offset-corporate-carbon-emissions/">APIs </a>to assess emissions for carbon offsetting (which in turn has led to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/sylvera-grabs-seed-backing-from-index-to-help-close-the-accountability-gap-around-carbon-offsetting/">other startups trying to tackle the data gap around offsetting projects</a>&#8230;).</p>
<p>One thing is clear: Requirements for sustainability reporting are only going to get broader and deeper from here on in.</p>
<p>Munich-based <a href="https://www.tanso.io">Tanso</a> is an early stage startup (founded this year) that&#8217;s building software to support sustainability reporting for a particular sector (industrial manufacturers) &#8212; with the goal of creating a data management system that can automate data capture and sustainability reporting geared towards the specific needs of the sector.</p>
<p>The startup says it decided to focus on industrial manufacturing because it&#8217;s both an emissions-heavy sector and underserved with supportive digital tech vs many other industries.</p>
<p>The founders met during their studies at universities in Munich and Zurich &#8212; where they&#8217;d been researching the assessment of organizational climate impact. Their collective expertise crystalized into the realization of a business opportunity to build a data management system for a notoriously polluting sector that&#8217;s facing a mandate to change.</p>
<p>In the coming years, European regulations will expand sustainability reporting requirements &#8212; with the EU&#8217;s &#8216;Green Deal&#8217; plan setting an overarching goal of Europe becoming the first &#8220;climate-neutral&#8221; continent by 2050.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Specific (existing) reporting requirements within the bloc include the EU Corporate Sustainability Reporting Directive (CSRD), which will apply to more than 50,000 companies &#8212; requiring they report on their sustainability metrics, starting in 2023.</p>
<p>The UK (now outside the EU) already introduced some reporting requirements for domestic companies, under the Streamlined Energy and Carbon Reporting (SECR) regulation, which has applied since 2019 and applies to over 12,000 businesses in the UK in varying degrees of detail depending on the size of the company.</p>
<p>So there is a clear direction of travel in the region requiring businesses to gather and report sustainability data.</p>
<p>Tanso has just closed a $1.9 million pre-seed raise with the aim of getting its data management support software to market in time for an expected surge in demand as sustainability regulations like CSRD start to bite.</p>
<p>The raise is led by German early stage b2b fund UVC Partners, with participation from Picus Capital, Possible Ventures, and a number of business angels.</p>
<p>Tanso is still in the R&amp;D/product development phase, with co-founder Gyri Reiersen telling TechCrunch it&#8217;s currently working with a number of manufacturers to &#8220;figure out the sweet spot&#8221; for automating data gathering so it can come to market with a scalable product offering. She says the team raised a relatively large pre-seed exactly to see it through until it&#8217;s got something fit to launch (it&#8217;s hoping to have something &#8220;solid, verified and scalable&#8221; by the end of 2022, per Reiersen).</p>
<p>The goal for the product is a single platform that gathers and holds all the customer&#8217;s sustainability data and can automate the generation of reports to meet regulatory requirements &#8212; including auditing.</p>
<p>From 2025, Reiersen points out that CSRD reporting needs to be &#8220;auditable&#8221;, meaning that you have to have &#8220;some form of transparency and traceability&#8221;; and also that the &#8220;correctness&#8221; of sustainability reporting will be a C-Suite responsibility. So that must concentrate boardroom minds.</p>
<p>&#8220;Going beyond that it&#8217;s all about how can you use this data and the insights that the data gives you to make predictions and models going forward for how should we develop our products? What makes sense to do going forward to make?&#8221; she adds.</p>
<p>&#8220;What we&#8217;re prototyping currently is to streamline the workflow of information gathering,&#8221; Reiersen also tells us, discussing the product dev process. &#8220;Also to have really good, fundamental user-flow for the users to use our product. And then doing the deep dives on integrations over time.&#8221;</p>
<p>She says the challenge is finding the trade-off between usability and &#8220;digging into the data&#8221;. &#8220;For us it&#8217;s very important to have a scalable product, especially having it fully scalable from 2023 when the CSRD are started because then there will be desperation on the market. Companies will need to have something,&#8221; she adds.</p>
<p>&#8220;We need to have these solutions&#8230; that take one step in the right direction for all companies and not just have a couple of carbon neutral companies&#8230; So for us it&#8217;s more about finding the productizable use-cases in the beginning to make this a scalable product.&#8221;</p>
<p>But she also warns over a proliferation of overly &#8220;shallow&#8221; offerings in the space &#8212; driven by marketing-led &#8216;greenwashing&#8217; (and bogus carbon offsetting) rather than a genuine desire to correctly identify the problem and course-correct which is what&#8217;s actually needed for humanity to avert climate disaster.</p>
<p>Reiersen adds that she got really interested in this space through her university work researching the overestimation of carbon offsets through deep learning.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is such a need for accountability and making sure that the product that is being developed actually do their job correctly. Because it&#8217;s so easy to just have a black box and trust it. We can&#8217;t afford having systems that overestimate or underestimate. It needs to be accurate and it needs to be validated,&#8221; she says.</p>
<p>&#8220;Going forward accuracy will mean more and more and then you need to access the &#8216;real data&#8217; and not just &#8216;guestimations&#8217;,&#8221; she predicts. &#8220;And that&#8217;s where we see that of course we need to be very front-end/UX-friendly, and making it easy for people to enter the right data and have a very user-friendly, usable product and that people are guided through the process of gathering the right data&#8230; but also over time really focusing on how do you integrate and get access to the data at the data-base level?&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FOMBw8DtP3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/sylvera-grabs-seed-backing-from-index-to-help-close-the-accountability-gap-around-carbon-offsetting/">Sylvera grabs seed backing from Index to help close the accountability gap around carbon offsetting</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sylvera grabs seed backing from Index to help close the accountability gap around carbon offsetting&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/sylvera-grabs-seed-backing-from-index-to-help-close-the-accountability-gap-around-carbon-offsetting/embed/#?secret=FOMBw8DtP3" data-secret="FOMBw8DtP3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tsovwclHpT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/index-leads-12-2m-seed-in-sourceful-a-data-play-to-make-supply-chains-greener/">Index leads $12.2M seed in Sourceful, a data play to make supply chains greener</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Index leads $12.2M seed in Sourceful, a data play to make supply chains greener&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/index-leads-12-2m-seed-in-sourceful-a-data-play-to-make-supply-chains-greener/embed/#?secret=tsovwclHpT" data-secret="tsovwclHpT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/tanso-nabs-1-9m-pre-seed-to-help-industrial-manufacturers-do-sustainability-reporting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203033</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A16z in talks to back CoinSwitch Kuber in first India investment</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/andreessen-horowitz-a16z-first-india-investment/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/andreessen-horowitz-a16z-first-india-investment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 07:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a16z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinswitch Kuber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A16z is inching closer to making its first investment in a startup in India, the world&#8217;s second largest internet market that has produced over two dozen unicorns this year. The Menlo Park-headquartered firm is in final stages of conversations to invest in Indian crypto trading startup CoinSwitch Kuber, three sources familiar with the matter told [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A16z is inching closer to making its first investment in a startup in India, the world&#8217;s second largest internet market that has produced over two dozen unicorns this year.</p>
<p>The Menlo Park-headquartered firm is in final stages of conversations to invest in Indian crypto trading startup CoinSwitch Kuber, three sources familiar with the matter told TechCrunch. The proposed deal values the Bangalore-based firm at $1.9 billion, two sources said. Coinbase is also investing in the new round, one of the sources said.</p>
<p>CoinSwitch Kuber was valued at over $500 million in a round in April this year when it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/tiger-global-backs-indian-crypto-startup-coinswitch-kuber-at-over-500m-valuation/">raised $25 million from Tiger Global</a>. If the deal with A16z materializes, it will be CoinSwitch Kuber&#8217;s third financing round this year.</p>
<p>TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/06/indian-crypto-exchange-coinswitch-kuber-in-talks-to-raise-funds-at-unicorn-valuation/">reported last week</a> that CoinSwitch Kuber was in talks to raise its Series C funding at up to $2 billion valuation. The report, which didn&#8217;t identify a lead investor, noted that the Indian startup had engaged with Andreessen Horowitz and Coinbase in recent weeks.</p>
<p>Usual caveats apply: terms of the proposed deal may change or the talks may not result in a deal. The author <a href="https://twitter.com/refsrc/status/1438057488205561861">reported</a> some details about the deal on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The startup declined to comment. Coinbase and A16z as well as existing investors Tiger Global and Sequoia Capital India did not respond to requests for comment.</p>
<p>The investment talks come at a time when CoinSwitch Kuber has more than doubled its user base in recent months — even as local authorities push back against crypto assets. Its eponymous app had over 10 million users in India last month, up from about 4 million in April this year, the startup said in a newspaper advertisement over the weekend.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A handful of crypto startups in India have demonstrated fast-pace growth in recent years &#8212; while impressively keeping their CAC very low &#8212; as millions of millennials in the South Asian nation kickstart their investment journeys. Several funds including those with big presence in India such as Accel, Lightspeed, WEH and Kalaari recently began <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/indian-startups-fundraise-spree/">working on their thesis to back crypto startups</a>, TechCrunch reported earlier.</p>
<p>B Capital backed CoinDCX, a rival of CoinSwitch Kuber that has amassed 3.5 million users, last month in a $90 million round that valued CoinDCX at about $1.1 billion.</p>
<p>Policymakers in India have been debating on the status of digital currencies in the South Asian market for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/30/india-plans-to-introduce-law-to-ban-bitcoin-other-private-cryptocurrencies/">several years</a>. India’s central bank, Reserve Bank of India, has expressed concerns about private virtual currencies though it is planning to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/india-considering-phased-roll-out-of-central-bank-digital-currency/">run trial programs of its first digital currency</a> as soon as December.</p>
<p>About 27 Indian startups have become a unicorn this year, up from 11 last year, as several high-profile investors &#8212; and global peers of Andreessen Horowitz &#8212; such as Tiger Global and Coatue have increased the pace of their investments in the South Asian market. Apna announced earlier on Thursday that it had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/tiger-global-led-100m-investment-makes-apna-indias-fastest-unicorn/">raised $100 million in a round led by Tiger Global</a> at $1.1 billion valuation, becoming the youngest Indian firm to attain the unicorn status.</p>
<p>Groww, an investment app for millennials, is in talks to raise a new financing round that would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/indias-groww-in-talks-to-raise-funds-at-a-3-billion-valuation/">value it at $3 billion</a>, TechCrunch reported on Wednesday. The startup has engaged with Coatue in recent days, the report said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="016Uy8o8c3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/andreessen-horowitz-triples-down-on-blockchain-startups-with-massive-2-2-billion-crypto-fund-iii/">Andreessen Horowitz triples down on blockchain startups with massive $2.2 billion Crypto Fund III</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Andreessen Horowitz triples down on blockchain startups with massive $2.2 billion Crypto Fund III&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/andreessen-horowitz-triples-down-on-blockchain-startups-with-massive-2-2-billion-crypto-fund-iii/embed/#?secret=016Uy8o8c3" data-secret="016Uy8o8c3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/andreessen-horowitz-a16z-first-india-investment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202982</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Liveblocks is an API that lets you add real-time collaboration to your product</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/liveblocks-is-an-api-that-lets-you-add-real-time-collaboration-to-your-product/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/liveblocks-is-an-api-that-lets-you-add-real-time-collaboration-to-your-product/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 07:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real-time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[realtime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203235</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meet Liveblocks, a startup that has been working on a set of APIs so that it’s easier to build a collaborative product. Essentially, it lets you create multiplayer experiences on the web or in your app. The company started with a live presence state API. If you integrate this API in your product, it means [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Meet <a href="https://liveblocks.io">Liveblocks</a>, a startup that has been working on a set of APIs so that it’s easier to build a collaborative product. Essentially, it lets you create multiplayer experiences on the web or in your app.</p>
<p>The company started with a live presence state API. If you integrate this API in your product, it means that you can show when somebody joins a page, a project or a document by displaying an avatar in a corner. You can also share the position of everyone’s cursor, text selection or content selection in real time.</p>
<p>Liveblocks is currently testing in private beta a live storage API. This is going to be a key feature as it is going to let multiple people view and edit the same data in real-time. For example, you can use it to develop a Google Docs competitor or if you want to add a whiteboard tool to your service.</p>
<p>The service works across multiple browsers and devices. Behind the scenes, the company uses a WebSocket connection for real-time communication. Pricing depends on the number of simultaneous connections that you expect around the same room, document, experience.</p>
<p>“Guillaume Salles and I decided to work together on a browser-based collaborative presentation/video tool. After months of iteration, we realized that we were spending a majority of our time figuring out how to handle the real‑time collaboration aspect of things, instead of focusing on the core mechanics of the tool,” co-founder and CEO Steven Fabre told me.</p>
<p>“We tried existing solutions, but none really stacked up for what we were trying to do so we decided to build our own. That&#39;s when it clicked and we decided to drop the presentation/video tool to ‘productify’ the APIs we had built for ourselves so any team could use them to build performant real-time collaborative products,” he added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company raised a $1.4 million pre-seed round during the summer. Investors include Boldstart, Seedcamp, Meta fund, Logic &amp; Rhythm, Ian Storm Taylor, Max Stoiber, Moritz Plassnig, Badrul Farooqi and Anthony DiMare.</p>
<p>Right now, the Liveblocks team is just the two founders. With this funding round, the company plans to hire some engineers and launch its live storage API.</p>
<p>Liveblocks’ main advantage is that it’s a high-level API. <a href="https://ably.com">Ably</a>, a startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/ably-raises-70-million-for-its-developer-platform-that-enables-realtime-features/">I&#8217;ve covered recently</a>, focuses more on the low-level aspect of the problem. A React front-end developer can read the documentation and integrate Liveblocks in its product. You don’t have to understand how the infrastructure layer actually works to get started.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E9dMAqi4cJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/ably-raises-70-million-for-its-developer-platform-that-enables-realtime-features/">Ably raises $70 million for its developer platform that enables realtime features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ably raises $70 million for its developer platform that enables realtime features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/ably-raises-70-million-for-its-developer-platform-that-enables-realtime-features/embed/#?secret=E9dMAqi4cJ" data-secret="E9dMAqi4cJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/liveblocks-is-an-api-that-lets-you-add-real-time-collaboration-to-your-product/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203235</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Skello raises $47.3 million for its employee scheduling tool</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/skello-raises-47-3-million-for-its-employee-scheduling-tool/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/skello-raises-47-3-million-for-its-employee-scheduling-tool/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 05:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scheduling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Skello]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Skello has raised a $47.3 million funding round (€40 million). The company has been working on a software-as-a-service tool that lets you manage the work schedule of your company. What makes it special is that Skello automatically takes into account local labor laws and collective agreements. Partech is leading today’s funding round. Existing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://en.skello.io">Skello</a> has raised a $47.3 million funding round (€40 million). The company has been working on a software-as-a-service tool that lets you manage the work schedule of your company. What makes it special is that Skello automatically takes into account local labor laws and collective agreements.</p>
<p>Partech is leading today’s funding round. Existing investors XAnge and Aglaé Ventures are also participating. The startup had previously raised a €300,000 seed round and a €6 million Series A round in 2018.</p>
<p>Skello works with companies across many industries, such as retail, hospitality, pharmacies, bakeries, gyms, escape games and more. And many of them were simply using Microsoft Excel to manage their schedule.</p>
<p>By using Skello, you get an online service that works for both managers and employees. On the manager side, you can view who is working and when. You can assign employees to fill some gaps.</p>
<p>For employees, they can also connect to the platform to see their own schedule. Employees can also say when they are unavailable and request time off. And when something unexpected comes up, employees can trade shifts.</p>
<p>“We really want to put employees at the center of the product,” co-founder and CEO Quitterie Mathelin-Moreaux told me. “They have a mobile app and the idea is to make the work schedule as collaborative as possible in order to allocate resources as efficiently as possible and increase team retention.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At every step of the scheduling process, Skello manages legal requirements. For instance, Skello remembers mandatory weekly rest periods. The platform knows that your employees can’t work across a long time range. And Skello can count overtime hours, holiday hours, Sunday shifts, etc.</p>
<p>When you’re approaching the end of the month, Skello can generate a report with everyone’s timesheet. You can integrate Skello directly with your payroll tool to make this process a bit less tedious as well.</p>
<p>Skello is currently used across 7,000 points of sale. Now, the company wants to expand to more European countries and increase the size of the team from 150 employees to 300 employees by 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/skello-raises-47-3-million-for-its-employee-scheduling-tool/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203207</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Online events platform Delegate Connect gets $10M AUD led by AirTree</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/online-events-platform-delegate-connect-gets-10m-aud-led-by-airtree/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/online-events-platform-delegate-connect-gets-10m-aud-led-by-airtree/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 04:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delegate Connect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Livestreaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Delegate Connect is the latest virtual/hybrid events platform to land funding. The Melbourne-based startup announced today it has raised $10 million AUD (about $7.3 million USD) in seed funding led by AirTree Ventures, which wrote Delegate Connect the biggest seed check in the fund’s history so far. Other participants included Skip Capital, TEN13 and Australian [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2203572" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203572" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203572" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png" alt="Delegate Connect founders Jordan Walsh and Jacob Thomas" width="1024" height="613" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png 1700w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=300,179 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=768,459 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=680,407 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=1536,919 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203572" class="wp-caption-text">Delegate Connect founders Jordan Walsh and Jacob Thomas</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.delegateconnect.co/">Delegate Connect</a> is the latest virtual/hybrid events platform to land funding. The Melbourne-based startup announced today it has raised $10 million AUD (about $7.3 million USD) in seed funding led by AirTree Ventures, which wrote Delegate Connect the biggest seed check in the fund’s history so far. Other participants included Skip Capital, TEN13 and Australian startup founders like LinkTree’s Alex Zaccaria and Go1’s Andrew Barnes.</p>
<p>The capital will be used to build Delegate Connect’s teams in Melbourne, London and Norway, which enable it to handle events around the world, increasing headcount from 45 to more than 100 by December. It also plans to open a United States-based office soon.</p>
<p>Founded in 2017 and bootstrapped until its seed round, Delegate Connect’s business grew during the COVID-19 pandemic, like many other virtual event platforms. Its clients have included the Edinburgh TV Festival, Sportsbet, the World Dental Congress and the World Library and Information Congress. Some of the sectors Delegate Connect focuses on include medical, pharmaceutical and industry associations.</p>
<p>Delegate Connect was created after co-founders Jordan Walsh and Jacob Thomas started a technical production and events business, and looked for a “technology platform that could do everything we needed at a large-scale event, including registration, live-streaming, hosting video-on-demand and integrate seamlessly with the venues.” They decided to build their own, initially as an internal tool. Then during a trip to India in 2019 to work on a symposium, the two realized that there was a wider need for their platform.</p>
<p>“[We] had a lightbulb moment where we thought ‘we are solving a genuine problem here.’ One of the world’s biggest technology companies was flying us to Mumbai to use our system (which wasn’t even built properly) to deliver the technical assets of their event!” Walsh told TechCrunch in an email.</p>
<p>The two finished building the platform at the end of 2019 and launched it in January 2020.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Walsh and Thomas were interested in hybrid events even before COVID-19.</p>
<p>“Hybrid events have been around for along time, especially in the medical, pharmaceutical and associations sectors,” said Walsh. “Before COVID, they typically involved someone broadcasting a live stream from the venue, recording it and then hosting it on-demand after the event. These are all fundamentals of the platform we’ve built, and we’re obsessed with creating a platform that expands the hybrid event experience to do so much more than live streaming and video on demand.”</p>
<p>Some features created for the medical and pharmaceutical sectors include the ability to log hours spent viewing educational or scientific content, which is useful for delegates who are attending events to earn professional development points (CPD), abstract submissions, content-restricted registrations and the ability to run concurrent streams.</p>
<p>Tracking professional development points is a major selling point in particular, since “this is typically super complex technically for clients, and we solve this for them by working out how they accredit, build it in, track it and then process the accreditation,” said Walsh.</p>
<p>If you’ve attended a lot of online events over the past year and a half, you are probably wondering how Delegate Connect is different from platforms like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/">Hopin</a> (which was used for TechCrunch Disrupt last year), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/bizzabo-raises-138m-for-a-platform-that-helps-you-build-and-run-virtual-conferences/">Bizzabo</a>, MeetingPlay or Cvent.</p>
<p>One of its main differentiators is that it was built with specific target audiences (medical, pharmaceutical, associations and international congresses) in mind, and plans to launch a self-service platform for them. Delegate Connect is also completely customizable, so events can use it as a white-label solution.</p>
<p>“Ease of use is central to the UX,” Walsh said. “For example, we have full content restrictions through our registration portal, allowing people to register for sessions, days, themes and streams. We can restrict sponsors form seeing other sponsor booths and ensure that content can’t be shared (e.g. if a pharmaceutical company can’t share info with non-pharmacists, we can restrict this) as well as allow certain delegates to view only some content if needed.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pwYEGfV47E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/">Hopin confirms $400M raise at $5.65B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hopin confirms $400M raise at $5.65B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/embed/#?secret=pwYEGfV47E" data-secret="pwYEGfV47E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The delta variant and resurgence of COVID-19 has forced many organizers to turn in-person events into online ones. Walsh said Delegate Connect has handled many last-minute requests and can do so in a matter of hours. For example, in August, the startup was working on a medical conference originally slated to run as a hybrid event from a venue in Japan with thousands of delegates. Just before it was supposed to start, however, the organizers told Delegate Connect that they needed to switch to fully virtual event.</p>
<p>“We can do this easily because the platform doesn’t change. It’s versatile, no matter the delivery method,” said Walsh. “Delegates just need to log in on the day and engage with the content just like they would if they were at the event.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fN9f3AKSja"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/virtual-events-startups-have-high-hopes-for-after-the-pandemic/">Virtual events startups have high hopes for after the pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Virtual events startups have high hopes for after the pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/virtual-events-startups-have-high-hopes-for-after-the-pandemic/embed/#?secret=fN9f3AKSja" data-secret="fN9f3AKSja" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/online-events-platform-delegate-connect-gets-10m-aud-led-by-airtree/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203567</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: Off the Wall</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/gillmor-gang-off-the-wall/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/gillmor-gang-off-the-wall/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 03:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Most of us count the golden age of Michael Jackson&#8217;s career with the Quincy Jones produced global smashes of Thriller and Bad. Fueled by the stream of videos and multi-single releases (5 on Bad), the records dominated the charts, radio, and MTV. But the real breakthrough came just before with Jackson&#8217;s first solo record Off [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QzTyKuqgQS4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Most of us count the golden age of Michael Jackson&#8217;s career with the Quincy Jones produced global smashes of Thriller and Bad. Fueled by the stream of videos and multi-single releases (5 on Bad), the records dominated the charts, radio, and MTV. But the real breakthrough came just before with Jackson&#8217;s first solo record Off the Wall.</p>
<p>Born in the thrall of the Disco Era, it wasn&#8217;t hip, a surrender to the feel of funk meets MGM. But in the mountains around Woodstock, we couldn&#8217;t pry this record off the turntable. Today, with a simple voice command to Siri, the mists evaporate and with them the pandemic, working, working, working day and night, the melting years. And the bass. My God but it drives us to Living Life off the wall.</p>
<p>Permission is what we&#8217;re given. We need it. No matter what lies in store for us, the grooves capture the essence of our future, unlock our hopes and dreams, our intuition. Can we dare to think this way, the blend of vocals, horns, percussion, and the coursing basses? A Stevie Wonder track recharges the battery. The record fades out quietly, priming the pump for Side One.</p>
<p>Today we lost a nightclub comedian, as Norm MacDonald called himself in a YouTube clip. Like the best of them, his comedy spooled out of him like a 50&#8217;s cop show, methodical and faux stupid. You could see his genius in the faces of the funny people who had him on their shows — Letterman, Leno, Conan, an agonizingly hilarious Dennis Miller on his foul-mouthed HBO cable show. Talk about off the wall.</p>
<p>Miller defined this most selfish of dark arts, the joy of being funnier in the presence of funny. In a time of excruciating not funny, these strange warriors tilt with the vagaries of the laugh. MacDonald&#8217;s careful construction of his sleight of word was all the richer for his seemingly aimless pursuit of the sweet spot, where the punchline is so McGuffin-like for its inevitability.</p>
<p>As the world slowly recovers its focus, Apple has released a new iPhone that can adjust reality after the fact, Knowing this feat is not possible to recover what and who we&#8217;ve lost, I&#8217;m so grateful for the time we&#8217;ve had with these greats and their great moments. When the traveler reached the top of the mountain and asked the wise man for the secret of life, he replied, &#8220;Could you give me a sec, I&#8217;m on the phone.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><em>the latest <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang/issues/gillmor-gang-newsletter-revue-13-745198">Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, August 27, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang">Subscribe to the new Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></strong> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.<img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/gillmor-gang-off-the-wall/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vietnam-based CoderSchool gets $2.6M pre-Series A to scale online course platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/vietnam-based-coderschool-gets-2-6m-pre-series-a-to-scale-online-course-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/vietnam-based-coderschool-gets-2-6m-pre-series-a-to-scale-online-course-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 01:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CoderSchool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monk’s Hill Venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CoderSchool, a Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam-based online coding school startup, announced today $2.6 million in pre-Series A funding to scale up its online coding school platform. This round was led by Monk’s Hill Ventures, with participation from returning seed investors Iterative, XA Network and iSeed Ventures. CoderSchool raised a seed round led by TRIVE [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">CoderSchool, a Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam-based online coding school startup, announced today $2.6 million in pre-Series A funding to scale up its online coding school platform.</p>
<p>This round was led by Monk’s Hill Ventures, with participation from returning seed investors Iterative, XA Network and iSeed Ventures. CoderSchool raised a seed round led by TRIVE Ventures in 2018.</p>
<p>CoderSchool will use the funding to accelerate its online teaching platform growth and technology infrastructure expansion for the company’s technical education programs that guarantee employment upon graduation.</p>
<p>The company, founded in 2015 by Charles Lee and Harley Trung, who previously worked as software engineers, pivoted from offline to online in early 2020 to bring high-quality technical training to everyone, everywhere. After switching to a fully online learning program, the company recorded 100% quarter-over-quarter (QoQ) growth in fully online enrollment, it said in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;Coding is the future. At CoderSchool, we believe everyone in Southeast Asia deserves a chance to be part of that future,&#8221; the company co-founder and CEO Lee said.</p>
<p>In Vietnam, the demand for IT talent is dramatically increasing by 47% a year, while supply is only increasing by 8% year-on-year.</p>
<p>“The need for strong engineers and developers in Southeast Asia has never been as <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">pertinent </span>as it is today with the growth of tech companies and digital businesses,” said Michele Daoud, partner of Monk’s Hill Ventures. “We have been impressed by the team’s focus on setting the standard for coding education in the region. We are excited to partner with CoderSchool to provide both opportunity and access to the millions of aspiring students in Vietnam.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fgxuOEuuRw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/vietnam-after-school-learning-startup-marathon-raises-1-5m-pre-seed-round/">Vietnam after-school learning startup Marathon raises $1.5M pre-seed round</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Vietnam after-school learning startup Marathon raises $1.5M pre-seed round&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/vietnam-after-school-learning-startup-marathon-raises-1-5m-pre-seed-round/embed/#?secret=fgxuOEuuRw" data-secret="fgxuOEuuRw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Given the strong engineer demand in Vietnam, the domestic market size is estimated between $100 million &#8211; $200 million, and still increasing every year, according to Lee. CoderSchool has been focusing on Vietnam for the last six years, but plans to enter the global market following the next round, Lee said, without providing exact timetable.</p>
<p>CoderSchool, which offers full-stack web development, machine learning and data sciences courses at a lower cost, has trained more than 2,000 alumni up to date, and recorded over 80% job placement rate for full-time graduates, getting jobs at companies such as BOSCHE, Microsoft, Lazada, Shopee, FE Credit, FPT Software, Sendo, Tiki and Momo.</p>
<p>&#8220;After having taught over 2,000 students, we&#8217;ve been able to refine our [coding education] content. We rewrote our full-stack web development course &#8212; from Ruby, Python to JavaScript &#8212; in two years, and added new machine learning and data science courses to our program,&#8221; Lee told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>CorderSchool&#8217;s online program enables students to interact with instructors and classmates before, during and after scheduled class sessions with its human-driven learning strategy. CoderSchool currently has 15 instructional staff, and plans to hire 35 additional instructors by Q4 2022.</p>
<p>CoderSchool&#8217;s data analytics has improved individual student performance while also allowing CoderSchool to increase its classroom size at scale, reaching a peak of 107 enrollments in a data science class.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="R0D4ztoHxS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/apple-expands-its-free-coding-courses-and-materials-for-educators/">Apple expands its free coding courses and materials for educators</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple expands its free coding courses and materials for educators&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/apple-expands-its-free-coding-courses-and-materials-for-educators/embed/#?secret=R0D4ztoHxS" data-secret="R0D4ztoHxS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3hJVWyyKi4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/lambda-school-raises-74m-for-its-virtual-coding-school-where-you-pay-tuition-only-after-you-get-a-job/">Lambda School raises $74M for its virtual coding school where you pay tuition only after you get a job</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lambda School raises $74M for its virtual coding school where you pay tuition only after you get a job&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/lambda-school-raises-74m-for-its-virtual-coding-school-where-you-pay-tuition-only-after-you-get-a-job/embed/#?secret=3hJVWyyKi4" data-secret="3hJVWyyKi4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/vietnam-based-coderschool-gets-2-6m-pre-series-a-to-scale-online-course-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203049</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok is hiding a viral challenge that has kids stealing their school&#8217;s soap dispensers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/tiktok-devious-licks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/tiktok-devious-licks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viral trends]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s back to school season and on TikTok, that means students are inexplicably stealing everything that isn&#8217;t bolted down. The latest TikTok trend to generally wreak social havoc sees students pulling off &#8220;devious licks&#8221; — small-scale heists of everything from soap dispensers, Covid test kits and hand sanitizer to high value items like classroom tech. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s back to school season and on TikTok, that means students are inexplicably stealing everything that isn&#8217;t bolted down.</p>
<p>The latest TikTok trend to generally wreak social havoc sees students pulling off &#8220;devious licks&#8221; — small-scale heists of everything from soap dispensers, Covid test kits and hand sanitizer to high value items like classroom tech.</p>
<p>The videos are set to an edited version of Lil B&#8217;s &#8220;Ski Ski BasedGod,&#8221; which had appeared in around 100,000 videos on TikTok by Monday, <a href="https://mashable.com/article/tiktok-devious-lick-trend-school">according to Mashable</a>, with the tag #deviouslick collecting more than 175 million views.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WgzwSuAOIm4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>TikTok cracked down on Wednesday, limiting search results for the viral stunt, removing videos with the tag and encouraging users to &#8220;please be kind&#8221; to teachers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We expect our community to create responsibly &#8211; online and IRL. We&#39;re removing content and redirecting hashtags &amp; search results to our Community Guidelines to discourage such behavior. Please be kind to your schools &amp; teachers. <a href="https://t.co/mIFtsYwFRb">pic.twitter.com/mIFtsYwFRb</a></p>
<p>&mdash; TikTokComms (@TikTokComms) <a href="https://twitter.com/TikTokComms/status/1438251247753121795?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 15, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&#8220;We expect our community to stay safe and create responsibly, and we do not allow content that promotes or enables criminal activities,&#8221; a TikTok spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;We are removing this content and redirecting hashtags and search results to our Community Guidelines to discourage such behavior.&#8221;</p>
<p>While it&#8217;s hard to know which videos are staged and which are legitimate, the trend is real enough to have teachers and parents across the country stressed out. At a <a href="https://www.8newsnow.com/news/local-news/destructive-devious-licks-tiktok-challenge-a-problem-at-some-valley-schools/">middle school in Las Vegas</a>, school administrators report students swiping speed limit signs, fire alarms, soap dispensers and classroom projectors. And in Portland, Oregon at least one high school saw an entire building&#8217;s worth of soap dispensers go missing — not a great start to another school year in the throes of a global pandemic.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="k8dxlQhAo6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/tiktok-bans-viral-milk-crate-challenge-over-safety-concerns/">TikTok bans viral &#8216;milk crate challenge&#8217; over safety concerns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok bans viral &#8216;milk crate challenge&#8217; over safety concerns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/tiktok-bans-viral-milk-crate-challenge-over-safety-concerns/embed/#?secret=k8dxlQhAo6" data-secret="k8dxlQhAo6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/tiktok-devious-licks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203425</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inspiration4 crew, meet outer space: SpaceX&#8217;s first all-civilian mission launches to orbit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/inspiration4-crew-meet-outer-space-spacexs-first-all-civilian-mission-launches-to-orbit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/inspiration4-crew-meet-outer-space-spacexs-first-all-civilian-mission-launches-to-orbit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The first all-civilian crew in history has made it to space. The Inspiration4 crew took off from NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida at 8:04 EST PM, commencing the first space mission in human history featuring zero trained astronauts. The reusable first-stage of the Falcon 9 rocket executed two burns in its journey back to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The first all-civilian crew in history has made it to space.</p>
<p>The Inspiration4 crew took off from NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida at 8:04 EST PM, commencing the first space mission in human history featuring zero trained astronauts.</p>
<p>The reusable first-stage of the Falcon 9 rocket executed two burns in its journey back to Earth, landing vertically on the SpaceX droneship &#8220;Just Read the Instructions&#8221; around 9-and-a-half minutes after launch. Dragon separated from the second stage at 8:16 EST PM.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203520" style="width: 1000px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203520" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203520" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/stage2-separation-inspiration4.gif" alt="" width="990" height="559" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203520" class="wp-caption-text">Second stage separation. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://spacex.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SpaceX <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The four-person crew will be spending time in orbit in a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule, which was affixed to a Falcon 9 rocket. (It&#8217;s the second journey for this particular Dragon and the third journey for the Falcon 9 first stage.) They’ll ascend to an altitude of around 575 kilometers – the highest that any humans have gone since the last Hubble telescope servicing mission in 2009. That altitude is above the current orbit of the Hubble and the International Space Station, so they’ll be flying over every other human in space, too.</p>
<p>The crew will be going around the earth around 15 times each day they’re in space. While they’re up there, they’ll be able to view outer space from a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/spacex-is-outfitting-it-dragon-spacecraft-with-an-observation-down-for-space-tourists/">transparent observation dome</a> &#8220;cupola&#8221; that was affixed to Crew Dragon’s the nose cone especially for this flight. It&#8217;s the largest continuous window to ever be in space. It won’t all be space tourism, however; the Inspiration4 is also ferrying a number of science experiments to orbit, including research to learn more about the impact of spaceflight on the human body. The research subjects will be themselves: the crew collect biomedical data and biological samples from themselves before, during and after the flight.</p>
<p>Nowadays, no private space mission is complete without a requisite billionaire, and Inspiration4 has one of those, too: the mission commander and man who fronted the bill, Jared Isaacman, who earned his fortune from his payment processing company Shift4 Payments. It must be said, however, that the remaining crew members, while clearly extremely talented and uncommonly brave, are refreshingly normal. They include physician assistant Hayley Arceneaux; geoscientist and science education doctorate Sian Proctor; and Lockheed Martin engineer Chris Sembroski.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2203485" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203485" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203485" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspo4.gif" alt="" width="640" height="304" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203485" class="wp-caption-text">The Inspiration4 crew admiring the Falcon 9 rocket on Launch Pad 39A.<strong> Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://spacex.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SpaceX <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The mission will be raising money for St. Jude Research Hospital (Sembroski was selected from nearly 72,000 donations to the St. Jude fundraising campaign). The crew aimed to raise $200 million in total; $100 million was donated by Isaacman and the mission far exceeded its goal prior to launch, hitting nearly $300 million at the time of launch.</p>
<p>To prepare for the mission, which is significantly longer than any other recent spaceflight featuring civilians, the crew undertook hundreds of hours of training, including 12- and 30-hour flight simulations in a replica Dragon capsule and climbing Washington State’s Mount Rainier in May.</p>
<p>SpaceX CEO Elon Musk was at Kennedy Space Center to see the crew off, and in true Muskian style the crew also travelled to the launch tower in two Model Xs (wearing custom SpaceX spacesuits). While NASA’s involvement in the mission was relatively nominal, beyond providing some services and equipment worth around $1 million, the agency has played a key role in bringing SpaceX to the place of supremacy it is today. SpaceX was awarded $2.6 billion from NASA in 2014 to develop Crew Dragon, under its Commercial Crew program.</p>
<p>It’s a major milestone for SpaceX, the largest and most profitable launch company in the world. This launch is also notably different than those undertaken by Jeff Bezos and Richard Branson in recent months – though I know the similarities are compelling – because the crew will be going higher and for longer than the Blue Origin or Virgin Galactic missions. But all three companies have a goal of making spaceflight “evolve toward an airline-like model,” as SpaceX senior director of human spaceflight Benji Reed put it yesterday.</p>
<p>“Ultimately, we want to we want to make life multiplanetary, and that means putting millions of people in space,” he said. “The long-term vision is that spaceflight becomes airline-like like you buy a ticket and you go.”</p>
<p>Even this year, SpaceX will be conducting more crewed missions (though none with an all-civilian crew). A Falcon 9 will be ferrying astronauts to ISS later this year, and at the beginning of next year will be the first commercial Axiom mission, also to the space station. “The Dragon manifest is getting busier by the moment,” he added.</p>
<p>If all goes as planned, we’ll be seeing the Inspiration4 crew in three days, when they’ll splash down back to Earth in either the Gulf or the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Florida. Weather is critical here, too: “We look at not only the launch weather but we have to look at the return weather […] when we come home in just three or four days from now,” Reed explained during a starry-eyed (no pun intended) press briefing Tuesday.</p>
<p>While the crew is in orbit, you can listen to a curated playlist by Inspiration4’s very own Sembroski (who plans to play a ukulele in space).</p>
<p><iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/37i9dQZF1DWUffIH68FPTm" width="100%" height="380" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203431" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203431" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203431" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203431" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://inspiration4.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Inspiration4 <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/inspiration4-crew-meet-outer-space-spacexs-first-all-civilian-mission-launches-to-orbit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203430</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch SpaceX launch the first all-civilian Inspiration4 mission to space live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/watch-spacex-launch-the-first-all-civilian-inspiration4-mission-to-space-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/watch-spacex-launch-the-first-all-civilian-inspiration4-mission-to-space-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 22:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crew dragon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Falcon 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203038</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After months of publicity, an NFT auction and even a Netflix docuseries, it’s finally here: the four-person crew of Inspiration4 will be heading to space today (weather permitting). What makes this launch different from any that came before it? None of the four people onboard are astronauts. The mission marks the first time that an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3pv01sSq44w" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>After months of publicity, an NFT auction and even a Netflix docuseries, it’s finally here: the four-person crew of Inspiration4 will be heading to space today (weather permitting).</p>
<p>What makes this launch different from any that came before it? None of the four people onboard are astronauts. The mission marks the first time that an all-civilian crew will fly to space. Let’s meet them:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jared Isaacman, a 38-year-old billionaire whose fortune comes from the payment processing company Shift4 Payments, which went public in the summer of last year. He is the mission commander.</li>
<li>Sian Proctor, a community college professor with a PhD in science education. Proctor was among 47 finalists chosen by NASA for a 2009 astronaut class, though she was not one of the nine eventually chosen to join the agency. She will be Inspiration4’s pilot, the first Black woman to pilot a spacecraft. She’s 51.</li>
<li>Hayley Arceneaux, a 29-year-old physician assistant at St. Jude’s Research Hospital and a survivor of childhood cancer. She’ll be the crew’s health officer.</li>
<li>Christopher Sembroski, a data engineer for Lockheed Martin, also a former camp counselor at none other than Space Camp. The 42-year-old will be acting as mission specialist.</li>
</ul>
<p>The crew will be cruising to orbit inside a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule, which will launch from a Falcon 9 rocket. They’ll spend three days flying around the Earth before splashing down in the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Florida.</p>
<p>SpaceX’s YouTube channel is hosting a live launch webcast starting from 3:45 PM EST, with the five-hour launch window opening at <strong>8:02 PM EST</strong>. As of Sunday, Inspiration4 said weather conditions at Kennedy Space Center looked 70% favorable. There’s also a back-up launch window opening at the same time the following day.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/watch-spacex-launch-the-first-all-civilian-inspiration4-mission-to-space-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203038</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
