<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 08:39:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s Mensa, a house of D2C brands, becomes unicorn in just six months</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/india-mensa-a-house-of-d2c-brands-becomes-unicorn-in-just-six-months/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/india-mensa-a-house-of-d2c-brands-becomes-unicorn-in-just-six-months/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 08:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ananth Narayanan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DealShare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[falcon edge capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meesho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mensa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mensa Brands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myntra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prosus Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mensa Brands, an Indian startup that acquires direct-to-consumer brands and helps them scale within the home market and overseas, has become a unicorn just six months after launching its business. Falcon Edge Capital led Mensa Brands’ $135 million Series B financing round that values the Indian startup at over $1 billion, the two said Tuesday. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mensa Brands, an Indian startup that acquires direct-to-consumer brands and helps them scale within the home market and overseas, has become a unicorn just six months after launching its business.</p>
<p>Falcon Edge Capital led Mensa Brands’ $135 million Series B financing round that values the Indian startup at over $1 billion, the two said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Prosus Ventures, as well as all existing investors including Tiger Global, Norwest Venture Partners, and Accel also participated in the new round, pushing Mensa’s all-time raise to over $300 million in equity and debt.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234638" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><a href="http://mensabrands.com">Mensa Brands</a> &#8212; founded by Ananth Narayanan, who previously founded fashion e-commerce giant Myntra that was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/05/22/flipkart-myntra-acqusition/">eventually scooped by Flipkart</a> &#8212; operates in the same space as Thrasio, the Boston-based startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/thrasio-the-amazon-aggregator-raises-1b-in-fresh-funding-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-10-billion/">widely credited with the success of this model.</a></p>
<p>But Narayanan believes that what Mensa is attempting to do is different. Mensa, which means constellation in Greek, is attempting to build a new age consumer brand similar to the Indian conglomerate Unilever or Bed Bath &amp; Beyond, he said.</p>
<p>“Brands today are getting built very differently. The distribution has completely been democratized. I think you can do brand building very differently and interestingly with a lot more virality and personalization,” he said in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2234641" style="width: 464px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2234641" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2234641 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ananth2.jpg?w=454" alt="" width="454" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ananth2.jpg 1281w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ananth2.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ananth2.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ananth2.jpg?resize=768,1151 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ananth2.jpg?resize=454,680 454w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ananth2.jpg?resize=1025,1536 1025w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ananth2.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 454px) 100vw, 454px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2234641" class="wp-caption-text">Ananth Narayanan founded Mensa Brands, which has become the youngest Indian startup to become a unicorn, earlier this year. Narayanan previously founded Myntra. (Image credits: Mensa Brands)</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Mensa Brands currently houses 12 brands, 80% of which are run by women, said Narayanan. The startup operates in three categories &#8212; apparel, beauty and personal care, and home. “In all of these categories, we are not trying to build a brand for India, but a brand for the globe,” he said, adding that 30% of the startup’s revenue already comes from overseas markets.</p>
<p>The startup buys a majority stake in each brand it partners with with plans to acquire fully acquire them in five years. All of these brands are profitable and their founding team joins Mensa Brands to work with the larger firm, said Narayanan.</p>
<p>Mensa helps these brands organize and optimize their inventories across all popular marketplaces and their official websites. On the demand side, the startup performs &#8220;tech-led marketing,&#8221; and also optimizes the prices of products, he said. &#8220;We also do a lot of tech-led product developments such as identifying the products consumers are looking for, and help the brands launch new line of products,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Villain, a leading men’s fragrance and accessories brand that is part of Mensa now, grew by over 250% in October, the startup said. Another partner brand, Karagiri, a high-end designer sarees brand grew by 140% last month, it said. Narayanan said the vast majority of brands Mensa has acquired so far have grown by over 100%.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are excited to continue backing Ananth Narayanan as he executes a best-in-class playbook of brand aggregation and acceleration focused on Indian and global e-commerce brands,&#8221; said Navroz Udwadia, co-founder and partner at Falcon Edge Capital, in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;Mensa demonstrates a tangible uplift through a combination of product and pricing optimization, technology-led process improvement, distribution and marketing augmentation and fine-tuning the supply chain. These levers meaningfully accelerate the growth and margin trajectory of the brands and make them well-poised to become category leaders. We believe Mensa is well on track to cement its reputation as the partner of choice for well-performing e-commerce brands.”</p>
<p>Mensa plans to partner with as many as 30 additional brands in the next one year, said Narayanan.</p>
<p><em>This is a developing story. More to follow&#8230;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/india-mensa-a-house-of-d2c-brands-becomes-unicorn-in-just-six-months/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234638</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigerian shared mobility startup Shuttlers raises $1.6M, plans pan-African expansion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/nigerian-shared-mobility-startup-shuttlers-raises-1-5m-plans-pan-african-expansion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/nigerian-shared-mobility-startup-shuttlers-raises-1-5m-plans-pan-african-expansion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 08:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lagos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public transport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shuttlers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VestedWorld]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shared transportation in Nigeria, Africa’s largest country by population, is a thriving business, at least when done the conventional way: offline. With millions of Nigerians using danfo minibuses and okadas to commute to their various workplaces and destinations, mobility startups have sought to digitize the market. However, most have found little luck, especially those in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shared transportation in Nigeria, Africa’s largest country by population, is a thriving business, at least when done the conventional way: </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">offline</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With millions of Nigerians using <a href="https://www.pulse.ng/lifestyle/food-travel/what-mini-buses-are-called-in-every-african-country/t0e8r6d"><em>danfo</em> minibuses</a> and <a href="https://tourismobserver.blogspot.com/2017/08/boda-boda-or-okada.html"><em>okadas</em> </a>to commute to their various workplaces and destinations, mobility startups have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/25/africas-ride-hail-markets-are-hot-spots-for-startups-and-vc/">sought to digitize the market</a>. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, most have found little luck, especially those in the two-wheeler mobility space.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While most mobility tech in the country </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is centred</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> around two-wheelers and car-hailing, there’s been hardly any deliberate disruption in the bus-sharing and mass transit space.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234465" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.shuttlers.ng/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shuttlers</a>, a “tech-enabled scheduled bus sharing” company, is itching to change that. After years of bootstrapping, the company has raised $1.6 million in seed funding from </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">several</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> investors to blitz scale within and outside Nigeria.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chicago and Africa-focused investment firm VestedWorld led the round. Fintech unicorn Interswitch, Africa-focused VCs Rising Tide Africa, Launch Africa, EchoVC, Consonance Investment, CcHub Syndicate, CMC 21 &amp; Alsa, ShEquity, Five35, Sakore and Nikky Taurus also participated in the round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/damilola-olokesusi-37638035">Damilola Olokesusi</a> founded Shuttlers in 2016 to address the issue of inefficient transportation costs in Nigeria’s most renowned urban city, Lagos. Via its ridesharing platform, Shuttlers provides companies with better mobility options for their employees.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But when Shuttlers launched in 2017, it did not have a functional mobile application. Instead, the company ran an unconventional online model using Slack, email and WhatsApp to communicate with its customers.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yet, that was enough to onboard its first set of business clients. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tech talent unicorn <a href="https://www.google.com/amp/s/techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/softbank-sinks-200m-into-andela-propels-company-into-unicorn-territory/amp/">Andela</a> was Shuttlers’ first B2B2C client, Olokesusi told TechCrunch over a call</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The B2B2C plan is one of three main offerings Shuttlers providers; here, companies split payment of transport fares with their employees whichever way they see fit. The others include B2B, where business clients pay the complete fares of their employees and B2C, where individual customers pay fares themselves.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our mission is to transform the way people commute </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">around the world by building a global partner network and connecting communities of shuttlers like we are </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">presently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> doing in Lagos, Nigeria,” Olokesusi said in a statement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Following a revamp in 2019, Shuttlers now offers a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">fully</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> functional app that allows mobile professionals on its three plans to book rides</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through the platform, commuters can book a seat on one of the buses that goes along predetermined and scheduled routes</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the company, commuters pay 80% less when using its service instead of other ride-hailing services “without surges and peak-period pricing.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of its other features include live bus tracking, optimal routing based on traffic and digital payments, the company said. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also has a subscription feature where commuters can schedule rides in advance over a period of time</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2234534" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2234534" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2234534" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-3.jpg?w=680" alt="Shuttlers" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-3.jpg 3224w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-3.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-3.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-3.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-3.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-3.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-3.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2234534" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Shuttlers</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite raising </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> <span class="LrzXr kno-fv wHYlTd z8gr9e">₦</span>3 million (~$6,000) from friends and family and grants since 2016, Shuttlers’ growth has been staggering</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The company claims to have over 10,000 users across its mobile app and website users. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More than</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 100 unbranded and branded buses are on its platform, ploughing over 30 routes in Lagos with over 300 bus stops. In total, they have recorded more than 2 million trips since the company’s inception</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Olokesusi added that her company sells more than 6,000 bus tickets daily, which means over 3,000 people take two-way trips each day</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having done this much with so little, why is the company raising a seed round now? For one, it seems the company wants to go head-to-head with VC-backed competition; its funding is coming at a time when newer entrants are gaining ground across the country, most </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">notably</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from Toronto and Lagos-based Plentywaka.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Techstars-backed company is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">actively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> fueling its expansion across Nigeria and Ghana having raised more than $1.5 million in funding, money also used to acquire <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/mobility-startup-plentywaka-picks-up-1-5m-seed-acquires-ghanas-stabus/">a similar player</a> in Ghana.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Olokesusi says investors’ interest in the company was the main reason behind the company’s first venture capital intake.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We were not </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">actively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> looking for investors; however</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, there is now more attention in the shared mobility industry because of companies like SWVL. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, investors are interested in this and think local mobility plays can be valuable solutions,” Olokesusi said</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> made the right decision for the company at this particular right time so we can get ready for the opportunity that happens after</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now we are ready to take over the African market, starting with Nigeria and West African markets in the next couple of months</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company has begun operations in Nigeria’s capital city Abuja, but Olokesusi doesn’t say which other cities within and outside Nigeria Shuttlers will expand to next.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a similar train of thought, Nneka Eze, the managing director at lead investor VestedWorld, said her firm believes the “investment will help Shuttlers extend its offering </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to adjacent markets and help solve inefficiencies in the transportation sector across regions in Africa.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Olokesusi is one of the few female founders on the continent to have raised a significant round from VCs this year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But her journey to Shuttlers was accidental, as she tells me how working in an oil and gas firm took the front seat of where she wanted to work after studying chemical engineering at university.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The founder was born in Lagos but grew up in Ibadan, a neighbouring city with a less chaotic transportation system than Lagos</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Years after returning to Nigeria’s commercial city, Olokesusi would encounter the infamous and troubling method of booking bus seats in public buses (<em>danfos</em>), which she says “troubled” her, narrating her experience <a href="https://techpoint.africa/2020/12/21/damilola-olokesusi-shuttlers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in this interview</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There were fewer issues of people running after buses in Ibadan. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Lagos, I remember when I was walking to a bus stop for the first time, I was actually shocked how people were running very fast to get seats</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. That was my first interaction using danfo buses in Lagos, but like everyone, I got used to it.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CEO said she attended some tech conferences and meetups that opened her mind to the possibilities of starting a tech company to solve problems around her. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, it wasn’t until her internship and her first place of work following graduation that the idea for Shuttlers started to take shape</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2234536" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2234536" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2234536" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-1.jpg?w=680" alt="Shuttlers" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-1.jpg 3277w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-1.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-1.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-1.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Body-of-Tech-Crunch-Piece-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2234536" class="wp-caption-text">Damilola Olokesusi (CEO, Shuttlers)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She experienced two contrasts in both workplaces. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Her first employer had buses to transport Olokesusi and her colleagues from home to work and vice versa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Meanwhile, at the second, she made use of danfos once again.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What broke the camels back was my first time leaving the country in 2014, experiencing what it meant to live in a city with smart transportation</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. By the time I came back to Nigeria, I didn’t want to go back to using public transportation,” she said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upon her return, Olokesusi recreated the staff bus model. She felt the model could replace <em>danfos</em> and personal cars &#8212; the first-choice options professionals use to get to work. With Shuttlers, she also wanted to democratize the model and make it accessible to other users whose companies might not afford such services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Five years in, Shuttlers is not only profitable while raising money and making expansion plans; it is also concerned about fostering its environmental impact. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The latter is evident in a recent survey Shuttlers recently conducted where almost 30% of its daily commuters own cars. In essence, the company, in its little way, is reducing the amount of carbon dioxide that those commuters would have otherwise emitted if they used their cars daily.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Every single time that our buses are on the road, we are reducing the number of cars on the road. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are also optimizing routes and reducing the number of buses and emissions on the road,” said the founder and CEO</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. “As we proceed, we’ll be very intentional in recording and calculating how much gas emissions we’re reducing per route and daily, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">maybe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> also release reports on how we’re impacting the environment </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">positively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/nigerian-shared-mobility-startup-shuttlers-raises-1-5m-plans-pan-african-expansion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234465</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Education startup MindX raises $3.3M to prepare Vietnamese students for tech careers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/education-startup-mindx-raises-3-3m-to-prepare-vietnamese-students-for-tech-careers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/education-startup-mindx-raises-3-3m-to-prepare-vietnamese-students-for-tech-careers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 03:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edutech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MindX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software engineers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vietnam’s digital economy is one of the fastest growing in the world, but the country is facing a growing shortage of IT workers. Many kids want to study coding, but school curriculums are limited, said Tung Nguyen, the co-founder of MindX, an online/offline education platform that focuses on preparing students for tech careers. The company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2234621" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2234621" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2234621" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MindX_cofounders.jpg" alt="Coding education platform co-founders Tung Nguyen and Ha Nguyen" width="1024" height="731" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MindX_cofounders.jpg 5575w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MindX_cofounders.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MindX_cofounders.jpg?resize=300,214 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MindX_cofounders.jpg?resize=768,549 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MindX_cofounders.jpg?resize=680,486 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MindX_cofounders.jpg?resize=1536,1097 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MindX_cofounders.jpg?resize=2048,1463 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MindX_cofounders.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2234621" class="wp-caption-text">Coding education platform co-founders Tung Nguyen and Ha Nguyen</p></div></p>
<p>Vietnam’s digital economy is one of the fastest growing in the world, but the country is facing a <a href="https://vietnamnet.vn/en/business/vietnam-faces-it-workforce-shortage-789733.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">growing shortage of IT workers</a>. Many kids want to study coding, but school curriculums are limited, said Tung Nguyen, the co-founder of <a href="https://mindx.edu.vn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MindX</a>, an online/offline education platform that focuses on preparing students for tech careers.</p>
<p>The company announced today that it has raised a $3 million Series A, led by Wavemaker Partners, Vietnamese investment bank Thien Viet Securities and an undisclosed United States-based investor. MindX also received debt funding from Beacon Fund, an investment firm that focuses on companies founded by women.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234618" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The funding will be used to expand MindX’s online platform, create more educational content and expand into Vietnamese Tier 2 and 3 cities and rural provinces. MindX plans to build its network of tech companies that offer jobs to students who complete its courses. The startup&#8217;s courses are focused on kids ranging from kindergarten to grade 12, and university students, too. It says alumni have gone on to work as software engineers at companies like Google, Amazon and Shopee.</p>
<p>For students who enter MindX with the goal of becoming tech professionals, the startup plans to began offering an income share agreement, where students only pay tuition after securing a job, eliminating the need for upfront payments.</p>
<p>“One concern for parents with low-income levels is that they want their kids to have a guaranteed job placement, but they don’t want to run out of money for tuition,” said Tung. “They asked for financing solutions and we plan to implement the income sharing model by the end of this year for our students.” One example will be a program geared toward students who already have one or two years of experience working at software companies in Vietnam. The course will prepare them to find a higher-paying job in Singapore and allow them to pay back tuition after they start working.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hEq2MMIsfB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/monks-hill-ventures-and-glints-on-how-southeast-asian-startups-can-cope-with-the-regions-talent-crunch/">Monk&#8217;s Hill Ventures and Glints on how Southeast Asian startups can cope with the region&#8217;s talent crunch</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Monk&#8217;s Hill Ventures and Glints on how Southeast Asian startups can cope with the region&#8217;s talent crunch&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/monks-hill-ventures-and-glints-on-how-southeast-asian-startups-can-cope-with-the-regions-talent-crunch/embed/#?secret=hEq2MMIsfB" data-secret="hEq2MMIsfB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>MindX was created as a non-profit in 2015 by Tung Nguyen and Ha Nguyen. At the time, both were working at tech companies, and taught part-time coding classes in between their jobs, supplying learning spaces and laptops for their students. After a year, demand increased to the point where the two decided to commit to MindX full time as a company.</p>
<p>MindX now has 13 offline locations in Vietnam, in addition to its online education platform, and claims it has been profitable for the last six years, even during COVID-19. In fact, MindX’s founders say that as of September 2021, MindX had seen a 1,000% year-on-year growth in online enrollment.</p>
<p>MindX partners with 200 tech companies in Vietnam, Singapore, Japan and other countries to help find jobs for its students after they complete training, and says its hiring rates for graduates is 100% in Vietnam and 55% in Singapore. Some of the companies also serve as educational partners. For example, they give MindX’s students chances to create tech products or live projects with them.</p>
<p>For both Tung Nguyen and Ha Nguyen, starting MindX was a personal mission. “We didn’t have opportunities to study technology early in our lives,” said Tung. “For example, I was born in a poor working family, in a remote province in Vietnam. Computers were very, very expensive, they cost a fortune for most Vietnamese families at that time, so of course my family could not afford one for me.”</p>
<p>Tung was the first person in his extended family to go to college, but dropped out after one year “because I didn’t find any passion in the university’s curriculum and didn’t see my future in it.” Instead, he spent two and a half years studying coding on his own. “I think the experience of learning software engineering and coding transformed my life, because it opened a lot of opportunities for me,” including a software engineering position at a tech company in Hamburg, Germany.</p>
<p>While there, Tung met many European colleagues who were about the same age as him, but had started coding much earlier, when they were in primary school. “I really realized that for myself, and other young students in Vietnam, if we had the same opportunity to study software engineering, we might have far better futures and far more opportunities to compete and participate in the global job market.”</p>
<p>MindX’s founders say that many STEM education centers in Vietnam only offer 3 to 4 month courses. On the other hand, MindX’s options range from one year to a decade, depending on students’ ages, levels and goals. Most parents and students initially chose shorter courses, but MindX has recently seen more students start with 2, 5 or 6 year programs, to prepare for a tech career. Students are organized into cohorts and work closely with teachers.</p>
<p>After they finish their courses, MindX’s career consultants help students build CVs and prepare for job interviews. Part of MindX’s new funding will be used to apply blockchain technology to keep track of the relationships between MindX alumni and the companies that hire them so the application and interviewing process can be automated.</p>
<p>In statement about investment, Wavemaker general partner Gavin Lee said, “We’re excited to back the MindX team with their vision to revolutionize Vietnam’s tech education landscape and unlock career opportunities for 20 million K-12 and university students. MindX is addressing a clear need, given the worsening shortage of software engineers in Vietnam.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sqR9l2Ng9N"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/the-2021-edtech-avalanche-has-just-begun/">The 2021 edtech avalanche has just begun</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The 2021 edtech avalanche has just begun&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/the-2021-edtech-avalanche-has-just-begun/embed/#?secret=sqR9l2Ng9N" data-secret="sqR9l2Ng9N" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SHbgkDbdUA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/employers-are-consumer-edtechs-next-beta-test/">Employers are consumer edtech&#8217;s next beta test</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Employers are consumer edtech&#8217;s next beta test&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/employers-are-consumer-edtechs-next-beta-test/embed/#?secret=SHbgkDbdUA" data-secret="SHbgkDbdUA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/education-startup-mindx-raises-3-3m-to-prepare-vietnamese-students-for-tech-careers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234618</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Form Energy, the buzzy battery tech company, offers more of a window into its work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/form-energy-the-buzzed-about-battery-tech-company-offers-more-of-a-window-into-its-work/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/form-energy-the-buzzed-about-battery-tech-company-offers-more-of-a-window-into-its-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 02:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ArcelorMittal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coatue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Engine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Form Energy, a company that says it&#8217;s developing a rechargeable battery that can store electricity for days at a fraction of the current cost, has been accused of being overly secretive, even as it has lined up more than $360 million in funding from blue-chip backers since its formation in 2017 by a handful of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://formenergy.com/">Form Energy</a>, a company that says it&#8217;s developing a rechargeable battery that can store electricity for days at a fraction of the current cost, has been accused of being <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/25/form-energy-raises-240-million-on-iron-air-battery-promise.html">overly secretive</a>, even as it has lined up more than $360 million in funding from <a href="https://www.breakthroughenergy.org/investing-in-innovation/bev-board-and-investors">blue-chip backers</a> since its formation in 2017 by a handful of founders.</p>
<p>One of those founders, Form Energy CEO Mateo Jaramillo, led the creation of Tesla’s Energy Storage group, and at an<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/145636603@N06/albums/72157720136032014"> event</a> last week, Jaramillo talked with former TechCrunch reporter and current CNBC correspondent Lora Kolodny about why the company has been operating in a kind of stealth mode. He shared more of how Form&#8217;s operations work. He also reflected on the more than seven years he spent at Tesla, working for Elon Musk, a period that we gather was, um, intense.</p>
<p>You can watch the entire interview below. In the meantime, following are excerpts from that conversation, edited for length.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234103" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><strong>On why we&#8217;re seeing a renewable energy wave right now, with many companies aside from Form garnering attention and investment dollars:</strong></p>
<p>The cheapest available source of electricity in the world today comes from a renewable resource, and that&#8217;s either solar or wind, depending on which region you&#8217;re in. But if you&#8217;re looking for the marginally cheapest cost of electricity, it is going to be renewable today. And of course, the thing about renewable energy is that it&#8217;s driven by weather, and weather in only predictable to a certain degree, and it&#8217;s intermittent. That means that in order to enable a fully renewable decarbonized grid, we need to be able to store intermittent sources of energy over all the relevant timescales.</p>
<p>Yes, the sun does go down every night and very helpfully comes back every morning &#8212; so  that&#8217;s one gap that we have to bridge. But then we start to think about gaps associated with seasons or with longer-period weather patterns, and because renewable electricity has made such huge gains in the last 15 to 20 years, we&#8217;re now at penetration levels where we do have to think very hard about the last 30% or 40% of the electric system and exactly how we&#8217;re going to provide a level of reliability and cost using a renewable or generator like what we have.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2234114" style="width: 2058px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2234114" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2234114 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51674485027_6ba6c1c7c9_k.jpg" alt="" width="2048" height="1365" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51674485027_6ba6c1c7c9_k.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51674485027_6ba6c1c7c9_k.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51674485027_6ba6c1c7c9_k.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51674485027_6ba6c1c7c9_k.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51674485027_6ba6c1c7c9_k.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51674485027_6ba6c1c7c9_k.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51674485027_6ba6c1c7c9_k.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2234114" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Dani Padgett /</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Jaramillo also addressed why iron-air technology, which is what Form relies on and that was first investigated nearly 50 years by federal agencies (and never commercialized), suddenly makes sense as a way to store energy:</strong></p>
<p>First of all, the technology that&#8217;s most deployed is pumped hydro. That&#8217;s by far the most amount of energy storage that we have out there in the world today. But the technology that is quickly coming up on that is, of course, lithium ion. Right now, at this event, I&#8217;m guessing everybody here has five lithium ion batteries on their person right now, just as an example of how prevalent that chemistry is. . . .</p>
<p>However, as we start to get to these deeper penetrations of renewable energies, we need something that&#8217;s a bit different from what lithium ion can do. If we&#8217;re going to have an electric system that is not only 100% renewables driven &#8212; by wind, water and solar &#8212; then we do need to think about these periods of intermittence that are longer than just a few hours at a time. And that means it also has to be a lot cheaper than what lithium ion can do . . .</p>
<p>Iron [meanwhile] is a phenomenally abundant metal substance. It&#8217;s the most mined metal on Earth. Humans know a lot about it. We had a whole age named after it because we were playing with it so much. And we figured out a lot about it. And we still use it, of course as the main input for steel production today. It&#8217;s also very cheap. It&#8217;s abundant on every continent . . .and it&#8217;s one of the largest scale industries in the world. And you&#8217;re right that it&#8217;s not a new chemistry. Form Energy did not invent iron air as a chemistry. What we did do, however, is take a chemistry that was sort of first studied by two national labs . . .and we pulled it 50 years into the future, and we applied modern techniques and modern methodologies, modern knowledge of electro chemistry, of corrosion, of metallurgy, and brought that performance from 40 to 50 years ago where it was initially to where it can be today. And that means that we are now working on devices that truly are 1/10th the cost of what lithium ion in the future could be. [That means] we really can enable this deeply decarbonized, highly renewable, affordable, reliable electric grid.</p>
<p>What does that mean &#8212; an iron air battery? It means very simply that we are rusting and unrusting iron, electrochemically. That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing. It&#8217;s a very reversible process, but you have to be really good at exactly how you do that.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mcXdJJ_4hwY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Jaramillo also addressed why the company has been secretive about the efficiency of its systems (&#8220;If we&#8217;ve been secret, it&#8217;s only because we&#8217;re trying to avoid unnecessary hype around what we&#8217;re doing&#8221;). </strong></p>
<p><strong>He talked more precisely about how the whole thing works. If you&#8217;re curious, we suggest tuning in around the 10-minute mark to hear how Form is making use of &#8220;higher purity,&#8221; blueberry-size iron pellets that are now mass produced by the steel industry to the tune of 100 million tons per year.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kolodny also asked what he learned at Tesla that he is trying to duplicate at Form Energy &#8212; and what he learned from his career with the automaker that he doesn&#8217;t want to repeat:</strong></p>
<p>I was a Tesla about seven and a half years. I started in 2009 and left in at the end of 2016. And Tesla is a lesson factory. You could say it makes cars, but really what it does is provide lessons to people. It was a wonderful place to be during that arc. When I joined, we were a couple hundred people and by the time I left, we were 30,000 or  40,000 employees, something like that.</p>
<p>I left because at the time, we had already launched the Tesla energy effort &#8212; the Powerwall and the Powerpack. I&#8217;m married. My wife and I have three kids. I would like to stay married and be a part of my kids lives, and seven and a half years in the circle with Elon was enough for me. I also very intentionally wanted to leave on good terms with Elon, and things were sort of in a good place, so that was it for me.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2234124 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51676161180_c3b61e2289_k.jpg" alt="" width="2047" height="1365" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51676161180_c3b61e2289_k.jpg 2047w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51676161180_c3b61e2289_k.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51676161180_c3b61e2289_k.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51676161180_c3b61e2289_k.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51676161180_c3b61e2289_k.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51676161180_c3b61e2289_k.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/51676161180_c3b61e2289_k.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2047px) 100vw, 2047px" /></p>
<p><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Dani Padgett</p>
<p>I left with no regrets but I take away a lot. I take away that there&#8217;s nothing more important than the people you work with, and the quality of those people. They have to be passionately committed in every possible way to the mission of what you&#8217;re working on.</p>
<p>The other part of the lesson is, sometimes you have to protect people from themselves. It can tip over, right? Every virtue, if driven too far, becomes a vice. And so it&#8217;s really important to also acknowledge that there can and should be limits around what you ask of people when they are that committed and when they are that passionate about the mission of the company. So hopefully, what we&#8217;ve done at Form Energy &#8212; and we&#8217;re now about 200 people &#8212; is create a culture where we are all extremely passionate and devoted and mission-oriented, and we also are able to sustain things like a family life. And those two things are not in opposition.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/form-energy-the-buzzed-about-battery-tech-company-offers-more-of-a-window-into-its-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234103</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wishly wills the Gen Z world well with a worthy wad of angel wealth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/wishly-social-good-angel-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/wishly-social-good-angel-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 01:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Philanthropy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jim Dreyfous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joshua Mailman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wishly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A brand new social media platform focusing on social responsibility today announced it snagged $1.2 million to change the face of fundraising from a Gen Z perspective. Wishly is aimed at the curious Venn-diagram intersection of consumer brands, philanthropists and nonprofit organizations. The hope is to leverage the power of social media for social good. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A brand new social media platform focusing on social responsibility today announced it snagged $1.2 million to change the face of fundraising from a Gen Z perspective. <a href="https://wishlyapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wishly</a> is aimed at the curious Venn-diagram intersection of consumer brands, philanthropists and nonprofit organizations. The hope is to leverage the power of social media for social good.</p>
<p>The app was created by a couple of experienced social impact marketers, nonprofit fundraisers and administrators, Joanne Gonzalez-Forster and Justine Makoff. They saw a need for a social platform that embraced the optimism and altruism of the Gen Z generation, and to help people band together to bring about real, positive change in the world.</p>
<p>&#8220;In early 2020 when support for COVID-19 and Black Lives Matter were exploding, we saw our kids and their friends using social media to inspire their followers to take action and give to the causes they care about,&#8221; said Joanne Gonzalez-Forster, co-founder and CEO. &#8220;There wasn’t an easy way for them to find and vet nonprofits, make small donations and inspire their friends to get involved.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234515" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company was able to drum up an impressive assortment of angel investors, including now-retired founding partner of Pelion Venture Partners Jim Dreyfous and social impact investor Joshua Mailman. The duo invested into a $400,000 pre-seed round in 2020, and came back with additional investors to invest in the company&#8217;s current seed round of $800,000.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re so excited to see what Gen Z and our young millennial kids are gonna do with it. There are so many opportunities and there&#8217;s so much to be done in the world. There are natural disasters every other day. There are so many social movements. We built Wishly for them &#8212; for young adults today &#8212; so that they can make a positive impact in the world with small actions,&#8221; said Gonzalez-Forster. &#8220;When you Google <em>philanthropist</em>, you see pictures of Bill Gates and Jeff Bezos and Warren Buffett, but you don&#8217;t see young faces. We want to change that. We want to see young faces of all different colors and shapes and sizes.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s business model is simple: it retains 5% of all the funds raised on the platform. Wishly also makes sure to vet every nonprofit that is featured on the platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;We actually pulled a list of every registered 501c3 organization from the IRS, so they are all already on our platform, and we can accept donations for them. Once a nonprofit goes on the app to claim its profile, that&#8217;s our cue to vet them,&#8221; says Gonzalez-Forster. &#8220;We use the IRS search tool to make sure they are in good standing with the IRS, which would mean that it has filed its taxes three years in a row. We also check Charity Navigator and the Better Business Bureau, and we do a quick Google check to make sure that there&#8217;s no scams or lawsuits or misleading information about the nonprofit. There are a lot of bad charities out there.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The app is available now on <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/id1562148566" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wishly" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Android</a>, although the team suggests that the product is mostly in a friends-and-family stage until a more public launch, which is coming up soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/wishly-social-good-angel-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234515</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook’s new academic research API opens in early access</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/facebooks-researcher-api-meta-academic-research/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/facebooks-researcher-api-meta-academic-research/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:19:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advertising data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real time data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, a handful of academic researcher teams will gain access to a new tool from Facebook designed to aggregate near-universal real-time data on the world’s biggest social network. When it comes to who gets access to Facebook data and how, the company now known as Meta is still feeling reverberations from 2018’s Cambridge Analytica [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This week, a handful of academic researcher teams will gain access to a new tool from Facebook designed to aggregate near-universal real-time data on the world’s biggest social network.</p>
<p>When it comes to who gets access to Facebook data and how, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-changes-its-corporate-branding-to-meta/">company now known as Meta</a> is still feeling reverberations from 2018’s Cambridge Analytica scandal, in which a political consulting firm harvested the personal data of millions of unaware Facebook users to build detailed profiles on potential voters. The company shut down thousands of APIs in the three years that followed and is only now beginning to restore broad access for academic research.</p>
<p>TechCrunch previewed Facebook&#8217;s new academic research API and spoke with Facebook Product Manager Kiran Jagadeesh, who spearheaded the project with the <a href="https://research.fb.com/data/">Facebook Open Research &amp; Transparency (FORT)</a> team.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234505" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eTtsWbh9Dl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/facebook-to-launch-a-researcher-api-for-the-academic-community/">Facebook to launch a &#8216;Researcher API&#8217; for the academic community</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook to launch a &#8216;Researcher API&#8217; for the academic community&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/facebook-to-launch-a-researcher-api-for-the-academic-community/embed/#?secret=eTtsWbh9Dl" data-secret="eTtsWbh9Dl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;This is just the beginning,” Jagadeesh told TechCrunch, characterizing the Researcher API as a beta version of the toolkit it eventually hopes to offer. The API, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/facebook-to-launch-a-researcher-api-for-the-academic-community/?guccounter=1">first announced at F8 this year</a>, is Python-based and runs in JupyterLab, an open source notebook interface</p>
<p>In light of Facebook’s many past privacy woes, the new Researcher API comes with some initial caveats. First, the API will only be made available to a small group of established academic researchers through an invite-only system. The company plans to expand access beyond the initial test group in February 2022, incorporating feedback from the trial into a broader launch to all academics.</p>
<p>Another precaution: The Researcher API runs in a very controlled environment that Jagadeesh described as a “digital clean room.” Academic researchers with access to the API can enter the environment through a Facebook VPN, collect data and crunch numbers, but the raw data can’t be exported — only the analysis.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The idea is to protect user privacy and to prevent any data analyzed from being re-identified, but the limitation might rub some of the company’s critics the wrong way considering that all of the public data the Researcher API gathers is already out there floating around but difficult to aggregate and analyze with Facebook’s existing tools.</p>
<p>At launch the API will provide access to four buckets of real-time Facebook data: pages, groups, events and posts. In each case, the tool will only pull from public data and only from sources within the U.S. and the EU initially. For groups and pages, at least one administrator will need to be located in a supported country for that data to be made available through the API.</p>
<p>Through the tool, researchers can analyze large swaths of raw text using methodologies like sentiment analysis, which tracks the valence and emotions people express through their speech on a given topic. Beyond the text-based posts that comprise most of the available data, researchers can also access related information like group and page descriptions, their creation dates as well as post reactions.</p>
<p>Multimedia data like raw images won’t be included nor will comments or user demographic data (age, gender etc.). The API also won’t collect any data from Instagram, though Jagadeesh recognizes that the platform is very valuable for researchers and the team is exploring ways to make Instagram data available.</p>
<p>The FORT team is hoping to work closely with academic researchers to develop and build out the current tools, which Jagadeesh describes as a work in progress. While Meta indicated that its initial set of academic partners isn’t yet nailed down, the company has invited researchers from 23 academic institutions around the globe to kick the tires.</p>
<p>Researchers who have completed the team’s onboarding process and agreed to its privacy policies were granted access on Monday, November 15. Facebook requires anyone accessing the research to agree to privacy constraints, including not re-identifying specific individuals within the data.</p>
<p>The research API is only available to a handful of academic institutions for now, but the FORT team plans to explore granting access to other groups, including journalists. The goal is to create a public roadmap that gives researchers and journalists a transparent look at what the team is working toward.</p>
<p>The company has plenty of trust-building to do in the research community. In August, Facebook <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/facebook-ad-observatory-nyu-researchers/">cut off access</a> to advertising data for two prominent researchers affiliated with NYU’s Cybersecurity for Democracy project, prompting a rebuke from many academics and regulators. Those researchers focused on tracking misinformation and political ads through an <a href="https://adobserver.org/">opt-in browser tool called Ad Observer</a>. In September, Facebook <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2020/2020-election-misinformation-distortions#facebook-sent-flawed-data-to-misinformation-researchers">apologized</a> to an elite group of researchers known as Social Science One for providing them with incomplete data — a mistake that undermined months of work and analysis.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lqjJCG37nJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/facebooks-ad-library-targeting-political-ad-election-data/">Facebook will give academic researchers access to 2020 election ad targeting data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook will give academic researchers access to 2020 election ad targeting data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/facebooks-ad-library-targeting-political-ad-election-data/embed/#?secret=lqjJCG37nJ" data-secret="lqjJCG37nJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yPMzxzh790"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/facebook-ad-observatory-nyu-researchers/">Facebook cuts off NYU researcher access, prompting rebuke from lawmakers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook cuts off NYU researcher access, prompting rebuke from lawmakers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/facebook-ad-observatory-nyu-researchers/embed/#?secret=yPMzxzh790" data-secret="yPMzxzh790" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Y7apXKwO9n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-changes-its-corporate-branding-to-meta/">Facebook changes its corporate branding to Meta</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook changes its corporate branding to Meta&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-changes-its-corporate-branding-to-meta/embed/#?secret=Y7apXKwO9n" data-secret="Y7apXKwO9n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/facebooks-researcher-api-meta-academic-research/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234505</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sleek secures $14M Series A to enhance its corporate service platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/sleek-secures-14m-series-a-to-enhance-its-corporate-service-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/sleek-secures-14m-series-a-to-enhance-its-corporate-service-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jungle ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sleek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white star capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Entrepreneurs and small and medium enterprises (SMEs) often struggle to deal with several siloed functions, such as company secretary, bookkeeping, banking, tax, payroll, employment services, insurance and more. French entrepreneurs Julien Labruyere and Adrien Barthel founded Sleek in 2017 to help entrepreneurs incorporate and operate businesses in Singapore and Hong Kong. The startup built a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Entrepreneurs and small and medium enterprises (SMEs) often struggle to deal with several siloed functions, such as company secretary, bookkeeping, banking, tax, payroll, employment services, insurance and more.</p>
<p>French entrepreneurs Julien Labruyere and Adrien Barthel founded <a href="https://sleek.com/sg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sleek</a> in 2017 to help entrepreneurs incorporate and operate businesses in Singapore and Hong Kong. The startup built a back-end operating system platform that handles everything from incorporation, government, accounting, taxes and visas to regulatory compliance.</p>
<p>Its mission is to be the go-to platform for entrepreneurs and business owners who want to focus on building their businesses, as Sleek takes away all the back-office hassle, Barthel said.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234446" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Sleek has announced today it has secured a $14 million Series A round led by White Star Capital and Jungle Ventures. It brings Sleek’s total raised to $24 million.</p>
<p>The new capital will be used to bolster technology and product development, ramp up its headcount, expand its presence in existing markets and enter new markets, including Australia and the U.K.</p>
<p>As it enters the U.K. market, Sleek has also announced the acquisition of <a href="https://www.ltd-companies.co.uk/new/index.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ltd Companies</a>, the U.K.-based incorporation management company that has incorporated more than 450,000 companies since its foundation in 2005. Sleek will add its stack to the existing Ltd Companies offering to build an operating system for U.K.-based SMEs.</p>
<p>Since its inception, Sleek has expanded offices beyond Singapore to Hong Kong, Australia, the U.K. and the Philippines.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dx3uA7Jpcw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/corporate-services-super-app-osome-lands-16m-series-a/">Corporate services &#8220;superapp&#8221; Osome lands $16M Series A</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Corporate services &#8220;superapp&#8221; Osome lands $16M Series A&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/corporate-services-super-app-osome-lands-16m-series-a/embed/#?secret=dx3uA7Jpcw" data-secret="dx3uA7Jpcw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The startup doubled its client portfolio size during the pandemic; the interesting point is Sleek clients appear to be less impacted by the overall economic turmoil, Barthel told TechCrunch. It generated $10 million annual recurring revenue earlier this year, Barthel noted.</p>
<p>Sleek, which manages a portfolio of more than 5,000 companies, handled over 1.4 million bookkeeping transactions and posted approximately $700 million of revenue in 2020.</p>
<p>Sleek recently launched Sleek Business Account that simplified opening bank accounts for SMEs. It enables entrepreneurs and small business owners to open a deposit account in just a day through the Sleek app and start transacting, getting rid of the onerous paperwork requirements before opening an account. Additionally, users can view the account details on the Sleek dashboard along with the other company metrics to streamline bank reconciliation for accounting and bookkeeping purposes. The company is also planning to release products addressing remittances and card issuance.</p>
<p>“With the launch of Sleek Business Account, we have added a major brick in our product vision of building the operating system (OS) for entrepreneurs,” Barthel said.</p>
<p>Sleek also launched CFO-services at a pilot level that enables experienced CFOs access to a client’s accounting data via a business intelligence tool to provide recommendations and analysis to clients (for budgeting, strategy and fundraising).</p>
<p>&#8220;In a future where technology enables super efficiency for humans, they spend more time advising clients than doing manual work. Today our corporate secretaries advise 4-5 times more clients than a traditional player, and we are aiming to achieve 100% automation of that function so they can focus solely on providing advice to clients,&#8221; Barthel told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>“We believe we can be an excellent partner to Sleek and leverage our global footprint to help address a fundamental problem for all SMEs and supercharge their growth into Europe and Australia,” said Eric Martineau-Fortin, founder and managing partner at White Star Capital.</p>
<p>“Sleek addresses the deeply underserved challenge of back-office management for entrepreneurs and SMEs globally. Their growth across geographies and rapid expansion is testament to the accelerated adoption of the platform the value it brings to the ecosystem,” said David Gowdey, managing partner of Jungle Ventures.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="v4klK0CBVN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/corporate-services-platform-sleek-lands-4-million-in-new-funding/">Corporate services platform Sleek lands $4 million in new funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Corporate services platform Sleek lands $4 million in new funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/corporate-services-platform-sleek-lands-4-million-in-new-funding/embed/#?secret=v4klK0CBVN" data-secret="v4klK0CBVN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HyPhmZcqEM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/13/sleek-raises-5m-to-help-companies-incorporate-and-operate-in-singapore-and-hong-kong/">Sleek raises $5M to help companies incorporate and operate in Singapore and Hong Kong</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sleek raises $5M to help companies incorporate and operate in Singapore and Hong Kong&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/13/sleek-raises-5m-to-help-companies-incorporate-and-operate-in-singapore-and-hong-kong/embed/#?secret=HyPhmZcqEM" data-secret="HyPhmZcqEM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/sleek-secures-14m-series-a-to-enhance-its-corporate-service-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234446</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Max Q: No (American) boots on the moon until 2025, NASA says</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/max-q-no-american-boots-on-the-moon-until-2025-nasa-says/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/max-q-no-american-boots-on-the-moon-until-2025-nasa-says/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Q]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spaceflight Inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpinLaunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Max Q! I know I said this last week, but TC Sessions: Space is right around the corner and we&#8217;d love for you to join. You can find a sneak peek of the agenda at the bottom of this post. Send tips, comments and reactions to aria.techcrunch@gmail.com. Don’t forget to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hello and welcome back to Max Q! I know I said this last week, but <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=TCnewsletter&amp;tpcc=TCspacenewsletter">TC Sessions: Space</a> is right around the corner and we&#8217;d love for you to join. You can find <strong>a sneak peek of the agenda </strong>at the bottom of this post.</p>
<p>Send tips, comments and reactions to <a href="mailto:aria.techcrunch@gmail.com">aria.techcrunch@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p><em>Don’t forget to sign up to get the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">free newsletter version</a> of Max Q delivered to your inbox.</em></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230814" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>NASA: Artemis-3 pushed back to 2025</h2>
<p>NASA officials <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/crewed-artemis-moon-landing-pushed-back-to-2025-nasa-says/">provided an update on the Artemis program</a> &#8212; which aims to send Americans to the moon for the first time since the Apollo days &#8212; during a briefing Tuesday, when they officially confirmed that Artemis-2 and Artemis-3 would be pushed back by at least a year.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s interesting is that NASA Administrator Bill Nelson was not shy about pinning the delay at least partially on Blue Origin&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-goes-toe-to-toe-with-nasa-in-federal-court-over-award-to-spacex/">ongoing protest</a> of the Human Landing System contract (this is the crewed vehicle that will make the final leg to the moon). NASA awarded the contract solely to SpaceX back in April, and Blue Orogin has been protesting ever since.</p>
<p>The agency lost “nearly seven months in litigation” over HLS, Nelson said. He also gave a shout-out to NASA&#8217;s legal team and the Department of Justice lawyers.</p>
<p>Nelson also repeatedly brought up China’s rapidly advancing space program, noting that the country is “increasingly capable” of landing taikonauts on the moon. He vowed that NASA would be as aggressive as it could be in a safe and technically feasibly way “to beat our competitors with boots on the moon.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_1989745" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1989745" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1989745" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/nasa-artemis-astronauts.jpg" alt="nasa-artemis-astronauts" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/nasa-artemis-astronauts.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/nasa-artemis-astronauts.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/nasa-artemis-astronauts.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/nasa-artemis-astronauts.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/nasa-artemis-astronauts.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/nasa-artemis-astronauts.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/nasa-artemis-astronauts.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/nasa-artemis-astronauts.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1989745" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> NASA</p></div></p>
<h2>SpaceX launches Crew-3, Rocket Lab launch delayed</h2>
<p>SpaceX is gaining a <em>lot </em>of experience in human spaceflight. The company brought back four astronauts from the ISS on Monday evening (&#8220;Crew-2&#8221;) &#8212; and then sent another quartet (&#8220;Crew-3&#8221;) to replace them on the station just two days later.</p>
<p>The Crew-3 mission is part of NASA’s Commercial Crew Program (CCP), a partnership between the agency and private industry to develop and use human space transportation vehicles. SpaceX began providing transportation services to and from the ISS under the CCP in 2020, under a $3.1 billion contract for six missions. (Boeing was awarded a $4.8 billion contract under the program for its Starliner capsule, which has faced a series of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/nasa-and-boeing-confirm-starliner-wont-fly-until-first-half-of-2022-as-valve-investigation-continues/">technical snafus</a> that will likely keep it grounded until the first half of next year.)</p>
<p>You can <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/watch-spacex-launch-four-crew-3-astronauts-for-nasa/">rewatch the launch here</a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Rocket Lab &#8212; the only other company besides SpaceX to achieve first-stage reusability &#8212; also had a launch scheduled for Wednesday, but that is now delayed until at least November 16.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are holding off on launch today out of an abundance of caution due to an out-of-family ground sensor reading and to allow more time to complete helicopter recovery preparations,&#8221; <a href="https://twitter.com/RocketLab/status/1458646267790168067" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rocket Lab said on Twitter</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2232304" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2232304" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2232304" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-3.jpeg" alt="SpaceX Crew-3" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-3.jpeg 3240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-3.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-3.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-3.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-3.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-3.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-3.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-3.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2232304" class="wp-caption-text">SpaceX Crew-3</p></div></p>
<h2>More space news from TC and around the web</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20211112005389/en/NASA-Taps-BlackSky-for-Rapid-Revisit-Satellite-Imaging-Data" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BlackSky</a> announced a five-year deal with NASA to provide satellite imagery to support the agency&#8217;s Earth observation research. The company reported revenues of $7.9 million for the quarter, up 49% from a year ago, with an EBIDTA loss of $16.2 million and $198 million on the balance sheet.</p>
<p><a href="https://brycetech.com/briefing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bryce Tech</a> released its quarterly report this week, focused on the global launch industry. Some tidbits: last quarter, state-owned China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation had the most orbital launches at 15, with Arianespace taking the No. 2 spot and SpaceX coming in third. Arianespace launched the most number of spacecraft, however.</p>
<p><div style="width: 801px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FDr8LhVXIA4uvZe?format=png&amp;name=900x900" alt="Image" width="791" height="647" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Tech</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/08/hawkeye-360-raises-145m-to-scale-space-based-radio-frequency-data-and-analytics/">HawkEye 360</a>, a company that collects and sells data from its radio frequency satellite constellation, raised a $145 million Series D. The company aims to expand its constellation from nine to 30 by the middle of 2023.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/spaceflight-aims-to-send-customer-payloads-to-two-separate-orbits-for-the-first-time/">Spaceflight Inc.</a>, a launch services provider, will use one of its Sherpa orbital transfer vehicles to deploy customer spacecraft to two distinct orbits for the first time. The vehicle that will attempt to execute the maneuver will be the electric propulsion space tug Sherpa-LTC1, after heading to orbit aboard the SpaceX Transporter 3 in January 2022.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/spinlaunch-completes-first-prototype-flight-using-kinetic-launch-system/">SpinLaunch</a>, a stealthy startup that is taking a <em>very </em>unconventional approach to launch, completed its first successful test of a subscale prototype of its kinetic launch system in October. Essentially, the startup is developing a system that uses a large, vacuum-sealed chamber and a hypersonic tether to spin a spacecraft at a high enough velocity — up to 5,000 miles per hour — to escape the atmosphere. That means no rocket, no rocket engines.</p>
<h2>The early agenda for TC Sessions: Space is here</h2>
<p>Last year we held our first dedicated space event, and it went so well that we decided to host it again in 2021. This year, it’s happening December 14 and 15, and it’s once again going to be an entirely virtual conference, so people from all over the world will be able to join — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=TCnewsletter&amp;tpcc=TCspacenewsletter">and you can, too</a>.</p>
<p>Check out a sneak peek of the early agenda by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/announcing-the-agenda-for-techcrunch-sessions-space-2021/">clicking here</a>. Suffice to say, you won&#8217;t want to miss it.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2159308" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png" alt="" width="1024" height="575" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></h2>
<h2><a href="http://www.techcrunch.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read more stories on TechCrunch.com</a></h2>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/max-q-no-american-boots-on-the-moon-until-2025-nasa-says/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230814</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lucid Group&#8217;s customer reservations top 17,000 since end of third quarter</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/lucid-groups-customer-reservations-top-17000-since-end-of-third-quarter/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/lucid-groups-customer-reservations-top-17000-since-end-of-third-quarter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lucid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lucid group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucid Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peter Rawlinson]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lucid Group completed its first quarter as a public company with a booming stock price and customer deliveries underway, as it seeks to grab the top spot in the burgeoning luxury EV market. The company has come a long way since its founding as Atieva in 2007. After shifting its focus from EV battery and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Lucid Group completed its first quarter as a public company with a booming stock price and customer deliveries underway, as it seeks to grab the top spot in the burgeoning luxury EV market.</p>
<p>The company has come a long way since its founding as Atieva in 2007. After shifting its focus from EV battery and powertrain manufacturing to producing a line of luxury vehicles, the company went public in July after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/lucid-motors-strikes-spac-deal-to-go-public-with-24-billion-valuation/">merging with Churchill Capital IV Corp.</a> in one of the most hotly anticipated EV SPAC deals of the year.</p>
<p>Shares of the new EV entrant have nearly doubled over the past calendar month, going from around $27 per share on October 27 to $44.88 at the close of market Monday. The jump is likely due to the company commencing more than two dozen customer deliveries of the $169,000 Air Dream Edition sedan at the end of October. Just a few weeks prior, the automaker announced this variant had the longest EPA-certified range of any EV on the market <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/lucid-air-snags-the-longest-range-ev-title-surpassing-tesla/">at more than 520 miles</a>, while the Lucid Grand Touring received a rating of 516 miles.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234491" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Overall, customer reservations increased to 13,000 in the third quarter, which reflects revenues of around $1.3 billion, the company said. Since the quarter’s closing, reservations jumped again to more than 17,000; that’s up from 11,000 reservations in July. The bulk of reservations are being made by people in the U.S., Lucid Group CEO Peter Rawlinson told investors Monday, with Saudi Arabia taking the second spot by order of reservations. The company has received major financial investment from Saudi Arabia’s sovereign wealth fund, and the fund continues to be the automaker’s largest shareholder.</p>
<p>Rawlinson said in a statement that he is confident the company will hit a production capacity of 20,000 vehicles next year. Lucid’s longer-term goal is just slightly more ambitious: 500,000 units by the end of the decade. But first, the company aims to deliver 520 Dream Editions to customers in the initial roll-out, followed by Grand Touring, Touring and Air Pure (the base model, which starts at around $77,000) next year.</p>
<p>The vehicles are manufactured in Lucid’s manufacturing facility in Casa Grande, Arizona, which it plans to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/lucid-motors-kicks-off-market-debut-with-ev-factory-expansion-plans/">expand by around 2.85 million square feet</a>. The aim is to eventually manufacture up to 90,000 vehicles per year at the facility by the end of 2023, including the mysterious “Project Gravity” SUV, and up to 365,000 units overall, Rawlinson said.</p>
<p>Gravity is on track for production in late 2023, executives confirmed in the investor call. Rawlinson didn’t add too much more detail on the SUV, other than vowing that it is going to be “equally as disruptive in the SUV space as Air is in its space.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Turning to the financials, the company is closing the quarter with around $4.8 billion in cash, which includes $4.4 billion from the SPAC merger and PIPE, as well as cash on the balance sheet at the time of the deal’s closing. CFO Sherry House specified that while the cost of production is reflected in this quarter’s earnings, vehicle revenues will not be reflected in financial statements until the next quarter as customer deliveries began October 30.</p>
<p>Also on Monday, Lucid Air was announced as MotorTrend’s 2022 Car of the Year. &#8220;For a new brand and a new company to win, to my knowledge, that’s only been done once before. I should know, I was there,” Rawlinson said, referring to Tesla’s win of the award for the Model S in 2012. Rawlinson previously worked as vehicle engineer of the Model S after joining the company in 2009.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/lucid-groups-customer-reservations-top-17000-since-end-of-third-quarter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234491</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Australian micromobility startup Zoomo spins up $60M Series B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/daily-crunch-92/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/daily-crunch-92/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 23:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for November 15, 2021! We have a ton to chat through, but first, briefly: We’re having a sale! Yep, you get a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/green-days-sale-save-30-on-techcrunch-membership/">hefty discount on TechCrunch+ here</a>, which I am happy to share because saving money is good. As is supporting your friendly local tech blog! OK, let’s talk news. — <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/green-days-sale-save-30-on-techcrunch-membership/"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2232450 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/techcrunch-plus-green-days-sale-2021-3200px.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/techcrunch-plus-green-days-sale-2021-3200px.jpg 3201w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/techcrunch-plus-green-days-sale-2021-3200px.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/techcrunch-plus-green-days-sale-2021-3200px.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/techcrunch-plus-green-days-sale-2021-3200px.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/techcrunch-plus-green-days-sale-2021-3200px.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/techcrunch-plus-green-days-sale-2021-3200px.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/techcrunch-plus-green-days-sale-2021-3200px.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/techcrunch-plus-green-days-sale-2021-3200px.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234285" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/meet-imprint-the-fintech-that-just-raised-38m-from-the-likes-of-kleiner-perkins-stripe-and-affirm/"><strong>More money to reinvent cards:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Startup card plays are popular enough that TechCrunch wrote a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/all-the-reasons-why-you-should-launch-a-credit-or-debit-card/">digest on when they make sense</a>. But there’s still more to be done in the space, reckons Imprint, which just bagged $38 million for its consumer-brand debit card effort, including funds from Kleiner Perkins and Stripe.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/caspers-return-to-private-life-isnt-a-canary-for-dtc-companies-going-public/"><strong>Casper says &#8220;boo&#8221; to public markets, plans exit:</strong></a><strong> </strong>After a tumultuous run, DTC mattress company — and former venture-backed startup — Casper is leaving the public markets for $6.90 per share, cash. The price is a steep premium on its previous share price though does little to provide a positive signal for the DTC space given its basement-level implied revenue multiple.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/utahs-podium-raises-pre-ipo-round-boosting-its-valuation-to-3-billion/"><strong>Utah’s tech scene stays hot:</strong></a> It’s been a good year for Utah startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/qualtrics-ipo-everything-you-need-to-know/">Qualtrics went public</a>. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/why-did-bill-com-pay-2-5b-for-divvy/">Divvy sold for $2.5 billion</a>. Weave went public. Now Podium has added just over $200 million to its accounts at a valuation of $3 billion. It was once a surprise that Utah was building a burgeoning tech scene, but in today’s more global startup world, the state is merely yet another success story when it comes to fostering upstart tech shops.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/mitra-chem-takes-aim-at-chinese-dominance-of-battery-materials-supply-chain/"><strong>Can you build a startup aimed at the battery supply chain?</strong></a><strong> </strong>Mitra Future Technologies and Chamath Palihapitiya’s Social Capital think so. The startup wants to “boost the North American battery supply chain industry that’s currently dominated by China by producing an iron-based cathode for non-Chinese applications.” Heck yes.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/sos-vending-machine-seed-round/"><strong>SOS raises $3.4M for women’s health-focused vending machines:</strong></a><strong> </strong>SOS is building a network of vending machines supplying health and hygiene products, replacing “the perennial problem of broken, out-of-stock tampon machines,” TechCrunch reports. The company intends to roll out advertising products and more hardware.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/seven-years-after-last-venture-investment-mixpanel-scores-200m-series-c/"><strong>Mixpanel returns to fundraising after long break:</strong></a><strong> </strong>After blasting to scale early in its life, Mixpanel found itself stuck between startup and public company. Now, seven years after its last round, the software company has added $200 million to its accounts via a Series C. Call it a comeback? Our own <a href="https://twitter.com/ron_miller">Ron Miller</a> has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/how-mixpanel-got-its-startup-groove-back-by-focusing-on-its-core-product/">even more on the Mixpanel turnaround here</a>.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/uk-based-virtuoso-raises-13-3m-series-a-led-by-paladin-capital-to-automate-software-testing/">Virtuoso raises more money for automated software testing:</a> </strong>If you combine machine learning and RPA and point the hybrid at software testing, you get Virtuoso, a U.K.-based startup that just raised $13.3 million in a round led by Paladin Capital. Not to turn this into a D&amp;D joke, but we suppose that Virtuoso has to run lawful good from here on out.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/monograph-raises-20m-series-b-to-help-designers-and-architects-manage-their-operations/"><strong>Vertical SaaS still finding places to deploy code:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The work to bring industry-tailored software products to market is not slowing down, it appears. Today’s evidence is Monograph raising $20 million in a Series B for its “cloud-based platform for architecture and design professionals to manage their projects,” TechCrunch reports.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/aplazo-takes-in-27m-to-increase-adoption-of-bnpl-in-mexico/"><strong>Aplazo raises $527M for BNPL in Mexico:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The Mexican startup market is crossing my radar more and more often. A good example came today with Aplazo’s new funding round, an event that comes just four months after it raised $5.25 million. Such rapid-fire funding was rare once in Silicon Valley. Today, hot startups around the world can access more capital than ever.</li>
<li>To close out our startup coverage today, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/e-bike-subscription-service-zoomo-raises-60m-series-b-to-disrupt-last-mile-delivery/"><strong>Zoomo has raised $60 million for its e-bike subscription service</strong></a>. We love the idea that the Aussie EV company is working on. Cars are bad for the environment and take up too much room in cities. How about electric bikes?</li>
</ul>
<h2>Offer decks and other fresh tips for startup hiring</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2233621" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/14/offer-decks-and-other-fresh-tips-for-startup-hiring/"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2233621" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2233621 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/handshake-red-flags-r.jpg" alt="handshaking in front of flags" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/handshake-red-flags-r.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/handshake-red-flags-r.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/handshake-red-flags-r.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/handshake-red-flags-r.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/handshake-red-flags-r.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/handshake-red-flags-r.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/handshake-red-flags-r.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/handshake-red-flags-r.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2233621" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin</p></div></p>
<p>Most new startups operate with a hybrid workforce, but that doesn&#8217;t guarantee that hiring processes have kept pace.</p>
<p>In a panel discussion at TechCrunch Disrupt, Managing Editor Eric Eldon interviewed Jaime Bott, talent partner at Sequoia, Tawni Nazario-Cranz, operating partner at SignalFire, and Doris Tong, founder and CEO of EQ Talent Group <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/14/offer-decks-and-other-fresh-tips-for-startup-hiring/">to learn more about recent shifts in recruiting.</a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s not just engineering talent that&#8217;s in high demand: With so many startups staffing up, &#8220;there aren’t enough senior people to hire overall in the world,&#8221; Eric writes.</p>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/snapchat-partners-with-sony-music-announces-plans-for-new-ar-music-lenses/"><strong>Snap keeps landing content deals:</strong></a><strong> </strong>After announcing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/snapchat-partners-with-nbcuniversal-to-give-users-access-to-more-audio-clips/">NBCUniversal the other week</a>, social network Snapchat has closed a deal with Sony Music, bringing the latter’s IP into the app’s Sound Library. A bit odd of a move for a camera company? Not when TikTok has shown the power of tunes fused to the creativity of the crowd.</li>
<li>In good news, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/say-goodbye-to-disappearing-tweets-twitter-no-longer-auto-loads-new-tweets-on-the-web/"><strong>Twitter has updated its web interface to prevent the disappearing tweet problem</strong></a>. We can file this story in the <em>“</em>Dang, Twitter’s product team really did find a new gear, huh<em>”</em> section of the site.</li>
<li>Sticking to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/twitter-acquires-threader-an-app-that-compiles-and-shares-threads/"><strong>Twitter: The company has acquired Threader</strong></a> as part of its larger, subscription-focused Twitter Blue project.</li>
<li>And to close us out, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/tesla-is-deploying-starlink-satellite-internet-dishes-at-superchargers/"><strong>Tesla is adding Starlink hubs to Supercharger stations</strong></a>. In the future, you may be able to sit in your car and work while you charge your ride. I do not know if this counts as corporate ~ synergy ~ but it is close.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Are you all caught up on last week’s coverage of growth marketing and software development? If not, read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/12/its-ok-to-borrow-ideas-when-building-your-startups-website/">here</a>.</p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/daily-crunch-92/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234285</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canoo is setting up headquarters in Walmart&#8217;s hometown, picks Panasonic as battery supplier</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/canoo-is-setting-up-headquarters-in-walmarts-hometown-picks-panasonic-as-battery-supplier/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/canoo-is-setting-up-headquarters-in-walmarts-hometown-picks-panasonic-as-battery-supplier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 22:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Canoo, the electric automaker that became a publicly traded company last year, is expanding its U.S. footprint with plans to establish its headquarters and an advanced manufacturing industrialized facility in Bentonville, Arkansas — a city most famously connected with Walmart. &#8220;This is an advanced manufacturing facility that will allow us to produce vehicles for unique [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Canoo, the electric automaker that became a publicly traded company last year, is expanding its U.S. footprint with plans to establish its headquarters and an advanced manufacturing industrialized facility in Bentonville, Arkansas — a city most famously connected with Walmart.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is an advanced manufacturing facility that will allow us to produce vehicles for unique use cases as well as accelerate our testing into gamma,&#8221; said Canoo CEO and Chai Tony Aquila on Monday. &#8220;We&#8217;re looking for ways to take down the traditional go-to-market way and this will produce vehicles that we will sell, as well.&#8221;</p>
<p>Aquila said engineering, design and sourcing of materials for its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/ev-startup-canoo-is-gearing-up-for-production-in-oklahoma-factory/">gamma platform</a> is complete, and the company is in the final steps before production. During the earnings call, Canoo played a video demonstrating the progress of its gamma build, hinting at a specific unnamed partner for which the company is producing vehicles in the United States. Canoo expects to build 120 to 150 of those vehicles, and &#8220;some of them will be in the hands of potential partners,&#8221; said Aquila.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234398" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Canoo also announced Panasonic as its battery supplier and other expansion plans during its third-quarter earnings call Monday, including the establishment of a technology hubs in Tulsa, Oklahoma and Fayetteville, Arkansas to support R&amp;D in electronics, power trains, battery, vehicle engineering and testing, as well as expanded operations at its first U.S. factory in Oklahoma, which is currently under construction. Canoo also announced a software development center in Tulsa and a customer support and finance center in Oklahoma City, and said it will continue to focus on engineering and vehicle design in California.</p>
<p>&#8220;Combined, these facilities are expected to employ as many as 1,200 people providing higher education and jobs in the region,&#8221; said Canoo CEO and Chai Tony Aquila on Monday.</p>
<p>On top of the expansion news, Canoo said it was moving up the start of production of its lifestyle vehicle from early 2023 to begin before the fourth quarter of 2022.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Canoo made dual manufacturing announcements. The startup named Dutch company VDL Nedcar as its contract manufacturing partner for its lifestyle vehicle. VDL Nedcar will manufacture the vehicle for the U.S. &amp; EU markets while Canoo builds its U.S.-based mega microfactory. Canoo previously estimated the Nedcar facility would build up to 1,000 units in 2022 for U.S. and European markets, with a target of 15,000 units in 2023. Aquila upgraded that figure in August <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/ev-startup-canoo-is-gearing-up-for-production-in-oklahoma-factory/">to 25,000 units in 2023</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company announced in June plans to build its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/canoo-to-build-its-first-electric-vehicle-factory-in-oklahoma/">first factory in Oklahoma</a>. At the time, the state had committed $300 million in non-dilutive financial incentives to support the facility and Phase 2 of manufacturing. On Monday, Aquila said the state has added another $100 million in additional non-dilutive financial incentives, pushing the total to $400 million.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our discipline continues to be Big News or No News. Therefore, we will accelerate our advanced manufacturing production in the U.S. to begin before Q4 2022,&#8221; Aquila said in a statement, adding that the company is targeting about $100 million in vehicle orders with the states and universities where it is locating facilities.</p>
<p>The Oklahoma factory will now include R&amp;D, software development, customer support and finance centers, according to the company.</p>
<p>On the money front, the company reported a net loss of $80.9 million in the third quarter, about a fourfold increase from the $23.4 million in losses it reported in the same period last year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/canoo-is-setting-up-headquarters-in-walmarts-hometown-picks-panasonic-as-battery-supplier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234398</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bird&#8217;s first public earnings show slight miss in Q3 revenue, full-year guidance improved</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/birds-first-public-earnings-show-missed-q3-revenue-but-potential-for-full-year-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/birds-first-public-earnings-show-missed-q3-revenue-but-potential-for-full-year-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 22:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bird]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[escooter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234437</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today after the bell, scooter-sharing company Bird disclosed its third-quarter earnings, the first time it has done so as a public company. Bird recently merged with a SPAC, bringing cash and public-status to the formerly private unicorn. In the third quarter, Bird’s revenues slightly missed expectations, but given an expanded global footprint and an expectation [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today after the bell, scooter-sharing company Bird disclosed </span><a href="https://ir.bird.co/news-events/press-releases/detail/25/bird-announces-record-third-quarter-2021-financial-results" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">its third-quarter earnings</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the first time it has done so as a public company. Bird </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/shareholders-approve-bird-spac-merger-stock-promptly-falls/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">recently merged</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with a SPAC, bringing cash and public-status to the formerly private unicorn.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the third quarter, Bird’s revenues slightly missed expectations, but given an expanded global footprint and an expectation that tourism and commuting will return to cities and global supply chain issues will ease, the company also boosted its guidance for the full-year 2021 period. Shares were up marginally at 1.14% in after-hours trading at the time of this writing.</span></p>
<h3><b>Bird’s Q3</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the third quarter, Bird generated nearly all of its revenue from what it describes as “sharing” efforts, or its scooter business. A smaller portion – 2.1%, or $1.38 million – of its total top line came from sales of scooters and </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/shared-micromobility-company-bird-launches-a-consumer-electric-bike-for-2299/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bird’s new e-bike</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. More simply, the hardware side of Bird is effectively nil compared to its larger business of providing hardware to independent fleet operators.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234437" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Supply chain was a particular headwind in our product sales business principally for our new e-bike launch,” said Yibo Ling, Bird’s CFO, during the Q3 earnings call on Monday. “Demand for e-bike is surpassing expectations given global supply chain issues. We have seen difficulties particularly around logistics. As an example, $10 million of product sales we expected to realize in the third quarter was pushed back to the fourth quarter as a result of shipping logistics, which directly impacted revenue recognition timing.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ling went on to say it will monitor the situation closely and look for ways to mitigate supply chain pressures. Do we smell more vertical integration in the future?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bird’s total revenue came to $65.4 million in the third quarter, up 63% compared to its year-ago period. However, public-market investors <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/BRDS/analysis?p=BRDS">had expected</a> Bird to generate $69.85 million* in revenues during the three-month period.</span></p>
<p><em style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">[*<strong>Update:</strong> The Yahoo Finance dataset that TechCrunch used to source analyst estimates was out of date. The most recent analyst average revenue estimate for Bird&#8217;s Q3 was <strong>$65.7 million</strong>. That figure represents a much smaller miss compared to what our initial reporting indicated.]</em></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From that revenue result, Bird managed to post gross margins of 21%, a huge improvement over the 3% that it recorded in Q3 2020. Still, the company was far from profitable. It lost $36.9 million on a net basis – an improvement on its year-ago Q3 net loss of $43.8 million – and had adjusted EBITDA of -$5.3 million, a huge improvement on its Q3 2020 adjusted loss of $28.0 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, don’t let that adjusted EBITDA number give you hope that Bird is about to have a profitable business. In its calculations to reach the -$5.3 million figure, Bird removed its hardware depreciation costs, effectively stripping out the expense of scooter wear and tear. That’s too </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">laissez faire</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to pass our muster; depreciation is not a one-time cost, and should thus be included in the company’s operating results, from our perspective.</span></p>
<h3><b>Guidance upgrade</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Per the company, Bird now expects:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Revenues of “between $195 million and $205 million” in 2021, up from a prior estimate of $188 million.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adjusted EBITDA of “between $(85) million and $(75) million,” an improvement of prior guidance indicating a -$96 million adjusted EBITDA result for the calendar year.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Larger revenues and smaller losses are welcome at any company, and especially so at public companies banking on growing their way to break-even status. Doing some simple subtraction from the company’s results through September 30, 2021, Bird estimates the following results for its fourth-quarter:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$32.6 million in adjusted EBITDA losses, calculated using the midpoint of Bird’s full-year guidance range.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$48.8 million in revenue, calculated using the midpoint of Bird’s full-year guidance range.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It should not surprise that Bird anticipates larger losses in the fourth-quarter on the back of slimmer revenues, given the seasonality inherent to its business. When it&#8217;s cold, people go outside less. And few people rent scooters to ride them inside their primary residences.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last month, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/bird-nabs-150m-up-from-40m-in-vehicle-financing-from-apollo-investment-corp/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bird upped its credit facility from Apollo Investment Corp. from $40 million to $150 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which will allow the company to be more capital efficient with vehicle financing. The money will allow Bird to purchase vehicles in the slow winter season, as long as supply chain constraints ease, and deploy them to existing and new markets in the spring and summer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the guidance gains, however, Bird anticipates undershooting the market’s expectations. Investors </span><a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/BRDS/analysis?p=BRDS"><span style="font-weight: 400;">anticipate</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that Bird will file $193.1 million in total revenues in 2021, though the company’s Q4 guidance in particular appears to be better than expectations as they stand ($45.45 million).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During Bird’s difficult 2020 and through its SPAC-led public debut, our question has been simple: Is the company building a sustainable business that has a real shot at long-term, GAAP profitability? So, let’s talk about just that.</span></p>
<h3><b>Core model questions</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are some positive notes in Bird’s latest results. The company, it said in an earnings release, has grown its operations to 350 cities. That’s a wide footprint that could provide attractive growth in the next year. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the company will need extensive growth to get closer to profitability. From total revenues of $65.4 million in the third quarter, Bird generated gross profits of $13.5 million. That figure is a massive improvement on its year-ago result of gross profits of just $1.08 million, to be clear, but remains miles from its $40.0 million worth of operating costs in the quarter. And the gap between the two numbers &#8212; gross profit and operating costs &#8212; will widen in the fourth quarter due to weather-related issues.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At its current 21% gross margin, a figure </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">inclusive</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of “depreciation on revenue earning vehicles,” Bird would need to generate $190.6 million worth of revenues in a quarter to cover the operating costs it posted in Q3 2021. That’s around triple its current run rate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Recall that Bird’s economics have improved dramatically </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/20/bird-shows-improving-scooter-economics-long-march-to-profitability/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">thanks to a shift to a third-party model</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, in which scooter fleet operations are handed to others. Previously, Bird ran a more centralized, and less profitable business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We&#8217;re seeing very strong retention with our fleet manager partners, and one of the reasons why is the hundred vehicles on average we ship to each fleet manager partner, which gives us a lot of leverage on the labor and allows them to actually really maximize their earnings,”  Travis VanderZanden, founder and CEO of Bird, said on Tuesday. “The very strong earnings we&#8217;re seeing with the fleet manager partners is in rev share potential, I think is why we&#8217;re seeing such strong retention on the fleet manager base despite some labor headwinds in other industries.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EDDUcE5ZKb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/20/bird-shows-improving-scooter-economics-long-march-to-profitability/">Bird shows improving scooter economics, long march to profitability</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bird shows improving scooter economics, long march to profitability&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/20/bird-shows-improving-scooter-economics-long-march-to-profitability/embed/#?secret=EDDUcE5ZKb" data-secret="EDDUcE5ZKb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are reasons for cautious optimism. Bird’s revenue won’t have to triple to cover its operating costs with gross profit if the company’s gross margins can improve further. And Bird has posted some encouraging signs to that effect. For example, despite boosting its “average deployed vehicles” by 52% on a year-over-year basis in Q3 2021 to 78,500, the company still saw its average daily rides scoot from 1.6x to 2.1x. More scooters </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">and</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> more rides per scooter per day is good news for Bird.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That 2.1x figure is the highest result on file in the company’s earnings report, indicating a slope that points up. Rising average ride volume will provide a nice tailwind to Bird’s profitability in the coming quarters, if it can be maintained.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There isn’t a quick fix between the large gap that remains between Bird’s operating costs and gross profit. But at least the company’s core operations are improving, and it recently recapitalized thanks to its SPAC-led public debut, so it has cash on hand. Bird reports, inclusive of its public debut, “total cash, cash equivalents, and restricted cash, as of September 30, 2021 were $309 million after adjusting for $246 million received at the closing of the business combination.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bird’s operations consumed $66.5 million worth of cash during the first nine months of 2021, while its investing cash flows ran a larger, negative $115.5 million during the same period. The company’s scooter purchases are recorded in investing cash flow, for reference.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking at the sum of Bird’s Q3, it’s clear that its recovery from its 2020-lows continues. If it is recovering quickly enough to keep investors happy is the next question.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/birds-first-public-earnings-show-missed-q3-revenue-but-potential-for-full-year-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234437</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growth marketing experts survey: How would you spend a $25,000 budget in Q1 2022?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/growth-marketing-experts-survey-how-would-you-spend-a-25000-budget-in-q1-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/growth-marketing-experts-survey-how-would-you-spend-a-25000-budget-in-q1-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 21:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Experts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2231485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you run marketing for an early-stage startup, these growth experts have some advice for how you can get the most value out of your meager budget.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">What could an early-stage founder do with a $25,000 investment?</p>
<p>Hypothetically, they could use that money to buy 50 Herman Miller Aeron chairs or five top-of-the-line MacBook Pros for the engineering team. Or, they could use the funds to kick-start their 2022 marketing efforts.</p>
<p>A new year is quickly approaching, which brings new resolutions — and new budgets. To get some expert advice about how to optimize next year&#8217;s marketing spending, we reached out to several professionals we identified through our TechCrunch<a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03"> Experts</a> project and asked: <strong>&#8220;If you only had a $25,000 marketing budget for Q1 2022, how would you spend it?&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;People really do come back from the holidays looking for new tools, new experiences, new ways to do things,&#8221; said Tracey Wallace, director of marketing at MarketerHire. She said companies can &#8220;make the most of that&#8221; by doing some industry-related research now that can be adapted after the new year for long-form site content and social media campaigns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Jonathan Martinez of JM Strategy advised running parallel campaigns on TikTok, Facebook and Google. &#8220;Instead of going full force on only one channel, I’d try to make the decision at about the halfway mark ($12,500) on which channel of the three to double down on,&#8221; he suggests.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s who we talked to:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/camsinclair1/">Cam Sinclair</a>, director/marketeer, <a href="https://www.ammo.marketing/">Ammo</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathanmetrick/">Jonathan Metrick</a>, chief growth officer, <a href="https://portagevc.com/">Portage Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/traceyrwallace/">Tracey Wallace</a>, director of marketing, <a href="https://marketerhire.com/">MarketerHire</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jmartinez-in/">Jonathan Martinez</a>, founder, <a href="http://www.jmstrategy.com/">JMStrategy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mmoufarek/">Maya Moufarek</a>, founder, <a href="https://marketingcube.co/">Marketing Cube</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/peeplaja/">Peep Laja</a>, CEO, <a href="https://wynter.com/">Wynter</a> and founder of <a href="https://cxl.com/">CXL</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindsay-goldman/">Lindsay Goldman</a>, strategic advisor, <a href="https://themopros.com/">MO Pros</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Cam Sinclair, director/marketeer, Ammo</h2>
<p>If we were advising one of our early-stage startups how best to deploy their $25,000 marketing budget for Q1 2022, here’s what we’d suggest.</p>
<p><strong>Budget breakdown:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Growth marketing course with Demand Curve: $2,500.</li>
<li>Minimum viable brand design: $5,000.</li>
<li>Events, PR: $5,000.</li>
<li>LinkedIn/Facebook/Instagram campaign: $5,000.</li>
<li>Video content: $5,000.</li>
<li>Copywriting: $2,500.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Understand growth</strong></p>
<p>There&#8217;s some great resources and communities out there that help founders understand and apply growth. One we have been loving lately at Ammo is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/demand-curve-how-zapier-acquires-customers-via-its-homepage/">Demand Curve</a>. They have a course, Slack community and templates for startups and can even review your campaigns when you get started. The other course/community I&#8217;d recommend for an introduction to growth is Growth Tribe based in Europe.</p>
<p><strong>Build a &#8220;minimum viable brand&#8221; that can scale</strong></p>
<p>Invest in brand and design upfront, but don’t go over the top. (We talked about the<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/20/australian-growth-marketing-agency-ammo-helps-startups-calibrate-their-efforts/"> minimum viable brand concept in a recent TechCrunch story</a>) Your brand touches everything you do in marketing so having a great foundation will put you in good stead and make sure you are looking professional in front of customers.</p>
<p><strong>Invest in a copywriter</strong></p>
<p>Distilling complex ideas into short, succinct copy is a superpower. Investing in a pro copywriter to explain your value proposition is always worth it.</p>
<p><strong>Grow your network with events and PR</strong></p>
<p>You may have been involved in your customer&#8217;s industry for a while before you started the company. Utilize these connections and ask for help. It&#8217;s amazing how many founders don&#8217;t first check with their immediate network when they start. After you take that first step, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/04/15/steve-blank-teaches-entrepreneurs-how-to-fail-less/">Steve Blank</a> says you need to &#8220;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a-J_SwmMJyo">get out of the building</a>&#8221; and start having conversations with customers but also be present in their community. Most of the time there will be events in your industry that you can sponsor or speak at as an expert in the field. If your technology is solving a big problem for the people in the room they should want to know about it.</p>
<p><strong>Run a short LinkedIn/Facebook/Instagram campaign on your topic or service</strong></p>
<p>Facebook and Instagram still remain amongst the cheapest marketing channels available. Not only does it give you a chance to test your brand message and content in front of live customers, but it can also help you build an audience or email list in the platform of your choice.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/growth-marketing-experts-survey-how-would-you-spend-a-25000-budget-in-q1-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2231485</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rocket Lab acquires Planetary Systems Corporation in cash and stock deal</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/rocket-lab-acquires-planetary-systems-corporation-in-cash-and-stock-deal/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/rocket-lab-acquires-planetary-systems-corporation-in-cash-and-stock-deal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 21:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planetary systems corporation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rocket Lab is continuing its acquisition strategy, this time with a cash and stock deal with Planetary Systems Corporation (PSC). The news was announced ahead of the company’s third-quarter earnings. Rocket Lab said it would purchase the company for $42 million in cash, plus 1,720,841 in shares of common stock, with the potential for additional [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rocket Lab is continuing its acquisition strategy, this time with a cash and stock deal with Planetary Systems Corporation (PSC).</p>
<p>The news was announced ahead of the company’s third-quarter earnings. Rocket Lab said it would purchase the company for $42 million in cash, plus 1,720,841 in shares of common stock, with the potential for additional shares based on future performance.</p>
<p>PSC is a spacecraft separation systems company based in Maryland. More than 100 missions have used its mechanical separation systems and satellite dispensers. The company makes a “Canisterized Satellite Dispenser,” a separation system to separate spacecraft from rockets while also protecting them during launch. PSC’s hardware has been integrated with launch vehicles developed domestically by SpaceX, United Launch Alliance and the now-retired NASA Space Shuttle; and internationally by Arianespace, the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency and others.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234384" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kEVc9HvJvy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/peter-beck-on-rocket-labs-public-listing-debut-space-spacs-and-the-neutron-rocket/">Peter Beck on Rocket Lab&#8217;s public listing debut, space SPACs and the Neutron rocket</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Peter Beck on Rocket Lab&#8217;s public listing debut, space SPACs and the Neutron rocket&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/peter-beck-on-rocket-labs-public-listing-debut-space-spacs-and-the-neutron-rocket/embed/#?secret=kEVc9HvJvy" data-secret="kEVc9HvJvy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The deal comes as Rocket Lab continues to pursue its goal of becoming not simply a launch provider, but a fully vertically integrated space services company, offering everything from transportation to orbit to the spacecraft themselves. Rocket Lab said in a statement that it will use the product hardware across its Space Systems division, which includes its Photon satellite buses and spacecraft component products.</p>
<p>This marks Rocket Lab’s third acquisition in around 18 months. Last month, the company announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/rocket-lab-acquires-spaceflight-software-and-mission-simulation-company-asi-for-40m/">it had acquired Advanced Solutions, Inc.,</a> a Colorado-based company that develops flight software for spacecraft. Rocket Lab also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/16/rocket-lab-to-acquire-satellite-hardware-maker-sinclair-interplanetary/">acquired Sinclair Interplanetary last year</a>, a manufacturer of space hardware.</p>
<p>PSC will continue to be headed by the current CEO, Mike Whalen. The deal is anticipated to close in the fourth quarter of this year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/rocket-lab-acquires-planetary-systems-corporation-in-cash-and-stock-deal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234384</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mark Cuban&#8217;s Fireside app attracts NFL stars and others as backers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/mark-cuban-fireside-app-attracts-nfl-stars-and-others-as-backers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/mark-cuban-fireside-app-attracts-nfl-stars-and-others-as-backers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 21:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[callin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Falon Fatemi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fireside]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark cuban]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mark Cuban’s Fireside, an interactive platform that is helping creators share their stories with audiences through live and virtual shows, is in advanced stages to close a “seed+” round, two sources familiar with the matter told me. The financing round has already received commitment from investors such as The Chainsmokers, HBSE, Goodwater, Animal Capital and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mark Cuban’s Fireside, an interactive platform that is helping creators <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/mark-cuban-backed-live-entertainment-app-fireside-launches-to-creators/">share their stories with audiences through live and virtual shows</a>, is in advanced stages to close a “seed+” round, two sources familiar with the matter told me.</p>
<p>The financing round has already received commitment from investors such as The Chainsmokers, HBSE, Goodwater, Animal Capital and NFL stars Larry Fitzgerald and Kelvin Beachum and former NBA star Baron Davis, the sources said, requesting anonymity as the details are private. The size of the round is close to $10 million, said another source familiar with the matter.</p>
<p>The seed+ round is being raised at an uncapped valuation, one of the sources said. Investing in an uncapped valuation round typically allows the participating investors to buy equity in the startup at a discounted valuation in the next round.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234319" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The deal has yet to finalize so the terms could change, sources cautioned.</p>
<p>Among those investing in the round are entrepreneur and investor Cuban, who also backed the startup’s seed round, Cuban confirmed in an email response to TechCrunch. “I love what we are doing. So yes I continue to invest. FSC [Fireside Chat] is the first Tactile Entertainment Platform and I think its upside is unlimited. Like their tagline says, ‘Feel the Audience,’&#8221; he told TechCrunch, without commenting on who else is investing in Fireside.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2212217" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212217" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2212217" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/fireside.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="713" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/fireside.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/fireside.jpg?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/fireside.jpg?resize=300,209 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/fireside.jpg?resize=768,534 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/fireside.jpg?resize=680,473 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/fireside.jpg?resize=1536,1069 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/fireside.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212217" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fireside</p></div></p>
<p>Others who invested in the seed round are Precursor Ventures, Chris Voss and Sujay Jaswa, the sources said. Details about the early backers have not been previously reported.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A number of startups including Andreessen Horowitz-backed Clubhouse and David Sacks’ Callin are betting that the next wave of social networks would be built atop audio.</p>
<p>Fireside has been able to attract a number of high-profile creators to its platform, including Jay Leno and Michael Dell. The platform offers creators the ability to distribute their shows everywhere with the click of a button, and supplies them with what it calls &#8220;sophisticated analytics&#8221; to help them understand the kind of content that is resonating well with the audiences in real time.</p>
<p>The app &#8212; co-founded by Falon Fatemi, who previously co-founded customer intelligence platform Node &#8212; allows creators to sell tickets and subscriptions. The sources said that Fireside plans to explore use cases around NFTs and crypto as well as merchandizing to make the platform more enticing to creators.</p>
<p>“There is nothing else like it for content creators online. And what we will be able to do for metaverse-based venues is game changing as well,” Cuban told TechCrunch. “For the first time, whether it’s Web2, Web3 or VR, we have a tactile platform that allows content creators to hear and see how their audience is responding to live content. It&#8217;s as close to being in real life as you can get.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/mark-cuban-fireside-app-attracts-nfl-stars-and-others-as-backers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234319</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto VC firm Paradigm debuts monster $2.5 billion fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/crypto-vc-firm-paradigm-debuts-monster-2-5-billion-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/crypto-vc-firm-paradigm-debuts-monster-2-5-billion-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 21:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[andreessen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fred Ehrsam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paradigm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the crypto market continues to push toward new heights, investors are finding heightened LP appetite for exposure to the space, leading to new venture funds that are huge &#8212; even by 2021 standards. Paradigm, a crypto VC firm founded in 2018 by Coinbase co-founder Fred Ehrsam and former Sequoia Capital partner Matt Huang, has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As the crypto market continues to push toward new heights, investors are finding heightened LP appetite for exposure to the space, leading to new venture funds that are huge &#8212; even by 2021 standards.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.paradigm.xyz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paradigm</a>, a crypto VC firm founded in 2018 by Coinbase co-founder Fred Ehrsam and former Sequoia Capital partner Matt Huang, has closed its latest fund, and it&#8217;s a doozy. The firm announced a $2.5 billion venture fund, the largest crypto fund ever, shooting past the $2.2 billion crypto-centric fund Andreessen Horowitz announced this summer.</p>
<p>&#8220;This new fund and its size are reflective of crypto being the most exciting frontier in technology,&#8221; the firm&#8217;s co-founders wrote in a <a href="https://www.paradigm.xyz/2021/11/paradigms-new-venture-fund/">blog post</a> announcing the fund&#8217;s debut.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234310" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Paradigm has been at the forefront of a class of so-called &#8220;crypto-native&#8221; VC firms that are aiming to out-maneuver investment orgs that place bets across the broader technology industry. Some of Paradigm&#8217;s most high-profile investments include FTX, Coinbase, BlockFi, Maker, Uniswap and Sky Mavis.</p>
<p>Paradigm now has an unrivaled war-chest to bankroll an industry that&#8217;s hotter and more varied than ever. The young firm has a major opportunity to establish itself deeper into the fibers of the crypto web, debuting its new fund during a time where traditional VC firms are being forced to reckon with the efficacy of their existing investment procedures and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/sequoia-dramatically-revamps-its-fund-structure-as-it-looks-to-rethink-venture-capital-model/">even their underlying structures</a>.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Paradigm has around 30 employees according to their website. Earlier this month, they brought in Nathan Apsel as CFO (he previously held the same title at Joe Lonsdale&#8217;s 8VC).</span></p>
<p>Several of the major venture firms have been slow to embrace crypto, but Paradigm&#8217;s chief VC competitor will likely be Andreessen Horowitz, which is on its third crypto-centric fund and has made dozens of deals this year, minting new crypto unicorns and then doubling down on many of those same investments months later. The crypto arm has more than 50 team members, after having dramatically scaled hiring in recent months.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VoVTJNA2M4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/andreessen-horowitz-triples-down-on-blockchain-startups-with-massive-2-2-billion-crypto-fund-iii/">Andreessen Horowitz triples down on blockchain startups with massive $2.2 billion Crypto Fund III</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Andreessen Horowitz triples down on blockchain startups with massive $2.2 billion Crypto Fund III&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/andreessen-horowitz-triples-down-on-blockchain-startups-with-massive-2-2-billion-crypto-fund-iii/embed/#?secret=VoVTJNA2M4" data-secret="VoVTJNA2M4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="c7qxWV6Mr0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/nft-sci-fi-card-game-parallel-raises-at-500m-valuation-from-paradigm/">NFT sci-fi card game Parallel raises at $500M valuation from Paradigm</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NFT sci-fi card game Parallel raises at $500M valuation from Paradigm&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/nft-sci-fi-card-game-parallel-raises-at-500m-valuation-from-paradigm/embed/#?secret=c7qxWV6Mr0" data-secret="c7qxWV6Mr0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/crypto-vc-firm-paradigm-debuts-monster-2-5-billion-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234310</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lifen raises $58 million to digitize the healthcare industry</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/lifen-raises-58-million-to-digitize-the-healthcare-industry/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/lifen-raises-58-million-to-digitize-the-healthcare-industry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creadev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lauxera Capital Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Lifen has raised a $58 million (€50 million) funding round. The startup has been working on digital infrastructure for the healthcare industry, starting with medical reports. Indeed, 600 healthcare facilities are using the product to send and receive medical documents. And each customer is using Lifen intensively as it represents 2 million medical [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.lifen.fr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lifen</a> has raised a $58 million (€50 million) funding round. The startup has been working on digital infrastructure for the healthcare industry, starting with medical reports. Indeed, 600 healthcare facilities are using the product to send and receive medical documents.</p>
<p>And each customer is using Lifen intensively as it represents 2 million medical documents sent to 240,000 doctors each month. Patients can also retrieve documents from Lifen directly, as well.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.creadev.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Creadev</a> and <a href="https://lauxera.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lauxera Capital Partners</a> led today’s Series C round. Existing investors <a href="https://www.serena.vc">Serena</a> and <a href="https://partechpartners.com">Partech</a> participated in the funding round once again.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234136" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Lifen started with messaging in the healthcare industry as the company saw an opportunity for an upgrade. Many stakeholders in the industry used to rely on good old physical letters to send medical documents. And hospitals were stuck as they couldn’t just switch to email due to data privacy.</p>
<p>The startup built a document platform that works with several electronic messaging protocols designed for medical records. It makes it much easier to go paperless and send reports automatically.</p>
<p>Lifen has also added some machine learning on top of its document product. The company tries to detect key information automatically to turn documents into structured data. For instance, the startup tries to automatically identify the name of the patient as well as sender information.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>And now, the company wants to go beyond messaging with a full-fledged digital platform for the healthcare industry. Healthcare facilities can use Lifen to start using other e-health apps.</p>
<p>Lifen has its own <a href="https://www.lifen.health/en/marketplace/connected-apps" target="_blank" rel="noopener">app store</a> that references all apps that work with Lifen’s user management system and connect with Lifen. This strategy has worked particularly well for Salesforce.</p>
<p>With today’s funding round, the company plans to hire more than 200 employees over the next 18 months. By 2025, the startup wants to work with 1,500 hospitals and 200 e-health solutions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/lifen-raises-58-million-to-digitize-the-healthcare-industry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234136</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>E-scooter startup Tier buys Nextbike to double down on commitment to e-bikes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/e-scooter-startup-tier-buys-nextbike-to-double-down-on-commitment-to-e-bikes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/e-scooter-startup-tier-buys-nextbike-to-double-down-on-commitment-to-e-bikes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 20:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bikeshare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebikes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[escooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nextbike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tier Mobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234293</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Berlin-based Tier Mobility, one of the largest e-scooter operators in Europe, has just acquired German bike-sharing platform Nextbike. The move signals Tier&#8217;s commitment to the same multi-modal approach that competitors like Lime and Voi have followed to take advantage of existing market share. It&#8217;s also the latest big acquisition in the micromobility industry that might [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Berlin-based Tier Mobility, one of the largest e-scooter operators in Europe, has just acquired German bike-sharing platform Nextbike. The move signals Tier&#8217;s commitment to the same multi-modal approach that competitors like Lime and Voi have followed to take advantage of existing market share. It&#8217;s also the latest big acquisition in the micromobility industry that might herald further consolidation in the future.</p>
<p>Last year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/uber-leads-170-million-lime-investment-offloads-jump-to-lime/">Lime acquired Uber&#8217;s micromobility subsidiary Jump</a> and all of its e-bikes and e-scooters as part of Uber&#8217;s $170 million investment in the company. Earlier this month, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/lime-raises-523-million-as-it-prepares-to-go-public/">Lime raised $523 million</a>, which it says might be its last raise as it prepares to go public.</p>
<p>Tier and Nextbike did not disclose the terms of the deal, but Tier would have funded the acquisition with the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/tier-scoots-off-with-first-close-of-its-200m-series-d/">$200 million all-equity Series D</a> led by Softbank Vision Fund 2 it raised last month to scale its multi-modal market presence globally and pursue strategic investments and acquisitions. The Series D followed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/tier-banks-60-million-in-debt-from-goldman-sachs-to-expand-scooter-fleet/">$60 million debt raised this summer</a> and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/e-scooter-startup-tier-raises-250-million-round-led-by-softbank-vision-fund-2/">$250 million Series C last November, also led by Softbank.</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234293" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Tier, which also has a fleet of e-mopeds, has been committing heavily to e-bikes in recent months with launches in London and Stockholm as part of a planned e-bike expansion across six countries. As part of the deal, Tier will acquire Nextbike&#8217;s fleet of around 115,000 analogue and electric bikes, as well as access to new territories per the 28 countries in which Nextbike currently operates. It will also acquire Nextbike&#8217;s headaches in certain cities.</p>
<p>Nextbike has just had to <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-wales-59210989" target="_blank" rel="noopener">suspend operations in Cardiff and the Vale of Glanmorgan</a> in Wales after more than half its bikes were stolen and destroyed. The company, which has been operating its public bikeshare scheme since 2004, now has to repair and replace vandalized bikes, and the scheme might be permanently shut down in the area if the situation does not improve, but that problem will ostensibly now fall to Tier to handle.</p>
<p>Tier, which operates in more than 160 cities across 16 countries in Europe and the Middle East, does not already have a presence in Wales. Combined with Nextbike, Tier will have more than 250,000 vehicles in over 400 cities. Its fleet will include bicycles, e-bikes, cargo bikes, e-scooters and e-mopeds in free-floating, station-based and hybrid sharing systems, according to the company.</p>
<p>&#8220;The acquisition of Nextbike – with its unrivalled experience and relationships across hundreds of cities – is a unique opportunity to take bikeshare to the next level, getting more people out of cars and offering the most sustainable mobility solution,&#8221; Lawrence Leuschner, CEO and co-founder of <span class="il">Tier, said in a statement.</span> &#8220;Our shared values of sustainability and respect for cities across two strong leadership teams, underpinned by Tier&#8217;s financial backing and capital efficiency, present an unstoppable, joint mission to change mobility for good.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/e-scooter-startup-tier-buys-nextbike-to-double-down-on-commitment-to-e-bikes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234293</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Peloton sues rivals over alleged patent infringement related to on-demand classes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/peloton-sues-rivals-over-alleged-patent-infringement-related-to-on-demand-classes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/peloton-sues-rivals-over-alleged-patent-infringement-related-to-on-demand-classes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 20:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[echelon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iFit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peloton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Peloton has filed fresh lawsuits against two of its rivals, iFit and Echelon. It alleges that the companies are violating up to four patents it holds related to on-demand classes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Kris Holt</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://www.twitter.com/krisholt">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Kris Holt is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/">Engadget</a>. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/peloton-sues-rivals-over-alleged-patent-infringement-related-to-on-demand-classes/">Peloton sues rivals over alleged patent infringement related to on-demand classes</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/halo-infinites-free-multiplayer-mode-is-available-now/">Halo Infinite&#8217;s free multiplayer mode is available now</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://engadget.com/tag/peloton" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1"><ins>Peloton</ins></a> has filed fresh lawsuits against two of its rivals, iFit and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/echelon/" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1"><ins>Echelon</ins></a>. It alleges that the companies are violating up to four patents it holds related to on-demand classes, one of which it only obtained last week, as <a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/ip-law/peloton-sues-ifit-echelon-over-new-patent-for-on-demand-classes" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1"><em><ins>Bloomberg Law</ins></em></a>notes. Peloton is seeking a court order to block sales of the devices until the patents expire, in addition to compensation. In both suits, Peloton accuses competitors of attempting to &#8220;free ride&#8221; off its technology.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://insight.rpxcorp.com/litigation_documents/14499580" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="26" data-v9y="1"><ins>iFit complaint</ins></a> concerns <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/nordictrack/" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="27" data-v9y="1"><ins>NordicTrack</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/ProForm/" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="28" data-v9y="1"><ins>ProForm</ins></a> and FreeMotion products that use the company&#8217;s leaderboard and/or its ActivePulse or SmartAdjust features. &#8220;Prior to the actions giving rise to this suit, iFit Functionality never delivered live classes — i.e., classes taught by instructors and streamed to users’ devices in substantially real time — or offered its members the ability to participate in competitive classes via a leaderboard. Instead, iFit Functionality only allowed subscribers to follow along with pre-recorded exercise classes on their machines, without any sort of community engagement,&#8221; Peloton wrote in the filing.</p>
<p>It accuses iFit of &#8220;profiting immensely from this infringement.&#8221; In October, iFit paused its plan to go public due to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-07/nordictrack-maker-ifit-postpones-ipo-citing-market-conditions" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="29" data-v9y="1"><ins>adverse market conditions</ins></a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234345" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>As for Echelon, Peloton is targeting the Smart Connect EX1, EX3, EX4s, EX5, EX5s, EX-7s, EX-Pro and GT+ bikes; Stride and Stride-5s treadmills; Row, Row-s and Row-7s rowers; and the Echelon Fit app. Peloton <a href="https://insight.rpxcorp.com/litigation_documents/14499574" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="30" data-v9y="1"><ins>claims that</ins></a>, before it released the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/peloton-tread-sale-120039581.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="31" data-v9y="1"><ins>Tread</ins></a>, &#8220;it was not well-known for treadmills to offer a leaderboard&#8221; and that Echelon now has a &#8220;copycat leaderboard&#8221; with an &#8220;&#8216;Online Filter&#8217; that allows users to &#8216;see who is taking an On Demand class at the same time.'&#8221;</p>
<p>Peloton has had a thorny relationship with both companies over the last few years. It has <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-05-18/peloton-claims-boring-nordictrack-maker-copies-fitness-program" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="32" data-v9y="1"><ins>sued iFit</ins></a> (previously known as Icon Health and Fitness) over patent infringement in the past <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/10/15/business/peloton-nordictrack-lawsuit/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="33" data-v9y="1"><ins>and vice versa</ins></a>. Peloton also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-19-flywheel-sports-bike-peloton.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="34" data-v9y="1"><ins>filed suit</ins></a> against Echelon in 2019 for, among other things, &#8220;imitating the Peloton Bike experience.&#8221; Engadget has contacted iFit and Echelon for comment.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/peloton-lawsuit-patent-infringement-on-demand-classes-202028622.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/peloton-sues-rivals-over-alleged-patent-infringement-related-to-on-demand-classes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234345</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Say goodbye to disappearing tweets: Twitter no longer auto-loads new tweets on the web</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/say-goodbye-to-disappearing-tweets-twitter-no-longer-auto-loads-new-tweets-on-the-web/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/say-goodbye-to-disappearing-tweets-twitter-no-longer-auto-loads-new-tweets-on-the-web/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 20:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter is updating its web platform to change the way users see new tweets. The social media giant will no longer automatically refresh timelines on the web with new tweets, and users can now decide when they want to load new tweets. Twitter acknowledged that in the past, tweets would often disappear from view mid-read [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter is <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1460304788621508618?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">updating its web platform</a> to change the way users see new tweets. The social media giant will no longer automatically refresh timelines on the web with new tweets, and users can now decide when they want to load new tweets. Twitter acknowledged that in the past, tweets would often disappear from view mid-read when a user’s timeline would automatically refresh. Now, users can load new tweets when they want to by clicking on the tweet counter bar at the top of their timelines.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">An update to the disappearing Tweet experience is rolling out for web! Now you can choose when you want new Tweets to load into your timeline –– click the Tweet counter bar at the top.</p>
<p>&mdash; Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1460304788621508618?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 15, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234280" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In September, the company noted it would be rolling out updates to the way it displays tweets so that they wouldn’t disappear while users were still reading them. It&#8217;s worth pointing out that Twitter&#8217;s iOS and Android apps also don&#8217;t automatically refresh users&#8217; timelines when they open up the app. Instead, users can click on the highlighted home button on the navigation bar to load new tweets.</p>
<p>Twitter also recently announced that it will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/twitter-no-longer-crops-image-previews-on-the-web/">no longer automatically</a> crop image previews on the web, after rolling out full-size image previews on mobile earlier this year. On Twitter for the web, images will now display in full without any cropping. Instead of gambling on how an image will show up in the timeline, images will look just like they did when you shot them.</p>
<p>These tweaks come as Twitter has been working to enhance its platform and make its services more accessible. The social media giant<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/twitter-now-lets-you-tune-into-spaces-without-an-account-via-direct-links/"> recently rolled out</a> the ability for users to share direct links to their Spaces to let others tune into a live audio session via the web without being logged into the platform. It also launched its premium subscription service, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/twitter-blue-launches-in-the-u-s-and-new-zealand-with-expanded-feature-set/">Twitter Blue</a>, in the U.S. and New Zealand on Monday, following its initial rollout in Canada and Australia earlier this year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/say-goodbye-to-disappearing-tweets-twitter-no-longer-auto-loads-new-tweets-on-the-web/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234280</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
