<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 09:24:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Sustainable tech developer Turntide Technologies raises $225M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/sustainable-tech-developer-turntide-technologies-raises-225m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/sustainable-tech-developer-turntide-technologies-raises-225m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric motor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turntide Technologies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171743</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Turntide Technologies, a sustainable technology developer, has announced $225 million in convertible note financing that it says will help fund projects to reduce carbon emissions in the commercial buildings, agriculture and transportation industries. Canadian Pension Plan Investment Board led the round, along with Monashee Capital Inc. and current investor JLL Spark. Other participating investors include [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Turntide Technologies, a sustainable technology developer, has announced $225 million in convertible note financing that it says will help fund projects to reduce carbon emissions in the commercial buildings, agriculture and transportation industries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Canadian Pension Plan Investment Board led the round, along with Monashee Capital Inc. and current investor JLL Spark. Other participating investors include Breakthrough Energy Ventures, Millennium Management and Suvretta Capital Management, bringing Turntide’s total funding to $400 million. Convertible note financing is short-term debt that will convert to equity in the form of shares of preferred stock which Turntide says will happen at a future determined valuation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The addition of a major national pension fund fortifies Turntide with permanent capital as we expand into new markets like electrified transport,” said Ryan Morris, Turntide’s chairman and CEO, in a statement.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Earlier this month, Turntide announced the acquisition of Hyperdrive Innovation and BorgWarner Gateshead and </span><a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/turntide-technologies-extends-its-smart-motor-system-to-transportation-sector-with-acquisition-of-electric-vehicle-technology-301307377.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the subsequent launch of Turntide Transport</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Using the drivetrain tech from those two U.K.-based companies, this division of Turntide is focused on modernizing legacy motor systems in the commercial transportation industry such as those found in construction equipment, high-speed rail, autonomous robots, freight trucking and shipping and air cargo. The fresh funds will also go towards Turntide Transport’s goal of creating a “one-stop powertrain platform that includes battery pack, power electronics, motor, and connected intelligence,” according to the company. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company says its so-called “Smart Motor System” reduces energy consumption by nearly 64%, and will address the need for sustainably electrifying more challenging markets than passenger vehicles, where most of the progress has been made to date.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Turntide says it is working with brands such as JCB, Hitachi Rail and Volkswagen’s MAN division to further develop a motor that doesn’t use environmentally damaging rare earth materials, and that can achieve net zero climate goals, which also makes it cheaper to produce. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The $225 million will also finance the development of a cloud-based software platform that the company expects to be released this year. The platform will integrate the Smart Motor System into different built environments and electric vehicles in a way that’s user friendly. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Turntide’s technology combines a redesigned electric motor wrapped in intelligent automation with cloud connectivity to dramatically improve the efficiency of building controls, electric vehicles, and agriculture,” Morris told TechCrunch. “Today, half of the world’s energy is used by electric motors and nearly half of that energy consumption is being wasted due to inefficiency and lack of intelligent controls.” </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/sustainable-tech-developer-turntide-technologies-raises-225m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171743</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google tightens UK policy on financial ads after watchdog pressure over scams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/google-tightens-uk-policy-on-financial-ads-after-watchdog-pressure-over-scams/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/google-tightens-uk-policy-on-financial-ads-after-watchdog-pressure-over-scams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 09:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial Conduct Authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial scams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Ads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Martin Lewis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online harms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK parliament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171927</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UK&#8217;s more expansive, post-Brexit role in digital regulation continues to be felt today via a policy change by Google which has announced that it will, in the near future, only run ads for financial products and services when the advertiser in question has been verified by the financial watchdog, the FCA. The Google Ads [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The UK&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/google-wont-end-support-for-tracking-cookies-unless-uks-competition-watchdog-agrees/">more expansive, post-Brexit role</a> in digital regulation continues to be felt today via a <a href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/united-kingdom/further-measures-help-fight-financial-fraud-uk/">policy change</a> by Google which has announced that it will, in the near future, only run ads for financial products and services when the advertiser in question has been verified by the financial watchdog, the FCA.</p>
<p>The Google Ads Financial Products and Services policy will be updated from August 30, per Google, which specifies that it will start enforcing the new policy from September 6 &#8212; meaning that purveyors of online financial scams who&#8217;ve been relying on its ad network to net their next victim still have more than two months to harvest unsuspecting clicks before the party is over (well, in the UK, anyway).</p>
<p>Google&#8217;s decision to allow only regulator authorized financial entities to run ads for financial products &amp; services follows warnings from the Financial Conduct Authority that it may take legal action if Google continued to accept unscreened financial ads, as <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/uk-regulator-warns-google-about-accepting-scam-adverts">the Guardian</a> reported earlier.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The FCA told a parliamentary committee this month that it&#8217;s able to contemplate taking such action as a result of no longer being bound by European Union rules on financial adverts, which do not extend to online platforms, per the newspaper&#8217;s report.</p>
<p>Until gaining the power to go after Google itself, the FCA appears to have been trying to combat the scourge of online financial fraud by paying Google large amounts of UK taxpayer money to fight scams with anti-scam warnings.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2021/06/18/fca_google_ad_refund/">the Register</a>, the FCA paid Google more than £600,000 (~$830k) in 2020 and 2021 to run &#8216;anti-scam&#8217; ads &#8212; with the regulator essentially engaged in a bidding war with scammers to pour enough money into Google&#8217;s coffers so that regulator warnings about financial scams might appear higher than the scams themselves.</p>
<p>The full-facepalm situation was presumably highly lucrative for Google. But the threat of legal action appears to have triggered a policy rethink.</p>
<p>Writing in its <a href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/united-kingdom/further-measures-help-fight-financial-fraud-uk/">blog post</a>, Ronan Harris, a VP and MD for Google UK &amp; Ireland, said: <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Financial services advertisers will be required to demonstrate that they are authorised by the UK Financial Conduct Authority or qualify for one of the limited exemptions described in the </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://support.google.com/adspolicy/answer/10770884" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-analytics-onclick="{&quot;event&quot;:&quot;page interaction&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;in-article links&quot;,&quot;action&quot;:&quot;link click&quot;,&quot;label&quot;:&quot;https://support.google.com/adspolicy/answer/10770884&quot;}">UK Financial Services verification page</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;This new update builds on significant work in partnership with the FCA over the last 18 months to help tackle this issue,&#8221; he added. &#8220;</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Today’s announcement reflects significant progress in delivering a safer experience for users, publishers and advertisers. While we understand that this policy update will impact a range of advertisers in the financial services space, our utmost priority is to keep users safe on our platforms &#8212; particularly in an area so disproportionately targeted by fraudsters.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The company&#8217;s blog also claims that it has pledged $5M in advertising credits to support financial fraud public awareness campaigns in the UK. So not $5M in actual money then.</p>
<p>Per the Register, Google did offer to refund the FCA&#8217;s anti-scam ad spend &#8212; but, again, with advertising credits.</p>
<p>The UK parliament&#8217;s Treasury Committee was keen to know whether the tech giant would be refunding the spend in cash. But the FCA&#8217;s director of enforcement and market insight, Mark Steward, was unable to confirm what it would do, according to the Register&#8217;s report of the committee hearing.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve reached out to the FCA for comment on Google&#8217;s policy change, and with questions about the refund situation, and will update this report with any response.</p>
<p>In recent years the financial watchdog has also been concerned about financial scam ads running on social media platforms.</p>
<p>Back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/23/facebook-hit-with-defamation-lawsuit-over-fake-ads/">2018</a>, legal action by a well-known UK consumer advice personality, Martin Lewis &#8212; who filed a defamation suit against Facebook &#8212; led the social media giant to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/23/facebook-agrees-to-do-more-to-tackle-scam-ads-after-celebrity-defamation-lawsuit/">add a &#8216;report scam ad&#8217; button</a> in the market as of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/16/uk-facebook-users-now-have-a-tool-to-report-scam-ads/">July 2019</a>.</p>
<p>However research by consumer group, Which?, earlier this year, suggested that neither Facebook nor Google had entirely purged financial scam ads &#8212; even when they&#8217;d been reported.</p>
<p>Per the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56888693">BBC</a>, Which?&#8217;s survey found that Google had failed to remove around a third (34%) of the scam adverts reported to it vs Facebook failing to remove well over a fifth (26%).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s almost like the incentives for online ad giants to act against lucrative online scam ads simply aren&#8217;t pressing enough&#8230;</p>
<p>More recently, Lewis has been pushing for scam ads to be included in the scope of the UK&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/uk-publishes-draft-online-safety-bill/">Online Safety Bill</a>.</p>
<p>The sweeping piece of digital regulation aims to tackle a plethora of so-called &#8216;online harms&#8217; by focusing on regulating user generated content. However Lewis makes the point that a scammer merely needs to pay an ad platform to promote their fraudulent content for it to escape the scope of the planned rules, telling the <em>Good Morning Britain </em>TV program today that the situation is &#8220;ludicrous&#8221; and &#8220;needs to change&#8221;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">&#39;It&#39;s ludicrous. It needs to change.&#39;<a href="https://twitter.com/MartinSLewis?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MartinSLewis</a> calls for changes to be made to the Online Safety Bill to include the policing of scam adverts.</p>
<p>Dame Margaret Hodge agrees with Martin as she highlights that only 1% of police money and time is spent on tackling fraud. <a href="https://t.co/PKI9obagmw">pic.twitter.com/PKI9obagmw</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Good Morning Britain (@GMB) <a href="https://twitter.com/GMB/status/1410128951905767431?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>It&#8217;s certainly a confusing carve-out, as we reported at the time the bill was presented. Nor is it the only confusing component of the planned legislation. However on the financial fraud point the government may believe the FCA has the necessary powers to tackle the problem.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve contacted the Department for Digital, Media, Culture and Sport for comment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="npVD3mXbSk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/23/facebook-agrees-to-do-more-to-tackle-scam-ads-after-celebrity-defamation-lawsuit/">Facebook agrees to do more to tackle scam ads after celebrity defamation lawsuit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook agrees to do more to tackle scam ads after celebrity defamation lawsuit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/23/facebook-agrees-to-do-more-to-tackle-scam-ads-after-celebrity-defamation-lawsuit/embed/#?secret=npVD3mXbSk" data-secret="npVD3mXbSk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pvV5H6hrgB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/uk-publishes-draft-online-safety-bill/">UK publishes draft Online Safety Bill</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK publishes draft Online Safety Bill&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/uk-publishes-draft-online-safety-bill/embed/#?secret=pvV5H6hrgB" data-secret="pvV5H6hrgB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/google-tightens-uk-policy-on-financial-ads-after-watchdog-pressure-over-scams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171927</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigeria&#8217;s MDaaS launches new healthtech product on the back of $2.3M seed extension</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/nigerias-mdaas-launches-new-healthtech-product-on-the-back-of-2-3m-seed-extension/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/nigerias-mdaas-launches-new-healthtech-product-on-the-back-of-2-3m-seed-extension/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 08:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is no secret that healthcare in Nigeria and most parts of Africa is not easily available and a lot of work needs to be done in that regard. However, there are instances where accessibility is taken for granted. Take for instance Nigeria where a majority of the population with some form of healthcare access [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is no secret that healthcare in Nigeria and most parts of Africa is not </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">easily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> available and a lot of work needs to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be done in that regard</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, there are instances where accessibility is taken for granted. Take f</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">or instance Nigeria where a majority of the population with some form of healthcare access would rather treat diseases than prevent them in the first place</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a result, people get to find out about life-threatening diseases, especially non-communicable ones (NCDs), much later in their lives</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Access to diagnostics and preventive care is key to addressing this situation, and Nigerian-based diagnostic startup <a href="https://www.mdaas.io/">MDaaS Global</a> is keen on making these services readily accessible</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, the startup also announcing the launch of its product <a href="https://www.sentinelx.io/">SentinelX</a>, has closed a seed extension round of $2.3 million to scale across Nigeria</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MDaaS, an abbreviation for medical devices-as-a-service, started back in 2016. It operates a network of tech-enabled diagnostic centers across Nigeria. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Two years ago, it raised <a href="https://www.mdaas.io/blog/seedround">a million-dollar seed round</a>. And i</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">n addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to the other investments secured over the last five years, the healthtech startup has raised a total of $3.7 million</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The investors in the round include lead</span><a href="https://www.newtownpartners.com/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Newtown Partners</span></a>,<span style="font-weight: 400;"> who invested via its Imperial Venture Fund, </span><a href="https://crifoundation.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CRI Foundation, </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">and return investors</span><a href="https://fincaventures.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> FINCA Ventures</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Techstars</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span> <a href="https://future.africa/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Future Africa</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The idea for MDaaS came when co-founder and CEO Oluwasoga Oni was tasked alongside his classmates at an MIT class </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to develop an idea that could impact a billion lives</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Coming from a medical background, he chose the one he could relate to.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;I wanted to solve the problem close to me and my dad in my early years. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">He had a 30-bed hospital and struggled so hard to find medical equipment that was good for him and also at a good rate,&#8221; he said to TechCrunch</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oni started MDaaS with Opeyemi Ologun, Genevieve Barnard Oni, and Joseph McCord. With their connections in the U.S., the founders began connecting secondary medical equipment marketplace in the U.S. to Nigeria</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They would import equipment, provide service support, and deploy to hospitals via rent, lease, or outright sale</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The founders did this for a while until they realized that the core problem wasn&#8217;t providing equipment pieces; it was a matter of necessity</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The money doctors spent on the pieces of equipment was more than the earnings from patients. Therefore it </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> didn&#8217;t make financial sense for doctors to own the equipment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MDaaS decided to revert to an aggregation model where they would look at a clinically underserved area</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, build a centralized diagnostic center, and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">aggregate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> demand from small, medium-sized hospitals within that community</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They launched the first center in the Nigerian southwestern city of Ibadan</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">subsequently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> got into Techstars and has since added six other centers across other cities in Nigeria</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171885" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171885" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2171885" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-co-founders-L-R-Oluwasoga-Oni-Opeyemi-Ologun-and-Genevieve-Oni.jpeg?w=680" alt="MDaaS" width="680" height="483" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-co-founders-L-R-Oluwasoga-Oni-Opeyemi-Ologun-and-Genevieve-Oni.jpeg 6238w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-co-founders-L-R-Oluwasoga-Oni-Opeyemi-Ologun-and-Genevieve-Oni.jpeg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-co-founders-L-R-Oluwasoga-Oni-Opeyemi-Ologun-and-Genevieve-Oni.jpeg?resize=300,213 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-co-founders-L-R-Oluwasoga-Oni-Opeyemi-Ologun-and-Genevieve-Oni.jpeg?resize=768,546 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-co-founders-L-R-Oluwasoga-Oni-Opeyemi-Ologun-and-Genevieve-Oni.jpeg?resize=680,483 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-co-founders-L-R-Oluwasoga-Oni-Opeyemi-Ologun-and-Genevieve-Oni.jpeg?resize=1536,1092 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-co-founders-L-R-Oluwasoga-Oni-Opeyemi-Ologun-and-Genevieve-Oni.jpeg?resize=2048,1456 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-co-founders-L-R-Oluwasoga-Oni-Opeyemi-Ologun-and-Genevieve-Oni.jpeg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171885" class="wp-caption-text">MDaaS co-founders (L-R) Oluwasoga Oni, Opeyemi Ologun and Genevieve Oni</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MDaaS diagnostic centers offer a wide range of services. First, there are</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> imaging services such as digital x-ray and ultrasound, cardiac services such as ECG and echo</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Then the lab services ranging from chemistry analysis and immunoassay to hematology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So how did SentinelX come about? Oni tells me that it was during the pandemic last year. As </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">MDaaS helped out with testing for COVID in patients, it was also taking time to screen for underlying health conditions</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We didn&#8217;t </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">really</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> find a lot of people that had COVID, but what we found was that a lot of people had underlying conditions like high blood pressure and high cholesterol that they didn&#8217;t know about</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. So we were really shocked about that.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the past two decades, NCDs have risen </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">dramatically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in sub-Saharan Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are driven by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a growing incidence of cardiovascular risk factors like unhealthy diets, reduced physical activity, hypertension, and diabetes</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Statistics point out that by 2030, NCDs are set to become the leading cause of mortality on the continent. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So far, MDaaS has done a reasonably good job with its diagnostic centers. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">To date, the healthcare startup has provided diagnostic services to over 40,000 patients in underserved communities</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It has also performed over 80,000 diagnostics tests across cardiology, radiology, neurology, laboratory, and general health checks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over 750 clinicians use its referral network, and it has locked partnerships with more than 500 health facilities and 10 HMO networks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Therefore, building SentinelX on the infrastructure already put in place serves as an opportunity to provide more customer-centric products for its users</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform acts as a personalized care program where patients pay a one-time fee of N35k (~$70) and access a doctor all year round</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the moment, users can run through a series of tests ranging from 60 or 70 biomarkers to assess individual risk for a wide range of diseases, including cancers, diabetes, kidney disease, and heart diseases</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clinical and family history and demographic data are also taken into consideration as part of the comprehensive analysis</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, MDaaS creates a care plan unique to customers should they have health concerns after screening</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171884" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171884" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2171884" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-Global-raises-2.3m-to-launch-digital-health-solution-SentinelX-and-expand-across-Nigeria.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-Global-raises-2.3m-to-launch-digital-health-solution-SentinelX-and-expand-across-Nigeria.jpeg 4368w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-Global-raises-2.3m-to-launch-digital-health-solution-SentinelX-and-expand-across-Nigeria.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-Global-raises-2.3m-to-launch-digital-health-solution-SentinelX-and-expand-across-Nigeria.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-Global-raises-2.3m-to-launch-digital-health-solution-SentinelX-and-expand-across-Nigeria.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-Global-raises-2.3m-to-launch-digital-health-solution-SentinelX-and-expand-across-Nigeria.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-Global-raises-2.3m-to-launch-digital-health-solution-SentinelX-and-expand-across-Nigeria.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-Global-raises-2.3m-to-launch-digital-health-solution-SentinelX-and-expand-across-Nigeria.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/MDaaS-Global-raises-2.3m-to-launch-digital-health-solution-SentinelX-and-expand-across-Nigeria.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171884" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> MDaaS</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SentinelX is currently in private beta. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the plan is to go live in September 2021. One would argue that $70 for a year might be cheap for this kind of service, Oni concurs but says</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it&#8217;s all about the long game for MDaaS.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;What we&#8217;re trying to solve is non-consumption. Most</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> people in Nigeria don&#8217;t go for annual screening, which is something meant to be </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">routinely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> done</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Instead, what</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> we tend to have in Nigeria is that people wait till they get sick before going for checkups. By that time, it costs so much money to solve the problem,&#8221; Oni echoes on the lackadaisical effort some Nigerians place on their health</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through SentinelX, MDaaS is trying to get as many people as possible to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">cheaply</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> pre-screen themselves for one year then pay for full value the next year after seeing the benefits of regular checkups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The service is one of many MDaaS can deploy on top of its diagnostic infrastructure built over the years</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">But getting to this point meant the startup had to scale through the capital-intensive hurdle associated with infrastructural plays</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Moreover, defining</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> what price to charge patients has even become more challenging due to the economic recession that has frequently plagued Nigeria.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We have had to get very creative in the way we build things because we target low to middle-income patients. As a result, we&#8217;ve</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> needed to customize our diagnostic infrastructure, especially as it relates to costs for the people we serve,&#8221; Oni added</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The economic recession has also affected one of MDaaS&#8217; most priced assets: doctors. Brain drain is a major challenge facing the Nigerian health system right now. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It has led to a dramatic reduction in the number of Nigerian doctors who leave for a better quality of life and pay, with</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> some reports estimating <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2019/4/8/nigerias-medical-brain-drain-healthcare-woes-as-doctors-flee">that over 2,000 doctors leave annually</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;When you hear about it in the news, it seems like a theoretical thing. But for us, it is real because we have staff leaving to go abroad,&#8221; the CEO remarked</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">MDaaS tries to approach the situation by training younger doctors and deploying them to its centers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Still, there&#8217;s some commitment play as both parties agree on a period of time the doctor would work with the company.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Per application of funds, MDaaS wants to scale its physical footprint across Nigeria by adding six more diagnostic centers this year. A</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ccording to Oni, the healthtech startup wants to become one of Nigeria&#8217;s three largest diagnostic centers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CEO also said MDaaS would consider a pan-African expansion to similar countries like Nigeria, although he gave no timeline</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But by 2025, the company aims to operate 100 centers across the continent and serve a million patients per year. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speaking on the news, the managing partner at Newtown Partners, Llew Claasen, said, “Most consumers in sub-Saharan Africa receive suboptimal medical care because of infrastructure gaps, low physician density, delays in diagnostics, and a lack of health data visibility</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the physical diagnostic infrastructure that MDaaS is building out, coupled with the means to collect data and deliver value-added software services, has the potential to completely change the way that physicians, clinicians, and pharmacists do their jobs and lead to better health outcomes for a huge number of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">previously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> underserved consumers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.” </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d3V3DUnyK4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/rising-african-venture-investment-powers-fintech-cleantech-bets-in-2020/">Rising African venture investment powers fintech, clean tech bets in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rising African venture investment powers fintech, clean tech bets in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/rising-african-venture-investment-powers-fintech-cleantech-bets-in-2020/embed/#?secret=d3V3DUnyK4" data-secret="d3V3DUnyK4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/nigerias-mdaas-launches-new-healthtech-product-on-the-back-of-2-3m-seed-extension/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171856</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>London-based insurtech Hyperexponential closes $18M round led by Highland Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/london-based-insurtech-hyperexponential-closes-18m-round-led-by-highland-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/london-based-insurtech-hyperexponential-closes-18m-round-led-by-highland-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 08:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Highland Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171634</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[London-based insurtech hyperexponential (“hx”) &#8211; which has a mathematical modeling software for the commercial insurance sector &#8211; has closed an $18m funding round led by growth capital fund Highland Europe. Hxsays it helps companies build, deploy and update their insurance pricing models faster, via a SaaS platform called Renew which is aimed at actuaries, data-scientists [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">London-based insurtech <a href="https://www.hyperexponential.com/">hyperexponential</a> (“hx”) &#8211; which has a mathematical modeling software for the commercial insurance sector &#8211; has closed an $18m funding round led by growth capital fund Highland Europe.</p>
<p>Hxsays it helps companies build, deploy and update their insurance pricing models faster, via a SaaS platform called Renew which is aimed at actuaries, data-scientists and underwriters.</p>
<p>Amrit Santhirasenan, hx’s CEO and co-founder, said: “The insurance industry is experiencing unprecedented growth, with data and technology being critical strategic drivers. Our software provides the tools that new entrants to the sector need in order to get to market with best-in-class analytics, and the functionality that incumbent insurers require in order to transform.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Launched in 2017 by Santhirasenan and co-founder Michael Johnson, both software engineers and qualified actuaries, it now services a client base in charge of $50bn worth of premium.</p>
<p>Laurence Garrett, Partner at Highland Europe, said: “We believe hx offers a unique combination of actuarial expertise and software engineering knowhow that delivers exactly the tools that commercial insurers need as their marketplace continues to evolve and transform. This is a sector that is changing very rapidly and hx has already demonstrated considerable growth; we want to help them bring their cloud-based tools and innovation to even more insurers and insurtech companies.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/london-based-insurtech-hyperexponential-closes-18m-round-led-by-highland-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171634</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>German identity verifier IDnow acquires France&#8217;s ARIADNEXT for $59 million, hits M&#038;A road</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/german-identity-verifier-idnow-acquires-frances-ariadnext-for-59-million-hits-ma-road/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/german-identity-verifier-idnow-acquires-frances-ariadnext-for-59-million-hits-ma-road/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 07:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[German]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IDnow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onfido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[verification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warsaw]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171616</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[IDnow, a German-based identity verification startup is acquiring ARIADNEXT, a French equivalent, specializing in remote identity verification and digital identity creation. A price was not released by either party but TechCrunch understands from sources that the deal was approximately $59 million / €50 million. Sources say IDnow is looking to do similar acquisitions. IDnow says [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.idnow.io/">IDnow</a>, a German-based identity verification startup is acquiring <a href="https://www.ariadnext.com/">ARIADNEXT</a>, a French equivalent, specializing in remote identity verification and digital identity creation. A price was not released by either party but TechCrunch understands from sources that the deal was approximately $59 million / €50 million. Sources say IDnow is looking to do similar acquisitions.</p>
<p>IDnow says the combined entity will be able to provide a comprehensive identity verification platform, ranging from AI-driven to human-assisted technology and from online to point-of-sale verification options. IDnow offers its services into the UK, French and German, Spain, Poland, Romania, and other international markets, and says it expects to increase revenue 3x in 2021 versus 2019.</p>
<p>The startup also says the pandemic has meant usage of its products has gone up 200% more compared to last year as companies switch to digital processes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Andreas Bodczek, CEO of IDnow said in a statement: “This combination with ARIADNEXT is an important step towards our vision of building the pan-European leader for identity verification-as-a-service solutions. With ARIADNEXT, in addition to our recent acquisition of identity Trust Management AG, IDnow can provide our customers with an even broader suite of products through a single platform with a seamless user experience.”</p>
<p>Guillaume Despagne, President of ARIADNEXT, said: “We are looking forward to joining a team of IDnow’s caliber, combining our experience and skills to work towards our shared vision of providing a pan-European secure and future-proof solution to customers.</p>
<p>IDnow will retain ARIADNEXT’s locations in Rennes, Paris, Madrid, Bucharest, Iasi, and Warsaw, as well as its over 125 employees. The acquisition is subject to regulatory approvals.</p>
<p>The acquisition means IDNow is now on a par with the other large player in Europe, OnFido. TechCrunch understands the company has done €50m+ revenue this year expect to over-perform its €100m revenue target for 2023.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/german-identity-verifier-idnow-acquires-frances-ariadnext-for-59-million-hits-ma-road/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171616</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ably raises $70 million for its developer platform that enables realtime features</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/ably-raises-70-million-for-its-developer-platform-that-enables-realtime-features/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/ably-raises-70-million-for-its-developer-platform-that-enables-realtime-features/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 07:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ably]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pub/sub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[realtime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ably is a Pub/Sub messaging platform that companies can use to develop realtime features in their products. The company just raised a $70 million Series B funding round co-led by Insight Partners and Dawn Capital. Every day, you use various apps that push and fetch data in realtime. When you send a message in your [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://ably.com">Ably</a> is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Publish%E2%80%93subscribe_pattern">Pub/Sub</a> messaging platform that companies can use to develop realtime features in their products. The company just raised a $70 million Series B funding round co-led by <a href="https://www.insightpartners.com">Insight Partners</a> and <a href="https://dawncapital.com">Dawn Capital</a>.</p>
<p>Every day, you use various apps that push and fetch data in realtime. When you send a message in your favorite chat app, when you edit a document collaboratively, when you start a video call or when you look at financial data, you expect to send and receive stuff in a fraction of a second. It should feel instantaneous otherwise it feels broken.</p>
<p>A popular system that lets you create realtime features is called Pub/Sub, as in publish-subscribe. As the name suggests, with that model, users publish and receive data through the same channel. Users who want to receive data in realtime establish a realtime connection saying that they want to receive new messages that are routed through that channel.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Whenever someone publishes a new message, the message is routed to subscribers as quickly as possible — ideally, the message arrives in a fraction of a second. Push notifications on your smartphone follow more or less the same logic, except that they eventually go through Google’s and Apple’s push notification services.</p>
<p>There are several realtime platform-as-a-service providers out there, including services developed by Amazon Web Services and Google Cloud. And yet, Ably thinks it has the best technology platform out there and can build a large, standalone realtime API-based startup.</p>
<p>Existing investors Triple Point, Digital Horizon, Forward Partners and MMC also participated in today’s funding round.</p>
<p>“We thought realtime data would underpin experiences instead of enhance them,” co-founder and CEO Matthew O’Riordan told me. Ably customers currently contact the startup at different pain points. They may be using different services for their realtime features. Or maybe it doesn’t scale properly.</p>
<p>A good example of that is CRM, sales and marketing startup <a href="https://www.hubspot.com">HubSpot</a>. “They had realtime features across all their products and they were struggling specifically with the chat feature,” O’Riordan said. HubSpot looked at Ably to solve that problem in particular. And they’re now using Ably for all their products, from analytics to live chat and updates.</p>
<p>Ably has built a global network of data centers so that it can route messages as efficiently as possible. Just like content delivery network (CDN) companies try to minimize latency, Ably routes messages based on latency.</p>
<p>The startup also promises redundancy and reliability with a self-healing network. If a data center goes down, your realtime features still operate as usual. You can also store messages in a traditional message queue in case a user is offline and you want to deliver a batch of messages later when they come back online.</p>
<p>Clients include virtual event company Hopin, Bloomberg, Verizon and Tennis Australia (Verizon is also TechCrunch’s parent company). There are also some big customers in the social media space but Ably can’t disclose the names of all its customers. They pay depending on usage, such as the number&nbsp;messages, concurrent connections and channels.</p>
<p>Overall, Ably reaches 250 million devices per month. It currently has 65 employees. With today’s funding round, it expects to hire another 125 employees by the end of 2022.</p>
<p>The company’s vision is straightforward. It wants to build an infrastructure company that becomes an essential part of the services that you use every day. Ably could become the realtime network that delivers messages from point A to point B as quickly and as reliably as possible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/ably-raises-70-million-for-its-developer-platform-that-enables-realtime-features/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171547</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian tech startup exposed Byju&#8217;s student data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/india-startup-byju-student-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/india-startup-byju-student-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 04:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bengaluru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[byju's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online tutoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhiteHat Jr.]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India-based technology startup Salesken.ai has secured an exposed server that was spilling private and sensitive data on one of its customers, Byju&#8217;s, an education technology giant and India&#8217;s most valuable startup. The server was left unprotected since at least June 14, according to historical data provided by Shodan, a search engine for exposed devices and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India-based technology startup Salesken.ai has secured an exposed server that was spilling private and sensitive data on one of its customers, Byju&#8217;s, an education technology giant and India&#8217;s most valuable startup.</p>
<p>The server was left unprotected since at least June 14, according to<a href="https://www.shodan.io/host/35.198.202.33/history"> historical data</a> provided by Shodan, a search engine for exposed devices and databases. Because the server was without a password, anyone could access the data inside. Security researcher <a href="https://twitter.com/hak1mlukha">Anurag Sen</a> found the exposed server, and asked TechCrunch for help in reporting it to the company.</p>
<p>The server was pulled offline a short time after we contacted Salesken.ai on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Salesken.ai provides customer relationship technology to companies like Byju&#8217;s to engage better with customers. The Bengaluru-based startup raised $8 million in Series A funding from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/06/sequoia-announces-1-35-billion-venture-and-growth-funds-for-india-and-southeast-asia/">Sequoia Capital India</a> in 2020, two years after the company was founded.</p>
<p>Much of the data contained on the exposed server pertained to WhiteHat Jr., an online coding school for students in India and the U.S., which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/indias-byjus-acquires-whitehat-jr-for-300-million/">Byju&#8217;s bought for $300 million</a> in 2020. Byju&#8217;s is currently valued at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/indian-edtech-giant-byjus-in-talks-to-raise-over-600-million-at-15-billion-valuation/">more than $16 billion</a> after raising $1.5 billion earlier this year.</p>
<p>The server contained the names and classes taken by students and email addresses and phone numbers of parents and teachers. The server also contained other data related to students, such as chat logs between parents — identified by their phone number — and WhiteHat Jr. staff, as well as comments recorded by teachers about their students.</p>
<p>The server also contained copies of emails containing codes to reset user accounts and other internal Salesken.ai data.</p>
<p>Surga Thilakan, co-founder and chief executive at Salesken.ai, told TechCrunch the startup was &#8220;evaluating&#8221; the security incident but did not dispute what kind of data was found on the exposed server..</p>
<p>&#8220;Our assessment suggests the exposed device appears to be a non-production, staging instance of one of our integration services having access to less than 1% of India based end-of-life sales logs for a fortnight,&#8221; said Thilakan. &#8220;Salesken.ai follows stringent data security norms and is certified under the highest standards of global security and safety. We have, in an abundance of caution, immediately severed access to the cloud device.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thilakan did not respond to a follow-up email from TechCrunch asking why real user data was stored in what the company claims is a &#8220;non-production, staging&#8221; server. The company also would not say if it has logs or any evidence to determine if data was accessed or downloaded as a result of the security lapse.</p>
<p>WhiteHat Jr. spokesperson Sameer Bajaj said the company is &#8220;currently communicating with Salesken.ai about the incident and will take appropriate action in accordance with our rigorous security policies.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Rn2sAQGU4Y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/indias-byjus-acquires-whitehat-jr-for-300-million/">India&#8217;s Byju&#8217;s acquires WhiteHat Jr. for $300 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India&#8217;s Byju&#8217;s acquires WhiteHat Jr. for $300 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/indias-byjus-acquires-whitehat-jr-for-300-million/embed/#?secret=Rn2sAQGU4Y" data-secret="Rn2sAQGU4Y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/india-startup-byju-student-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171687</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequoia Capital India unveils fifth group of startups for Surge</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/sequoia-unveils-fifth-group-of-startups-for-surge/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/sequoia-unveils-fifth-group-of-startups-for-surge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 02:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mesh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nexus Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veera health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India has selected 23 early-stage startups for its fifth cohort of Surge, its accelerator program for India and Southeast Asia, at a time when dealflow activity is at its peak in the region. The new cohort, Surge&#8217;s largest to date, have collectively raised $55 million, the storied investment firm said Wednesday. The group [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Sequoia Capital India has selected 23 early-stage startups for its fifth cohort of Surge, its accelerator program for India and Southeast Asia, at a time when dealflow activity is at its peak in the region.</p>
<p>The new cohort, Surge&#8217;s largest to date, have collectively raised $55 million, the storied investment firm said Wednesday. The group also includes 10 women founders, another record for the accelerator program which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/19/sequoia-surge-inaugural-cohort-india-southeast-asia/">started its journey in March 2019</a> and has backed 91 startups to-date.</p>
<p>The Surge program has enabled Sequoia Capital India &#8212; which has always backed early-stage startups but historically focused more on cutting checks in Series A and beyond rounds &#8212; to more aggressively identify promising startups while they are too young and increase the probability of broadening its portfolio with more winners, investors in the industry said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>And those odds have gotten much better in recent months. As Tiger Global and Falcon Edge begin to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/11/tiger-global-goes-super-aggressive-in-india/">chase early-stage deals in India</a>, both the firms have picked several Surge startups.</p>
<p>Sequoia India said nearly 50% of startups from its first three cohorts have grown to raise their Series A financing rounds.</p>
<p>The Surge program, for which Sequoia India <a href="https://www.surgeahead.com/sequoia-capital-india-announces-new-195m-seed-fund-to-double-down-on-surge/">raised an additional $195 million</a> earlier this year, is now “tried, tested and proven to support founders through strategic mentorship from some of the world’s best startups and business minds, hands-on company building support, and a community of founder-to-founder support,” said the investment firm, which employs over 30 people in advisory roles in the region.</p>
<p>Some investors also said Sequoia India, which offers very aggressive terms and a plethora of resources (App Annie subscription, for instance) to startups in Surge, that the accelerator program has diminished the significance of Y Combinator in India. (Rajan Anandan, who spearheads Surge, told me earlier this year that he doesn&#8217;t see Y Combinator and Surge as rivals.)</p>
<p>The new cohort, several names of which TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/investors-race-to-win-early-stage-startup-deals-in-india/">scooped early this month</a>, includes 13 startups that are building services in fintech, payments, communications, logistics, and SaaS sectors, Surge said.</p>
<p>“We are incredibly proud of all 23 companies who have joined Surge 05 and the founders who have forged their businesses in sectors that have seen tremendous tailwinds. These leaders have displayed grit, exceptional talent, and relentless purpose in shaping the world,” said Anandan, who prior to joining Sequoia Capital India as MD led Google&#8217;s business in India and Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>“At this inflection point of global regrowth, we are excited to be part of the journey of our founders and their companies, many of which we believe will grow into large, enduring businesses,” he added.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2171890 aligncenter" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Surge-05-all-founders-collage.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="536" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Surge-05-all-founders-collage.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Surge-05-all-founders-collage.jpg?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Surge-05-all-founders-collage.jpg?resize=300,157 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Surge-05-all-founders-collage.jpg?resize=768,402 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Surge-05-all-founders-collage.jpg?resize=680,356 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Surge-05-all-founders-collage.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>The new cohort features the following startups as well as one that is operating in stealth mode.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Absolute</strong> is building a plant bioscience and AI-driven adaptive platform for precision agriculture that helps horticulture growers radically transform yields, grade and nutritional value of produce. The startup has also received an investment from Lets Venture.</li>
<li><strong>ADPList</strong> is attempting to &#8220;democratise&#8221; mentorship and make it accessible for everyone through a community platform where people can find, book and meet mentors around the world.</li>
<li><strong>ApnaKlub</strong> is an agent-led business-to-business wholesale platform for fast-moving consumer goods (FMCG). The startup aims to encourage and empower people to set up their own hyper-local micro-distribution businesses by providing them with better profit margins, access to a large assortment of brands and SKUs, and supply consistency.</li>
<li><strong>Belora</strong> produces clean, high-performance, vegan makeup &#8212; free from toxins and harmful ingredients. The startup, which has also secured investment from DSG Consumer Partners, says it wants to create makeup that doubles up as skincare, so that women can wear products that are not only dermatologically tested, but also good for their skin.</li>
<li><strong>Durianpay</strong> is building an integrated and comprehensive payments stack that enables businesses to grow and scale.</li>
<li><strong>Dyte</strong> is a developer-friendly real time audio and video calling software development kit (SDK). The startup, which has also secured investments from Nexus Venture Partners and Y Combinator, allows developers to integrate live video into their apps in interesting and innovative ways. The SDK is simple, offers integrations within hours, and has a large number of plug-ins and configurations. These configurations provide developers with a quick and efficient way to embed audio and video calling, AI video augmentation, and collaboration features.</li>
<li><strong>Gumlet</strong> provides a new-age media delivery infrastructure that provides low code or no-code integration plugins, which automates the entire media publishing pipeline. Developers all over the world use Gumlet to automatically provide the lowest size images and videos with the best resolution and performance.</li>
<li><strong>Locad</strong> is making multi-channel e-commerce fulfilment easier than ever by offering a distributed warehousing network, which reduces shipping time and costs by storing products closer to customers. The startup has also secured investments from Antler and others.</li>
<li><strong>Mailmodo</strong> is an email marketing platform that helps marketers create app-like experiences within emails and increase conversions.</li>
<li><strong>Mesh</strong> is a new-age people management platform that makes it easy for employees to manage goals, get timely feedback, and grow faster. Y Combinator Continuity fund and RTP Global have also invested in Mesh.</li>
<li><strong>Multiplier</strong> is a new-age employer of record that simplifies international hiring. It counts Golden Gate Ventures, MS&amp;AD Ventures, Picus Capital among its investors.</li>
<li><strong>OneCode</strong> is an app that connects companies with sales agents, giving these agents access to sell the products and services to less tech-savvy buyers. The startup’s mission is to digitise 50 million sales agents across India, and bridge the gap between brands and potential buyers who may need in-person interactions and physical touch points before committing to a purchase. Nexus Venture Partners and WaterBridge Ventures have also invested in the startup.</li>
<li><strong>Powerplay</strong> is a mobile-first, vernacular construction site management app that enables project managers and workers to communicate and collaborate more effectively. The startup, also backed by Accel, helps them track their progress, deliverables, and payments across projects.</li>
<li><strong>Pankhuri</strong> is a social community platform where women can network, learn and shop online through live streaming, chat, and micro courses.</li>
<li><strong>RaRa Delivery</strong> is attempting to reimagine instant delivery for e-commerce in Indonesia through data driven logistics. It also counts 500 Startups among its investors.</li>
<li><strong>Revery</strong> is using game thinking to revolutionise wellness, and the team is on a mission to make wellness affordable and accessible to anyone with a mobile phone. The startup has also secured funds from GGV Capital and Pascal Capital.</li>
<li><strong>TWID (That’s What I Do)</strong> is a rewards-based payment network that enables customer reward or loyalty points to be used as a payment instrument. (Beenext is a co-investor.)</li>
<li><strong>Vah Vah!</strong> is a live, online vocational training platform that offers professional beauty courses.</li>
<li><strong>Vara</strong> is an easy-to-use and lightweight staff management platform for SMEs across Southeast Asia. It enables small companies to effortlessly manage their attendance and payroll. The startup counts RTP Global and a number of other firms among its investors.</li>
<li><strong>Veera Health</strong> is on a mission to help women lead healthier lives. Veera’s first offering is a digital therapeutics platform that helps women identify and navigate Polycystic Ovary Syndrome (PCOS), with a comprehensive offering of therapy, coaching and specialist support. Global Founders Capital, Harvard University, and Y Combinator have also backed Veera.</li>
<li><strong>Virtual Internships</strong> are redesigning internships for the 21st century workforce, mirroring the future of work.</li>
<li><strong>WATI</strong> helps companies have personalised conversations with customers at scale with an easy-to-use customer engagement software that’s built on WhatApp’s Business API.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/sequoia-unveils-fifth-group-of-startups-for-surge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171887</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiger Global leads $31.5M investment in interactive edtech Quizizz</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/tiger-global-leads-31-5-million-investment-in-interactive-edtech-quizizz/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/tiger-global-leads-31-5-million-investment-in-interactive-edtech-quizizz/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eight Roads Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GSV Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jerry Yang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nexus Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171852</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Quizizz, an Indian startup that is making learning more interactive so that students find it compelling to spend more hours studying, said on Wednesday it has raised $31.5 million in a new financing round. Tiger Global led the Series B financing round in the five-and-a-half-year-old startup. Yahoo co-founder Jerry Yang and existing investors Eight Roads [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://quizizz.com/">Quizizz</a>, an Indian startup that is making learning more interactive so that students find it compelling to spend more hours studying, said on Wednesday it has raised $31.5 million in a new financing round.</p>
<p>Tiger Global led the Series B financing round in the five-and-a-half-year-old startup. Yahoo co-founder Jerry Yang and existing investors Eight Roads Ventures, GSV Ventures, Nexus Venture Partners also participated in the new round.</p>
<p>Quizizz, which concluded its previous financing round in March this year, has raised $47 million to-date. The new round values it at about $300 million, I heard earlier this month.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“When we were kids, it was so difficult to focus on studies. Our thesis has been that with kids now living in a world with so much distraction, there’s a need to make learning more interesting,” said Ankit Gupta, co-founder and chief executive of Quizizz, in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Along with Deepak Cheenath, Quizizz’s other co-founder, Gupta started the startup’s journey in a non-profit school in Bangalore, where they built several prototypes. The same year &#8212; 2015 &#8212; the duo engaged closely with teachers and students in the U.S., and pivoted to Quizizz, said Gupta.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ja1lIQwGLl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/mapping-out-one-edtech-companys-200m-bet-on-lifelong-learning/">Mapping out one edtech company’s $200M bet on lifelong learning</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mapping out one edtech company’s $200M bet on lifelong learning&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/mapping-out-one-edtech-companys-200m-bet-on-lifelong-learning/embed/#?secret=Ja1lIQwGLl" data-secret="Ja1lIQwGLl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>On Quizizz, teachers and the community develop gamified lessons for students. (Teachers don’t have to build these lessons. For the concepts that they want to explain to students, if lessons exist, many just use those instead. The platform has over 20 million quizzes today.)</p>
<p>These lessons have enabled students to find learning more engaging, said Gupta. The platform also enables teachers to identify in real-time students who are struggling with grasping any concept and then to address those gaps, he said.</p>
<p>The platform covers a range of subjects, including computer science, English, mathematics, science, social studies, world languages and creative arts.</p>
<p>Over the years, Quizizz has grown organically across the globe with many classrooms today using the platform, said Gupta. The platform is used by teachers in over 120 nations today with students answering more than 300 million questions on Quizizz each week. In the U.S., which is Quizizz’s largest market now, over 80% of K-12 schools use the platform, he said.</p>
<p>“During the pandemic, Quizziz made the transition to teaching online seamless. Now that we’re back in the building, I&#8217;ve used it almost exclusively. Making, finding, and altering lessons using Quizizz has become almost a hobby for me,” said Rory Roberts, a math teacher at Brigantine Community School, in a prepared statement.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yahaLw092t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/how-is-edtech-spending-its-extra-capital/">How is edtech spending its extra capital?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How is edtech spending its extra capital?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/how-is-edtech-spending-its-extra-capital/embed/#?secret=yahaLw092t" data-secret="yahaLw092t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“This week, we conducted user-testing with teachers in California, saw a video of students cheering on their classmates in an auditorium in Kenya, and got a thank you note from a group of teachers wearing Quizizz branded t-shirts in Indonesia. We’re incredibly proud of the role our growing team, and teacher community, have played in this movement,” said Quizizz&#8217;s Cheenath.</p>
<p>The startup plans to deploy the fresh capital to expand its team across both the U.S. and India to keep up with its growth. It is also looking to form partnerships to accelerate its international expansion.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/tiger-global-leads-31-5-million-investment-in-interactive-edtech-quizizz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171852</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toca Football raises $40 million to fuel its budding chain of giant soccer and entertainment facilities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/toca-football-raises-40-million-to-fuel-its-budding-chain-of-giant-soccer-and-entertainment-facilities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/toca-football-raises-40-million-to-fuel-its-budding-chain-of-giant-soccer-and-entertainment-facilities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 23:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toca Football]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Toca Football, a nine-year-old, Costa Mesa, Ca.-based company that operates 14 sports centers across the U.S. that are focused on soccer training, has raised $40 million in Series E funding to roughly double the number of facilities that are now up and running in the U.S., as well as to open a site in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://tocafootball.com/">Toca Football</a>, a nine-year-old, Costa Mesa, Ca.-based company that operates 14 sports centers across the U.S. that are focused on soccer training, has raised $40 million in Series E funding to roughly double the number of facilities that are now up and running in the U.S., as well as to open a site in the U.K. that CEO Yoshi Maruyama describes as a &#8220;highly themed game-experiences-based dining and entertainment facility focused on soccer training.&#8221;</p>
<p>Maruyama knows a thing or two about building destinations to which people gravitate. Before joining Toca &#8212; which was founded by the American former soccer player <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eddie_Lewis_(American_soccer)">Eddie Lewis</a> (&#8220;toca&#8221; refers to the first touch of the ball in soccer) &#8212; Maruyama spent six years as the global head of location-based entertainment for Dreamworks. He spent 14 years before that as an SVP with Universal Parks &amp; Resorts.</p>
<p>Indeed, he was brought into Toca in 2019 to transform it from a manufacturing business that sells Major League Soccer teams a ball-tossing machine that Lewis had developed, to the services business it has become.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>On its face, its new model seems like a pretty smart one, given soccer&#8217;s growing popularity in the U.S. According to Statista, the number of participants in U.S. high school soccer programs recorded an all-time high in the 2018/19 season, with more than <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/267963/participation-in-us-high-school-soccer/">850,000</a> playing the sport across the country.</p>
<p>But Toca isn&#8217;t built just for kids, even if kids &#8212; and their parents &#8212; are its primary customers. According to Maruyama, there are several populations that are coming to its various centers throughout the day. In the morning, the centers feature a curriculum for children up to age six to introduce them to soccer; the afternoons feature largely one-on-one soccer training programs where Toca is able to employ its touch trainer; and during the evenings, Toca operates a leagues business for both children and adults.</p>
<p>Some of the centers are huge, by the way. Among Toca&#8217;s newest sites, for example, in Naperville, Illinois, outside of Chicago, it has built a 95,000-square-foot facility that features four indoor, full-size soccer fields, as well as one-on-one individual training spaces. (Maruyama suggests the company has been able to take advantage of a depressed commercial real estate market over the last year or so.)</p>
<p>Little wonder that investors see a big opportunity potentially.</p>
<p>The newest round of funding for Toca comes from earlier investors WestRiver Group, RNS TOCA Partners, and D2 Futbol Investors; they were joined by new investors, including angel investor Jared Smith, the co-founder and former COO of Qualtrics.</p>
<p>The company &#8212; which plans to expand into Asia as quickly as possible (China has been mandated by the country’s leadership to become “<a href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/world/article-can-china-become-a-soccer-superpower/">a first-class football superpower</a>” by 2050) &#8212;  has now raised $105 million in total funding.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/toca-football-raises-40-million-to-fuel-its-budding-chain-of-giant-soccer-and-entertainment-facilities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171770</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lollipop AI launches online grocery marketplace where you can build your own recipes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/lollipop-ai-launches-online-grocery-marketplace-where-you-can-build-your-own-recipes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/lollipop-ai-launches-online-grocery-marketplace-where-you-can-build-your-own-recipes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 23:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[curve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deliveroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hello fresh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HelloFresh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lollipop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ocado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Foster-Carter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waitrose]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I’ve taken to online grocery shopping over the pandemic, I’ve always wondered why supermarkets didn&#8217;t offer simple ‘recipe’ features that would have automatically collected items for a homemade meal. It seemed an opportunity missed. But it is missed no more. Lollipop AI, the new British online grocery marketplace, is launching its public beta today [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As I’ve taken to online grocery shopping over the pandemic, I’ve always wondered why supermarkets didn&#8217;t offer simple ‘recipe’ features that would have automatically collected items for a homemade meal. It seemed an opportunity missed. But it is missed no more.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.lollipopai.com/">Lollipop AI</a>, the new British online grocery marketplace, is launching its public beta today to do that, and it’s been created by a serial UK entrepreneur who was there at the start of successful UK startups Osper, Monzo and Curve.</p>
<p>Founder and CEO Tom Foster-Carter has envisaged a platform allowing people to build meal plans from recipes, assembling the ingredients automatically into their shopping baskets, and suggesting remaining household essentials. He says the Lollipop could well help with health goals, improve culinary skills and minimize food waste. Built as a marketplace, it will be partnering with Sainsbury’s and BBC Good Food with more partners, and fulfillment will be completed by retail partners. The business model will be taking a small commission from retail partners, allowing selected advertising, e.g. from CPG brand owners.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The site will be free to use, while a premium tier is planned. The first 10K beta testers to sign up to the waitlist will be offered access to premium features &#8220;for life,” says the startup, which will offer prices at the same rate as normal supermarkets.</p>
<p>Foster-Carter, who had the idea after having a baby and realizing he was spending hours trying to use a normal supermarket, says the approach will save several hours a week for the average household. (We will briefly note the fact that a man had to create a site like this after doing the weekly shop&#8230;). Lollipop claims 80% of households spend over an hour a week meal-planning and online grocery shopping.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171585" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171585" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2171585" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lollipop_UI_MealPlanner.png" alt="Lollipop MealPlanner" width="1024" height="711" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lollipop_UI_MealPlanner.png 1440w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lollipop_UI_MealPlanner.png?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lollipop_UI_MealPlanner.png?resize=300,208 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lollipop_UI_MealPlanner.png?resize=768,533 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lollipop_UI_MealPlanner.png?resize=680,472 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lollipop_UI_MealPlanner.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171585" class="wp-caption-text">Lollipop MealPlanner</p></div></p>
<p>The founding team includes former employees of Monzo, Farmdrop, Amazon, Sainsbury’s and HelloFresh, such as cofounders Chris Parsons and Ib Warnerbring.</p>
<p>Although Foster-Carter is coy about how much he has raised for this approach, he says he has raised a pre-seed round backed by JamJar Investments, Speedinvest, and a &#8220;raft of grocery/technology big hitters&#8221; including Ian Marsh (former UK GM of HelloFresh) and former leadership and founders of online grocers in the U.K. and abroad plus &#8216;super angels&#8217; Charles Songhurst and Ed Lando.</p>
<p>In particular, the site is likely to appeal to people looking to lose weight, as meal planning would be simpler and may even have an impact on recipe-box startups.</p>
<p>Lollipop is not alone in its ambitions. Jupiter.co in the U.S. bills itself as “groceries on autopilot”; Jow is recipe-led shopping, as is Side Chef; while Cooklist is a meal-planner + cooking support, also in the U.S.</p>
<p>Foster-Carter told me: &#8220;It’s a marketplace so we could partner with traditional supermarkets (Sainbury’s, Tescos, Waitrose etc) + online retailers (Ocado, Amazon), direct to farm / organic (Riverford, Farmdrop), mission-led single component (Oddbox, Milk &amp; More, etc); recipe boxes (Gousto, Hello Fresh, Mindful Chef etc); and rapid delivery (Gorillas, Getir, Weezy, etc).</p>
<p>“This is just the start… The plan is to be the single place you go to for all your food needs &#8211; we’ll enable you to order your Deliveroo or restaurant kit (e.g. Dishpatch) from us. Groceries are delivered by our partners, and then when it’s time to cook you’ll be able to use a cooking companion app (due out next month). In the future you’ll be able to improve your cooking skills through Lollipop.”</p>
<p>Few players have nailed the ability to buy a lot of items (50-100+) really fast, not even Amazon &#8211; this might be Lollipop’s USP, if it can crack it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/lollipop-ai-launches-online-grocery-marketplace-where-you-can-build-your-own-recipes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171560</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MWC 2021 day two: Is this thing on?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/mwc-2021-day-two-is-this-thing-on/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/mwc-2021-day-two-is-this-thing-on/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 22:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Huawei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mwc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mwc 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Listen, it’s probably not the best sign when a show feels like it’s running out of steam on its first day. Mobile World Congress’ opening salvo was headlined by Samsung in an event that touched on some partnerships and spent equal time teasing an upcoming event where it will actually launch some hardware. It’s hard [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Listen, it’s probably not the best sign when a show feels like it’s running out of steam on its first day. Mobile World Congress’ opening salvo was headlined by Samsung in an event that touched on some partnerships and spent equal time teasing an upcoming event where it will actually launch some hardware. It’s hard to get too down on the GSMA, and I really ought to preface all of these by reiterating that – even in a normal year – running an event is hard as hell. Canceling its flagship show last year had to be gut-wrenching, and deciding to go forward with this one must have also been – albeit for dramatically different reasons?</p>
<p>It’s not like the show didn’t come with some wins. What’s that? Elon Musk videoed in? That’s a pretty massive get by any measure, with all of the standard “whatever you think about the guy” preambles. Love him or hate, you’ve heard about him and probably have extremely strong feelings about the dude, one way or another.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171507" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171507" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2171507" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_5C685E71D930-1.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_5C685E71D930-1.jpeg 2208w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_5C685E71D930-1.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_5C685E71D930-1.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_5C685E71D930-1.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_5C685E71D930-1.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_5C685E71D930-1.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_5C685E71D930-1.jpeg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_5C685E71D930-1.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171507" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://mwcbarcelona.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mobile World Congress </a><span class="screen-reader-text"><a href="https://mwcbarcelona.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">(opens in a new window)</a></span></p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The High Priest of Dogeking beamed in to talk SpaceX StarLink. “To be totally frank, we are losing money on that terminal right now,” Musk said in the interview. “That terminal costs us more than $1,000, so obviously I’m subsidizing the cost of the terminal.” Good thing he’s got deep pockets.</p>
<p>He promised a new version of the company’s satellite next year, “which will be significantly more capable.”</p>
<p><a href="https://www.huawei.com/en/news/2021/6/5g-industry-unique-all-band-all-scenario-2021">Huawei thus far has focused much more on networking than consumer</a> – it’s important to caveat this by adding that MWC is as much, if not more, a networking show, in spite of all of the press that tends to focus on consumer device launches. The company launched a bunch of 5G networking hardware, including several MIMO products.</p>
<p>Speaking of networks, I totally forgot to include this bit from TechCrunch parent co (you know, for now). Verizon trotted out a bunch of robots with 5G branding. The company was making a point about the importance of cellular for future robotics communication.</p>
<p>Here’s CSO Rima Qureshi, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/verizon-shows-off-5g-connected-robots-barcelona-conference-2021-06-28/">quoted by Reuter</a>s, &#8220;5G will make it possible for robots to connect with other robots and devices of all kinds in a way that simply wasn&#8217;t possible before.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171799" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171799" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2171799" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210628-2.png" alt="" width="800" height="438" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210628-2.png 800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210628-2.png?resize=150,82 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210628-2.png?resize=300,164 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210628-2.png?resize=768,420 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210628-2.png?resize=680,372 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210628-2.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171799" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Huawei</p></div></p>
<p>Let’s be honest, though, mostly robots make for cool stage fodder. From what I can tell, the Boston Dynamics-esque quadruped was this bot from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/19/the-vivacious-acrobatic-minitaur-robot-will-definitely-improve-your-day/">Ghost Robotics</a>, which Verizon also trotted out (well, it trotted itself out, I suppose) at CES in January:</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/3icRite6RMk?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Given the choice, would I have put on an in-person event in Barcelona in the summer of 2021? No. Nuh-uh. No way. Did the GSMA feel like they had a choice financially or otherwise? That’s a much more difficult question to answer. When you’re a company that runs on events and partnerships, even canceling a single big show is a shock to the system.</p>
<p>I’m going back and forth on whether I’ll be doing any more of these roundups as the show progresses through Thursday. Definitely if some more interesting stuff shows up, or if there’s like video of Elon hoverboarding through the sparsely populated convention center halls or something. But I’m not holding my breath.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/mwc-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/mwc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about Mobile World Congress 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/mwc-2021-day-two-is-this-thing-on/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171797</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Language-learning app Duolingo translates strong revenues into IPO filing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/daily-crunch-25/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/daily-crunch-25/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 22:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for June 29, 2021. Have you ever wanted to ditch civilization and move to the woods, but still be able to work? We have good news if that’s you. Below you’ll find lots more, including Facebook’s latest product offering and how one startup wants to save bees. Enjoy! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/duolingo-s-1/"><strong>Duolingo is going public! </strong></a>Well-known edtech unicorn Duolingo is going public. TechCrunch has an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/duolingo-s-1/">overview of the IPO</a> and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/duolingos-s-1-depicts-heady-growth-monetization-new-focus-on-english-certification/">deeper dive into the company’s business health</a>. Based on traffic to our coverage on the matter since last night, ya’ll are really into learning languages. Also make sure to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1/">check out the Duolingo EC-1</a>.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/facebooks-newsletter-platform-bulletin-is-now-live/">Facebook launches newsletters:</a> </strong>Say hello to Bulletin, Facebook’s new newsletter service. Competing with Substack, Twitter’s Revu and other services, Facebook signed up a Boomer-friendly list of initial authors including Malcolm Gladwell. The social giant has a history of testing in-house versions of products that are successful externally. We’ll have to wait and see if Bulletin manages to survive on its own merit.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/spacex-is-losing-money-on-its-starlink-terminals-but-sees-lower-costs-ahead/"><strong>SpaceX plans to spend billions on Starlink:</strong></a> According to Elon Musk, SpaceX is losing money on early Starlink connector kits. Starlink is the space company’s low-orbit satellite network that could bring about global internet connectivity. Per TechCrunch reporting of Musk’s comments, “SpaceX’s overall investment in the project could be between $5 billion-$10 billion initially and as much as $30 billion over time.” For the sake of freelancers everywhere, let’s hope the tech shakes out to match the investment.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Up top today in our roundup of recent startup news is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/beeflow-raises-8-3-million-to-save-the-bees-and-put-them-to-work/">Beeflow</a>. We’re putting it at the top of the list because (1) It’s about bees and (2) It’s called Beeflow. What’s not to love? Per <a href="https://twitter.com/jordanrcrook">Jordan Crook</a>, the startup may have an answer to the decimation of the global bee population. And it might make money to boot.</p>
<p>Now, the rest of the news:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/late-stage-capital-is-having-a-cascading-effect-on-european-vc-activity/">Europe’s early-stage market is on fire:</a> </strong>That’s the takeaway from a recent TechCrunch dig into the continent’s venture capital trade. So <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/25/like-the-us-a-two-tier-venture-capital-market-is-emerging-in-latin-america/">is Latin America’s</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/the-early-stage-venture-capital-market-is-weird-and-chaotic/">the United States’</a>. In brief, the regional startup zones of the world are becoming increasingly blurred thanks to Zoom deal-making; what was once true in one place may now be the case in every hub.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/zomatos-100-million-investment-to-turn-grofers-into-a-unicorn/"><strong>Zomato to drop $100M on Grofer</strong></a><strong>: </strong>The Indian tech scene is busy these days, with <a href="https://twitter.com/refsrc?lang=en">Manish Singh</a> reporting that IPO-headed food-delivery giant Zomato intends to invest $100 million in online grocer Grofer. Grofer would become a unicorn in the transaction.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/sources-sentinelone-expects-to-raise-over-1b-in-nyse-ipo-tomorrow-listing-with-a-10b-market-cap/">SentinelOne could be worth $10 billion in its IPO:</a></strong> That’s the latest on the SentinelOne public debut, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/23/investors-thirst-for-growth-could-bode-well-for-sentinelones-ipo/">which we’ve looked at here</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/sentinelones-upgraded-ipo-pricing-is-good-news-for-tiger-public-markets-and-your-local-vc/">dug into the pricing of here</a>. The cybersecurity company’s IPO could help kick off a hot third quarter for IPOs more generally, especially at the prices at which it is set to debut.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/training-platform-virti-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-iq-capital-to-teach-soft-skills-in-vr/"><strong>$10M to teach soft skills with VR:</strong></a><strong> </strong>That’s the latest on Virti, which wants to turn “a lot of subjectively assessed skills into more objective and measurable” outputs. VR is cool, and soft skills matter. Let’s see what their union can bring. Please, no &#8220;Black Mirror&#8221; jokes.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/digital-greeting-card-startup-givingli-wraps-3-million-seed-round/"><strong>Givingli raises $3M for greeting card tech:</strong></a> Not every venture capital round is large. Some are small enough to fit into an envelope. That’s the case with Givingli’s latest round, which should give the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/givingli/id1386635163?ls=1">digital card and gifting app</a> more room to build out its service.</li>
</ul>
<p>And I would be remiss to not mention that I covered venture capital rounds this morning from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/co-op-raises-5-8m-round-to-help-online-merchants-land-customers-for-less/">co-op</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/arrows-raises-2-75m-to-build-out-its-customer-onboarding-software/">Arrows</a>, along with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/saas-focused-acceleprise-rebrands-raises-30m-in-new-capital/">news regarding Acceleprise’s rebrand</a>.</p>
<h2>How VCs can get the most out of co-investing alongside LPs</h2>
<p>In a recent private equity survey, 80% of respondents said their co-investments with people outside traditional VC firms outperformed their PE fund investments.</p>
<p>Alternative investors are highly motivated, and because they&#8217;re seeking higher returns than are generally available in public markets, they are less daunted by risk. In return, they benefit from less expensive fee structures and develop close ties with VCs, enlarging the talent pool as they build investment skills.</p>
<p>These relationships have direct benefits for VCs as well, such as more flexibility with diversification and consolidated decision-making power.</p>
<p>&#8220;With the right deal structure, deal selection and deal investigation, co-investors can significantly increase their returns,&#8221; says C5 Capital Managing Partner William Kilmer, who wrote an Extra Crunch post for VCs considering an alternative path.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DBoz7ahL4t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/how-vcs-can-get-the-most-out-of-co-investing-alongside-lps/">How VCs can get the most out of co-investing alongside LPs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How VCs can get the most out of co-investing alongside LPs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/how-vcs-can-get-the-most-out-of-co-investing-alongside-lps/embed/#?secret=DBoz7ahL4t" data-secret="DBoz7ahL4t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Turning from the smaller upstarts to the megagiants, it’s been a good week to be a Big Tech company. Facebook crossed the $1 trillion market cap threshold, though it dipped back under the magic number this afternoon. Here’s what else is going on from the Bigs:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/shopify-drops-its-app-store-commissions-to-0-on-developers-first-million-in-revenue/"><strong>Shopify cuts its cut to 0%:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Shopify will charge zero for developers’ first million in revenue that they make on its application marketplace. The move fits into a larger trend of app stores lowering their cuts as Apple fights tooth and nail to avoid doing the same with its own application emporium. The Shopify news is probably more aimed at e-commerce rival Amazon than Apple, but the move still gently undercuts Cupertino’s argument that it deserves around a third of all commerce that happens on iOS.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/github-previews-new-ai-tool-that-makes-coding-suggestions/"><strong>AI developers are coming:</strong></a><strong> </strong>News out today from Microsoft’s GitHub product is notable, with the sub-org announcing an AI-powered tool that “suggests code as you type.” GitHub teamed up with OpenAI to build the tool. For beginners, the coding service could prove to be super freaking neat.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how these surveys are shaping our coverage, check out this interview Extra Crunch Managing Editor <a href="https://twitter.com/eldon">Eric Eldon</a> did with Scott Tong, “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/the-pandemic-showed-why-product-and-brand-design-need-to-sit-together/">The pandemic showed why product and brand design need to sit together</a>.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z4Yo6WHDEd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/the-pandemic-showed-why-product-and-brand-design-need-to-sit-together/">The pandemic showed why product and brand design need to sit together</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The pandemic showed why product and brand design need to sit together&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/the-pandemic-showed-why-product-and-brand-design-need-to-sit-together/embed/#?secret=Z4Yo6WHDEd" data-secret="Z4Yo6WHDEd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/daily-crunch-25/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171660</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rimac Automobili founder Mate Rimac shares lessons from bootstrapping an EV company</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/rimac-automobili-founder-mate-rimac-shares-lessons-from-bootstrapping-an-ev-company/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/rimac-automobili-founder-mate-rimac-shares-lessons-from-bootstrapping-an-ev-company/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 22:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[croatia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Croatia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mate Rimac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rimac automobili]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2168938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["They didn't want to touch Croatia, like 'Where the hell is that?' It was quite a ride."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mate Rimac&#8217;s founder story has the makings of automotive folklore. He started Rimac Automobili in his garage in 2009 as a literal one-person operation that has grown to a company with more than 1,000 employees, supply contracts with automakers like Porsche and a new electric hypercar moving into production.</p>
<p>What might not be known is how close the company came to failing. &#8220;It has been such a wild ride,&#8221; Mate Rimac said during an interview at at the virtual <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a> event. &#8220;The first seven years, we were like out of money and technically bankrupt all the time.&#8221;</p>
<p>The founder and CEO of Croatian electric hypercar and components developer Rimac Automobili joined TechCrunch on our virtual stage to talk about the company&#8217;s new Nevera vehicle, his interest in electric robotaxis and the prospect of an acquisition of Bugatti. Throughout the interview, he gave a candid account of some of the company&#8217;s lowest points, how he and the company survived and what other founders can learn from his experience.</p>
<h2>&#8220;It was quite a ride.&#8221;</h2>
<p>Today, Rimac Automobili is a household name in Croatia with plans to grow even larger. Rimac is currently building a headquarters and technology campus on a 49-acre site that is slated to be completed in 2023. It was a far more solitary experience the first few years of Rimac Automobili&#8217;s existence. Even when it gained recognition, the company came close to failing numerous times, Rimac said in the interview.</p>
<blockquote><p>It has been such a wild ride. And like the first seven years, we were like out of money and technically bankrupt all the time.</p>
<p>We had situations where I can&#8217;t even start to explain what we survived. I set out this company 12 years ago, I was alone for two years. The first employee joined me in 2011. So it was really built from a garage.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/rimac-automobili-founder-mate-rimac-shares-lessons-from-bootstrapping-an-ev-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2168938</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>If you pay an emotional labor fee, Postdates will get your stuff from your ex</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/if-you-pay-an-emotional-labor-fee-postdates-will-get-your-stuff-from-your-ex/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/if-you-pay-an-emotional-labor-fee-postdates-will-get-your-stuff-from-your-ex/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 21:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ani Acopian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[films]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postmates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[producer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, the team behind the parody Amazon Dating delivered us Postdates. It&#8217;s like Postmates, but for getting your stuff back from your ex. Postdates looks like the actual Postmates website — you can select a type of relationship (&#8220;casually dated,&#8221; &#8220;lived together,&#8221; &#8220;one night stand,&#8221; etc.) like it&#8217;s a type of restaurant. Then, you can [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Yesterday, the team behind the parody <a href="https://twitter.com/aniacopian/status/1224760570374524929">Amazon Dating</a> delivered us <a href="https://postdates.co/feed">Postdates</a>. It&#8217;s like Postmates, but for getting your stuff back from your ex.</p>
<p>Postdates looks like the actual Postmates website — you can select a type of relationship (&#8220;casually dated,&#8221; &#8220;lived together,&#8221; &#8220;one night stand,&#8221; etc.) like it&#8217;s a type of restaurant. Then, you can choose from preset items to retrieve (concert tickets if you were friend-zoned, family heirlooms if you were divorced) or add a custom item. Delivery starts at $25 in LA and $30 in NY, along with an additional emotional labor fee of $3.99. Yes, you can actually use this service if you&#8217;re in one of these two cities, but Postdates isn&#8217;t here to stay &#8212; it&#8217;s a pop-up business. Or, as Postdates &#8220;founder&#8221; Ani Acopian puts it, &#8220;It&#8217;s kind of like watching a &#8216;Black Mirror&#8217; episode, but it&#8217;s your real life.&#8221;</p>
<p>You might remember Elon Musk’s failed comedy startup/&#8221;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/14/elon-musks-media-empire-staffed-by-ex-onion-writers-might-be-called-thud/">intergalactic media empire</a>&#8221; Thud, which aimed to create immersive digital experiences that blurred the lines between what’s real and fake. Or, you might not remember Thud, since it <a href="https://www.mic.com/p/elon-musks-first-foray-into-comedy-was-a-strange-satirical-website-called-thud-77009671">failed spectacularly</a> and wasn’t very funny. Postdates struck the satire gold that Elon Musk dreamed of with Thud, only they did it without $2 million dollars in funding from one of the richest men in the world.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p1">TechCrunch talked to conceptual artist Ani Acopian, producer Suzy Shinn and product developer Brian Wagner to get the lowdown on just how legit Postdates is.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171732" style="width: 1066px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171732" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171732 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.25-PM.png" alt="" width="1056" height="934" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.25-PM.png 1056w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.25-PM.png?resize=150,133 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.25-PM.png?resize=300,265 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.25-PM.png?resize=768,679 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.25-PM.png?resize=680,601 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.25-PM.png?resize=50,44 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1056px) 100vw, 1056px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171732" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://postdates.co" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Postdates </a><span class="screen-reader-text"><a href="http://postdates.co" target="_blank" rel="noopener">(opens in a new window)</a></span></p></div></p>
<p><strong>TechCrunch:</strong> <strong>Why Postdates? How did the idea come about?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Suzy Shinn:</strong> At the start of quarantine when everything was falling apart, Ani and I made <a href="https://aniacopian.com/SCRUBHUB">ScrubHub</a>, like PornHub for hand washing. We raised $50,000 for charity.</p>
<p><strong>Ani Acopian: </strong>I think we had this creative juice inside of us that we wanted to find an outlet for.</p>
<p><strong>SS:</strong> Then, we had the Postdates idea, and we actually tried to get investors and artists to fund it, because we were like … This is going to cost something, we want to make it real and actually function. No one wanted anything to do with it, because they were like, &#8220;What&#8217;s the return?&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>AA:</strong> And we were like, &#8220;Well, the return is that it&#8217;s a vibe.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>SS:</strong> No one wanted anything to do with us fundingwise, so we built it ourselves.</p>
<p><strong>So, you <em>can</em> actually use this?</strong></p>
<p><strong>AA:</strong> Yeah, we partnered with two local courier companies, <a href="https://www.gourmetrunnerla.com/">Gourmet Runner</a> in LA and <a href="https://airpals.net/">Airpals</a> in New York. We wanted to make sure we work with people that treat their workers right.</p>
<p><strong>SS:</strong> You can put in a request, and the ex has to consent obviously and be like, &#8220;Yeah, I have this stuff for you, I&#8217;ll put it outside,&#8221; and our couriers have Postdates bags that we give to them. But legitimately, you can use it in both of those cities as long as you&#8217;re not sending a cat, or a child, or alcohol, or drugs, or something that won&#8217;t fit in a bag.</p>
<p><strong>AA:</strong> We spent a lot of time on the workflow to make sure no addresses are shared, that everyone&#8217;s consenting to be involved, and we&#8217;re trying to keep it no contact, so we&#8217;re asking people to put stuff on their door handle. You&#8217;re not charged until your ex accepts the order.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171734" style="width: 1042px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171734" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171734 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.23.30-PM.png" alt="" width="1032" height="555" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.23.30-PM.png 1032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.23.30-PM.png?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.23.30-PM.png?resize=300,161 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.23.30-PM.png?resize=768,413 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.23.30-PM.png?resize=680,366 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.23.30-PM.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1032px) 100vw, 1032px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171734" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://postdates.co" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Postdates <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p><strong>You just launched yesterday, but have people actually been using the service so far?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Brian Wagner:</strong> We had some people who would post a screenshot in response to Ani&#8217;s tweet and be like, &#8220;Oh snap, I actually got Postdated by my ex!&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>SS:</strong> There&#8217;s about 30 to 40 pending requests, and we&#8217;ve gotten a handful that just as of this morning have been delivered successfully.</p>
<p><strong>Do you think this could be a viable business?</strong></p>
<p><strong>AA:</strong> Not everything needs to be a viable business. I would actually be … not surprised, but upset if this actually became a thing, because I don&#8217;t think the world needs that level of stuff, but I think we&#8217;re pretty much already there. All you can do is hold the mirror up.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171736" style="width: 432px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171736" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171736 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.39-PM.png" alt="" width="422" height="504" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.39-PM.png 422w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.39-PM.png?resize=126,150 126w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.39-PM.png?resize=251,300 251w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-9.18.39-PM.png?resize=42,50 42w" sizes="(max-width: 422px) 100vw, 422px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171736" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://postdates.co" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Postdates <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p><strong>As satire, what are you trying to say with Postdates?</strong></p>
<p><strong>SS:</strong> I think in the tech world, it seems like all of these tech startups get crazy amounts of funding, and they spend so much money, and they take themselves so seriously. The three of us, with the help of our friends, were able to do this, and we didn&#8217;t need $13 million in funding or five years. But we were staying up until like 5 a.m., and we were like, &#8220;Can we hire someone to help us?&#8221; but we were like, &#8220;No, we can&#8217;t pay.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>BW:</strong> Especially with the rise of the gig economy, we&#8217;ve seen some positives and some pretty serious negatives, especially during quarantine. It helps people get the things that they need, but also, a lot of workers aren&#8217;t being paid fairly and don&#8217;t have health insurance. So there&#8217;s a sentiment a lot more often now that a lot of tech is redistributing labor, and you&#8217;re just paying for people to be moved around. So in a way, we&#8217;re sort of like … We&#8217;ve redistributed emotional labor here.</p>
<p><strong>There&#8217;s an emotional labor tax on the site, yeah.</strong></p>
<p><strong>BW:</strong> There&#8217;s a bit of poking fun of that, saying how far will we go in terms of actually moving labor along for money. Will people pay for someone else to deal with the emotional handling of a situation?</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">i wasn’t having much luck with dating apps so i partnered with <a href="https://twitter.com/amazon?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@amazon</a> to make a better one <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f440.png" alt="👀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f498.png" alt="💘" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><a href="https://t.co/ticxR7j7CO">https://t.co/ticxR7j7CO</a></p>
<p>&mdash; ani (@aniacopian) <a href="https://twitter.com/aniacopian/status/1224760570374524929?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 4, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><strong>How did Postdates build upon Amazon Dating?</strong></p>
<p><strong>AA:</strong> We&#8217;ve made two parody sites now, and we wanted to take that to the next level and make it experiential. It&#8217;s kind of like watching a &#8220;Black Mirror&#8221; episode, but it&#8217;s your real life.</p>
<p><strong>SS:</strong> What is the literal price you will pay not to see someone? This is a real thing that happens all the time &#8212; my friends will be like, &#8220;I broke up with my girlfriend, I need you to go get my stuff,&#8221; and I&#8217;m like, &#8220;I don&#8217;t want to go get your stuff.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>AA:</strong> I don&#8217;t think we should outsource it, though.</p>
<p><strong>So you don&#8217;t think we should outsource it, but also, you made Postdates.</strong></p>
<p><strong>AA:</strong> I think that&#8217;s the whole …</p>
<p><strong>That&#8217;s the joke.</strong></p>
<p><strong>AA:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>What does it say about startup culture to make a product that you don&#8217;t think should exist?</strong></p>
<p><strong>SS:</strong> Startups are so, so serious, there&#8217;s no humor in it, and they think it&#8217;s going to last forever. Well, we&#8217;re doing the opposite.  We&#8217;re going to make this last a couple of weeks for a limited time only, and then we&#8217;re gonna take it away. But we would love to keep doing these, making something where art meets tech meets entertainment.</p>
<p><strong>BW:</strong> Companies and experiences can just be fun. They don&#8217;t have to be a billion dollar idea, they don&#8217;t have to be something that&#8217;s going to go on &#8220;Shark Tank.&#8221; Imagine us entering &#8220;Shark Tank … .&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="c24rAqNaQ0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/summer-sale-save-10-on-extra-crunch-membership/">Summer Sale: Save 10% on Extra Crunch membership</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Summer Sale: Save 10% on Extra Crunch membership&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/summer-sale-save-10-on-extra-crunch-membership/embed/#?secret=c24rAqNaQ0" data-secret="c24rAqNaQ0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/if-you-pay-an-emotional-labor-fee-postdates-will-get-your-stuff-from-your-ex/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171573</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM&#8217;s newest startup aims squarely at the commercial EV market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gms-newest-startup-aims-squarely-at-the-commercial-ev-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gms-newest-startup-aims-squarely-at-the-commercial-ev-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roberto Baldwin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 20:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BrightDrop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fedex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2170674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the next few years, you'll more likely see an electric delivery van dropping off your packages than an electric car in your neighbor's driveway.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ford and GM&#8217;s century-old battle for market share is no longer restricted to gas- and diesel-powered passenger car, truck and SUV sales. The hottest market in the next decade is commercial and electric.</p>
<p>In this new race, the two companies are taking different strategies as they square off against each other &#8212; along with a growing list of EV startups &#8212; to win over as many delivery and fleet-vehicle customers as possible.</p>
<p>GM&#8217;s weapon is BrightDrop, a new startup incubated and launched at CES 2021 by Chairman and CEO Mary Barra. The venture boasts an ecosystem of EV hardware and logistical software products aimed squarely at fleet and delivery companies. GM&#8217;s interest in the space is far from merely exploratory; it anticipates that the market for delivery, including food and parcels in the United States, will be <a href="https://plants.gm.com/media/us/en/gm/home.detail.html/content/Pages/news/us/en/2021/jan/ces/0112-brightdrop.html">more than $850 billion by 2025</a>.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			For fleet managers, it comes down to the numbers on a spreadsheet, and thanks to incentives and lower maintenance costs associated with EVs, vans that run on electrons instead of dead dinosaurs make financial sense.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>&#8220;Folks on the commercial side don&#8217;t really care about the technology &#8212; they care about the economics,&#8221; <a href="https://www.cargroup.org/person/brett-smith/?gclid=Cj0KCQjw5auGBhDEARIsAFyNm9Eb_lVYmOo6bbaCEx12-XSJlM7SDoRgo07aUo3jxSdkdWTpbeUKmpcaAlnHEALw_wcB">Brett Smith</a>, director of technology at research firm CAR, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Electric vehicles might be more ecologically sound than traditional gas- or diesel-powered vehicles, but for fleet managers, it comes down to the numbers on a spreadsheet, and thanks to incentives and lower maintenance costs associated with EVs, vans that run on electrons instead of dead dinosaurs make financial sense.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gms-newest-startup-aims-squarely-at-the-commercial-ev-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2170674</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook&#8217;s newsletter platform Bulletin is now live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/facebooks-newsletter-platform-bulletin-is-now-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/facebooks-newsletter-platform-bulletin-is-now-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bulletin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Substack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171605</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The cool new thing on Facebook is for Mark Zuckerberg to drop product news in live audio rooms. So today, Zuckerberg took to his brand&#8217;s Clubhouse competitor to announce its next new thing: Bulletin, a newsletter platform. Bulletin is built on a separate platform from Facebook &#8212; on its website, the FAQ states that this is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The cool new thing on Facebook is for Mark Zuckerberg to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/facebook-whatsapp-e-commerce-features/">drop product news</a> in live audio rooms. So today, Zuckerberg took to his brand&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebook-officially-launches-live-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-in-the-u-s/">Clubhouse competitor</a> to announce its <em>next</em> new thing: Bulletin, a newsletter platform.</p>
<p>Bulletin is built on a separate platform from Facebook &#8212; on its <a href="https://www.bulletin.com/">website</a>, the FAQ states that this is to &#8220;enable creators to grow their audience in ways that are not exclusively dependent on the Facebook platform.&#8221; You don&#8217;t need a Facebook account to subscribe to a newsletter, but Bulletin relies on Facebook&#8217;s infrastructure, including the use of Facebook Pay to purchase premium subscriptions and join subscriber-only groups and live audio rooms.</p>
<p>Competitors like Substack take a &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/substack-explains-its-hands-off-approach-to-content-moderation/">hands-off</a>&#8221; approach to content moderation, allowing anyone to start a newsletter. But every writer currently on Facebook&#8217;s Bulletin was hand-picked to contribute. Still, Substack has received scrutiny for <a href="https://doyles.substack.com/p/in-queers-we-trust-all-others-pay">subsidizing anti-trans rhetoric</a> through its controversial <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/22338802/substack-pro-newsletter-controversy-jude-doyle">Substack Pro program</a>, which commissioned particular writers to write on Substack. So, Bulletin won&#8217;t be immune to the issues that plague Substack despite its heavily curated model.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The initial slate of writers on Bulletin includes Malcom Gladwell, Mitch Albom, Erin Andrews and Tan France &#8212; the FAQ also notes that its beta program is U.S.-centric, with only two international writers at the moment (&#8220;We will look to include more international creators after our beta program launch,&#8221; Bulletin says.) Facebook is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-bulletin-newsletters-180747141.html">paying its writers up front</a> for their contributions, and so far, doesn&#8217;t plan to take a cut of their profits. If writers choose to move off the platform, they will have the ability to take their subscriber lists with them.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Lcp4tfxjYU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/">Is Substack really worth $650M?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Is Substack really worth $650M?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/embed/#?secret=Lcp4tfxjYU" data-secret="Lcp4tfxjYU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/facebooks-newsletter-platform-bulletin-is-now-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171605</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How VCs can get the most out of co-investing alongside LPs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/how-vcs-can-get-the-most-out-of-co-investing-alongside-lps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/how-vcs-can-get-the-most-out-of-co-investing-alongside-lps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C5 Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[co-investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[co-investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[limited partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nontraditional investors, which include anyone outside of traditional VC firms investing in venture capital deals, are increasingly making their presence felt in the investing community.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">William Kilmer</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/wkilmer">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/wkilmer">William Kilmer</a> is managing partner with <a href="https://www.c5capital.com/">C5 Capital</a>, a venture capital fund investing in the secure data ecosystem. He was formerly an operating partner at Mercato Growth Partners and served as CEO and chairman of PublicEngines (acquired by Motorola), and Avinti (merged with M86 Security) and served as chief marketing officer/chief strategy officer of M86 Security (acquired by Trustwave).	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/chasing-the-cybersecurity-investment-opportunity/">Talent and capital are shifting cybersecurity investors&#8217; focus away from Silicon Valley</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">It has rarely been easier for people looking to invest. Nontraditional investors, which include anyone outside of traditional VC firms investing in venture capital deals, are increasingly making their presence felt in the investing community.</p>
<p>McKinsey <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/mckinsey/industries/private%20equity%20and%20principal%20investors/our%20insights/the%20rise%20and%20rise%20of%20private%20equity/the-rise-and-rise-of-private-markets-mckinsey-global-private-markets-review-2018.ashx">found</a> that the value of co-investment deals has more than doubled to $104 billion from 2012 to 2018. And by some counts, there are as many as <a href="https://pitchbook.com/media/press-releases/pitchbook-publishes-2021-us-venture-capital-outlook-predicting-record-nontraditional-investor-participatio">1,600 “nontraditional” investors helping to fund venture capital deals in 2021</a>.</p>
<p>The primary motivator for nontraditional investors is seeking better returns, and investing alongside VC funds is a great way to achieve that. A recent <a href="https://www.valuewalk.com/2015/11/80-of-private-equity-investors-see-their-co-investments-outperform-commingled-funds/">Preqin study</a> shows co-investing funds significantly outperform traditional funds.</p>
<p>Research shows that 80% of investors found their co-investments outperforming private equity fund investments, with 46% outperforming by a margin of more than 5%. Investors also benefit from a generally less expensive fee structure compared to traditional private equity or VC funds.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			When evaluating deals, keep in mind that most companies are not going to be the next tech unicorn, so set realistic views on exits.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Co-investors can also profit by sharing the investment risk, which benefits all investors and builds loyalty and trust. And because this kind of investing requires a hands-on approach, investors get the chance to work closely with top sponsors — the general partners (GPs) — to foster deeper relationships and gain a better understanding of the GPs&#8217; investment strategies and deal review processes. For new investors, building these relationships is essential for strengthening their own investment skills in the long run.</p>
<h2>Why VCs love alternative investors</h2>
<p>Alternative investors aren’t the only ones who benefit from co-investing, it&#8217;s also a boon for GPs. They gain a broader array of funding options by partnering with alternative investors, and they can leverage their own capital more effectively with prospective investments.</p>
<p>VCs have other benefits too: While co-investing LPs remain passive in the business, the VC can use that voting power to preserve investor rights and consolidate decision-making. It also allows them to put more money to work in any company while staying within diversification limits.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/how-vcs-can-get-the-most-out-of-co-investing-alongside-lps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171387</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The engineering daring that led to the first Chinese personal computer</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/the-engineering-daring-that-led-to-the-first-chinese-personal-computer/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/the-engineering-daring-that-led-to-the-first-chinese-personal-computer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 18:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2170972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China is one of the world’s wealthiest digital economies today, with a hardware supply chain that is unrivaled and a panoply of prominent and massively profitable companies like Alibaba, Tencent and ByteDance taking a leading role in the world. Yet, all of this cutting-edge innovation rests on a 40-year-old solution to one of the great [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">China is one of the world’s wealthiest digital economies today, with a hardware supply chain that is unrivaled and a panoply of prominent and massively profitable companies like Alibaba, Tencent and ByteDance taking a leading role in the world. Yet, all of this cutting-edge innovation rests on a 40-year-old solution to one of the great computing challenges: the development of Chinese word processing.</p>
<p>Beginning in the early 1980s, China dramatically expanded its computing purchases from the United States and the West, importing just 600 foreign-built microcomputers in the year 1980, as compared to 130,000 in 1985. Companies in the United States, Japan and Europe clamored to get in on this “buying binge,” as one observer called it.</p>
<p>There was a major problem, however, both for potential Chinese computer users and Western manufacturers: No Western-built personal computer, printer, monitor, operating system, program or otherwise was capable of handling Chinese character input or output — not in the early- and mid-1980s, anyway, and certainly not “out of the box.” Without some major overhauls, mass-manufactured personal computers were effectively useless for anyone wanting to operate in Chinese.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			The major problem for both potential Chinese computer users and Western manufacturers was that no Western-built personal computer, printer, monitor, operating system, program or otherwise was capable of handling Chinese character input or output.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>One of the most important reasons was the problem of memory — specifically the memory required for Chinese fonts. At the advent of Latin alphabetic computing, Western engineers and designers determined that a font for English could be built upon a 5-by-7 bitmap grid — requiring only 5 bytes of memory per symbol. Although far from aesthetically pleasing, this grid offered sufficient resolution to render the letters of the Latin alphabet legibly on a computer terminal or a paper printout. Storing the 95 printable characters of U.S. ASCII required just 475 bytes of memory — a tiny fraction of, for example, the Apple II’s then 48 KB of motherboard memory.</p>
<p>To achieve comparable, bare-minimum legibility for Chinese characters, the 5-by-7 grid was far too small. When designing a bitmap font for Chinese, engineers had no choice but to increase the size of the Latin alphabetic grid geometrically, from 5-by-7 pixels to upward of 16-by-16 pixels or larger, or at least 32 bytes of memory <i>per Chinese character</i>. The total memory required to store <i>just the bitmaps </i>(in either simplified or traditional form, but not both, and with no accompanying metadata) would equal approximately 256 KB for the 8,000 most commonly used Chinese characters, or four times the total capacity<i> </i>of most off-the-shelf personal computers in the early 1980s. All this, even before accounting for the RAM requirements for the operating system and application software.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171139" style="width: 536px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171139" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171139 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-1.jpg?w=526" alt="" width="526" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-1.jpg 1855w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-1.jpg?resize=116,150 116w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-1.jpg?resize=232,300 232w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-1.jpg?resize=768,994 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-1.jpg?resize=526,680 526w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-1.jpg?resize=1187,1536 1187w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-1.jpg?resize=1583,2048 1583w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-1.jpg?resize=39,50 39w" sizes="(max-width: 526px) 100vw, 526px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171139" class="wp-caption-text">Draft bitmaps from the Sinotype III Chinese font, prepared prior to digitization. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Louis Rosenblum Papers, Stanford University Special Collections</p></div></p>
<p>Such is the context for one of the great engineering histories of modern computing, a tale of entrepreneurial daring and engineering ingenuity that provides a unique look into the global development of the digital revolution.</p>
<p>This is the first of two articles on TechCrunch in which I examine the Sinotype III, an experimental machine that was among the first personal computers to handle Chinese-language input and output. Built atop a store-bought Apple II — but outfitted with a custom-programmed word processor and operating system — Sinotype III served as a “proof of concept” that demonstrated how one could “translate” Western-manufactured computers into Chinese, and thereby open up a vast new marketplace.</p>
<p>In this first part, I will examine the profound technical challenges around computer memory, fonts and operating systems faced by the creators of Sinotype III, and how they devised novel solutions to overcome them.</p>
<h2>“The chutzpah of a newly minted graduate who had no immediate job prospects”</h2>
<p>Our story begins with the Graphic Arts Research Foundation (GARF) — the organization where, arguably, Chinese computing was born. The Ideographic Composing Machine, also known as the Sinotype, was invented in the late 1950s by MIT electrical engineer Samuel Hawks Caldwell with GARF funding. Following his untimely death in 1960, the project came to a standstill. During the 1960s and 1970s, the Sinotype project was kept alive by a number of different parties, including the Itek Corporation, RCA, and finally, GARF once again.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171145" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171145" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171145 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-7.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="540" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-7.jpg 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-7.jpg?resize=150,119 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-7.jpg?resize=300,238 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-7.jpg?resize=768,610 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-7.jpg?resize=680,540 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-7.jpg?resize=1536,1220 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-7.jpg?resize=2048,1627 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-7.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171145" class="wp-caption-text">Keyboard of Sinotype I, designed by Samuel Caldwell in the late 1950s. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Louis Rosenblum Papers, Stanford University Special Collections</p></div></p>
<p>Sinotype’s homecoming was thanks in large part to one man: Louis Rosenblum. Born in 1921 in New York City, he was yet another member of the MIT family, graduating in 1942 with an undergraduate degree in Applied Math. Studying under Harold Edgerton, the world-renowned professor of electrical engineering (and who shot the famous “<a href="http://100photos.time.com/photos/harold-edgerton-milk-drop">milk drop coronet</a>” photo in the 1930s), Rosenblum took a job at Polaroid immediately following graduation, working with Edwin Land on a variety of projects, including the development of instant photography. In 1954, he moved to Photon — where he worked on photocomposition of non-Latin writing systems. Deeply familiar with the late Caldwell’s pioneering work on Sinotype, Rosenblum effectively adopted the project, and revived it when he joined GARF as a consultant in the mid-1970s.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171140" style="width: 536px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171140" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171140 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-2.jpg?w=526" alt="" width="526" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-2.jpg 1855w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-2.jpg?resize=116,150 116w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-2.jpg?resize=232,300 232w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-2.jpg?resize=768,994 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-2.jpg?resize=526,680 526w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-2.jpg?resize=1187,1536 1187w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-2.jpg?resize=1583,2048 1583w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-2.jpg?resize=39,50 39w" sizes="(max-width: 526px) 100vw, 526px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171140" class="wp-caption-text">Diagram showing configuration of Sinotype II system, running on a Nova 1200 CPU. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Louis Rosenblum Papers, Stanford University Special Collections</p></div></p>
<p>GARF continued to work on the Sinotype project well into the early 1980s, by which point it had developed an advisory board featuring a host of renowned scholars, as well as those with deep China experience. Harvard linguist Susumo Kuno came on board; as did Richard Solomon, known for <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/richard-solomon-former-diplomat-who-helped-nixon-open-relations-with-china-dies-1489532159">his pivotal role in Richard Nixon’s visit to the PRC in 1972</a> and then head of the Social Science Department at the RAND Corporation.</p>
<p>As stellar as this brain trust was, however, GARF’s major breakthrough on the Sinotype project — the leap from a minicomputer-based system (Sinotype II) to one based on a microcomputer (Sinotype III) — was catalyzed by a college student whose only experience at GARF to date was a brief, two-week gig working on data management for the Sinotype II project in 1979. He was Bruce Rosenblum, Louis Rosenblum’s son.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171142" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171142" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171142 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-4.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="522" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-4.jpg 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-4.jpg?resize=150,115 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-4.jpg?resize=300,230 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-4.jpg?resize=768,589 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-4.jpg?resize=680,522 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-4.jpg?resize=1536,1179 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-4.jpg?resize=2048,1572 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-4.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171142" class="wp-caption-text">Bruce Rosenblum using the Sinotype III system. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Louis Rosenblum Papers, Stanford University Special Collections</p></div></p>
<p>As an undergraduate at the University of Pennsylvania and an aspiring photojournalist, Bruce was balancing his time between coursework and his role as photo editor for the independent student-run newspaper Daily Pennsylvanian. The paper was remarkably advanced in terms of the equipment it ran, as well as the deep expertise of the students in charge.</p>
<p>By the fall of Bruce’s junior year, the paper’s existing typesetting equipment (two Compugraphic typesetters) were on their last legs and needed to be replaced. Along with three of his student colleagues at the paper, Bruce assisted in the process of researching potential replacements, eventually settling on a combined $125,000 contract with two companies: Mycro-Tek in Wichita, Kansas, and Compugraphic, in Wilmington, Massachusetts.</p>
<p>As for the Sinotype project — one that Bruce was well aware of, thanks to his father, but with which he had no involvement — a pivotal moment came in early May 1981. Bruce had just completed his final exams, and stopped by the offices of the paper. His colleague Eric Jacobs was there, hard at work on a TRS-80 Model II personal computer from Radio Shack. Jacobs was contemplating how this microcomputer might be used to run the newspaper’s business operations. Bruce observed for perhaps 30 minutes, before heading on with his day.</p>
<p>Those 30 minutes stuck with him, however. “It was the first time I’d ever seen anyone work on a microcomputer,” Bruce recalled by email to me, “and those few minutes were the inspiration that triggered the whole Sinotype III project and eventually my career in computers.”</p>
<p>Later that same week, Bruce made a somewhat off-the-cuff remark in a phone call with his father. Referencing the immense cost of the Data General hardware GARF was then using to build Sinotype II, Bruce remarked that someone could probably program something equivalent or better on a microcomputer for a fraction of the cost — perhaps with as little as $10,000 worth of hardware, as compared to the more than $100,000 price tag for the equipment GARF was currently funding.</p>
<p>His father was intrigued. Louis asked Bruce if he himself might be up to the task of programming such a machine. Bruce boasted no formal training in computer science, although he had worked extensively with computers in high school and taught himself both PDP-8 assembly language and BASIC. “Sure,” he responded to his father’s query with “the chutzpah of a newly minted graduate who had no immediate job prospects.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171141" style="width: 536px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171141" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171141 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-3.jpg?w=526" alt="" width="526" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-3.jpg 1855w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-3.jpg?resize=116,150 116w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-3.jpg?resize=232,300 232w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-3.jpg?resize=768,994 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-3.jpg?resize=526,680 526w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-3.jpg?resize=1187,1536 1187w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-3.jpg?resize=1583,2048 1583w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-3.jpg?resize=39,50 39w" sizes="(max-width: 526px) 100vw, 526px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171141" class="wp-caption-text">During his world tour, Bruce Rosenblum continued to work on the Sinotype III project, including on notepaper from New Delhi. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Louis Rosenblum Papers, Stanford University Special Collections.</p></div></p>
<p>In June 1981, Bruce had a formal meeting in New York with Bill Garth, Prescott Low and his father Louis to present his Sinotype III proposal. Bruce dressed for the part, arriving in a three-piece suit. In Bruce’s formal proposal, he cited a total of $7,500 in hardware costs, with an additional $5,000 for programming fees. The plan promised a Chinese word processor, running on an Apple II, delivered in approximately four months. If this worked, it would reduce the cost of such a machine by an order of magnitude.</p>
<p>Bruce got the job and went on to program Sinotype III from June to November 1981, balancing time between this and his full-time job as a tour guide for the National Park Service at Independence Hall in Philadelphia. During daytime breaks he would write out assembly code by hand, transcribing it at night. When Labor Day in 1981 came, and Bruce’s tour guide job ended, he dedicated two months straight to finishing the code and delivered it to GARF.</p>
<h2>Memory hacking</h2>
<p>The first problem that GARF and the Rosenblums faced was that of computer memory. Developers of early Chinese personal computers explored every available option in their effort to juice as much memory as possible out of their systems. We will explore two strategies in particular, sometimes employed in isolation, but often in concert: Adaptive Memory and Chinese Character Cards.</p>
<p>The Sinotype III system comprised five components: a Sanyo DM5012CM 12-inch monitor; an Epson MX-70 printer; a Corvus 10 MB “Rigid Disk Storage” for storing the Chinese character bitmap database and their corresponding “descriptor codes”; an Apple Disk Drive “for storage of text files”; and the Apple II itself.</p>
<p>Out of the box, the Apple II came with 32 KB of RAM, extensible to 48 KB on the motherboard. “We maxed that out even before the Apple II left the store,” Bruce Rosenblum remarked by email to me. 48 KB of memory was still far too little for his purposes, however, and so Bruce opted for what, at the time, was a fully standard modification, commonly employed by so-called “power users” of the era: namely, to insert an additional 16 KB memory card in slot 0, thereby bringing the total available memory to 64 KB.<br />
Even this was too little, however. “I needed more RAM to store a full encoding system,” he said, “and also the 16-by-16 bitmaps for the 100 most frequent ideographs.”</p>
<p>He began to explore a “mod” of the Apple II that few if any others had tried before. “Somehow,” he said, “I figured out I could put a second 16 KB board in slot 2 of the Apple II, and that gave me a total of 80 KB. Completely nonstandard,” he continued, “but it worked with off-the-shelf components.”</p>
<p>This modification pushed the machine past its own limitations, however. The 6502 microprocessor on the Apple II was only capable of accessing 64 KB of memory directly — meaning that, even with the additional 16 KB Bruce had managed to bootstrap in with the second memory board, there was simply no built-in way for the Apple II to simultaneously access these additional addresses in memory. So “nonstandard” was this mod that, when he told an Apple engineer about it during one of his many conversations, the Apple rep was shocked — he had never heard of, or thought of, doing such a thing.</p>
<p>To enable the Apple II to access 80 KB of memory, rather than just 64 KB, Bruce dispensed with the out-of-the-box operating system and programmed his own in assembly language. Key to his custom-designed program was the possibility of “selecting between two banks of 16 KB that overlap each other.” In other words, although only 64 KB worth of memory locations would be accessible at any one instant, by rapidly oscillating between the two memory expansion cards, he could in effect trick the computer into accessing both at speeds that, from the perspective of the user, would have been negligible. That squeezed 25% more memory out of the system, enabling the inclusion of perhaps as many as 400 more Chinese characters in on-board memory.</p>
<p>Bruce delivered the final code to GARF the week before Thanksgiving, and then set out on a world backpacking tour that would take him across Europe and Asia. From this point on, development of Sinotype III would be largely in the hands of Louis Rosenblum and GARF, although Bruce continued to serve as a consultant, exchanging frequent correspondence with his father from wherever in Europe, China, India or elsewhere he found himself at the moment.</p>
<h2>Speeding toward real-time Chinese typing</h2>
<p>Even with his ingenious mod, however, Louis and Bruce estimated that a mere 600 to 1,000 Chinese characters would be able to fit in on-board memory. When accounting for the size of Sinotype III’s operating system, program applications and the memory requirements of each Chinese character, the vast majority of Chinese characters in the machine’s lexicon would need to be stored somewhere else, whether on floppy disks, an external hard drive or via some other hardware solution.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171144" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171144" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171144 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-6.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="471" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-6.jpg 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-6.jpg?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-6.jpg?resize=300,208 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-6.jpg?resize=768,532 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-6.jpg?resize=680,471 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-6.jpg?resize=1536,1064 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-6.jpg?resize=2048,1418 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-6.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171144" class="wp-caption-text">Sinotype III Computer Monitor. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Louis Rosenblum Papers, Stanford University Special Collections</p></div></p>
<p>Early on, Bruce briefly contemplated using PROM (programmable read-only memory) chips — but this idea quickly revealed itself to be a dead end. Circa 1981 and 1982, the largest PROM chips on the market maxed out at 2 KB of memory, which translated into a mere 28 to 51 Chinese characters. In order to store 7,000 Chinese characters in this fashion, then, Bruce would have needed either 138 or 250 PROM chips. “That’s a lot of chips,” he remarked.</p>
<p>Bruce then considered the possibility of storing characters on floppy disks. This, too, proved unworkable, not only because of the large number of disks it would have required, but also the slow access and retrieval speeds involved in fetching character bitmaps from floppy drive storage. GARF opted instead for a third solution: to outfit Sinotype III with an external hard drive, which at the time was an almost unheard-of microcomputer accessory. In order to overcome the profound memory limitations, GARF would store thousands of lower-frequency Chinese characters “off-site” in the system’s external hard drive: a 10 MB Corvus “Rigid Disk Storage.”</p>
<p>This had negative implications for the operating speed of Sinotype III, however. Within the space-time continuum of computing, in which most operations take place at blazing subsecond speeds, hard drives were cumbersome beasts. Particularly at this time, they relied on rigid magnetic disks — “platters” — that rotated within the device, not unlike a record player. The contents of various “tracks” were read by a head, similar to how the grooves on a record are read by the needle. Retrieval speeds depended upon the location of the head, and the particular rotational position of the disk at the moment of the retrieval request. Not unlike arriving at the stop to find that the bus has just departed, one had no option except to wait until the bus came back around again.</p>
<p>In concrete terms, retrieval times for Chinese characters stored on the hard drive were 10 times slower than those stored in RAM. Specifically, the retrieval time for those Chinese characters stored in RAM could be achieved in approximately 100 milliseconds per character — a unit of time imperceptible by human cognition. As for the characters stored in external storage, however, the input of any of these characters required as much as a full second to access and retrieve — a unit of time well within the threshold of human perception.</p>
<p>A one-second input time would have proven devastatingly slow within the context of mid-1980s personal computing, where users in English-language contexts were quickly becoming accustomed to real-time typing. In addition, one second is, obviously, 10 times as long<i> </i>as 100 milliseconds, meaning that the average user would be able to feel this differential each and every time they wished to input lower-frequency characters.</p>
<p>In order to mitigate this problem, Louis Rosenblum hit upon an idea that he referred to as “adaptive temporary storage.” Sinotype III would be able to adjust the set of characters stored in RAM depending upon what the user had recently inputted. Upon initial boot, Sinotype III’s on-board RAM would be outfitted only with a predetermined set of high-frequency characters. The inputting of any hard-drive-based infrequent character would take up to one second, as noted above. However, “as each of the less frequent ideographs is keyboarded,” he explained in a letter at the time, “its code and dot matrix pattern will be noted in the random access memory.” In other words, such characters would be temporarily copied from the hard drive to on-board RAM cache, thereby reducing subsequent retrieval times.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171149" style="width: 491px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171149" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2171149 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-11.jpg?w=481" alt="" width="481" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-11.jpg 1697w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-11.jpg?resize=106,150 106w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-11.jpg?resize=212,300 212w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-11.jpg?resize=768,1086 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-11.jpg?resize=481,680 481w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-11.jpg?resize=1086,1536 1086w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-11.jpg?resize=1448,2048 1448w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Sinotype-11.jpg?resize=35,50 35w" sizes="(max-width: 481px) 100vw, 481px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171149" class="wp-caption-text">Internal GARF document showing Sinotype III character database and metadata. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Louis Rosenblum Papers, Stanford University Special Collections</p></div></p>
<h2>Chinese-on-a-Chip</h2>
<p>Even with recourse to toggling and adaptive memory, there remained many thousands of characters that fell beyond the limits of such strategies. While high-frequency Chinese characters accounted for a large percentage of overall usage, the production of any kind of technical or specialist content would have certainly brought the user repeatedly into the “off-site” repository of Chinese characters. More of these “low-frequency” characters needed to be brought “on-site” if the experience of Chinese computing was ever going to approach the same feeling of instantaneity enjoyed by English-language counterparts.</p>
<p>Engineers in the late 1970s and early 1980s began to explore a different hardware solution, referred to as “Chinese Character Cards” (<i>Hanka</i>), “Chinese Cards” (<i>Zhongwenka</i>), “Chinese Character Generators,” “Chinese Font Generators” (<i>Hanzi zimo fashengqi</i>) or, as one article delightfully referred to them, “Chinese-on-a-Chip.” Much like memory cards and graphic cards, “Chinese character cards” were designed to be installed directly into motherboard expansion slots. Hardwired into these cards were thousands of Chinese bitmaps and input encodings. In effect, they served the same role as an external hard drive, but at far faster speeds and with more reliable performance.</p>
<p>“Chinese-on-a-chip” cards were not the focus of research at GARF. Rather, they grew out of the earlier era of custom-designed Chinese systems, all prior to the personal computing revolution. These included systems such as the Ideographix IPX, by Chan Yeh, and the Olympia 1011, which were outfitted with microprocessors whose sole purpose was the generation of character bitmaps and the storage of input descriptors. On the Olympia 1011 Chinese word processor — basically a single-purpose electric Chinese typewriter — one of the three Intel 8085 processors was dedicated exclusively to Chinese character generation.</p>
<p>During the early 1980s, such character generators were commoditized and turned into salable products themselves. No longer did one need to buy a full-fledged word processor, such as the Olympia 1011, to gain access to this kind of on-board character generator. Instead, one could purchase a “Chinese Character Card” and then install it on one’s personal computer of choice.</p>
<p>Among the earliest centers of Chinese computing to focus on Chinese Character Cards was Tsinghua University, where researchers developed an early card capable of storing approximately 6,000 Chinese bitmap patterns in 32-by-32 dot matrix format. By the mid- and late-1980s, there were dozens of different “Hanka” on the market, manufactured and marketed by companies across Japan, China, Taiwan, Hong Kong, the United States and elsewhere.</p>
<p>By the mid- and late-1980s, the “Chinese-on-a-chip” approach became so important and common that practically all computers boasting Chinese or Japanese-language capabilities featured a character generator card of one sort or another.</p>
<p>Thus, from the 1950s with Caldwell’s Sinotype to the duo father-son Rosenblum team and GARF around Sinotype III in the 1980s, solving the memory problems associated with Chinese characters was the linchpin to opening the Chinese market to computing. Hacking computers with more memory, creating adaptive memory algorithms for prioritizing characters, and building dedicated hardware bridged the problem and initiated the computer revolution in China.</p>
<p>Yet, the next step was how to expand beyond the computer itself to everything that might connect to it. In part two of this series, coming up shortly on TechCrunch, our discussion will continue with a deep dive into the challenges of designing and programming early computer monitors, printers and other peripherals capable of handling Chinese text output.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="B86NON1czL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/summer-sale-save-10-on-extra-crunch-membership/">Summer Sale: Save 10% on Extra Crunch membership</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Summer Sale: Save 10% on Extra Crunch membership&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/summer-sale-save-10-on-extra-crunch-membership/embed/#?secret=B86NON1czL" data-secret="B86NON1czL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/the-engineering-daring-that-led-to-the-first-chinese-personal-computer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2170972</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zomato&#8217;s $100 million investment to turn Grofers into a unicorn</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/zomatos-100-million-investment-to-turn-grofers-into-a-unicorn/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/zomatos-100-million-investment-to-turn-grofers-into-a-unicorn/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 18:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BigBasket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grofers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zomato]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian food delivery giant Zomato, which is working to explore the public markets later this year, has reached an agreement to invest $100 million in online grocer Grofers for about 10% stake in the seven-year-old startup, according to a source and multiple others familiar with the matter. The proposed investment values Grofers, which counts SoftBank [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Indian food delivery giant Zomato, which is working to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/indian-food-delivery-startup-zomato-files-for-an-ipo/">explore the public markets later this year</a>, has reached an agreement to invest $100 million in online grocer Grofers for about 10% stake in the seven-year-old startup, according to a source and multiple others familiar with the matter.</p>
<p>The proposed investment values Grofers, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/15/grofers-lands-200m/">counts SoftBank as its largest investor</a>, at over $1 billion. (Indian regulator, the Competition Commission of India, needs to approve the investment.) Zomato’s proposed investment is part of a broader round, in which others including Tiger Global and SoftBank Vision Fund 2 are expected to chip in some capital. Zomato said it had no comment.</p>
<p>The leadership teams at Grofers and Zomato have long been close friends and began exploring this investment earlier this year. Both the firms are also open to the idea of Zomato acquiring a majority stake in Grofers in the coming quarters, though a decision hasn’t been reached and won’t be fully explored until Zomato becomes a publicly traded company, the source told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Zomato, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/20/uber-sells-food-delivery-business-in-india-to-zomato/">acquired Uber&#8217;s Indian food delivery business early last year</a>, has told some of its major investors that it envisions a future where the Gurgaon-based firm has expanded much beyond the food delivery category, the source said, requesting anonymity as the talks are private.</p>
<p>Grofers operates an online grocery delivery service in India. The startup has witnessed a sharp surge in its popularity in the past year as several Indian states enforced strict lockdown restrictions to contain the spread of the virus. The startup competes with BigBasket, which recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/tata-group-reaches-agreement-to-buy-majority-stake-in-bigbasket/">sold its majority stake</a> to Indian conglomerate Tata Group.</p>
<p>The Indian online grocery market has seen a new player emerge in the past one year, Reliance Industries, India’s most valuable firm. Reliance, which operates the largest retail chain in India, last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/23/jiomart-the-e-commerce-venture-by-indias-richest-man-launches-in-additional-cities/">launched JioMart</a>.</p>
<p>“JioMart&#8217;s growth is a testament to its already loyal customer base, 80% of whom are repeat shoppers. JioMart New commerce&#8217;s aim is to transform and grow the small merchant ecosystem, so our merchant partners prosper. Over the past year, over 300,000 merchant or shopkeeper partners across 150 cities were enabled and empowered to transform their businesses both physically and digitally,” said Mukesh Ambani, the chairman of Reliance Industries, earlier this month.</p>
<p>In a note to clients earlier this year, Bank of America analysts estimated that the online grocery delivery market could be worth $12 billion in India by 2023.</p>
<p>“Competition is high in the sector with large verticals like BigBasket/Grofers and horizontal like Amazon/Flipkart trying to convert the unorganized market to an organized one. Until recently the No. 1 player in the space was BigBasket, with it hitting $1 billion annualized GMV and selling over 300,000 orders every day. Reliance Industries also threw its hat with the company launching its JioMart app May 20 across 200 cites,” they wrote.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2DAf0t5TBI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/summer-sale-save-10-on-extra-crunch-membership/">Summer Sale: Save 10% on Extra Crunch membership</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Summer Sale: Save 10% on Extra Crunch membership&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/summer-sale-save-10-on-extra-crunch-membership/embed/#?secret=2DAf0t5TBI" data-secret="2DAf0t5TBI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/zomatos-100-million-investment-to-turn-grofers-into-a-unicorn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171581</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
