<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 21:06:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Dabbel gets $4.4M to cut CO2 by automating HVAC for commercial buildings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/dabbel-gets-4-4m-to-cut-co2-by-automating-hvac-for-commercial-buildings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/dabbel-gets-4-4m-to-cut-co2-by-automating-hvac-for-commercial-buildings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 21:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[building automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CommerzBank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dusseldorf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy consumption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proptech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target Global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Düsseldorf-based proptech startup Dabbel is using AI to drive energy efficiency savings in commercial buildings. It&#8217;s developed cloud-based self-learning building management software that plugs into the existing building management systems (BMS) &#8212; taking over control of heating and cooling systems in a way that&#8217;s more dynamic than legacy systems based on fixed set-point resets. Dabbel [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Düsseldorf-based proptech startup <a href="https://www.dabbel.eu">Dabbel</a> is using AI to drive energy efficiency savings in commercial buildings.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s developed cloud-based self-learning building management software that plugs into the existing building management systems (BMS) &#8212; taking over control of heating and cooling systems in a way that&#8217;s more dynamic than legacy systems based on fixed set-point resets.</p>
<p>Dabbel says its AI considers factors such as building orientation and thermal insulation, and reviews calibration decisions every five minutes &#8212; meaning it can respond dynamically to changes in outdoor and indoor conditions.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The 2018-founded startup claims this approach of layering AI-powered predictive modelling atop legacy BMS to power next-gen building automation is able to generate substantial energy savings &#8212; touting reductions in energy consumption of up to 40%.</p>
<p>&#8220;Every five minutes Dabbel reviews its decisions based on all available data,&#8221; explains CEO and co-founder, Abel Samaniego. &#8220;With each iteration, Dabbel improves or adapts and changes its decisions based on the current circumstances inside and outside the building. It does this by using cognitive artificial intelligence to drive a Model-Based Predictive Control (MPC) System&#8230; which can dynamically adjust all HVAC setpoints based on current/future conditions.&#8221;</p>
<p>In essence, the self-learning system predicts ahead of time the tweaks that are needed to adapt for future conditions &#8212; saving energy vs a pre-set BMS that would keep firing the boilers for longer.</p>
<p>The added carrot for commercial building owners (or tenants) is that Dabbel squeezes these energy savings without the need to rip and replace legacy systems &#8212; nor, indeed, to install lots of IoT devices or sensor hardware to create a &#8216;smart&#8217; interior environment; the AI integrates with (and automatically calibrates) the existing heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC) systems.</p>
<p>All that&#8217;s needed is Dabbel&#8217;s SaaS &#8212; and less than a week for the system to be implemented (it also says installation can be done remotely).</p>
<p>&#8220;There are no limitations in terms of Heating and Cooling systems,&#8221; confirms Samaniego, who has a background in industrial engineering and several years&#8217; experience automating high tech plants in Germany. &#8220;We need a building with a Building Management System in place and ideally a BACnet communication protocol.&#8221;</p>
<p>Average reductions achieved so far across the circa 250,000m² of space where its AI is in charge of building management systems are a little more modest but a still impressive 27%. (He says the maximum savings seen at some &#8220;peak times&#8221; is 42%.)</p>
<p>The touted savings aren&#8217;t limited to a single location or type of building/client, according to Dabbel, which says they&#8217;ve been &#8220;validated across different use cases and geographies spanning Europe, the U.S., China, and Australia&#8221;.</p>
<p>Early clients are facility managers of large commercial buildings &#8212; Commerzbank clearly sees potential, having incubated the startup via its early-stage investment arm &#8212; and several schools.</p>
<p>A further 1,000,000m² is in the contract or offer phase &#8212; slated to be installed &#8220;in the next six months&#8221;.</p>
<p>Dabbel envisages its tech being useful to other types of education institutions and even other use-cases. (It&#8217;s also toying with adding a predictive maintenance functionality to expand its software&#8217;s utility by offering the ability to alert building owners to potential malfunctions ahead of time.)</p>
<p>And as policymakers around the global <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/startups-have-about-1-trillion-worth-of-reasons-to-love-the-biden-infrastructure-plan/">turn their attention</a> to how to achieve the very major reductions in carbon emissions that are needed to meet ambitious climate goals the energy efficiency of buildings certainly can&#8217;t be overlooked.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IGIW5dZoPg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/startups-have-about-1-trillion-worth-of-reasons-to-love-the-biden-infrastructure-plan/">Startups have about $1 trillion worth of reasons to love the Biden infrastructure plan</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startups have about $1 trillion worth of reasons to love the Biden infrastructure plan&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/startups-have-about-1-trillion-worth-of-reasons-to-love-the-biden-infrastructure-plan/embed/#?secret=IGIW5dZoPg" data-secret="IGIW5dZoPg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“The time for passive responses to addressing the critical issue of carbon emission reduction is over,&#8221; said Samaniego in a statement. &#8220;That is why we decided to take matters into our own hands and develop a solution that actively replaces a flawed human-based decision-making process with an autonomous one that acts with surgical precision and thanks to artificial intelligence, will only improve with each iteration.&#8221;</p>
<p>If the idea of hooking your building&#8217;s heating/cooling up to a cloud-based AI sounds a tad risky for Internet security reasons, Dabbel points out it&#8217;s connecting to the BMS network &#8212; not the (separate) IT network of the company/building.</p>
<p>It also notes that it uses one-way communication via a VPN tunnel &#8212; &#8220;creating an end-to-end encrypted connection under high market standards&#8221;, as Samaniego puts it.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The startup has just closed a €3.6 million (~$4.4M) pre-Series A funding round led by Target Global, alongside <a href="https://main-incubator.com/en/home/">main incubator</a> (Commerzbank’s early-stage investment arm), SeedX, plus some strategic angel investors.</span></p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Dr. Ricardo Schaefer, partner at Target Global, added: “We are enthusiastic to work with the team at Dabbel as they offer their clients a tangible and frictionless way to significantly reduce their carbon footprint, helping to close the gap between passive measurement and active remediation.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a2Lb1ViLjJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/9-proptech-investors-talk-co-living-home-offices-and-other-pandemic-trends/">9 proptech investors talk co-living, home offices and other pandemic trends</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;9 proptech investors talk co-living, home offices and other pandemic trends&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/9-proptech-investors-talk-co-living-home-offices-and-other-pandemic-trends/embed/#?secret=a2Lb1ViLjJ" data-secret="a2Lb1ViLjJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="clMJbGUdGL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/bringing-jobs-and-health-benefits-blocpower-unlocks-energy-efficiency-retrofits-for-low-income-communities/">Bringing jobs and health benefits, BlocPower unlocks energy efficiency retrofits for low-income communities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bringing jobs and health benefits, BlocPower unlocks energy efficiency retrofits for low-income communities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/bringing-jobs-and-health-benefits-blocpower-unlocks-energy-efficiency-retrofits-for-low-income-communities/embed/#?secret=clMJbGUdGL" data-secret="clMJbGUdGL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WOtsFIMyQp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/14/pitching-tech-to-optimize-building-design-for-sustainability-atlanta-based-cove-tool-raises-5-7-million/">Pitching tech to optimize building design for sustainability, Atlanta-based Cove.tool raises $5.7 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pitching tech to optimize building design for sustainability, Atlanta-based Cove.tool raises $5.7 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/14/pitching-tech-to-optimize-building-design-for-sustainability-atlanta-based-cove-tool-raises-5-7-million/embed/#?secret=WOtsFIMyQp" data-secret="WOtsFIMyQp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/dabbel-gets-4-4m-to-cut-co2-by-automating-hvac-for-commercial-buildings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154171</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch&#8217;s Equity podcast wins a Webby Award</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/techcrunchs-equity-podcast-wins-a-webby-award/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/techcrunchs-equity-podcast-wins-a-webby-award/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Henry Pickavet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 20:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the fine folks at the Webbys announced that TechCrunch’s flagship podcast, Equity, is the best of its kind in the technology category. We’re stoked! Alex Wilhelm, Natasha Mascarenhas and Danny Crichton sit down in front of their mics multiple times each week to regale dedicated listeners with news and analysis from the money part [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today, the fine folks at the Webbys announced that TechCrunch’s flagship podcast, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/equity-podcast/">Equity</a>, is the best of its kind in the technology category. We’re stoked!</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex Wilhelm</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha Mascarenhas</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/DannyCrichton">Danny Crichton</a> sit down in front of their mics multiple times each week to regale dedicated listeners with news and analysis from the money part of the startup world.</p>
<p>Led by the deft production touch of <a href="https://twitter.com/cgates123">Chris Gates</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall">Grace Mendenhall</a>, the entertaining trio goes deep into companies, topics and news multiple times each week – while mostly in a good mood. And they’ve come a long way.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Check out the shortest acceptance speech in TechCrunch history <a href="https://watch.webbyawards.com/winner/180-equity">here</a>!</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Here is our 5-word acceptance speech for winning a <a href="https://twitter.com/TheWebbyAwards?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@TheWebbyAwards</a> for best technology podcast!!!<a href="https://t.co/sNnNnGpsTU">https://t.co/sNnNnGpsTU</a> <a href="https://t.co/Vg2NSOD6Q9">pic.twitter.com/Vg2NSOD6Q9</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Equity Podcast (@EquityPod) <a href="https://twitter.com/EquityPod/status/1394748617227784195?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 18, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Equity launched in March 2017 in a back room &#8212; a veritable closet, if you will! &#8212; at our old San Francisco office. Alex would come down once a week from his then-digs at Crunchbase News to join Katie Roof and Matt Lynley. Other hosts on our fun ride have included Kate Clark and our very own Connie Loizos.</p>
<p>We’ve got all kinds of podcast goodies up our award-winning sleeves and we hope you and five of your closest friends keep coming along for the ride.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/techcrunchs-equity-podcast-wins-a-webby-award/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154254</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A new book aims to blow up some widely held assumptions about the best founding teams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/super_founders/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/super_founders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 20:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DCVC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153293</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s a lot of how-to guidance out there when it comes to starting a company, and much of it has reinforced certain beliefs, including that solo founders don&#8217;t get very far on their own, that the most successful founders attend a small circle of top schools, and that the best companies are created by people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There&#8217;s a lot of how-to guidance out there when it comes to starting a company, and much of it has reinforced certain beliefs, including that solo founders don&#8217;t get very far on their own, that the most successful founders attend a small circle of top schools, and that the best companies are created by people who launched them to solve a personal problem into which they had a particular insight.</p>
<p>Ali Tamaseb, who studied biomedical engineering at Imperial College London, attended business school at Stanford, and founded a wearable tech startup before joining the venture firm DCVC as an investor in 2018, says that lot of that guidance is, well, misguided. Tamaseb says he knows this because over the past four years, to improve his own decision-making, he amassed more than 30,000 data points about so-called &#8220;super founders,&#8221; from their age when their breakout company was founded to how many competitors they faced from the outset; in doing so, he says, he wound up discovering that much of what is espoused in startup circles is off the mark.</p>
<p>To share some of those learnings, Tamaseb has written a newly published  book called <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Super-Founders-Reveals-Billion-Dollar-Startups/dp/1541768426"><em>Super Founders: What Data Reveals About Billion Dollar Startups</em></a>. We talked with him yesterday. Our chat has been edited lightly for length.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>TC: Why write this book?</strong></p>
<p>AT: When I was a founder, a lot of my perception was shaped through this lens of what the media tells us. Even now, when I&#8217;m on Twitter or Clubhouse, a lot of what I hear feels very different compared with what I see as a venture capitalist. Of course, nobody knows everything, and even the most successful venture capitalists have maybe invested in 10 of these breakout companies in their lifetime. So to get to the ground truth, and because nobody has collected this data because it&#8217;s hard, over four years of weekends and evenings, I began to collect [it], ultimately establishing 65 data points per company.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What are some of these data points and how much of them were publicly available?</strong></p>
<p>AT: The data includes the career path of the founder and whether their earlier roles were technical or not;  the founder&#8217;s education and degree and the school they attended; what the market looked like when their company was started, including what the defensibility factors were; how many competitors they had; their fundraising history &#8212; how much did they raise and when and from whom?</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a bit of this data in a Pitchbook or Crunchbase, but nobody had put [these other pieces] into [context]. I was going to their LinkedIn profiles, reading interviews, going to the internet&#8217;s Wayback Machine and other archives to read reports to understand what these companies looked like at the time they were founded. I also called a lot of these founders to ask them for answers where I couldn&#8217;t find the information. It was a very manual thing.</p>
<p><strong>TC: How many founders did you research?</strong></p>
<p>AT: I researched more than 200 unicorns, [launched by] around 500 founders. Because no study has meaning unless you also collect data on a control group, I selected companies that over the same time period had raised a minimum of $3 million in venture capital as my baseline group. I then compared the two groups based on these 65 different elements.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Your research led you to invest in the primary and urgent care company Carbon Health on behalf of DCVC. How so?</strong></p>
<p>AT: Specifically here, founder Eren Bali had had built a bunch of companies before, and a bunch had failed or succeeded on a smaller level, then his last company was [the edtech giant] Udemy, where he spent four years.</p>
<p>One of the key things that I observed in the data is that it&#8217;s all about these small steps &#8212; and the small or neutral exits. Around 60% of these &#8220;super founders&#8221; started something earlier, and many actually lost a bunch of money; just 42% of them had a previous exit of $10 million or more, so the majority had &#8220;failed&#8221; in the world of venture capital. But [the data suggests that] practice makes perfect.</p>
<p><strong>TC: You also found that solo founders aren&#8217;t doomed to run smaller companies, despite some earlier thinking by Y Combinator&#8217;s Paul Graham that you need at least two cofounders to do something big.</strong></p>
<p>AT: Right, 20% of the founders in both groups &#8212; the unicorn and non unicorn group &#8212; were solo founders, so VCs are funding solo founders and they are building billion-dollar companies. Basically, one out of every five unicorn companies has a solo founder. So I think that&#8217;s another narrative that gets retold, including on Twitter, but that doesn&#8217;t match reality. Flexport, for example, has a solo founder [in Ryan Petersen]. So does CarGurus, which was founded by Langley Steinert, who, by the way, first cofounded TripAdvisor [and more recently founded ApartmentAdvisor].</p>
<p><strong>TC: Your book also asserts that there are plenty of founders of billion-dollar companies that didn&#8217;t attend elite American universities.</strong></p>
<p>AT: There are schools that founders attended more than others &#8212; Stanford, MIT, Wharton and Harvard &#8212; but as many of these founders attended schools that aren&#8217;t even at the top 100 [ranked U.S. schools] compared to those who went into the top 10. It&#8217;s a barbell distribution. Around 36% went to the top 10 schools, the same percentage went to schools not in the top 100, and there&#8217;s another 30% or so in the middle.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Two other observations in the book that are interesting are that half the founding CEOs you researched were non-technical, and only 30% had domain expertise in the industry they were disrupting. The latter may surprise readers particularly.</strong></p>
<p>AT: Yes, 30% of founders in consumer tech and 40% in enterprise tech did not come from the same domain [that their company now operates in]. And I see the same thing in startups that are just now getting funded. What it tells you is that domain expertise is not necessarily correlated to success.</p>
<p>Take Nat Turner of Flatiron Health [a cancer-focused start-up that sold to Roche Group in 2018]. These guys were serial entrepreneurs and they had a bunch of successes before, and they jumped from one industry to another, starting with a pizza delivery company they started in college, where they learned about the restaurant industry and deliveries and logistics. They also sold an ad tech company to Google. Then they go and start this company in the cancer oncology IP and data space, where they didn&#8217;t know anything, but they learned as much as anybody after spending two years going and talking with every oncologist they could find in New York to understand the space. So maybe founders apply their tech background to different industries or they apply soft skills like resources and connections to learn about a specific industry rather than coming from that industry.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What did your research tell you about funding and its impacts? We&#8217;re seeing companies raise bigger rounds faster than ever before, including from Tiger Global.  </strong></p>
<p>AT: I don&#8217;t specifically have any brilliant thoughts on Tiger or anyone else, but these unicorns that I studied &#8212; even in their seed round and Series A rounds, they had raised two to three times larger rounds than the companies that did not become billion dollar companies. In fact, 92% of these billion-dollar companies were venture backed and they raised a lot of money, which allowed them to attract better talent and go to market faster. Even from the early stage, this kingmaker strategy kind of works.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/super_founders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153293</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WalkMe is going public: Let&#8217;s stroll through its numbers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/walkme-is-going-public-lets-stroll-through-its-numbers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/walkme-is-going-public-lets-stroll-through-its-numbers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 20:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[walkme]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153813</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon, we're parsing the WalkMe IPO filing, the second Israel-based tech company to file to go public this week.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hot off the heels of our look <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/inside-marqetas-fascinating-fintech-ipo/">into Marqeta&#8217;s IPO filing</a> and dives into SPACs for<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/industrial-automation-startup-bright-machines-hauls-in-435m-by-going-public-via-spac/"> Bright Machines</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-spac-filing-shows-scooter-nomics-just-doesnt-fly/">Bird</a>, we&#8217;re parsing the <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001847584/000119312521163950/d143770df1.htm">WalkMe IPO filing</a>. Later this week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/as-q2s-lull-fades-unicorn-ipos-are-revving-up/">Squarespace will direct list</a> and we&#8217;ll see <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/as-procore-looks-to-nearly-double-its-private-valuation-the-ipo-market-shows-signs-of-life/">IPOs from Oatly and Procore</a>. It&#8217;s a super busy time for public debuts of all sorts.</p>
<p>Given how hectic the IPO market is, we&#8217;re going to skip our usual throat clearing and dig into WalkMe&#8217;s IPO document. As always, we&#8217;ll start with a brief overview of its product and then move into discussing its financial performance.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153942" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153942" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2153942 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/meme.jpg?w=225" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/meme.jpg 500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/meme.jpg?resize=113,150 113w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/meme.jpg?resize=225,300 225w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/meme.jpg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2153942" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Alex Wilhelm</p></div></p>
<p>WalkMe is the second Israel-based technology company to file to go public <em>this week: </em>No-code startup Monday.com is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/fast-growth-pushes-an-unprofitable-no-code-startup-into-the-public-markets-inside-monday-coms-ipo-filing/">also pursuing an American IPO</a>.</p>
<p>Alright! Into the breach.</p>
<h2>What does WalkMe do?</h2>
<p>WalkMe&#8217;s software provides visual overlays on websites that help users navigate the product in question. I base that explanation on my time at Crunchbase, which was a customer during at least part of my time there. WalkMe is popular with marketing teams who want to introduce users to a new or refreshed experience.</p>
<p>Per the company&#8217;s F-1 filing, other elements of its service that matter include its onboarding system and what WalkMe calls Workstation, or its &#8220;single interface to the applications within an enterprise and simplifies task completion through a natural language conversational interface and automation.&#8221; We&#8217;re including that last feature because it says &#8220;automation,&#8221; which, in the wake of the UiPath IPO, is a word worth watching. Investors are.</p>
<p>At a high level, WalkMe is a SaaS business, which means that when we digest its results we are digging into a modern software company. Let&#8217;s do just that.</p>
<h2>WalkMe&#8217;s numbers</h2>
<p>From 2019 to 2020, WalkMe grew its revenues from $105.1 million to $148.3 million, a gain of 41%. In its most recent quarter, the company&#8217;s growth rate slowed: From Q1 2020 to Q1 2021, WalkMe&#8217;s top line grew 25% from $34.2 million to $42.7 million.</p>
<p>In SaaS terms, WalkMe calculates that its annual recurring revenue, or ARR, grew from $131.2 million at the end of 2019 to $164.3 million in 2020. In more granular terms, the company&#8217;s ARR grew from $137.8 million to $177.5 million in the first quarters of 2020, and 2021, respectively.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/walkme-is-going-public-lets-stroll-through-its-numbers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153813</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Skittish is what you&#8217;d get if you crossed Animal Crossing with Clubhouse</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/skittish-andy-baio-virtual-events/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/skittish-andy-baio-virtual-events/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 20:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[andy baio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[High Fidelity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new horizons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philip Rosedale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xoxo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If the Instagram ads feel like they’re closing in and you can’t bring yourself to toggle your Zoom camera on these days, you’re far from alone. Well into 2021, many of the social apps and virtual chat tools that kept the world connected during the pandemic feel more exhausting than the real-life interactions they’re meant [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If the Instagram ads feel like they’re closing in and you can’t bring yourself to toggle your Zoom camera on these days, you’re far from alone. Well into 2021, many of the social apps and virtual chat tools that kept the world connected during the pandemic feel more exhausting than the real-life interactions they’re meant to simulate.</p>
<p>But what if hanging out online was… not miserable?</p>
<p>That’s the idea behind <a href="https://skittish.com/">Skittish</a>, a virtual browser-based event platform from<a href="https://xoxofest.com/"> XOXO co-founder Andy Baio</a>. Skittish is a playful cross between a social audio chat app like Discord or Clubhouse and a cute video game, replete with round, colorful animal avatars to choose from. Unlike a Zoom call, Skittish is a <em>place</em> — one where its inhabitants can bump into one another, do activities together and wait for serendipity to strike.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Skittish is a natural extension of Baio’s interests, a sort of inviting, lightly indie-gamified space where creative people can showcase their work and hang out. “I think I&#8217;m just drawn to places where people can be themselves,” Baio told TechCrunch. “With Skittish, it&#8217;s been really important to me that people can engage at the level they&#8217;re comfortable with.”</p>
<p>Baio has a reputation for curating social spaces, though previously they were mostly IRL. In 2012, Baio co-created XOXO, a whimsical Portland-based festival for quirky people who make stuff. While the <a href="https://xoxofest.com/blog/2020-xoxo-2020-is-canceled">festival took a few years off due to Covid</a>, the event lives on in a bustling online community full of indie game devs, offbeat podcasters and digital artists. Prior to XOXO, Baio worked on Kickstarter pre-launch and went on to serve as the crowdfunding site’s first chief technology officer. (Full disclosure: I’m a former XOXO attendee who is part of the community.)</p>
<p>The aptly named Skittish is meant to create an online social space that doesn’t put people on the spot. In Baio’s ideal virtual world, introverts could circle the periphery while extroverts could plunge right in and hold court at the center, just like they might in real life. That range of social styles that isn’t reflected in virtual environments that are either explicitly for work or modeled after work and it’s enough to inspire dread for a lot of people.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/-HbyOS3mz18?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>For Baio, audio chat hits a sweet spot. Taking the camera out of the equation makes people feel socially fluid, but audio still evokes a degree of social presence that text can’t compete with.</p>
<p>“There&#8217;s an assumption in a lot of virtual events that people want to be on camera all the time with strangers, which feels alien to me,” Baio said. “Skittish is audio by default, and uses spatial audio so that you can hear people around you and lurk a little bit before deciding if you want to jump into a conversation. Socializing anywhere, even online, can be really anxiety-inducing.”</p>
<p>Clubhouse might be synonymous with social audio right now, but its structure still doesn’t appeal to everyone. “I like the casual and conversational approach to audio, but [it] just feels like a series of conference panels and needs a strong moderator to be compelling enough to tune in,” Baio said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed--video">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rHwMmkjlVT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/24/xoxo-drip-kickstarter-xoxo-fest/">The team behind XOXO is taking over Kickstarter&#8217;s Drip crowdfunding community</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The team behind XOXO is taking over Kickstarter&#8217;s Drip crowdfunding community&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/24/xoxo-drip-kickstarter-xoxo-fest/embed/#?secret=rHwMmkjlVT" data-secret="rHwMmkjlVT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>How Skittish works</h3>
<p>In Skittish, walking up to a group of people (animals, really — Skittish users can differentiate themselves by choosing one of more than 75 deeply cute animal avatars) allows you to hear a conversation just like you would in real life. Backing away, you’d hear that chatter fade until eventually it wouldn’t be audible any more. To have a more private side conversation, you and a friend (a crocodile, maybe?) could peel off from a cluster of other people and deepen your chat on a virtual walk.</p>
<p>Inside a Skittish room, event participants can walk around, chat with others over a mic, place virtual objects and even hop through portals to other rooms. Anyone running a Skittish space can stream videos and music from YouTube or Soundcloud to a virtual screen. Event organizers can also broadcast themselves or other speakers to the full room, overriding the normal proximity rules that let you hear what’s around you.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2154182" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Watching-Videos.png?w=680" alt="Skittish avatars watching a video" width="680" height="465" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Watching-Videos.png 1384w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Watching-Videos.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Watching-Videos.png?resize=300,205 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Watching-Videos.png?resize=768,525 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Watching-Videos.png?resize=680,465 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Watching-Videos.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Baio doesn&#8217;t imagine Skittish as a persistent social space, but instead wants it to provide a flexible, playful platform for all kinds of events, everything from live podcast readings and tabletop games to larger company events. Baio says the core target audience for Skittish is “anybody with a Patreon,” and larger company events will offset costs for creators who use Skittish to connect with their communities. Anyone hosting an event can choose to either populate a virtual space with pre-designed virtual objects (think pirate ships and giant doughnuts) or dream up their own environment from scratch.</p>
<p>By designing a service that only exists when people need it, he hopes to avoid the harassment and toxicity that abounds on big social networks. Skittish will still pack a set of tools that allow a space’s creator to mute, kick or even ban users, but ideally, it won’t need it.</p>
<p>“I&#8217;m a big fan of dark social, in general, where people can feel more like themselves and moderation is much more human and manageable,” Baio said.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2154179 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/skittish-mod-tools.png?w=680" alt="Skittish mod tools (mute, kick, ban buttons)" width="680" height="433" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/skittish-mod-tools.png 950w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/skittish-mod-tools.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/skittish-mod-tools.png?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/skittish-mod-tools.png?resize=768,489 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/skittish-mod-tools.png?resize=680,433 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/skittish-mod-tools.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<h3>Building Skittish and what’s next</h3>
<p>The pandemic shed new light on what people really want out of online social spaces. Zoom’s novelty wore off quickly, and by late 2020 group video chat felt like an entrenched fixture of virtual work, not virtual play. It shouldn’t be surprising that a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/animal-crossing/">gentle social simulator with light multiplayer features</a> emerged as the game of 2020.</p>
<p>“It&#8217;s a bit of a cliché, but Animal Crossing: New Horizons became a reliable escape for me during the pandemic, a daily source of comfort and routine when we couldn&#8217;t go outside,” Baio said. He was charmed by his first foray into the series’ famously soothing rhythms and the game helped him envision Skittish.</p>
<p>“&#8230; I think what inspired me most were the simplicity of the controls and camera, the overall tone of the game, and the social features, limited as they are,” Baio said. “You&#8217;re capped at seven visitors and it takes forever for people to fly in, but despite that, it&#8217;s just a joyful experience to have a bunch of people over to your island.”</p>
<p>With the Nintendo Switch sold out everywhere and Animal Crossing racing up the console’s all-time sales charts, it was obvious early on that something resonated. People who wouldn’t normally consider themselves gamers bought Switches and spent hours shaking virtual trees, chatting with squirrels and touring friends’ islands for interior design tips. With Skittish, Baio hopes to capture a little of that same magic.</p>
<p>Games that double as social networks are booming right now — and with good reason. For many people it’s more natural to socialize when you’re ambiently doing something else together, whether that’s teaming up for a Fortnite duo, building a viking longhouse in Valheim or sampling user-built games within Roblox.</p>
<p>Socializing online with avatars also lets you express yourself in a meaningful enough way that Epic built an entire business around it, with sales of skins (virtual outfits) and emotes (dance moves and gestures) making up the lion’s share of Fortnite revenue.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2154210" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Asset-Editor.png?w=680" alt="Skittish - Asset Editor" width="680" height="465" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Asset-Editor.png 1384w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Asset-Editor.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Asset-Editor.png?resize=300,205 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Asset-Editor.png?resize=768,525 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Asset-Editor.png?resize=680,465 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Skittish-Asset-Editor.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Skittish grew out of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/16/100m-grant-for-the-web-fund-aims-to-jump-start-a-new-way-to-pay-online/">a $100,000 grant awarded by Grant For The Web</a>, a fund created by Coil, Mozilla and Creative Commons to support projects that incorporate micropayments for online creators. Baio began prototyping Skittish last July, imagining it as a pop-up space for events rather than a persistent virtual world.</p>
<p>Skittish spaces initially accommodated up to 120 mixed voices in a single room, but the audio capacity is even higher now. Though he’s still testing what the new limits might be, Skittish is getting closer to Baio’s goal of hosting 1000-person events. Skittish rooms can now be password protected, invite-only or public, and Baio imagines special “cozy” 3-5 person spaces in the project&#8217;s future.</p>
<p>For its high quality spatial audio chat, <a href="https://www.highfidelity.com/">Skittish uses an API from High Fidelity</a>, the latest project from Second Life creator Philip Rosedale. Amazingly, Second Life <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/id/wbna17389286">added spatial audio to its online worlds all the way back in 2007</a> — <em>fourteen years ago</em>.</p>
<p>Skittish will host its first paid events this month as a test, with invites to follow after that. Baio plans to rely on paid events for revenue and he’s on the fence about offering a free tier due to moderation concerns and the costs associated with hosting hundreds of simultaneous conversations between virtual elephants, zebras and raccoons.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RmB0ZCFZWg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/16/100m-grant-for-the-web-fund-aims-to-jump-start-a-new-way-to-pay-online/">$100M Grant for the Web fund aims to jump-start a new way to pay online</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;$100M Grant for the Web fund aims to jump-start a new way to pay online&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/16/100m-grant-for-the-web-fund-aims-to-jump-start-a-new-way-to-pay-online/embed/#?secret=RmB0ZCFZWg" data-secret="RmB0ZCFZWg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>A walk in Skittish</h3>
<p>I met up with Baio in Skittish to chat about the project and it immediately felt less awkward than a Zoom call or Google Hangout. As a noble trash panda, I followed Baio’s owl around the colorful polygonal virtual set like we might have walked around a park having coffee together.</p>
<p>Skittish looks like a video game and you can move around using WASD if you want, but it’s straightforward enough that anyone can get the hang of it right away. The world&#8217;s simple graphical style sets a chill, creative vibe and the avatars even have a gentle idle animation, a kind of bounce that brings your respective elephant, raccoon or zebra to life.</p>
<p>Like experiences I&#8217;ve had in a few other innovative avatar-based virtual worlds (<a href="https://www.dailydot.com/debug/altspace-vr-virtual-reality-social-platform/">AltspaceVR comes to mind</a>), the sense of really being there, just hanging out, feels revelatory. Multiplayer games have been miles ahead of traditional social networks on this phenomenon for ages; it&#8217;s no wonder that Fortnite and Minecraft are de facto social networks for a huge swath of younger people. In Skittish, the high quality spatial audio and playful sense of presence offer something similarly transporting.</p>
<p>Virtual owls aside, Baio says says Skittish will be a success when people start make real connections there that follow them beyond the virtual world he&#8217;s created.</p>
<p>“Just like the events I&#8217;ve run in real life, I&#8217;ll know it&#8217;s working when I hear stories about people meeting each other in a playful environment and making new friends,” Baio said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DHrCxG4DMX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/02/virtual-worlds-video-games-coronavirus-social-networks-fortnite-animal-crossing/">We need more video games that are social platforms first, games second</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;We need more video games that are social platforms first, games second&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/02/virtual-worlds-video-games-coronavirus-social-networks-fortnite-animal-crossing/embed/#?secret=DHrCxG4DMX" data-secret="DHrCxG4DMX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/skittish-andy-baio-virtual-events/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153363</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google updates Firebase with new personalization features, security tools and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-updates-firebase-with-new-personalization-features-security-tools-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-updates-firebase-with-new-personalization-features-security-tools-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 19:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Algolia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Firebase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Allo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product manager]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2152996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its I/O developer conference, Google today announced a slew of updates to its Firebase developer platform, which, as the company also announced, now powers over 3 million apps. There&#8217;s a number of major updates here, most of which center around improving existing tools like Firebase Remote Config and Firebase&#8217;s monitoring capabilities, but there are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its <a href="https://events.google.com/io/?lng=en">I/O developer conference</a>, Google today announced a slew of updates to its Firebase developer platform, which, as the company also announced, now powers over 3 million apps.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a number of major updates here, most of which center around improving existing tools like Firebase Remote Config and Firebase&#8217;s monitoring capabilities, but there are also a number of completely new features here as well, including the ability to create Android App Bundles and a new security tool called <a href="https://firebase.google.com/docs/app-check">App Check</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Helping developers be successful is what makes Firebase successful,&#8221; Firebase product manager Kristen Richards told me ahead of today&#8217;s announcements. &#8220;So we put helpfulness and helping developers at the center of everything that we do.&#8221; She noted that during the pandemic, Google saw a lot of people who started to focus on app development &#8212; both as learners and as professional developers. But the team also saw a lot of enterprises move to its platform as those companies looked to quickly bring new apps online.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Maybe the marquee Firebase announcement at I/O is the updated Remote Config. That&#8217;s always been a very powerful feature that allows developers to make changes to live production apps on the go without having to release a new version of their app. Developers can use this for anything from A/B testing to providing tailored in-app experience to specific user groups.</p>
<p>With this update, Google is introducing updates to the Remote Config console, to make it easier for developers to see how they are using this tool, as well as an updated publish flow and redesigned test results pages for A/B tests.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153020" style="width: 990px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/firebase_ab_testing.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153020" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2153020" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/firebase_ab_testing.png" alt="" width="980" height="673" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/firebase_ab_testing.png 980w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/firebase_ab_testing.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/firebase_ab_testing.png?resize=300,206 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/firebase_ab_testing.png?resize=768,527 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/firebase_ab_testing.png?resize=680,467 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/firebase_ab_testing.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 980px) 100vw, 980px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2153020" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>What&#8217;s most important, though, is that Google is taking Remote Config a step further now by launching a new Personalization feature that helps developers automatically optimize the user experience for individual users. &#8220;It&#8217;s a new feature of [Remote Config] that uses Google&#8217;s machine learning to create unique individual app experiences,&#8221; Richards explained. &#8220;It&#8217;s super simple to set up and it automatically creates these personalized experiences that&#8217;s tailored to each individual user. Maybe you have something that you would like, which would be something different for me. In that way, we&#8217;re able to get a tailored experience, which is really what customers expect nowadays. I think we&#8217;re all expecting things to be more personalized than they have in the past.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153025" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-102729.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153025" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2153025" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-102729.png" alt="" width="1024" height="572" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-102729.png 1156w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-102729.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-102729.png?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-102729.png?resize=768,429 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-102729.png?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-102729.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2153025" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Google is also improving a number of Firebase&#8217;s analytics and monitoring capabilities, including its Crashlytics service for figuring out app crashes. For game developers, that means improved support for games written with the help of the <a href="https://unity.com/">Unity platform</a>, for example, but for all developers, the fact that Firebase&#8217;s Performance Monitoring service now processes data in real time is a major update to having performance data (especially on launch day) arrive with a delay of almost half a day.</p>
<p>Firebase is also now finally adding support for <a href="https://developer.android.com/guide/app-bundle">Android App Bundles</a>, Google&#8217;s relatively new format for packaging up all of an app&#8217;s code and resources, with Google Play optimizing the actual APK with the right resources for the kind of device the app gets installed on. This typically leads to smaller downloads and faster installs.</p>
<p>On the security side, the Firebase team is launching App Check, now available in beta. App Check helps developers guard their apps against outside threats and is meant to automatically block any traffic to online resources like Cloud Storage, Realtime Database and Cloud Functions for Firebase (with others coming soon) that doesn&#8217;t provide valid credentials.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153049" style="width: 958px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-103633.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153049" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2153049" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-103633.png" alt="" width="948" height="412" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-103633.png 948w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-103633.png?resize=150,65 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-103633.png?resize=300,130 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-103633.png?resize=768,334 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-103633.png?resize=680,296 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-17-103633.png?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 948px) 100vw, 948px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2153049" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>The other update worth mentioning here is to Firebase Extensions, which launched a while ago, but which is getting support for a few more extensions today. These are new extensions from Algolia, Mailchimp and MessageBird, that helps bring new features like Algolia&#8217;s search capabilities or MessageBird&#8217;s communications features directly to the platform. Google itself is also launching a <a href="https://jigsaw.google.com/">new extension</a> that helps developers detect comments that could be considered &#8220;rude, disrespectful, or unreasonable in a way that will make people leave a conversation.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-updates-firebase-with-new-personalization-features-security-tools-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2152996</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Cloud launches Vertex AI, a new managed machine learning platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-cloud-launches-vertex-a-new-managed-machine-learning-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-cloud-launches-vertex-a-new-managed-machine-learning-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 19:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon SageMaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Moore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google cloud platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harvard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At Google I/O today Google Cloud announced Vertex AI, a new managed machine learning platform that is meant to make it easier for developers to deploy and maintain their AI models. It&#8217;s a bit of an odd announcement at I/O, which tends to focus on mobile and web developers and doesn&#8217;t traditionally feature a lot [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At Google I/O today Google Cloud announced Vertex AI, a new managed machine learning platform that is meant to make it easier for developers to deploy and maintain their AI models. It&#8217;s a bit of an odd announcement at I/O, which tends to focus on mobile and web developers and doesn&#8217;t traditionally feature a lot of Google Cloud news, but the fact that Google decided to announce Vertex today goes to show how important it thinks this new service is for a wide range of developers.</p>
<p>The launch of Vertex is the result of quite a bit of introspection by the Google Cloud team. &#8220;Machine learning in the enterprise is in crisis, in my view,&#8221; Craig Wiley, the director of product management for Google Cloud&#8217;s AI Platform, told me. &#8220;As someone who has worked in that space for a number of years, if you look at the Harvard Business Review or analyst reviews, or what have you &#8212; every single one of them comes out saying that the vast majority of companies are either investing or are interested in investing in machine learning and are <em>not</em> getting value from it. That has to change. It has to change.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153838" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-in-the-details.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153838" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2153838" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-in-the-details.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-in-the-details.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-in-the-details.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-in-the-details.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-in-the-details.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-in-the-details.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-in-the-details.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-in-the-details.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-in-the-details.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2153838" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Wiley, who was also the general manager of AWS&#8217;s SageMaker AI service from 2016 to 2018 before coming to Google in 2019, noted that Google and others who were able to make machine learning work for themselves saw how it can have a transformational impact, but he also noted that the way the big clouds started offering these services was by launching dozens of services, &#8220;many of which were dead ends,&#8221; according to him (including some of Google&#8217;s own). &#8220;Ultimately, our goal with Vertex is to reduce the time to ROI for these enterprises, to make sure that they can not just build a model but get real value from the models they&#8217;re building.&#8221;</p>
<p>Vertex then is meant to be a very flexible platform that allows developers and data scientist across skill levels to quickly train models. Google says it takes about 80% fewer lines of code to train a model versus some of its competitors, for example, and then help them manage the entire lifecycle of these models.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153839" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-512-color.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153839" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2153839" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-512-color.png?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-512-color.png 513w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-512-color.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-512-color.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-512-color.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-512-color.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-512-color.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-512-color.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/VertexAI-512-color.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2153839" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>The service is also integrated with <a href="https://cloud.google.com/ai-platform/optimizer/docs/overview">Vizier</a>, Google&#8217;s AI optimizer that can automatically tune hyperparameters in machine learning models. This greatly reduces the time it takes to tune a model and allows engineers to run more experiments and do so faster.</p>
<p>Vertex also offers a &#8220;Feature Store&#8221; that helps its users serve, share and reuse the machine learning features and Vertex Experiments to help them accelerate the deployment of their models into producing with faster model selection.</p>
<p>Deployment is backed by a continuous monitoring service and Vertex Pipelines, a rebrand of Google Cloud&#8217;s <a href="https://cloud.google.com/ai-platform/pipelines/docs">AI Platform Pipelines</a> that helps teams manage the workflows involved in preparing and analyzing data for the models, train them, evaluate them and deploy them to production.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="c07tEAZTXi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/13/9-investors-discuss-challenges-opportunities-and-the-impact-of-cloud-vendors-in-enterprise-data-lakes/">9 investors discuss hurdles, opportunities and the impact of cloud vendors in enterprise data lakes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;9 investors discuss hurdles, opportunities and the impact of cloud vendors in enterprise data lakes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/13/9-investors-discuss-challenges-opportunities-and-the-impact-of-cloud-vendors-in-enterprise-data-lakes/embed/#?secret=c07tEAZTXi" data-secret="c07tEAZTXi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>To give a wide variety of developers the right entry points, the service provides three interfaces: a drag-and-drop tool, notebooks for advanced users and &#8212; and this may be a bit of a surprise &#8212; <a href="https://cloud.google.com/bigquery-ml/docs/introduction">BigQuery ML</a>, Google&#8217;s tool for using standard SQL queries to create and execute machine learning models in its BigQuery data warehouse.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">We had two guiding lights while building </span><span class="il" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Vertex</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> AI: get data scientists and engineers out of the orchestration weeds, and create an industry-wide shift that would make everyone get serious about moving AI out of pilot purgatory and into full-scale production,&#8221; said Andrew Moore, vice president and general manager of Cloud AI and Industry Solutions at Google Cloud. &#8220;We are very proud of what we came up with in this platform, as it enables serious deployments for a new generation of AI that will empower data scientists and engineers to do fulfilling and creative work.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-cloud-launches-vertex-a-new-managed-machine-learning-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153124</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google adds foldable-focused Android developer updates</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-adds-foldable-focused-android-developer-updates/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-adds-foldable-focused-android-developer-updates/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 19:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foldables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google io 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Things have been a bit quiet on the foldables front of late, but plenty of parties are still bullish about the form factor’s future. Ahead of today’s big I/O kickoff, Samsung (undoubtedly the most bullish of the bunch) posted a bunch of metrics this morning, noting, The global outlook is just as impressive. This year [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Things have been a bit quiet on the foldables front of late, but plenty of parties are still bullish about the form factor’s future. Ahead of today’s big I/O kickoff, Samsung (undoubtedly the most bullish of the bunch) <a href="https://news.samsung.com/us/how-samsung-foldables-changing-way-use-smartphones-google/?utm_source=pr_media&amp;utm_medium=email">posted a bunch of metrics this morning</a>, noting,</p>
<blockquote><p>The global outlook is just as impressive. This year alone, the foldables market is expected to triple over last year — a year in which Samsung accounted for three out of every four foldable smartphones shipped worldwide.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xxnD7tF0RQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/07/google-is-adding-android-support-for-foldable-screens/">Google is adding Android support for foldable screens</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google is adding Android support for foldable screens&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/07/google-is-adding-android-support-for-foldable-screens/embed/#?secret=xxnD7tF0RQ" data-secret="xxnD7tF0RQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Part of anticipating growth in the category is ensuring that the software is ready it. Samsung has been tweaking things for a while now on its end, and at I/O in 2018, Google announced that it would be adding support for foldable screens. Recent rumors have suggested that the company is working on its own foldable Pixel, but even beyond that, it’s probably in the company’s best interest to ensure that Android plays nicely with the form factor.</p>
<p>“We studied how people interact with large screens,&#8221; the company said in today&#8217;s developer keynote. This includes a variety of different aspects, including where users place their hands while using the device &#8212; which can be a bit all over the place when dealing with different applications in different orientations and form factors. Essentially, you don&#8217;t want to, say, put buttons where people generally place your hands.</p>
<p>The list of upgrades includes the ability to resize content automatically, without overly stretching it out to fit multiple panels. All of this is no doubt going to be a learning curve as foldables end up in the hands of more users. But at very least, it signals Google&#8217;s continued view of foldables as a growing category. It&#8217;s also one of multiple updates today that involve the company working more closely with Samsung.</p>
<p>The two tech giants also announced a joint Wear OS/Tizen play early today.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Hl9EyfE5Au"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-and-samsung-are-teaming-up-to-take-on-apples-watchos/">Google and Samsung are teaming up to take on Apple’s watchOS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google and Samsung are teaming up to take on Apple’s watchOS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-and-samsung-are-teaming-up-to-take-on-apples-watchos/embed/#?secret=Hl9EyfE5Au" data-secret="Hl9EyfE5Au" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-adds-foldable-focused-android-developer-updates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153913</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google updates its cross-platform Flutter UI toolkit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-updates-its-cross-platform-flutter-ui-toolkit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-updates-its-cross-platform-flutter-ui-toolkit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Caching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrome os]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flutter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Pay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[play store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Universal Windows Platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeChat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Flutter, Google&#8217;s cross-platform UI toolkit for building mobile and desktop apps, is getting a small but important update at the company&#8217;s I/O conference today. Google also announced that Flutter now powers 200,000 apps in the Play Store alone, including popular apps from companies like WeChat, ByteDance, BMW, Grab and DiDi. Indeed, Google notes that 1 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://flutter.dev/">Flutter</a>, Google&#8217;s cross-platform UI toolkit for building mobile and desktop apps, is getting a small but important update at the company&#8217;s I/O conference today. Google also announced that Flutter now powers 200,000 apps in the Play Store alone, including popular apps from companies like WeChat, ByteDance, BMW, Grab and DiDi. Indeed, Google notes that 1 in 8 new apps in the Play Store are now Flutter apps.</p>
<p>The launch of Flutter 2.2 follows Google&#8217;s rollout of Flutter 2, which first added support for desktop and web apps <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/version-2-of-googles-flutter-toolkit-adds-support-for-desktop-and-web-apps/">in March</a>, so it&#8217;s no surprise that this is a relatively minor release. In many ways, the update builds on top of the features the company introduced in version 2 and reliability and performance improvements.</p>
<p>Version 2.2 makes null safety the default for new projects, for example, to add protections against null reference exceptions. As for performance, web apps can now use background caching using service workers, for example, while Android apps can use deferred components and iOS apps get support for precompiled shaders to make first runs smoother.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Google also worked on streamlining the overall process of bringing Flutter apps to desktop platforms (Windows, macOS and Linux).</p>
<p>But as Google notes, a lot of the work right now is happening in the ecosystem. Google itself is introducing a new payment plugin for Flutter built in partnership with the Google Pay team and Google&#8217;s ads SDK for Flutter is getting support for adaptive banner formats. Meanwhile, Samsung is now porting Flutter to Tizen and Sony is leading an effort to bring it to embedded Linux. Adobe recently announced its XD to Flutter plugin for its design tool and Microsoft today launched the alpha of Flutter support for Universal Windows Platform (UWP) apps for Windows 10 in alpha.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/2S-KkvFuLWs?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="l4xRtN2m4L"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/version-2-of-googles-flutter-toolkit-adds-support-for-desktop-and-web-apps/">Version 2 of Google&#8217;s Flutter toolkit adds support for desktop and web apps</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Version 2 of Google&#8217;s Flutter toolkit adds support for desktop and web apps&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/version-2-of-googles-flutter-toolkit-adds-support-for-desktop-and-web-apps/embed/#?secret=l4xRtN2m4L" data-secret="l4xRtN2m4L" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-updates-its-cross-platform-flutter-ui-toolkit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153346</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google launches the first beta of Android Studio Arctic Fox</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-launches-the-first-beta-of-android-studio-arctic-fox/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-launches-the-first-beta-of-android-studio-arctic-fox/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 19:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wear os]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its I/O developer conference, Google today announced the first beta of the next version of its Android Studio IDE, Arctic Fox. For the most part, the idea here is to bring more of the tooling around building Android apps directly into the IDE. While there is a lot that&#8217;s new in Arctic Fox, maybe [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its I/O developer conference, Google today announced the first beta of the next version of its Android Studio IDE, Arctic Fox. For the most part, the idea here is to bring more of the tooling around building Android apps directly into the IDE.</p>
<p>While there is a lot that&#8217;s new in Arctic Fox, maybe the marquee feature of this update is the integration of <a href="https://developer.android.com/jetpack/compose">Jetpack Compose</a>, Google&#8217;s toolkit for building modern user interfaces for Android. In Android Studio, developers can now use Compose Preview to create previews of different configurations (think themes and devices) or deploy a preview directly to a device, all while the layout inspector makes it easier for developers to understand how (and why) a layout is rendered the way it is. With Live Updates enabled any change is then also directly streamed to the device.</p>
<p>The team also integrated the Android Accessibility Test Framework directly into Android Studio to help developers find accessibility issues like missing content descriptions or a low contrast in their designs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2153332" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153332" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2153332" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="487" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_1.png 1679w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_1.png?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_1.png?resize=300,143 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_1.png?resize=768,365 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_1.png?resize=680,323 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_1.png?resize=1536,730 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_1.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2153332" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Just like with some of the updates to Android itself, the team is also looking at making it easier to develop for a wider range of form factors. To build Wear OS apps, developers previously had to physically connect the watch to their development machine or go through a lot of steps to pair the watch. Now, users can simply pair a watch and phone emulator (or physical phone) with the new Wear OS Pairing feature. All this takes now is a few clicks.</p>
<p>Also new on the Wear OS side is a new heart rate sensor for the Wear OS Emulators in Android Studio, while the Android Automotive emulator gains the ability to replay car sensor data to help those developers with their development and testing workflow.</p>
<p>Android Studio users who work on a Mac will be happy to hear that Google is also launching a first preview of Android Studio for the Apple Silicon (arm64) architecture.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153337" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_2.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153337" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2153337" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_2.png 1682w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_2.png?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_2.png?resize=300,149 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_2.png?resize=768,383 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_2.png?resize=680,339 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_2.png?resize=1536,765 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/android_studio_2.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2153337" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-launches-the-first-beta-of-android-studio-arctic-fox/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153246</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google is making a 3D, life-size video calling booth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-is-making-a-3d-life-size-video-calling-booth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-is-making-a-3d-life-size-video-calling-booth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 19:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google io 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light field]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google is working on a video calling booth that uses 3D imagery on a 3D display to create a lifelike image of the people on both sides. While it&#8217;s still experimental, &#8220;Project Starline&#8221; builds on years of research and acquisitions, and could be the core of a more personal-feeling video meeting in the near future. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google is working on a video calling booth that uses 3D imagery on a 3D display to create a lifelike image of the people on both sides. While it&#8217;s still experimental, <a href="https://blog.google/technology/research/project-starline/">&#8220;Project Starline&#8221;</a> builds on years of research and acquisitions, and could be the core of a more personal-feeling video meeting in the near future.</p>
<p>The system was only shown via video of unsuspecting participants, who were asked to enter a room with a heavily obscured screen and camera setup. Then the screen lit up with a video feed of a loved one, but in a way none of them expected:</p>
<p>&#8220;I could feel her and see her, it was like this 3D experience. It was like she was here.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I felt like I could really touch him!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It really, really felt like she and I were in the same room.&#8221;</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q13CishCKXY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>CEO Sundar Pichai explained that this &#8220;experience&#8221; was made possible with high-resolution cameras and custom depth sensors, almost certainly related to these Google research projects into essentially converting videos of people and locations into interactive 3D scenes:</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eq84NGDyEB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/googles-46-camera-light-field-videos-let-you-change-perspective-and-peek-around-corners/">Google&#8217;s 46-camera &#8216;light field videos&#8217; let you change perspective and peek around corners</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google&#8217;s 46-camera &#8216;light field videos&#8217; let you change perspective and peek around corners&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/googles-46-camera-light-field-videos-let-you-change-perspective-and-peek-around-corners/embed/#?secret=eq84NGDyEB" data-secret="eq84NGDyEB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UFzOe1ibC0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/18/this-room-sized-led-egg-captures-amazing-3d-models-of-the-people-inside-it/">This room-sized LED egg captures amazing 3D models of the people inside it</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;This room-sized LED egg captures amazing 3D models of the people inside it&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/18/this-room-sized-led-egg-captures-amazing-3d-models-of-the-people-inside-it/embed/#?secret=UFzOe1ibC0" data-secret="UFzOe1ibC0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The cameras and sensors — probably a dozen or more hidden around the display — capture the person from multiple angles and figure out their exact shape, creating a live 3D model of them. This model and all the color and lighting information is then (after a lot of compression and processing) sent to the other person&#8217;s setup, which shows it in convincing 3D. It even tracks their heads and bodies to adjust the image to their perspective. (There&#8217;s a bit more on an early version of the technique <a href="https://blog.siggraph.org/2020/08/how-google-is-making-streamable-light-field-video-a-reality.html/">here</a>.)</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/starline-gif.gif"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2154181" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/starline-gif.gif" alt="" width="800" height="455" /></a></p>
<p>But 3D TVs have more or less fallen by the wayside; turns out no one wants to wear special glasses for hours at a time, and the quality on glasses-free 3D was generally pretty bad. So what&#8217;s making this special 3D image?</p>
<p>Pichai said &#8220;we have developed a breakthrough light field display,&#8221; probably with the help of the people and IP it scooped up from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/27/lytro-is-shutting-down/">Lytro, the light field camera company</a> that didn&#8217;t manage to get its own tech off the ground and dissolved in 2018.</p>
<p>Light field cameras and displays create and show 3D imagery using a variety of techniques that are very difficult to explain or show in 2D. The startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/looking-glass-is-launching-3d-photo-software-for-its-holographic-tech/">Looking Glass</a> has made several that are extremely arresting to view in person, showing 3D models and photographic scenes that truly look like tiny holograms.</p>
<p>Whether Google&#8217;s approach is similar or different, the effect appears to be equally impressive, as the participants indicate. They&#8217;ve been testing this internally and are getting ready to send out units to partners in various industries (such as medicine) where the feeling of a person&#8217;s presence makes a big difference.</p>
<p>At this point Project Starline is still very much a prototype, and probably a ridiculously expensive one — so don&#8217;t expect to get one in your home any time soon. But it&#8217;s not wild to think that a consumer version of this light field setup may be available down the line. Google promises to share more later this year.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-io-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-is-making-a-3d-life-size-video-calling-booth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154131</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>May Mobility&#8217;s Edwin Olson and Nina Grooms Lee and Toyota AI Ventures&#8217; Jim Adler on validating your startup idea</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/may-mobilitys-edwin-olson-and-nina-grooms-lee-and-toyota-ai-ventures-jim-adler-on-validating-your-startup-idea/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/may-mobilitys-edwin-olson-and-nina-grooms-lee-and-toyota-ai-ventures-jim-adler-on-validating-your-startup-idea/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 19:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ECL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live Recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[May Mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota AI Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Read on for highlights from our chat with Olson, Grooms Lee and Adler, or watch a recording of the full session, including our live pitch-off.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When a founder has a work history that includes the name of the parent company of one of their key investors, you probably assume that was one of the first deals to come together. Not so with May Mobility and Toyota AI Ventures, which connected for the company&#8217;s second seed round, after May went out and raised its original seed purely on the strength of its own ideas and proposed solutions.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s one of the many interesting things we learned from speaking to May Mobility co-founder and CEO Edwin Olson, as well as Chief Product Officer Nina Grooms Lee and Toyota AI Ventures founding partner Jim Adler on an episode of Extra Crunch Live.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">Extra Crunch Live</a> goes down every Wednesday at 3 p.m. EDT/noon PDT. Our next episode is with <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-sequoia-and-vise">Sequoia&#8217;s Shaun Maguire and Vise&#8217;s Samir Vasavada</a>, and you can check out the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/check-out-the-tech-leaders-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-may/">upcoming schedule right here</a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, read on for highlights from our chat with Olson, Grooms Lee and Adler, and then stay tuned at the end for a recording of the full session, including our live pitch-off.</p>
<h2>A different approach to corporate VC</h2>
<p>One thing Adler brought up early in the chat is that Toyota AI Ventures likely takes a different approach than most traditional corporate VCs, which are often thought of as being more incentivized by strategic alignment than by venture-scale returns. Adler says the firm he founded within the automaker&#8217;s corporate umbrella actually does behave much more like a traditional VC in some ways than many would assume.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/may-mobilitys-edwin-olson-and-nina-grooms-lee-and-toyota-ai-ventures-jim-adler-on-validating-your-startup-idea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153131</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google partners with Shopify on online shopping expansion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-partners-with-shopify-on-online-shopping-expansion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-partners-with-shopify-on-online-shopping-expansion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google io 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google today announced it&#8217;s partnering with Shopify, giving the e-commerce platform&#8217;s over 1.7 million merchants the ability to reach consumers through Google Search and its other services. The integration will allow merchants to sign up in just a few clicks to have their products appear across Google&#8217;s 1 billion &#8220;shopping journeys&#8221; that take place every [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google today announced it&#8217;s partnering with Shopify, giving the e-commerce platform&#8217;s over 1.7 million merchants the ability to reach consumers through Google Search and its other services. The integration will allow merchants to sign up in just a few clicks to have their products appear across Google&#8217;s 1 billion &#8220;shopping journeys&#8221; that take place every day through Search, Maps, Images, Lens and YouTube.</p>
<p>The company didn&#8217;t offer extensive details about the integration when it was announced during Google&#8217;s I/O Developer event this afternoon. But the news follows a series of updates to Google Shopping resulting from <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/29/amazons-ads-business-nears-7-billion-a-quarter-posts-77percent-growth.html">Amazon&#8217;s increased investment in its own advertising business</a>, which threatens Google&#8217;s core ads business.</p>
<p>Google made its pitch to online advertisers today, describing how its so-called &#8220;Shopping Graph&#8221; would now begin to pull together information from across websites, price reviews, videos and product data pulled directly from brands and retailers, to help better inform online shoppers about where to find items, how well they were received, which merchant has the best price, and more.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This Shopping Graph can span across Google&#8217;s platforms, whether someone is discovering products through Google Search or even watching videos on YouTube, among other things.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2154126" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154126" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2154126" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-18-at-2.38.40-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="396" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-18-at-2.38.40-PM.jpg 1259w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-18-at-2.38.40-PM.jpg?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-18-at-2.38.40-PM.jpg?resize=300,175 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-18-at-2.38.40-PM.jpg?resize=768,448 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-18-at-2.38.40-PM.jpg?resize=680,396 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-18-at-2.38.40-PM.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2154126" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google I/O 2021</p></div></p>
<p>For example, when you now view screenshots of products in Google Photos, there will be a suggestion to search the photo using Google Lens, to help you find the item for sale. And Google <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/youtube-to-expand-shorts-to-the-u-s-add-4k-and-dvr-to-youtube-tv-launch-in-video-shopping-and-more-in-2021/">announced</a> earlier this year it was pilot-testing a new experience on YouTube that allows users to shop products they learn about from their favorite creators &#8212; a move to counteract the growing threats from TikTok and Facebook, and their own investments in e-commerce.</p>
<p>But before any of this Shopping Graph functionality can really work, Google needs consumers to find shopping for products via Google actually useful. That&#8217;s partly why <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/21/google-switches-its-shopping-search-service-to-mostly-free-listings/">Google made it free for merchants to sell their products across Google </a>this past year &#8212; a change that Google says drove an 80% increase in merchants on Google, with the &#8220;vast majority&#8221; being small to medium-sized business.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s where the partnership with Shopify comes in, too. Though this integration doesn&#8217;t mean that every Shopify storefront will be included on Google &#8212; the merchants have to take an action to make that happen &#8212; it would be almost a no-brainer for them not to leverage the new option.</p>
<p>Shopify isn&#8217;t playing favorites when it comes to distribution, however. It&#8217;s integrated with other large platforms, too, including <a href="https://news.shopify.com/shopify-partners-with-facebook-to-help-businesses-launch-branded-facebook-shops">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/tiktok-invests-in-social-commerce-via-new-shopify-partnership/">TikTok</a>. And it&#8217;s been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/15/walmart-partners-with-shopify-to-expand-its-online-marketplace/">working with Walmart</a> to expand the retailer&#8217;s online marketplace, as well.</p>
<p>Investors seemed happy with the Shopify news this afternoon. Shortly after Google&#8217;s announcement, the <a href="https://www.google.com/finance/quote/SHOP:NYSE?sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjZv_LZ7tPwAhUgElkFHTjtBJ0Q3ecFMAB6BAgNEBo">stock</a> popped 3.52%.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-partners-with-shopify-on-online-shopping-expansion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154066</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>With Android 12, Google will turn your smartphone into a car key</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/with-android-12-google-will-turn-your-smartphone-into-a-car-key/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/with-android-12-google-will-turn-your-smartphone-into-a-car-key/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android Auto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BMW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google is working with BMW and other automakers to develop a digital key that will let car owners lock, unlock and start a vehicle from their Android smartphone, the company announced Tuesday during its 2021 Google I/O developer event. The digital key is one many new features coming to Android 12, the latest version of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google is working with BMW and other automakers to develop a digital key that will let car owners lock, unlock and start a vehicle from their Android smartphone, the company announced Tuesday during its 2021 Google I/O developer event.</p>
<p>The digital key is one many new features coming to Android 12, the latest version of the company&#8217;s mobile operating system. The digital car keys will become available on select Pixel and Samsung Galaxy phones later this year, according to Sameer Samat, VP of PM for Android &amp; Google Play. The digital car key will be available in yet unnamed 2022 vehicle models, including ones made by BMW, and some 2021 models.</p>
<p>The digital key uses so-called Ultra Wideband (UWB) technology, a form of radio transmission for which the sensor can tell the direction of the signal, sort of like a tiny radar. This lets the antenna in your phone locate and identify objects equipped with UWB transmitters. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">By using UWB technology, the Android user will be able to lock and unlock their vehicle without taking their phone out. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2153897" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153897" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2153897" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?w=680" alt="Google Android digital car key" width="400" height="400" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg 5760w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Digital-Car-Key.jpeg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2153897" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Consumers who own car models that have enabled NFC technology, or near-field communication, will be able unlock their car by tapping their phone against the door. The phone communicates with an NFC reader in the user&#8217;s car, which is typically located within the door handle. Google said users will also be able to securely and remotely share their car key with friends and family if they need to borrow the car.</p>
<p>The announcement follows a similar move made by Apple last year that allowed users to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/apple-turns-the-iphone-into-the-key-for-your-car/">add a digital car key</a> to their iPhone or Apple Watch. That feature, which was part of iOS 14, works over NFC and first became available in the 2021 BMW 5 Series.</p>
<p>A growing number of automakers have developed their own apps, which can also control certain functions such as remote locking and unlocking. The big benefit, in Google&#8217;s and likely Apple&#8217;s view, is that by offering the digital car key in its mobile operating system, users don&#8217;t have to download an app.</p>
<p>The intent is for a less clunky experience. And there&#8217;s a movement to make it even more seamless. The Car Connectivity Consortium, which Apple, Google, Samsung along with automakers BMW, GM, Honda, Hyundai and Volkswagen are members of, have spent the past several years creating an underlying agreement to make it easier to work in a seamless way and to standardize a digital key solution.</p>
<p>The development of the digital car key is just part of Google&#8217;s push to ensure the smartphone is the centerpiece of consumers&#8217; lives. And it&#8217;s a goal that can&#8217;t be achieved without including vehicles.</p>
<p>&#8220;When purchasing a phone these days, we’re buying not only a phone, but also an entire ecosystem of devices that are all expected to work together &#8212; such as TVs, laptops, cars and wearables like smartwatches or fitness tracker, Google&#8217;s vp of engineering Erik Kay wrote in a blog post accompanying the announcement during the event. &#8220;In North America, the average person now has around eight connected devices, and by 2022, this is predicted to grow to 13 connected devices.&#8221;</p>
<p>Google said it is expanding its &#8220;fast pair&#8221; feature, which lets users pair their devices via Bluetooth with a single tap, to other products, including vehicles. To date, consumers have used &#8220;fast pair&#8221; more than 36 million times to connect their Android phones with Bluetooth accessories, including Sony, Microsoft, JBL, Philips, Google and many other popular brands, according to Kay.</p>
<p>The feature will be rolled out to more devices in the coming months, including Beats headphones as well as cars from BMW and Ford, Sameer Samat, VP of PM for Android &amp; Google Play said during Google I/O.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/with-android-12-google-will-turn-your-smartphone-into-a-car-key/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153809</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After closing Fitbit acquisition, Google is going big with Wear OS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/after-closing-fitbit-acquisition-google-is-going-big-with-wear-os/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/after-closing-fitbit-acquisition-google-is-going-big-with-wear-os/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google io 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tizen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wear os]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For years, Wear OS has been, at best, something of a dark horse among Google operating systems. It’s certainly not for lack of partnership or investment, but for whatever reason, the company has never really stuck the landing with its wearable operating system. It’s a category in which Apple has been utterly dominant for some [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For years, Wear OS has been, at best, something of a dark horse among Google operating systems. It’s certainly not for lack of partnership or investment, but for whatever reason, the company has never really stuck the landing with its wearable operating system.</p>
<p>It’s a category in which Apple has been utterly dominant for some time. Google has largely failed to chip away at that market, in spite of enlisting some of the biggest names in consumer electronics as partners. Figures <a href="https://news.strategyanalytics.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2020/Strategy-Analytics-Global-Smartwatch-Shipments-Grow-20-Percent-to-14-Million-in-Q1-2020/default.aspx">from Strategy Analytics</a> classify Wear OS among the “others” category.</p>
<p>Google’s strategy is, once again, the result of partnerships – or, more precisely, partnerships combined with acquisitions. At the top of the list is an “if you can’t beat ‘em, join em’” approach to Samsung’s longstanding preference for open-source Tizen. It seemed like one of the stranger plays in the category, but building out its own version of Tizen has proven a winning strategy for the company, which trails only Apple in the category.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’re making the biggest update ever to <a href="https://twitter.com/WearOSbyGoogle?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@wearosbygoogle</a>, including new capabilities for Google apps — like turn-by-turn navigation in Google Maps, or downloading songs from YouTube Music for offline listening… even if you leave your phone behind. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoogleIO?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GoogleIO</a> <a href="https://t.co/vOnxnWl0MA">pic.twitter.com/vOnxnWl0MA</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Google (@Google) <a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1394723641758306308?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 18, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>During today’s I/O keynote, the company company revealed a new partnership with Samsung, “combining the best of Wear OS and Tizen.” We’re still waiting to see how that will play out, but it will be fascinating watching two big players combine forces to take on Apple. You come at the king, you best not miss, to quote a popular prestige television program. On the developer side, this seems to allude to the ability to create joint apps for both platforms, as third-party app selection has been a sticking point for both.</p>
<p>The other big change sheds some more light on precisely why the company was interested in Fitbit. Sure the company was a wearables leader that dominated fitness bands and eventually created its own solid smartwatches (courtesy of, among other things, its own acquisition of Pebble), but health is really the key here.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2154142" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154142" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2154142" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/15_AndroidWear_Playicon_Still_2K.max-1000x1000-1.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="562" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/15_AndroidWear_Playicon_Still_2K.max-1000x1000-1.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/15_AndroidWear_Playicon_Still_2K.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/15_AndroidWear_Playicon_Still_2K.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/15_AndroidWear_Playicon_Still_2K.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/15_AndroidWear_Playicon_Still_2K.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/15_AndroidWear_Playicon_Still_2K.max-1000x1000-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2154142" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Health monitoring has become the dominant conversation around wearables in recent years, and Google’s acquisition seems to be, above all, about integrating that information. “[A] world-class health and fitness service from Fitbit is coming to the platform,” the company noted. Beyond adding Fitbit&#8217;s well-loved tracking features, the company will also be integrated Wear features into Google&#8217;s hardware, working to blur the line between the two companies.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Health and fitness tracking is essential for wearables,&#8221; Google notes in a blog post. &#8220;With the latest Wear update, we welcome Fitbit’s many years of health expertise to the experience. The best of Fitbit, including features like tracking your health progress throughout your day and on-wrist goal celebrations, will motivate you on your journey to better health.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The consumer-facing experience has been revamped here, as well. Apps like Calm, Sleep Cycle and Flo are getting their own tiles, while shortcuts are now accessible from anywhere. A number of Google&#8217;s own apps are getting a refresh, as well, including Maps, Assistant and Pay, the latter of which is rolling out to an additional 26 countries &#8212; adding to the 11 currently available. Later this year, the company will also be introducing a Watch version of the YouTube Music app.</p>
<p>The aforementioned updates are set to arrive later this year.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/after-closing-fitbit-acquisition-google-is-going-big-with-wear-os/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153832</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google and Samsung are teaming up to take on Apple’s watchOS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-and-samsung-are-teaming-up-to-take-on-apples-watchos/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-and-samsung-are-teaming-up-to-take-on-apples-watchos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google io 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tizen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wear os]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With a long-standing history of working together on the mobile side, it’s always been a bit of a surprise that Samsung hasn’t had much patience for Google’s wearables play. The hardware giant had flirted with Android Wear in the past, but for the last several years, it’s been invested in building out its own version [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With a long-standing history of working together on the mobile side, it’s always been a bit of a surprise that Samsung hasn’t had much patience for Google’s wearables play. The hardware giant had flirted with Android Wear in the past, but for the last several years, it’s been invested in building out its own version of open-source operating system, Tizen.</p>
<p>Today, both companies announced a partnership featuring a “unified platform” between the two some-time competitors. The goal of the deal is to essentially create a way for devs to build apps for both Wear OS and Tizen at once. The deal makes sense from that perspective. Third-party apps have been something of a sticking point for both companies.</p>
<p>Even more to the point, it’s an opportunity for two smaller players in the space to join forces and take on Apple, which has been utterly dominant in the smartwatch category, more or less since the first Apple Watch arrived.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’re combining the best of <a href="https://twitter.com/WearOSbyGoogle?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@wearosbygoogle</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/SamsungMobile?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@SamsungMobile</a> Tizen into a unified wearable platform. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/231a.png" alt="⌚" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Apps will start faster, battery life will be longer and you&#39;ll have more choice than ever before, from devices to apps and watch faces. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoogleIO?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GoogleIO</a> <a href="https://t.co/vj2aYZD81x">pic.twitter.com/vj2aYZD81x</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Google (@Google) <a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1394722430212616192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 18, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Wear OS has already gone through a number of cycles, including a big rebrand from Android OS a while back, but nothing has really stuck over the years, leaving the wearable operating as something of an also-ran. For now, at least, this is far from a full-throated embrace of Wear OS on Samsung’s part and appears to be something more akin to an &#8220;the enemy of my enemy&#8221; situation. Along with developing a unified API, the companies are joining forces to pluck the best from each operating system, including longer battery life &#8212; perhaps the largest hurdle facing smartwatches at the moment.</p>
<p>&#8220;We know that health and wellness are at the forefront of consumers’ minds, and we’re excited to continue building the industry-leading health experience on our new unified platform with Google,&#8221; Samsung said in a blog post. &#8220;As our consumers turn to wearable technology to monitor their wellbeing, we’re meeting these needs head on. By creating world-class health technology, we hope to elevate how users approach to their wellbeing, and enable them to make positive changes in their everyday lives.&#8221;</p>
<p>Samsung added that the next version of the Galaxy Watch will be the first to leverage this partnership, but offered little additional information on the hardware front. I’d anticipate big news on the Wear OS front in the next year. If nothing else, the company’s partnership with Google is a sign that it’s ready to go for broke with the platform.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-and-samsung-are-teaming-up-to-take-on-apples-watchos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153877</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google offers the best look yet at Android 12</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-offers-the-best-look-yet-at-android-12/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-offers-the-best-look-yet-at-android-12/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android 12]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google io 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153927</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The one-dozenth version of Android has been something of an odd duck. The latest version of Google’s mobile operating system was announced back in February, and a beta version is already available to developers. But up to now, we’ve known glancingly little about how the final version of Android 12 will actually look. Fittingly, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The one-dozenth version of Android has been something of an odd duck. The latest version of Google’s mobile operating system was announced back in February, and a beta version is already available to developers. But up to now, we’ve known glancingly little about how the final version of Android 12 will actually look. Fittingly, the new version looks to be delivering one of the biggest design updates in recent memory. The news arrives as Google is announcing there are now more than 3 billion Android devices currently in use.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We first introduced <a href="https://twitter.com/Android?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Android</a> in 2008 — and now there are 3 billion active Android devices around the world. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f92f.png" alt="🤯" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoogleIO?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GoogleIO</a> <a href="https://t.co/G6wMXfWgNZ">pic.twitter.com/G6wMXfWgNZ</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Google (@Google) <a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1394719458921431040?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 18, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The company unveiled Material You, a new cross-platform adaptable UI designed to give users more control over how their operating systems work. Among other things, that means that the content can be tailored to different design languages on the phones themselves. The feature will arrive first on Pixel phones this fall and will roll out to additional devices from there.</p>
<p>Per Google:</p>
<blockquote><p>The notification shade is more intuitive and playful, with a crisp, at-a-glance view of your app notifications, whatever you’re currently listening to or watching, and Quick Settings that let you control practically the entire operating system with a swipe and a tap. The Quick Settings space doesn’t just look and feel different. It’s been rebuilt to include Google Pay and Home Controls, while still allowing for customization so you can have everything you need most in one easy-to-access place.</p></blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_2154085" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154085" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2154085 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/custom-palette-photo-01-android-google-io-2021.jpg" alt="custom palette settings on Android" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/custom-palette-photo-01-android-google-io-2021.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/custom-palette-photo-01-android-google-io-2021.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/custom-palette-photo-01-android-google-io-2021.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/custom-palette-photo-01-android-google-io-2021.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/custom-palette-photo-01-android-google-io-2021.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/custom-palette-photo-01-android-google-io-2021.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/custom-palette-photo-01-android-google-io-2021.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/custom-palette-photo-01-android-google-io-2021.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2154085" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Google</p></div></p>
<p>Android 12 will be the first to get the redesigned UI and widgets, along with other design elements. The company is calling it &#8220;the biggest design change to Android in years.&#8221; The updates include across-the-board refreshes to things, including the lock screen and wallpaper, which uses a variety of algorithms to offer an ever-adapting color palette. The operative word here seems to be &#8220;dynamic,&#8221; as different elements and widgets adapt to things like the time of day.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Android has a new look. Inspired by Material You, we’ve rethought the entire experience for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Android12?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Android12</a>, from colors to shapes, light and motion. It’s more personal and expressive — a one-of-a-kind design, just for you. <a href="https://t.co/xCRLr7XLWM">pic.twitter.com/xCRLr7XLWM</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Google (@Google) <a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1394720932820832264?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 18, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Along with ever-changing design, Google is also touting adapting security features with this latest update. The list includes new indicators for access to the microphone and camera &#8212; permissions that can be revoked directly from the operating system&#8217;s dashboard. The Private Compute Core, meanwhile, offers access to things like Smart Reply, based on the user&#8217;s personal setting. That information is isolated from the network, while the computing happens directly on the device itself.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2154108" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154108" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2154108 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/5._Andriod_12_Fluid_Motion.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="745" /><p id="caption-attachment-2154108" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Google</p></div></p>
<p>Android handsets will also work more closely with Chrome OS going forward, including the ability to use the mobile device to log directly into a Chromebook, as well as cross-platform notifications.</p>
<p>On the dev side, the company says it has improved performance. &#8220;We reduced the CPU time needed for core system services by 22%, so devices will be faster and more responsive,&#8221; Google writes on its developer blog. &#8220;We also improved Android&#8217;s power efficiency by reducing the use of big cores by the system server by 15% to help devices run longer before needing to charge.&#8221; Transition and app startup times have been improved here, as well.</p>
<p>The new beta is available starting today. Google is promising more updates in the near future to what appears to be the largest update to the mobile operating system in recent memory. The final version is set to arrive in the fall.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-offers-the-best-look-yet-at-android-12/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153927</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Android now powers 3B devices</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/android-now-powers-3b-devices/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/android-now-powers-3b-devices/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google I/O 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet computer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2152968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google&#8217;s Android operating system is now running on 3 billion active devices, Google announced at its (virtual) I/O developer conference today. In a briefing before today&#8217;s event, the company also noted that there were 250 million active tablets running Android last year, which is likely a larger number than some expected, but which explains Google&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google&#8217;s Android operating system is now running on 3 billion active devices, Google announced at its (virtual) I/O developer conference today. In a briefing before today&#8217;s event, the company also noted that there were 250 million active tablets running Android last year, which is likely a larger number than some expected, but which explains Google&#8217;s increased focus on these large-screen devices at I/O this year.</p>
<p>Traditionally, Google shares new device stats at I/O, but since it canceled the event last year, we didn&#8217;t get an update for 2020. The most recent number Google provided was 2.5 billion active devices in May 2019. That was up from 2 billion devices in 2017, so at least for the time being, this growth rate of about 500 million new devices every two years continues to remain true.</p>
<p>In comparison, Apple in January <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-apple-results/apple-tops-wall-street-expectations-on-record-iphone-revenue-china-sales-surge-idUSKBN29W2TD">announced</a> that it has an install base of 1 billion iPhones and there are now a total of 1.65 billion active devices in its ecosystem, up from 1.5 billion devices a year before (this last number includes all active Apple devices, though).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="p8BMF81CiK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/07/android-now-has-2-5b-users/">Android now powers 2.5B devices</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Android now powers 2.5B devices&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/07/android-now-has-2-5b-users/embed/#?secret=p8BMF81CiK" data-secret="p8BMF81CiK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/google-io-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/android-now-powers-3b-devices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2152968</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beta Technologies adds $368 million in Series A funding for its electric aviation ecosystem</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/beta-technologies-adds-368-million-in-series-a-funding-for-its-electric-aviation-ecosystem/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/beta-technologies-adds-368-million-in-series-a-funding-for-its-electric-aviation-ecosystem/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Climate Pledge Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beta Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eVTOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fidelity management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fidelity Management & Research Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban air mobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154034</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Electric aviation startup Beta Technologies closed a $368 million Series A funding round on Tuesday, with investments from Amazon’s Climate Pledge Fund. The new capital is the second round of funding announced by the company this year, after the company raised $143 million in private capital in March. The funding round was led by Fidelity [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Electric aviation startup Beta Technologies closed a $368 million Series A funding round on Tuesday, with investments from Amazon’s Climate Pledge Fund. The new capital is the second round of funding announced by the company this year, after the company raised $143 million in private capital in March.</p>
<p>The funding round was led by Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company, with undisclosed additions from Amazon’s Climate Pledge Fund, a $2 billion fund established in September 2019 to advance the development of sustainable technologies. The Climate Pledge fund has also made contributions toward electric vehicle manufacturer Rivian, battery recycler Redwood Materials and ZeroAvia, a hydrogen fuel cell aviation company.</p>
<p>The company’s valuation is now at $1.4 billion, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/18/beta-becomes-latest-eva-unicorn-with-amazon-fidelity-backing.html">CNBC reported</a>, putting it in a small circle of electric vertical take-off and landing (eVTOL) companies to have achieved valuations at over a billion dollars.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Unlike developers Joby Aviation and Archer Aviation, which have each also achieved valuations over the billion-dollar mark, Beta is not primarily focused on air taxis. Instead, it’s been targeting defense applications, cargo delivery and medical logistics, as well as building out its network of rapid-charging systems in the northeast U.S. Its debut aircraft, the ALIA-250c, was built to serve these various solutions by being capable of carrying six people or a pilot and 1,500 pounds.</p>
<p>The Vermont-based startup has already scored major partnerships in all of these industries, including with United Therapeutics to transport synthetic organs for human transplant; UPS, which purchased 10 ALIA aircraft with the option of buying 140 more; and the U.S. Air Force.</p>
<p>The company has not entirely ignored passenger transportation, however, announcing last month a partnership with Blade Urban Air Mobility for five aircraft to be delivered in 2024.</p>
<p>Beta was the first company to be awarded airworthiness approval from the U.S. Air Force. The company expects to sign a contract in June with the Air Force to allow access to Beta’s aircraft and flight simulators in Washington, D.C. and Springfield, Ohio. However, it still must achieve certification with the Federal Aviation Administration.</p>
<p>The funds will be used to refine the ALIA’s electric propulsion system and controls, as well as to build out manufacturing space, including expanding its footprint in Vermont on land at the Burlington International Airport, the company said in a news release Tuesday.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rmzSWwG0to"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/giving-ev-batteries-a-second-life-for-sustainability-and-profit/">Giving EV batteries a second life for sustainability and profit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Giving EV batteries a second life for sustainability and profit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/giving-ev-batteries-a-second-life-for-sustainability-and-profit/embed/#?secret=rmzSWwG0to" data-secret="rmzSWwG0to" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/beta-technologies-adds-368-million-in-series-a-funding-for-its-electric-aviation-ecosystem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154034</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commission-free trading app Stake secures $30M from Tiger Global to expand into Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/commission-free-trading-app-stake-secures-30m-from-tiger-global-to-expand-into-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/commission-free-trading-app-stake-secures-30m-from-tiger-global-to-expand-into-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DST Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[etoro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154052</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Commission-free trading app Stake, which is available in the U.K., Brazil and New Zealand, has raised $30 million from Tiger Global and partners of London-based DST Global to expand into Europe. Matt Leibowitz, founder and CEO of Stake said: “We’re really excited to get to this point but it’s just the start. We set out [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Commission-free trading app <a href="https://hellostake.com/">Stake</a>, which is available in the U.K., Brazil and New Zealand, has raised $30 million from Tiger Global and partners of London-based DST Global to expand into Europe.</p>
<p>Matt Leibowitz, founder and CEO of Stake said: “We’re really excited to get to this point but it’s just the start. We set out to change the game for retail investors and were self-funded for the first four years of our journey. We’ve proven the model and now have the chance to expand our product and bring our zero-brokerage service to more retail investors.”</p>
<p>Since launching in the U.K. in early 2020, Stake claims to have grown its total customer base more than six times over, with 25% month-on-month customer growth on average and hitting over 330,000 customers globally.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It was the first to offer commission-free access to the U.S. market in Australia, offering retail investors access to over 4,400 U.S. stocks &amp; ETFs without a brokerage fee.</p>
<p>In the U.K. it competes with eToro, Libertex, Fineco, Plus500 and IG, among others.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/commission-free-trading-app-stake-secures-30m-from-tiger-global-to-expand-into-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154052</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
