<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 05:23:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Skello raises $47.3 million for its employee scheduling tool</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/skello-raises-47-3-million-for-its-employee-scheduling-tool/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/skello-raises-47-3-million-for-its-employee-scheduling-tool/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 05:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scheduling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Skello]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Skello has raised a $47.3 million funding round (€40 million). The company has been working on a software-as-a-service tool that lets you manage the work schedule of your company. What makes it special is that Skello automatically takes into account local labor laws and collective agreements. Partech is leading today’s funding round. Existing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://en.skello.io">Skello</a> has raised a $47.3 million funding round (€40 million). The company has been working on a software-as-a-service tool that lets you manage the work schedule of your company. What makes it special is that Skello automatically takes into account local labor laws and collective agreements.</p>
<p>Partech is leading today’s funding round. Existing investors XAnge and Aglaé Ventures are also participating. The startup had previously raised a €300,000 seed round and a €6 million Series A round in 2018.</p>
<p>Skello works with companies across many industries, such as retail, hospitality, pharmacies, bakeries, gyms, escape games and more. And many of them were simply using Microsoft Excel to manage their schedule.</p>
<p>By using Skello, you get an online service that works for both managers and employees. On the manager side, you can view who is working and when. You can assign employees to fill some gaps.</p>
<p>For employees, they can also connect to the platform to see their own schedule. Employees can also say when they are unavailable and request time off. And when something unexpected comes up, employees can trade shifts.</p>
<p>“We really want to put employees at the center of the product,” co-founder and CEO Quitterie Mathelin-Moreaux told me. “They have a mobile app and the idea is to make the work schedule as collaborative as possible in order to allocate resources as efficiently as possible and increase team retention.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At every step of the scheduling process, Skello manages legal requirements. For instance, Skello remembers mandatory weekly rest periods. The platform knows that your employees can’t work across a long time range. And Skello can count overtime hours, holiday hours, Sunday shifts, etc.</p>
<p>When you’re approaching the end of the month, Skello can generate a report with everyone’s timesheet. You can integrate Skello directly with your payroll tool to make this process a bit less tedious as well.</p>
<p>Skello is currently used across 7,000 points of sale. Now, the company wants to expand to more European countries and increase the size of the team from 150 employees to 300 employees by 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/skello-raises-47-3-million-for-its-employee-scheduling-tool/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203207</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Online events platform Delegate Connect gets $10M AUD led by AirTree</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/online-events-platform-delegate-connect-gets-10m-aud-led-by-airtree/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/online-events-platform-delegate-connect-gets-10m-aud-led-by-airtree/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 04:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delegate Connect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Livestreaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Delegate Connect is the latest virtual/hybrid events platform to land funding. The Melbourne-based startup announced today it has raised $10 million AUD (about $7.3 million USD) in seed funding led by AirTree Ventures, which wrote Delegate Connect the biggest seed check in the fund’s history so far. Other participants included Skip Capital, TEN13 and Australian [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2203572" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203572" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203572" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png" alt="Delegate Connect founders Jordan Walsh and Jacob Thomas" width="1024" height="613" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png 1700w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=300,179 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=768,459 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=680,407 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=1536,919 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jordan-Walsh-CEO-and-Jacob-Thomas-CIO-Delegate-Connect.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203572" class="wp-caption-text">Delegate Connect founders Jordan Walsh and Jacob Thomas</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.delegateconnect.co/">Delegate Connect</a> is the latest virtual/hybrid events platform to land funding. The Melbourne-based startup announced today it has raised $10 million AUD (about $7.3 million USD) in seed funding led by AirTree Ventures, which wrote Delegate Connect the biggest seed check in the fund’s history so far. Other participants included Skip Capital, TEN13 and Australian startup founders like LinkTree’s Alex Zaccaria and Go1’s Andrew Barnes.</p>
<p>The capital will be used to build Delegate Connect’s teams in Melbourne, London and Norway, which enable it to handle events around the world, increasing headcount from 45 to more than 100 by December. It also plans to open a United States-based office soon.</p>
<p>Founded in 2017 and bootstrapped until its seed round, Delegate Connect’s business grew during the COVID-19 pandemic, like many other virtual event platforms. Its clients have included the Edinburgh TV Festival, Sportsbet, the World Dental Congress and the World Library and Information Congress. Some of the sectors Delegate Connect focuses on include medical, pharmaceutical and industry associations.</p>
<p>Delegate Connect was created after co-founders Jordan Walsh and Jacob Thomas started a technical production and events business, and looked for a “technology platform that could do everything we needed at a large-scale event, including registration, live-streaming, hosting video-on-demand and integrate seamlessly with the venues.” They decided to build their own, initially as an internal tool. Then during a trip to India in 2019 to work on a symposium, the two realized that there was a wider need for their platform.</p>
<p>“[We] had a lightbulb moment where we thought ‘we are solving a genuine problem here.’ One of the world’s biggest technology companies was flying us to Mumbai to use our system (which wasn’t even built properly) to deliver the technical assets of their event!” Walsh told TechCrunch in an email.</p>
<p>The two finished building the platform at the end of 2019 and launched it in January 2020.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Walsh and Thomas were interested in hybrid events even before COVID-19.</p>
<p>“Hybrid events have been around for along time, especially in the medical, pharmaceutical and associations sectors,” said Walsh. “Before COVID, they typically involved someone broadcasting a live stream from the venue, recording it and then hosting it on-demand after the event. These are all fundamentals of the platform we’ve built, and we’re obsessed with creating a platform that expands the hybrid event experience to do so much more than live streaming and video on demand.”</p>
<p>Some features created for the medical and pharmaceutical sectors include the ability to log hours spent viewing educational or scientific content, which is useful for delegates who are attending events to earn professional development points (CPD), abstract submissions, content-restricted registrations and the ability to run concurrent streams.</p>
<p>Tracking professional development points is a major selling point in particular, since “this is typically super complex technically for clients, and we solve this for them by working out how they accredit, build it in, track it and then process the accreditation,” said Walsh.</p>
<p>If you’ve attended a lot of online events over the past year and a half, you are probably wondering how Delegate Connect is different from platforms like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/">Hopin</a> (which was used for TechCrunch Disrupt last year), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/bizzabo-raises-138m-for-a-platform-that-helps-you-build-and-run-virtual-conferences/">Bizzabo</a>, MeetingPlay or Cvent.</p>
<p>One of its main differentiators is that it was built with specific target audiences (medical, pharmaceutical, associations and international congresses) in mind, and plans to launch a self-service platform for them. Delegate Connect is also completely customizable, so events can use it as a white-label solution.</p>
<p>“Ease of use is central to the UX,” Walsh said. “For example, we have full content restrictions through our registration portal, allowing people to register for sessions, days, themes and streams. We can restrict sponsors form seeing other sponsor booths and ensure that content can’t be shared (e.g. if a pharmaceutical company can’t share info with non-pharmacists, we can restrict this) as well as allow certain delegates to view only some content if needed.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pwYEGfV47E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/">Hopin confirms $400M raise at $5.65B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hopin confirms $400M raise at $5.65B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/embed/#?secret=pwYEGfV47E" data-secret="pwYEGfV47E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The delta variant and resurgence of COVID-19 has forced many organizers to turn in-person events into online ones. Walsh said Delegate Connect has handled many last-minute requests and can do so in a matter of hours. For example, in August, the startup was working on a medical conference originally slated to run as a hybrid event from a venue in Japan with thousands of delegates. Just before it was supposed to start, however, the organizers told Delegate Connect that they needed to switch to fully virtual event.</p>
<p>“We can do this easily because the platform doesn’t change. It’s versatile, no matter the delivery method,” said Walsh. “Delegates just need to log in on the day and engage with the content just like they would if they were at the event.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fN9f3AKSja"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/virtual-events-startups-have-high-hopes-for-after-the-pandemic/">Virtual events startups have high hopes for after the pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Virtual events startups have high hopes for after the pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/virtual-events-startups-have-high-hopes-for-after-the-pandemic/embed/#?secret=fN9f3AKSja" data-secret="fN9f3AKSja" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/online-events-platform-delegate-connect-gets-10m-aud-led-by-airtree/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203567</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: Off the Wall</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/gillmor-gang-off-the-wall/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/gillmor-gang-off-the-wall/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 03:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Most of us count the golden age of Michael Jackson&#8217;s career with the Quincy Jones produced global smashes of Thriller and Bad. Fueled by the stream of videos and multi-single releases (5 on Bad), the records dominated the charts, radio, and MTV. But the real breakthrough came just before with Jackson&#8217;s first solo record Off [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QzTyKuqgQS4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Most of us count the golden age of Michael Jackson&#8217;s career with the Quincy Jones produced global smashes of Thriller and Bad. Fueled by the stream of videos and multi-single releases (5 on Bad), the records dominated the charts, radio, and MTV. But the real breakthrough came just before with Jackson&#8217;s first solo record Off the Wall.</p>
<p>Born in the thrall of the Disco Era, it wasn&#8217;t hip, a surrender to the feel of funk meets MGM. But in the mountains around Woodstock, we couldn&#8217;t pry this record off the turntable. Today, with a simple voice command to Siri, the mists evaporate and with them the pandemic, working, working, working day and night, the melting years. And the bass. My God but it drives us to Living Life off the wall.</p>
<p>Permission is what we&#8217;re given. We need it. No matter what lies in store for us, the grooves capture the essence of our future, unlock our hopes and dreams, our intuition. Can we dare to think this way, the blend of vocals, horns, percussion, and the coursing basses? A Stevie Wonder track recharges the battery. The record fades out quietly, priming the pump for Side One.</p>
<p>Today we lost a nightclub comedian, as Norm MacDonald called himself in a YouTube clip. Like the best of them, his comedy spooled out of him like a 50&#8217;s cop show, methodical and faux stupid. You could see his genius in the faces of the funny people who had him on their shows — Letterman, Leno, Conan, an agonizingly hilarious Dennis Miller on his foul-mouthed HBO cable show. Talk about off the wall.</p>
<p>Miller defined this most selfish of dark arts, the joy of being funnier in the presence of funny. In a time of excruciating not funny, these strange warriors tilt with the vagaries of the laugh. MacDonald&#8217;s careful construction of his sleight of word was all the richer for his seemingly aimless pursuit of the sweet spot, where the punchline is so McGuffin-like for its inevitability.</p>
<p>As the world slowly recovers its focus, Apple has released a new iPhone that can adjust reality after the fact, Knowing this feat is not possible to recover what and who we&#8217;ve lost, I&#8217;m so grateful for the time we&#8217;ve had with these greats and their great moments. When the traveler reached the top of the mountain and asked the wise man for the secret of life, he replied, &#8220;Could you give me a sec, I&#8217;m on the phone.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><em>the latest <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang/issues/gillmor-gang-newsletter-revue-13-745198">Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, August 27, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang">Subscribe to the new Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></strong> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.<img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/gillmor-gang-off-the-wall/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vietnam-based CoderSchool gets $2.6M pre-Series A to scale online course platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/vietnam-based-coderschool-gets-2-6m-pre-series-a-to-scale-online-course-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/vietnam-based-coderschool-gets-2-6m-pre-series-a-to-scale-online-course-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 01:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CoderSchool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monk’s Hill Venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CoderSchool, a Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam-based online coding school startup, announced today $2.6 million in pre-Series A funding to scale up its online coding school platform. This round was led by Monk’s Hill Ventures, with participation from returning seed investors Iterative, XA Network and iSeed Ventures. CoderSchool raised a seed round led by TRIVE [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">CoderSchool, a Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam-based online coding school startup, announced today $2.6 million in pre-Series A funding to scale up its online coding school platform.</p>
<p>This round was led by Monk’s Hill Ventures, with participation from returning seed investors Iterative, XA Network and iSeed Ventures. CoderSchool raised a seed round led by TRIVE Ventures in 2018.</p>
<p>CoderSchool will use the funding to accelerate its online teaching platform growth and technology infrastructure expansion for the company’s technical education programs that guarantee employment upon graduation.</p>
<p>The company, founded in 2015 by Charles Lee and Harley Trung, who previously worked as software engineers, pivoted from offline to online in early 2020 to bring high-quality technical training to everyone, everywhere. After switching to a fully online learning program, the company recorded 100% quarter-over-quarter (QoQ) growth in fully online enrollment, it said in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;Coding is the future. At CoderSchool, we believe everyone in Southeast Asia deserves a chance to be part of that future,&#8221; the company co-founder and CEO Lee said.</p>
<p>In Vietnam, the demand for IT talent is dramatically increasing by 47% a year, while supply is only increasing by 8% year-on-year.</p>
<p>“The need for strong engineers and developers in Southeast Asia has never been as <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">pertinent </span>as it is today with the growth of tech companies and digital businesses,” said Michele Daoud, partner of Monk’s Hill Ventures. “We have been impressed by the team’s focus on setting the standard for coding education in the region. We are excited to partner with CoderSchool to provide both opportunity and access to the millions of aspiring students in Vietnam.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fgxuOEuuRw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/vietnam-after-school-learning-startup-marathon-raises-1-5m-pre-seed-round/">Vietnam after-school learning startup Marathon raises $1.5M pre-seed round</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Vietnam after-school learning startup Marathon raises $1.5M pre-seed round&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/vietnam-after-school-learning-startup-marathon-raises-1-5m-pre-seed-round/embed/#?secret=fgxuOEuuRw" data-secret="fgxuOEuuRw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Given the strong engineer demand in Vietnam, the domestic market size is estimated between $100 million &#8211; $200 million, and still increasing every year, according to Lee. CoderSchool has been focusing on Vietnam for the last six years, but plans to enter the global market following the next round, Lee said, without providing exact timetable.</p>
<p>CoderSchool, which offers full-stack web development, machine learning and data sciences courses at a lower cost, has trained more than 2,000 alumni up to date, and recorded over 80% job placement rate for full-time graduates, getting jobs at companies such as BOSCHE, Microsoft, Lazada, Shopee, FE Credit, FPT Software, Sendo, Tiki and Momo.</p>
<p>&#8220;After having taught over 2,000 students, we&#8217;ve been able to refine our [coding education] content. We rewrote our full-stack web development course &#8212; from Ruby, Python to JavaScript &#8212; in two years, and added new machine learning and data science courses to our program,&#8221; Lee told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>CorderSchool&#8217;s online program enables students to interact with instructors and classmates before, during and after scheduled class sessions with its human-driven learning strategy. CoderSchool currently has 15 instructional staff, and plans to hire 35 additional instructors by Q4 2022.</p>
<p>CoderSchool&#8217;s data analytics has improved individual student performance while also allowing CoderSchool to increase its classroom size at scale, reaching a peak of 107 enrollments in a data science class.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="R0D4ztoHxS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/apple-expands-its-free-coding-courses-and-materials-for-educators/">Apple expands its free coding courses and materials for educators</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple expands its free coding courses and materials for educators&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/apple-expands-its-free-coding-courses-and-materials-for-educators/embed/#?secret=R0D4ztoHxS" data-secret="R0D4ztoHxS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3hJVWyyKi4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/lambda-school-raises-74m-for-its-virtual-coding-school-where-you-pay-tuition-only-after-you-get-a-job/">Lambda School raises $74M for its virtual coding school where you pay tuition only after you get a job</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lambda School raises $74M for its virtual coding school where you pay tuition only after you get a job&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/lambda-school-raises-74m-for-its-virtual-coding-school-where-you-pay-tuition-only-after-you-get-a-job/embed/#?secret=3hJVWyyKi4" data-secret="3hJVWyyKi4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/vietnam-based-coderschool-gets-2-6m-pre-series-a-to-scale-online-course-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203049</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok is hiding a viral challenge that has kids stealing their school&#8217;s soap dispensers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/tiktok-devious-licks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/tiktok-devious-licks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viral trends]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s back to school season and on TikTok, that means students are inexplicably stealing everything that isn&#8217;t bolted down. The latest TikTok trend to generally wreak social havoc sees students pulling off &#8220;devious licks&#8221; — small-scale heists of everything from soap dispensers, Covid test kits and hand sanitizer to high value items like classroom tech. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s back to school season and on TikTok, that means students are inexplicably stealing everything that isn&#8217;t bolted down.</p>
<p>The latest TikTok trend to generally wreak social havoc sees students pulling off &#8220;devious licks&#8221; — small-scale heists of everything from soap dispensers, Covid test kits and hand sanitizer to high value items like classroom tech.</p>
<p>The videos are set to an edited version of Lil B&#8217;s &#8220;Ski Ski BasedGod,&#8221; which had appeared in around 100,000 videos on TikTok by Monday, <a href="https://mashable.com/article/tiktok-devious-lick-trend-school">according to Mashable</a>, with the tag #deviouslick collecting more than 175 million views.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WgzwSuAOIm4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>TikTok cracked down on Wednesday, limiting search results for the viral stunt, removing videos with the tag and encouraging users to &#8220;please be kind&#8221; to teachers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We expect our community to create responsibly &#8211; online and IRL. We&#39;re removing content and redirecting hashtags &amp; search results to our Community Guidelines to discourage such behavior. Please be kind to your schools &amp; teachers. <a href="https://t.co/mIFtsYwFRb">pic.twitter.com/mIFtsYwFRb</a></p>
<p>&mdash; TikTokComms (@TikTokComms) <a href="https://twitter.com/TikTokComms/status/1438251247753121795?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 15, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&#8220;We expect our community to stay safe and create responsibly, and we do not allow content that promotes or enables criminal activities,&#8221; a TikTok spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;We are removing this content and redirecting hashtags and search results to our Community Guidelines to discourage such behavior.&#8221;</p>
<p>While it&#8217;s hard to know which videos are staged and which are legitimate, the trend is real enough to have teachers and parents across the country stressed out. At a <a href="https://www.8newsnow.com/news/local-news/destructive-devious-licks-tiktok-challenge-a-problem-at-some-valley-schools/">middle school in Las Vegas</a>, school administrators report students swiping speed limit signs, fire alarms, soap dispensers and classroom projectors. And in Portland, Oregon at least one high school saw an entire building&#8217;s worth of soap dispensers go missing — not a great start to another school year in the throes of a global pandemic.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="k8dxlQhAo6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/tiktok-bans-viral-milk-crate-challenge-over-safety-concerns/">TikTok bans viral &#8216;milk crate challenge&#8217; over safety concerns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok bans viral &#8216;milk crate challenge&#8217; over safety concerns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/tiktok-bans-viral-milk-crate-challenge-over-safety-concerns/embed/#?secret=k8dxlQhAo6" data-secret="k8dxlQhAo6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/tiktok-devious-licks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203425</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inspiration4 crew, meet outer space: SpaceX&#8217;s first all-civilian mission launches to orbit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/inspiration4-crew-meet-outer-space-spacexs-first-all-civilian-mission-launches-to-orbit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/inspiration4-crew-meet-outer-space-spacexs-first-all-civilian-mission-launches-to-orbit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The first all-civilian crew in history has made it to space. The Inspiration4 crew took off from NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida at 8:04 EST PM, commencing the first space mission in human history featuring zero trained astronauts. The reusable first-stage of the Falcon 9 rocket executed two burns in its journey back to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The first all-civilian crew in history has made it to space.</p>
<p>The Inspiration4 crew took off from NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida at 8:04 EST PM, commencing the first space mission in human history featuring zero trained astronauts.</p>
<p>The reusable first-stage of the Falcon 9 rocket executed two burns in its journey back to Earth, landing vertically on the SpaceX droneship &#8220;Just Read the Instructions&#8221; around 9-and-a-half minutes after launch. Dragon separated from the second stage at 8:16 EST PM.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203520" style="width: 1000px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203520" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203520" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/stage2-separation-inspiration4.gif" alt="" width="990" height="559" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203520" class="wp-caption-text">Second stage separation. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://spacex.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SpaceX <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The four-person crew will be spending time in orbit in a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule, which was affixed to a Falcon 9 rocket. (It&#8217;s the second journey for this particular Dragon and the third journey for the Falcon 9 first stage.) They’ll ascend to an altitude of around 575 kilometers – the highest that any humans have gone since the last Hubble telescope servicing mission in 2009. That altitude is above the current orbit of the Hubble and the International Space Station, so they’ll be flying over every other human in space, too.</p>
<p>The crew will be going around the earth around 15 times each day they’re in space. While they’re up there, they’ll be able to view outer space from a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/spacex-is-outfitting-it-dragon-spacecraft-with-an-observation-down-for-space-tourists/">transparent observation dome</a> &#8220;cupola&#8221; that was affixed to Crew Dragon’s the nose cone especially for this flight. It&#8217;s the largest continuous window to ever be in space. It won’t all be space tourism, however; the Inspiration4 is also ferrying a number of science experiments to orbit, including research to learn more about the impact of spaceflight on the human body. The research subjects will be themselves: the crew collect biomedical data and biological samples from themselves before, during and after the flight.</p>
<p>Nowadays, no private space mission is complete without a requisite billionaire, and Inspiration4 has one of those, too: the mission commander and man who fronted the bill, Jared Isaacman, who earned his fortune from his payment processing company Shift4 Payments. It must be said, however, that the remaining crew members, while clearly extremely talented and uncommonly brave, are refreshingly normal. They include physician assistant Hayley Arceneaux; geoscientist and science education doctorate Sian Proctor; and Lockheed Martin engineer Chris Sembroski.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2203485" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203485" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203485" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspo4.gif" alt="" width="640" height="304" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203485" class="wp-caption-text">The Inspiration4 crew admiring the Falcon 9 rocket on Launch Pad 39A.<strong> Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://spacex.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SpaceX <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The mission will be raising money for St. Jude Research Hospital (Sembroski was selected from nearly 72,000 donations to the St. Jude fundraising campaign). The crew aimed to raise $200 million in total; $100 million was donated by Isaacman and the mission far exceeded its goal prior to launch, hitting nearly $300 million at the time of launch.</p>
<p>To prepare for the mission, which is significantly longer than any other recent spaceflight featuring civilians, the crew undertook hundreds of hours of training, including 12- and 30-hour flight simulations in a replica Dragon capsule and climbing Washington State’s Mount Rainier in May.</p>
<p>SpaceX CEO Elon Musk was at Kennedy Space Center to see the crew off, and in true Muskian style the crew also travelled to the launch tower in two Model Xs (wearing custom SpaceX spacesuits). While NASA’s involvement in the mission was relatively nominal, beyond providing some services and equipment worth around $1 million, the agency has played a key role in bringing SpaceX to the place of supremacy it is today. SpaceX was awarded $2.6 billion from NASA in 2014 to develop Crew Dragon, under its Commercial Crew program.</p>
<p>It’s a major milestone for SpaceX, the largest and most profitable launch company in the world. This launch is also notably different than those undertaken by Jeff Bezos and Richard Branson in recent months – though I know the similarities are compelling – because the crew will be going higher and for longer than the Blue Origin or Virgin Galactic missions. But all three companies have a goal of making spaceflight “evolve toward an airline-like model,” as SpaceX senior director of human spaceflight Benji Reed put it yesterday.</p>
<p>“Ultimately, we want to we want to make life multiplanetary, and that means putting millions of people in space,” he said. “The long-term vision is that spaceflight becomes airline-like like you buy a ticket and you go.”</p>
<p>Even this year, SpaceX will be conducting more crewed missions (though none with an all-civilian crew). A Falcon 9 will be ferrying astronauts to ISS later this year, and at the beginning of next year will be the first commercial Axiom mission, also to the space station. “The Dragon manifest is getting busier by the moment,” he added.</p>
<p>If all goes as planned, we’ll be seeing the Inspiration4 crew in three days, when they’ll splash down back to Earth in either the Gulf or the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Florida. Weather is critical here, too: “We look at not only the launch weather but we have to look at the return weather […] when we come home in just three or four days from now,” Reed explained during a starry-eyed (no pun intended) press briefing Tuesday.</p>
<p>While the crew is in orbit, you can listen to a curated playlist by Inspiration4’s very own Sembroski (who plans to play a ukulele in space).</p>
<p><iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/37i9dQZF1DWUffIH68FPTm" width="100%" height="380" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203431" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203431" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203431" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/inspiration-4-.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203431" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://inspiration4.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Inspiration4 <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/inspiration4-crew-meet-outer-space-spacexs-first-all-civilian-mission-launches-to-orbit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203430</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch SpaceX launch the first all-civilian Inspiration4 mission to space live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/watch-spacex-launch-the-first-all-civilian-inspiration4-mission-to-space-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/watch-spacex-launch-the-first-all-civilian-inspiration4-mission-to-space-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 22:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crew dragon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Falcon 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203038</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After months of publicity, an NFT auction and even a Netflix docuseries, it’s finally here: the four-person crew of Inspiration4 will be heading to space today (weather permitting). What makes this launch different from any that came before it? None of the four people onboard are astronauts. The mission marks the first time that an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3pv01sSq44w" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>After months of publicity, an NFT auction and even a Netflix docuseries, it’s finally here: the four-person crew of Inspiration4 will be heading to space today (weather permitting).</p>
<p>What makes this launch different from any that came before it? None of the four people onboard are astronauts. The mission marks the first time that an all-civilian crew will fly to space. Let’s meet them:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jared Isaacman, a 38-year-old billionaire whose fortune comes from the payment processing company Shift4 Payments, which went public in the summer of last year. He is the mission commander.</li>
<li>Sian Proctor, a community college professor with a PhD in science education. Proctor was among 47 finalists chosen by NASA for a 2009 astronaut class, though she was not one of the nine eventually chosen to join the agency. She will be Inspiration4’s pilot, the first Black woman to pilot a spacecraft. She’s 51.</li>
<li>Hayley Arceneaux, a 29-year-old physician assistant at St. Jude’s Research Hospital and a survivor of childhood cancer. She’ll be the crew’s health officer.</li>
<li>Christopher Sembroski, a data engineer for Lockheed Martin, also a former camp counselor at none other than Space Camp. The 42-year-old will be acting as mission specialist.</li>
</ul>
<p>The crew will be cruising to orbit inside a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule, which will launch from a Falcon 9 rocket. They’ll spend three days flying around the Earth before splashing down in the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Florida.</p>
<p>SpaceX’s YouTube channel is hosting a live launch webcast starting from 3:45 PM EST, with the five-hour launch window opening at <strong>8:02 PM EST</strong>. As of Sunday, Inspiration4 said weather conditions at Kennedy Space Center looked 70% favorable. There’s also a back-up launch window opening at the same time the following day.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/watch-spacex-launch-the-first-all-civilian-inspiration4-mission-to-space-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203038</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goldman says $2.2B purchase of BNPL provider GreenSky will help expand Marcus</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/goldman-greensky-bnpl/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/goldman-greensky-bnpl/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Lawler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 22:28:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The acquisition is positioned to bolster the firm's consumer business and offer new products and new ways to attract consumers to its Marcus by Goldman Sachs brand of finance products.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning, Goldman Sachs announced plans to acquire B2B2C lender <a href="https://www.greensky.com/">GreenSky</a> in a <a href="https://www.goldmansachs.com/media-relations/press-releases/2021/goldman-sachs-to-acquire-greensky.html">deal worth $2.24 billion</a>. The acquisition, which is still subject to regulatory approval and is expected to close in the fourth quarter of 2020 or the first quarter of 2021, is positioned to bolster the firm&#8217;s consumer business and offer new products and new ways to attract consumers to its <a href="https://www.marcus.com/">Marcus by Goldman Sachs</a> brand of finance products.</p>
<p>Goldman launched Marcus five years ago as a consumer-focused brand in part to compete with a growing set of fintech startups, neobanks, and online trading platforms that have sprung up over the last decade. While it has attracted 8 million users since launch &#8212; putting it ahead of many <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/ronshevlin/2021/02/01/challenger-bank-chime-hits-12-million-customer-mark/?sh=6a44317d23f5">so-called challenger banks</a> &#8212; Marcus still trails Chime and Robinhood among banking and trading apps (at least among number of users).</p>
<p>But with the purchase of GreenSky, it&#8217;s hoping to add another way to pull consumers into its Marcus funnel.</p>
<p>GreenSky operates a platform that facilitates loans for big-ticket items like <a href="https://www.greensky.com/home-improvement/">home improvement projects</a> or <a href="https://www.greensky.com/healthcare/">elective dental or medical procedures</a>. It enables brands like Home Depot, as well as medical and dental practices, to offer installment loans to customers at the point of sale, thereby increasing sales and conversions for its clients. GreenSky then sells off those loans to a number of banks and other lending partners.</p>
<p>The deal could be seen as a way for Goldman to buy its way into the &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; trend, offering Marcus users additional ways to finance their purchases. That market <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/11/2201091/">has taken off lately</a>, as evidenced by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/">Square&#8217;s acquisition of Afterpay</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/paypal-acquires-japans-paidy-for-2-7b-to-crack-the-buy-now-pay-later-market-in-asia/">PayPal&#8217;s acquisition of Paidy</a>, and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/27/business/amazon-affirm.html">Amazon striking a deal to offer BNPL financing through Affirm</a>.</p>
<p>But according to Stephanie Cohen, the global co-head of Consumer &amp; Wealth Management at Goldman Sachs, the acquisition is as much about bringing GreenSky&#8217;s customers into the Marcus ecosystem. She also believes that by bringing GreenSky into Goldman Sachs and lending off its balance sheet, there&#8217;s no limit to the scale at which it can grow.</p>
<p>That said, don&#8217;t expect Goldman or Marcus to begin offering BNPL lending for everyday shopping anytime soon, as Cohen says GreenSky is attractive in part due to the big-ticket nature of home improvement lending.</p>
<p>To learn more about the firm&#8217;s plans, we spoke with Cohen about the deal and asked how GreenSky fits in with Marcus and the rest of Goldman&#8217;s business. The full interview, slightly edited for length and clarity, is below.</p>
<p><strong><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/goldman-greensky-bnpl/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203278</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: SpaceX set to launch 4 civilians into orbit for 3-day mission</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/daily-crunch-63/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/daily-crunch-63/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 22:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203312</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for September 15, 2021. Today we have everything in the newsletter. Bad behavior in the crypto world? Yep. Why the Mailchimp deal might make good sense? You bet.</p>
<p>But before we get into the mix, a few TechCrunch notes. First, Jordan Crook’s regular series of streamed chats with investors and founders is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/check-out-the-amazing-speakers-joining-us-on-extra-cru-ahem-techcrunch-live/">now called TechCrunch Live</a>. And <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/chamath-palihapitiya-is-coming-to-disrupt/">Chamath Palihapitiya is coming to Disrupt</a>. Which is in less than a week!</p>
<p>Oh, and as you are reading this, SpaceX’s first “all-civilian crew” <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/watch-spacex-launch-the-first-all-civilian-inspiration4-mission-to-space-live/">may be taking off into space</a>. In case you wanted to tune in. &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1SiIXdT2W2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/chamath-palihapitiya-is-coming-to-disrupt/">Chamath Palihapitiya is coming to Disrupt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chamath Palihapitiya is coming to Disrupt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/chamath-palihapitiya-is-coming-to-disrupt/embed/#?secret=1SiIXdT2W2" data-secret="1SiIXdT2W2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Today in bad actors: </strong>Want to know if you are living in overheated times? Check for a rise in fraud and related bad behavior. And oh boy has there been news in the last day. Startup App Annie <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/app-annie-and-co-founder-charged-with-securities-fraud-will-pay-10m-settlement/">will pay $10 million in SEC fines for securities fraud</a>. Which is Not Good. And NFT marketplace OpenSea <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/opensea-admits-incident-as-top-exec-is-accused-of-trading-nfts-on-insider-information/">ate a buffet of crow earlier today</a> when it admitted that an executive at the concern was front-running NFT sales. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f611.png" alt="😑" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/intuits-12b-mailchimp-acquisition-is-about-expanding-its-small-business-focus/"><strong>Maybe the Intuit-Mailchimp deal is not dumb?</strong></a><strong> </strong>Sure, TechCrunch’s first reaction to the news that TurboTax parent company Intuit wants to spend $12 billion on Mailchimp was skeptical. But Ron Miller hit up a bunch of smart folks, and there was more positive sentiment to be recorded than we might have guessed.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/forges-spac-deal-is-a-bet-on-unicorn-illiquidity/"><strong>Tech companies are still going public:</strong></a><strong> </strong>We’re waiting for Toast and Freshworks and Warby Parker to get their debuts launched, but other companies aren’t waiting for a clear news cycle. Secondary share marketplace Forge is going public via a SPAC, so we <em>had</em> to take a look.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>First things first, more news from the BNPL beat. Yes, the method of paying for a transaction in installments is still making news. This time it’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/ascend-raises-5-5m-to-provide-a-bnpl-option-for-commercial-insurance/">Ascend raising $5.5 million to bring BNPL services to the commercial insurance world</a>. Recent liquidity in the fintech market <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/heres-what-your-bnpl-startup-could-be-worth/">could help drive fresh venture interest in coming quarters</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/sendcloud-nabs-177m-led-by-softbank-to-double-down-on-saas-shipping-as-a-service/">Sendcloud raises $177M for SaaS:</a> </strong>No, not <i data-stringify-type="italic">that </i>SaaS<i data-stringify-type="italic">.</i> <i data-stringify-type="italic">Shipping</i> as a service, in Sendcloud’s space. The Dutch startup now flush with SoftBank cash “has built a service [that provides] a cloud-based platform to easily organize and carry out shipping services by choosing from a wide range of carriers and other options.” It sounds <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/shippo-raises-45m-more-at-495m-valuation-as-ecommerce-booms/">a bit like a European Shippo</a></strong>?</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/rivians-first-production-r1t-electric-pickup-truck-rolls-off-the-line/"><strong>Rivian proves it’s not vaporware:</strong></a><strong> </strong>After raising dump trucks worth of capital, Rivian’s first <em>production</em> R1T electric pickup has rolled off the line. It’s a big moment for the company and sets Rivian apart from a host of other EV companies that hope to match its new milestone. Also apparently there is a color called Rivian Blue, and I am here for it.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/clubhouse-head-of-news/"><strong>Clubhouse hires head of news:</strong></a><strong> </strong>NPR vet Nina Gregory has taken on the role of Clubhouse’s head of News and Media Publishers, TechCrunch reports. Her role will be to work with both the social platform and news orgs. Perhaps her job would be a smidgen easier if Clubhouse backer a16z wasn’t so antagonistic toward the media. But, hey, the hire still makes good sense.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/news-aggregator-smartnews-raises-230-million-valuing-its-business-at-2-billion/">Speaking of news, SmartNews is now worth $2 billion:</a></strong> Sure, <em>media</em> is a trash business &#8212; mostly &#8212; but perhaps media aggregation is the golden ticket. Investors just put $230 million into news aggregator SmartNews, giving it a shiny new valuation. I have a soft spot for SmartNews as we partnered with them back in the Crunchbase News days, but past that, I am impressed and <em>curious</em> how it is going to generate the revenue needed to surpass its new price tag.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/airbase-adds-spend-support-for-international-subsidiaries/"><strong>Airbase further differentiates itself from Brex, Ramp:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The corporate spend wars are good fun because there are a number of startups in the space that are growing quickly, raising money and making deals. And they are increasingly carving up their market. Airbase just built some new capabilities that may help it attack larger customers than what some of its rivals appear to have their eyes on.</li>
<li><strong>Finally today, Inspired Capital</strong> has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/two-years-after-launching-inspired-capital-has-finished-raising-its-second-fund/">raised a second fund</a> just two years after its first.</li>
</ul>
<h2>5 things you need to win your first customer</h2>
<p>Congratulations on shipping your product, but how much do you know about your target customers?</p>
<p>Companies that haven&#8217;t created an ideal customer profile and performed a SWOT analysis are making big bets on guesswork and intuition. Sometimes that works out, but more frequently, it leads to tears.</p>
<p>In a guest post that walks readers through the fundamentals of creating customer personals that map to your company&#8217;s goals, Grammarly product marketing lead Bryan Dsouza shares five basic requirements for customer acquisition.</p>
<p>&#8220;Understanding and executing on these things can guarantee you that first customer win, provided you do them well and with sincerity,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Your investors will also see the fruits of your labor and be comforted knowing their dollars are at good work.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Fm8mojPU1S"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/5-things-you-need-to-win-your-first-customer/">5 things you need to win your first customer</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 things you need to win your first customer&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/5-things-you-need-to-win-your-first-customer/embed/#?secret=Fm8mojPU1S" data-secret="Fm8mojPU1S" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Want some government news? Yes, you do. Trust me. This stuff matters:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/europe-plans-a-chips-act-to-boost-semiconductor-sovereignty/"><strong>Semiconductor sovereignty is a phrase that you should get used to reading:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Back in the day, the ability for a nation to feed itself was pretty dang important. It’s less so today thanks to global trade. Taking its place in the Maslowian hierarchy of national needs is <em>semiconductor</em> The ability for a nation or bloc to make all the chips that it needs. Why? Because we’re in a global semiconductor crunch, and China is making waves &#8212; <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3145305/china-shows-military-might-exercises-taiwan-response">literally</a> &#8212; about Taiwan, where <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/16/2-charts-show-how-much-the-world-depends-on-taiwan-for-semiconductors.html">much of the world’s silicon is manufactured</a>. And Europe is looking to get its own processor hour in order.</li>
<li>Sticking to Europe, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/ireland-probes-tiktoks-handling-of-kids-data-and-transfers-to-china/"><strong>Ireland is looking into how TikTok handles data</strong></a>. Why? Because it has questions about data from children and about what sort of transfers might happen with China.</li>
<li>The founder and CEO of social media app Dispo, Daniel Liss, thinks that “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/the-fda-should-regulate-instagrams-algorithm-as-a-drug/"><strong>the FDA should regulate Instagram’s algorithm as a drug</strong></a>.”</li>
<li>Finally, in less controversial news, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/walmart-to-launch-autonomous-delivery-service-with-ford-and-argo-ai/"><strong>Walmart wants to work with Ford and Argo AI on autonomous deliveries</strong></a>. Which I am in favor of as it sounds like a way to get closer to self-driving cars.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2159841 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1500" height="942" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants to help startups find the right expert for their needs. To do this, we’re building a shortlist of the top growth marketers. We’ve received great recommendations for growth marketers in the startup industry since we launched our survey.</p>
<p>We’re excited to read more responses as they come in! <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>Our editorial coverage about growth marketing includes articles from the TechCrunch team, guest columns and posts like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/in-growth-marketing-signal-determines-success/">“In growth marketing, signal determines success”</a> by Jonathan Martinez.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mS5q08BM6q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/in-growth-marketing-signal-determines-success/">In growth marketing, signal determines success</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;In growth marketing, signal determines success&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/in-growth-marketing-signal-determines-success/embed/#?secret=mS5q08BM6q" data-secret="mS5q08BM6q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Community</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2202722" style="width: 204px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://www.basicbooks.com/titles/martin-ford/rule-of-the-robots/9781541674721/"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202722" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2202722 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ruleofrobots.jpg?w=194" alt="" width="194" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ruleofrobots.jpg 323w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ruleofrobots.jpg?resize=97,150 97w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ruleofrobots.jpg?resize=194,300 194w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ruleofrobots.jpg?resize=32,50 32w" sizes="(max-width: 194px) 100vw, 194px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2202722" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Basic Books</p></div></p>
<p>Join Danny Crichton, tomorrow Thursday, September 16, at 3 p.m. PDT/6 p.m. EDT on Twitter Spaces. Danny will be joined by Martin Ford, author of <a href="https://www.basicbooks.com/titles/martin-ford/rule-of-the-robots/9781541674721/">“Rule of the Robots: How Artificial Intelligence Will Transform Everything.”</a> Make sure you’re following the <a href="https://twitter.com/TechCrunch">TechCrunch</a> Twitter account to stay up to date with our news and events.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/daily-crunch-63/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203312</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The responsibilities of AI-first investors</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/the-responsibilities-of-ai-first-investors/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/the-responsibilities-of-ai-first-investors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 21:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial general intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybernetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NSO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palantir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202296</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How do investors ensure that the startups in which they invest responsibly apply AI?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Ash Fontana</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ashfontana">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Ash Fontana, a managing director at <a href="http://zettavp.com/">Zetta Ventures</a>, is the author of “The AI-First Company: How to Compete and Win with Artificial Intelligence.”	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/26/growing-up-in-the-intelligence-era/">Growing up in the intelligence era</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Investors in AI-first technology companies serving the defense industry, such as Palantir, Primer and Anduril, are doing well. Anduril, for one, reached a valuation of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/anduril-funding-series-d-valuation/">over $4 billion in less than four years</a>. Many other companies that build general-purpose, AI-first technologies — such as image labeling — receive large (undisclosed) portions of their revenue from the defense industry.</p>
<p>Investors in AI-first technology companies that aren’t even intended to serve the defense industry often find that these firms eventually (and sometimes inadvertently) help other powerful institutions, such as police forces, municipal agencies and media companies, prosecute their duties.</p>
<p>Most do a lot of good work, such as <a href="https://www.datarobot.com/covid/">DataRobot helping agencies understand</a> the spread of COVID, <a href="https://hash.ai/blog/vaccine-distribution-scenario-modeling">HASH running simulations</a> of vaccine distribution or <a href="https://lilt.com/press">Lilt</a> making school communications available to immigrant parents in a U.S. school district.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			The first step in taking responsibility is knowing what on earth is going on. It&#8217;s easy for startup investors to shrug off the need to know what’s going on inside AI-based models.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>However, there are also some less positive examples — technology made by Israeli cyber-intelligence firm NSO was <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/interactive/2021/nso-spyware-pegasus-cellphones/">used to hack 37 smartphones</a> belonging to journalists, human-rights activists, business executives and the fiancée of murdered Saudi journalist Jamal Khashoggi, according to a report by The Washington Post and 16 media partners. The report claims the phones were on a list of over 50,000 numbers based in countries that surveil their citizens and are known to have hired the services of the Israeli firm.</p>
<p>Investors in these companies may now be asked challenging questions by other founders, limited partners and governments about whether the technology is too powerful, enables too much or is applied too broadly. These are questions of degree, but are sometimes not even asked upon making an investment.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve had the privilege of talking to a lot of people with lots of perspectives — CEOs of big companies, founders of (currently!) small companies and politicians — since publishing <a href="http://theaifirstcompany.com">&#8220;The AI-First Company&#8221;</a> and investing in such firms for the better part of a decade. I&#8217;ve been getting one important question over and over again: How do investors ensure that the startups in which they invest responsibly apply AI?</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s be frank: It&#8217;s easy for startup investors to hand-wave away such an important question by saying something like, &#8220;It&#8217;s so hard to tell when we invest.” Startups are nascent forms of something to come. However, AI-first startups are working with something powerful from day one: Tools that allow leverage far beyond our physical, intellectual and temporal reach.</p>
<p>AI not only gives people the ability to put their hands around heavier objects (robots) or get their heads around more data (analytics), it also gives them the ability to bend their minds around time (predictions). When people can make predictions and learn as they play out, they can learn fast. When people can learn fast, they can act fast.</p>
<p>Like any tool, one can use these tools for good or for bad. You can use a rock to build a house or you can throw it at someone. You can use gunpowder for beautiful fireworks or firing bullets.</p>
<p>Substantially similar, AI-based computer vision models can be used to figure out the moves of a dance group or a terrorist group. AI-powered drones can aim a camera at us while going off ski jumps, but they can also aim a gun at us.</p>
<p>This article covers the basics, metrics and politics of responsibly investing in AI-first companies.</p>
<h2>The basics</h2>
<p>Investors in and board members of AI-first companies must take at least partial responsibility for the decisions of the companies in which they invest.</p>
<p>Investors influence founders, whether they intend to or not. Founders constantly ask investors about what products to build, which customers to approach and which deals to execute. They do this to learn and improve their chances of winning. They also do this, in part, to keep investors engaged and informed because they may be a valuable source of capital.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/the-responsibilities-of-ai-first-investors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202296</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inside Reach Capital&#8217;s edtech-powered returns</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/inside-reach-capitals-edtech-powered-returns/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/inside-reach-capitals-edtech-powered-returns/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 21:06:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reach Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reach Capital, a San Francisco-based venture firm co-founded by Jennifer Carolan and Shauntel Garvey, focused exclusively on edtech for years before the sector ballooned with unicorns. The rare, female-led partnership closed its third fund in February, a $165 million vehicle and its largest to date. That said, returns from its previous funds show that the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.reachcapital.com/">Reach Capital,</a> a San Francisco-based venture firm co-founded by <a href="https://twitter.com/jencarolan">Jennifer Carolan</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/SLP_EDU">Shauntel Garvey</a>, focused exclusively on edtech for years before the sector ballooned with unicorns. The rare, female-led partnership closed its third fund in February, a $165 million vehicle <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/reach-capital-fund-3/">and its largest to date.</a> That said, returns from its previous funds show that the early bet on a now-revitalized sector is paying off.</p>
<p>Reach Capital’s second fund, an $82 million vehicle closed in 2017, posted a net internal return rate of 72.1% as of Q2 2021, according to data intended for LPs and obtained by TechCrunch. The fund, which put investments into Paper, Winnie and now-unicorns Handshake and Outschool, ranks multiple percentage points above the top quartile of funds of that vintage. According to Cambridge Associates data, the top quartile of funds of that vintage had a net IRR of 47.64% the same quarter.</p>
<p>By comparison, Reach Capital’s first fund was multiple percentage points below the top quartile of fund performers of its vintage year, 2015.</p>
<p>It’s worth noting that Reach Capital’s returns for its second fund are mostly paper gains, meaning that the net IRR is based on an uptick in valuations. Given the fact that the firm is heavily concentrated in follow-on rounds, the IRR is thus a snapshot of a single moment of its performance in time. Reach recently had its first cash exit, seeing portfolio company <a href="https://ellevationeducation.com/news/ellevation-merges-curriculum-associates">Ellevation</a> merge with Curriculum Associates, but that is not represented in the data.</p>
<p>A number of blooming startups may explain what’s driving the improved performance between Reach I and Reach II. Per an impact report, Reach II invested $32 million into 14 core investments, including Newsela, Handshake and Outschool, all companies that have now gone to pass the billion-dollar valuation mark, making them unicorns. It also put money into Paper, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/paper-series-c-ivp/">recently landed a nine-figure round led by IVP</a>. By getting into those companies early, and then watching them get marked up as edtech booms as a category, Reach’s positions get validated.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4Azdp3jo5O"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/">Outschool is the newest edtech unicorn</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Outschool is the newest edtech unicorn&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/embed/#?secret=4Azdp3jo5O" data-secret="4Azdp3jo5O" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://reachcapital.com/impact/#/how-invest">The diversity of Reach II’s portfolio</a> beats industry averages, but the founders are still concentrated as white and male. About 74% of investments are founded by men, while 26% are founded by women, the report states. About 62% of founders identify as white, 20% identify as Asian, 14% identify as LatinX and 4% identify as Middle Eastern. There are no Black founders in Reach Capital II’s portfolio.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Reach’s impressive returns come at a time when venture more broadly is booming. A number of investors and founders spoke on background to offer context about whether the returns are impressive for a seed-stage fund of that vintage. One investment strategist said that, while it’s not unheard of in this environment, the return percentage is “crazy good.”</p>
<p>“Easily upper quartile and probably upper decile,” they said. “Unless we are talking crypto, in which case it&#8217;s pretty ordinary.” A separate seed-stage investor pointed to Fred Wilson’s recent blogpost &#8220;<a href="https://avc.com/2021/07/cash-on-cash-vs-irr/">Cash on Cash vs IRR</a>,&#8221; alluding to the idea that holding periods can skew fund performance data.</p>
<p>Still, Reach&#8217;s returns offer an impressive window into how one of the most diverse partnerships in venture capital is performing within one of the most revitalized sectors in startupland. The momentum isn&#8217;t going unnoticed. Filings show that Reach is raising money for a $50 million opportunity fund. The company has been on a hiring spree as of late, too, bringing on <a href="https://twitter.com/jomayra_herrera">Jomayra Herrera</a> from Cowboy Ventures as a partner and<a href="https://twitter.com/tonywan"> Tony Wan</a> from EdSurge as head of investor content.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="igGne1maZ9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/reach-capital-fund-3/">Goldman Sachs and Sesame Workshop pour money into this edtech firm&#8217;s newest fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Goldman Sachs and Sesame Workshop pour money into this edtech firm&#8217;s newest fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/reach-capital-fund-3/embed/#?secret=igGne1maZ9" data-secret="igGne1maZ9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/inside-reach-capitals-edtech-powered-returns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202682</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiger Global-led $100M investment makes Apna India&#8217;s fastest unicorn</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/tiger-global-led-100m-investment-makes-apna-indias-fastest-unicorn/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/tiger-global-led-100m-investment-makes-apna-indias-fastest-unicorn/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 20:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A 22-month-old startup that is helping millions of blue- and gray-collar workers in India learn new skills and find jobs has become the youngest firm to join the coveted unicorn status in the world’s second-largest internet market. Apna announced on Thursday that it has raised $100 million in a round led by Tiger Global. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A 22-month-old startup that is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/31/apple-alums-jobs-app-for-indias-workers-secures-8-million/">helping millions of blue- and gray-collar workers in India</a> learn new skills and find jobs has become the youngest firm to join the coveted unicorn status in the world’s second-largest internet market.</p>
<p><a href="http://apna.co/">Apna</a> announced on Thursday that it has raised $100 million in a round led by Tiger Global. The new round &#8212; a Series C &#8212; valued Apna at $1.1 billion. TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/tiger-global-in-talks-to-make-apna-indias-fastest-unicorn/">reported</a> last month that Tiger Global, an existing investor in Apna, was in talks to lead a $100 million financing round in the startup at the unicorn valuation.</p>
<p>Owl Ventures, Insight Partners, Sequoia Capital India, Maverick Ventures and GSV Ventures also participated in the new round, which is the third investment secured by Apna this year. Apna was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/tiger-global-in-talks-to-make-apna-indias-fastest-unicorn/">valued at $570 million</a> in its Series B round in June this year.</p>
<p>The investors’ excitement comes as Apna has demonstrated an impressive growth in recent months. The startup has amassed over 16 million users on its 15-month-old eponymous Android app, up from 10 million in June this year.</p>
<p>Indian cities are home to hundreds of millions of low-skilled workers who hail from villages in search of work. Many of them have lost their jobs amid the coronavirus pandemic that has slowed several economic activities in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>Apna has built a platform that provides a community to these workers. In the community, they engage with each other, exchange notes to perform better at interviews and share tips to negotiate better compensation.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203355" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203355" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2203355 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apna-app.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="560" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apna-app.jpg 800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apna-app.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apna-app.jpg?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apna-app.jpg?resize=768,538 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apna-app.jpg?resize=680,476 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apna-app.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203355" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apna</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>On top of this, Apna connects these workers to potential employers. In an interview with TechCrunch, Apna founder and chief executive Nirmit Parikh said more than 150,000 employers &#8212; including Zomato, Bharti AXA, Urban Company, BYJU’S, PhonePe, Burger King, Delhivery, Teamlease and G4S Global &#8212; are on the platform, and over 5 million jobs are active.</p>
<p>The startup, whose name is inspired from a cheerful 2019 Bollywood song, has facilitated over 18 million job interviews in the past 30 days, he said. Apna is currently operational in 28 Indian cities.</p>
<p>The idea for Apna came, Parikh has said, after he was puzzled to find that even as there are hundreds of millions of blue- and gray-collar workers in India, locating them when you need assistance with a task often proves very difficult.</p>
<p>Prior to starting Apna, Parikh, who previously worked at Apple, met these workers and went undercover as an electrician and floor manager to understand the problems they were facing. The problem, he found, was the disconnect. Workers had no means to find who needed them for jobs, and they were also not connected with one another. The community aspect of Apna, which now has over 70 such groups, is aimed at addressing this challenge.</p>
<p>The Apna app allows these workers to learn new skills to become eligible for more work opportunities. Apna has emerged as one of the fastest growing upskilling platforms &#8212; and that would explain why GSV Ventures and Owl Ventures, two high-profile firms known to back edtech startups, are investing in the Bangalore-based firm.</p>
<p>“Apna’s viral adoption is driven by a novel social and interactive approach to connecting employers with job seekers. We expect job seekers in search of meaningful connections and vetted opportunities to drive Apna’s continued explosive growth across India &#8212; and the world,&#8221; said Griffin Schroeder, partner at Tiger Global, in a statement.</p>
<p>Now the startup, which has started to monetize the platform, is ready to aggressively expand. Parikh said Apna will continue to expand to more cities in India and by early next year, Apna will begin its global expansion. Parikh said the startup is eyeing expansion in the USA, South East Asia and Middle East and Africa.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have already created a dent. Now we want to impact the lives of 2.3 billion,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We will require crazy amounts of resources and a world-class team to deliver. It&#8217;s a herculean task, and is going to take a village. But somebody has to solve it.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mtxgzXFh0V"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/11/tiger-global-goes-super-aggressive-in-india/">Tiger Global goes super aggressive in India</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tiger Global goes super aggressive in India&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/11/tiger-global-goes-super-aggressive-in-india/embed/#?secret=mtxgzXFh0V" data-secret="mtxgzXFh0V" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/tiger-global-led-100m-investment-makes-apna-indias-fastest-unicorn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 things you need to win your first customer</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/5-things-you-need-to-win-your-first-customer/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/5-things-you-need-to-win-your-first-customer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 18:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[market research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ask any founder what really proves their startup has taken off, and they will almost instantly say it’s when they win their first customer. That’s easier said than done, though.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Bryan Dsouza</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bbbryannn/">Bryan Dsouza</a> leads product marketing at Grammarly, and previously led various product management and product marketing roles across B2C and B2B at Microsoft.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">A startup is a beautiful thing. It’s the tangible outcome of an idea birthed in a garage or on the back of a napkin. But ask any founder what really proves their startup has taken off, and they will almost instantly say it’s when they win their first customer.</p>
<p>That’s easier said than done, though, because winning that first customer will take a lot more than an Ivy-educated founder and/or a celebrity investor pool.</p>
<p>To begin with, you’ll have to craft a strong ideal customer profile to know your customer’s pain points, while developing a competitive SWOT analysis to scope out alternatives your customers can go to.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Your target customer will pick a solution that will help them achieve their goals. In other words, your goals should align with your customer’s goals.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>You’ll also need to create a shortlist of influencers who have your customer’s trust, identify their decision-makers who make the call to buy (or not), and create a mapped list of goals that align your customer’s goals to yours.</p>
<p>Understanding and executing on these things can guarantee you that first customer win, provided you do them well and with sincerity. Your investors will also see the fruits of your labor and be comforted knowing their dollars are at good work.</p>
<p>Let’s see how:</p>
<h2>1. Craft the ideal customer profile (ICP)</h2>
<p>The ICP is a great framework for figuring out who your target customer is, how big they are, where they operate, and why they exist. As you write up your ICP, you will soon see the pain points you assumed about them start to become more real.</p>
<p>To create an ICP, you will need to have a strong articulation of the problem you are trying to solve and the customers that experience this problem the most. This will be your baseline hypothesis. Then, as you develop your ICP, keep testing your baseline hypothesis to weed out inaccurate assumptions.</p>
<p>Getting crystal clear here will set you up with the proper launchpad. No shortcuts.</p>
<h3>Here’s how to get started:</h3>
<ol>
<li>Develop an <a href="https://about.crunchbase.com/blog/what-is-an-ideal-customer-profile-and-how-do-you-create-one/">ICP (Ideal Customer Profile)</a> framework.</li>
<li>Identify three target customers that fit your defined ICP.</li>
<li>Write a problem statement for each identified target customer.</li>
<li>Prioritize the problem statement that resonates with your product the most.</li>
<li>Lock on the target customer of the prioritized problem statement.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Practice use case:</h3>
<p>You are the co-founder at an upcoming SaaS startup focused on simplifying the shopping experience in car showrooms so buyers enjoy the process. What would your ICP look like?</p>
<h2>2. Develop the SWOT</h2>
<p>The SWOT framework cannot be overrated. This is a great structure to articulate who your competitors are and how you show up against them. Note that your competitors can be direct or indirect (as an alternative), and it’s important to categorize these buckets correctly.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/5-things-you-need-to-win-your-first-customer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203184</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In growth marketing, signal determines success</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/in-growth-marketing-signal-determines-success/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/in-growth-marketing-signal-determines-success/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 18:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[targeted advertising]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So what exactly is “signal” in growth marketing? It can carry many different meanings, but holistically speaking, it’s the event data in our arsenal to help guide decisions. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jonathan Martinez</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/onjonon">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="http://www.jmstrategy.com/">Jonathan Martinez</a> is a former YouTuber, UC Berkeley alum and growth marketing nerd who's helped scale Uber, Postmates, Chime and various startups.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/early-stage-brands-should-also-unlock-the-power-of-influencers/">Early-stage brands should also unlock the power of influencers</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/in-growth-marketing-creative-is-the-critical-x-factor/">In growth marketing, creative is the critical X factor</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Unlike a weak phone signal solely causing a grainy sound, in growth marketing, it can mean the difference between a successful program or a massive cash bleed. As we move toward an increasingly privacy-centric world, it is even more necessary for companies to nail down signal early on.</p>
<p>So what exactly is “signal” in growth marketing? It can carry many different meanings, but holistically speaking, it’s the event data in our arsenal to help guide decisions. When it comes to paid acquisition, it’s vital to optimize and pass back the correct event data to paid channels. This is so that targeting and bidding algorithms have the most enriched data to utilize.</p>
<p>I’ve seen startups spend thousands of dollars inefficiently as a result of not having optimal signal in their paid acquisition campaigns. I’ve also spent millions at companies such as Postmates refining our signal to the best possible state. I’d like every startup to avoid the painful mistake of not having this set up correctly, instead making the most of every important ad dollar.</p>
<h2>The selection</h2>
<p>When starting out, it may seem obvious to optimize toward a north-star metric such as a purchase. If spend is very minimal, that could mean that the conversion volume will be low across campaigns. On the flip side, if the optimization event is set at a top-of-funnel event such as a landing page view, the signal strength may be very weak. The reason that the strength may be weak is due to passing back a low-intent event as successful to the paid channels. By marking a landing page view as successful, paid channels such as Facebook will continue to find users that are similar to these lower-propensity users that are converting.</p>
<p>Let’s take an example of a health-and-wellness app with a goal of driving memberships to their coaching program. They’re just starting out with exploring paid acquisition and spending $5,000 per week on Facebook. Below is a look at their events in the funnel, weekly volume and cost per event:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202596" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202596" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2202596 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM-1.png 1154w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM-1.png?resize=150,59 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM-1.png?resize=300,118 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM-1.png?resize=768,301 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM-1.png?resize=680,266 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM-1.png?resize=50,20 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202596" class="wp-caption-text">Example of a health-and-wellness app and their weekly conversion volume at $5,000 spend. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Jonathan Martinez</p></div></p>
<p>In the above example, we can see that there’s significant volume for landing page views. As we go down the <em>simplified</em> flow, there is less volume as users drop off the funnel. Almost everyone’s instinct would be to optimize for either the landing page view, because there’s so much data, or the subscription event, because it’s the strongest. I would argue (after extensive testing across multiple ad accounts) that neither of these events would be the correct pick. With landing page views as an optimization event, the users have an egregiously low propensity since the landing page view to subscription conversion rate is 0.61%.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The correct event to optimize for here would either be sign up or trial start because they have sufficient enough volume and are strong signals of a user converting to the north-star metric (subscription). Looking at the conversion rate between sign up and subscription, it’s a much healthier 10.21%, versus the 0.61% from landing page view.</p>
<p>I’m always a huge proponent of testing all events, as there can definitely be big surprises in what may work best for you. When testing events, make sure that there’s a stat-sig baseline that’s being followed to make decisions. Additionally, I think it’s a great practice to test events regularly early on because conversion rates can change as other channel variables are adjusted.</p>
<h2>Flow adjustments</h2>
<p>In certain cases, the current events that are set up aren’t optimal for paid acquisition campaigns. I’ve seen this happen frequently with startups that have long windows of time between conversion events. Take a startup such as Thumbtack, which provides a marketplace of providers who can help with home repairs. After someone signs up to their app, the user may place a request but not hire someone until a few weeks later. In this case, making flow adjustments could potentially improve the signal and data that you collect from users.</p>
<p>A solution that Thumbtack could implement to gather a stronger signal would be to add another step between the request being placed and hiring someone. This could potentially be a survey with propensity check questions that could ask how soon the user needs help or how important their project is from a 1–10.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202600" style="width: 892px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202600" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2202600" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM2.png" alt="" width="882" height="564" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM2.png 882w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM2.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM2.png?resize=300,192 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM2.png?resize=768,491 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM2.png?resize=680,435 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/JM2.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 882px) 100vw, 882px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202600" class="wp-caption-text">Example of in-app survey responses to “How important is your project?” <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Jonathan Martinez.</p></div></p>
<p>After accumulating the data, if there’s a high correlation between survey answers and someone starting their project, we can start to explore optimizing for that event.</p>
<p>In the above example, we see that users who responded with “9” have a 7.66% likelihood to convert. Therefore, this should be the event we optimize for. Artificially adding steps that qualify users in a longer flow can help steer optimization targeting in the right direction.</p>
<h2>Enhancing signal</h2>
<p>Let’s imagine that you have the most ideal flow that captures large volumes of event signal without much of a delay to your optimization event. That’s still far from perfect. There are myriad solutions that can be implemented to further enhance the signal.</p>
<p>For Facebook specifically, there are connections such as<a href="https://developers.facebook.com/videos/2020/conversion-api-capi-overview/"> CAPI</a> that can be integrated to pass back data in a more accurate way. CAPI is a method of passing back web events server-to-server rather than relying on cookies and the Facebook pixel. This helps mitigate browsers that block cookies or users who may delete their web history. This is just one example. I won’t run through all the channels, but each has its own solution to help enhance event signal being passed back to it.</p>
<h2>iOS 14 signal</h2>
<p>This wouldn’t be a column written in 2021 without mention of iOS 14 and the strategies that can be leveraged for this growing user segment. I’ve written another <a href="https://jmstrategy.substack.com/p/impactful-strategies-amid-ios14">piece</a> about iOS-14-specific tactics, but I’ll cover it here on a broad level. If the north-star metric (i.e., purchase) event can be triggered within 24 hours of the initial app launch, then that’s golden.</p>
<p>This would bring large volumes of high-intent data that would not be at the mercy of the SKAD 24-hour event timer. For most companies, this may sound like a lofty goal, so the target should be to have an event fire within 24 hours that is a high-likelihood indicator of someone completing your north-star metric. Think of which events happen in the flow that lead to someone eventually purchasing. Maybe someone adding a payment method happens within 24 hours and historically has a 90% conversion rate to someone purchasing. An “add payment info” event would be a great conversion event to use in this case. The landscape of iOS 14 is constantly changing but this should apply for the immediate future.</p>
<h2>Incrementality and staying ahead</h2>
<p>As a rule of thumb, incrementality checks should constantly be performed in growth marketing. It gives an important read on whether advertising dollars are bringing in users that wouldn’t have converted had they not seen an ad.</p>
<p>When comparing optimization events, this rule still applies. Make sure that costs per action aren’t the only metric that’s being used as a measure of success, but instead, use the incremental lift on each conversion event as the ultimate key performance indicator. <a href="https://jmstrategy.substack.com/p/easy-incrementality-testing">In this piece,</a> I detail how to run lean incrementality tests without swarms of data scientists.</p>
<p>So how do you stay ahead and continue moving the needle on your growth marketing campaigns? First and foremost, constantly question the events you’re optimizing for. And second, leave no stone unturned.</p>
<p>If you’re using the same optimization event forever, it will be a disservice to your campaign performance potential. By experimenting with flow changes and running tests on new events, you’ll be way ahead of the curve. When iterating on the flow, think about user behavior and events from the user’s perspective. Which flow events, if added, would correlate to a high propensity conversion segment?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/in-growth-marketing-signal-determines-success/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202493</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clubhouse hires a head of news from NPR to build out publisher relationships</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/clubhouse-head-of-news/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/clubhouse-head-of-news/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 18:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadcasting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa today]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Clubhouse has hired a veteran editor from NPR to lead news publishing for the app. Nina Gregory will serve as Clubhouse&#8217;s head of News and Media Publishers, working as a liaison between news publishers and the Clubhouse&#8217;s ecosystem of audio-based communities. Gregory led NPR&#8217;s Arts Desk for the last seven years, shaping the news outlet&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Clubhouse has hired a veteran editor from NPR to lead news publishing for the app. Nina Gregory will serve as Clubhouse&#8217;s head of News and Media Publishers, working as a liaison between news publishers and the Clubhouse&#8217;s ecosystem of audio-based communities.</p>
<p>Gregory led NPR&#8217;s Arts Desk for the last seven years, shaping the news outlet&#8217;s culture and entertainment coverage. &#8220;As an audio journalist, [Clubhouse] aligned with what I&#8217;ve always believed is the best medium for news,&#8221; <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/09/15/media/clubhouse-head-of-news/index.html">Gregory told CNN</a>. &#8220;You don&#8217;t need to know how to read to be able to hear radio news. You don&#8217;t need to have an expensive subscription. You don&#8217;t need cable.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I’ve got some news… <a href="https://t.co/Q2wAqBb22y">https://t.co/Q2wAqBb22y</a></p>
<p>&mdash; nina gregory (@ninaberries) <a href="https://twitter.com/ninaberries/status/1438157192675221505?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 15, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Helping publishers and other brands get plugged in is one path toward maturation for Clubhouse. Online media properties from USA Today to TechCrunch have built a presence on the app, which exploded in growth as the pandemic limited in-person social interactions. But with competition from more entrenched competitors looming, Clubhouse may need to get creative to stay in the game.</p>
<p>Clubhouse&#8217;s quick ascent saw Twitter, Spotify, Facebook and other established tech companies scramble to integrate live audio rooms into their own products. Twitter quickly launched <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/twitter-spaces/">Spaces</a>, while Spotify launched a standalone Clubhouse clone known as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/spotifys-clubhouse-rival-greenroom-tops-140k-installs-on-ios-100k-on-android/">Greenroom</a>. Facebook first announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebook-officially-launches-live-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-in-the-u-s/">its own live audio rooms</a> in April, opening them to U.S. users two months later.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6WRiTW4HgI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebook-officially-launches-live-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-in-the-u-s/">Facebook officially launches Live Audio Rooms and podcasts in the US</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook officially launches Live Audio Rooms and podcasts in the US&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebook-officially-launches-live-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-in-the-u-s/embed/#?secret=6WRiTW4HgI" data-secret="6WRiTW4HgI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The kind of viral attention that Clubhouse enjoyed over the last year is almost impossible to maintain, but the company has added features, introduced an Android app and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/clubhouse-invite-open-to-everyone-exits-beta/">opened its doors to everyone</a>. Clubhouse might not be able to top its February peak, but the app still notched 7.7 million global monthly downloads after expanding to Android this summer, and continues to build out its vision for audio-first social networking.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Mb4If1EgzQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/29/clubhouse-spatial-audio/">Clubhouse is adding spatial audio effects to make users feel like they&#8217;re really in the room</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clubhouse is adding spatial audio effects to make users feel like they&#8217;re really in the room&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/29/clubhouse-spatial-audio/embed/#?secret=Mb4If1EgzQ" data-secret="Mb4If1EgzQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1WumnAYDr0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/clubhouse-invite-open-to-everyone-exits-beta/">Clubhouse is now out of beta and open to everyone</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clubhouse is now out of beta and open to everyone&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/clubhouse-invite-open-to-everyone-exits-beta/embed/#?secret=1WumnAYDr0" data-secret="1WumnAYDr0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/clubhouse-head-of-news/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203229</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The FDA should regulate Instagram’s algorithm as a drug</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/the-fda-should-regulate-instagrams-algorithm-as-a-drug/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/the-fda-should-regulate-instagrams-algorithm-as-a-drug/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 18:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food and Drug Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Section 230]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sheryl Sandberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the wall street journal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram’s unwillingness to do what is right is a clarion call for regulation: The FDA must assert its codified right to regulate the algorithm powering the drug of Instagram. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Daniel Liss</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Dlisscious">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Daniel Liss is the founder and CEO of <a href="https://dispo.fun/">Dispo</a>, the digital disposable camera social network.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/29/move-fast-and-break-facebook-a-bull-case-for-antitrust-enforcement/">Move fast and break Facebook: A bull case for antitrust enforcement</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/todays-real-story-the-facebook-monopoly/">Today&#8217;s real story: The Facebook monopoly</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The Wall Street Journal on Tuesday <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-knows-instagram-is-toxic-for-teen-girls-company-documents-show-11631620739">reported</a> Silicon Valley’s worst-kept secret: Instagram harms teens’ mental health; in fact, its impact is so negative that it introduces suicidal thoughts.</p>
<p>Thirty-two percent of teen girls who feel bad about their bodies report that Instagram makes them feel worse. Of teens with suicidal thoughts, 13% of British and 6% of American users trace those thoughts to Instagram, the WSJ report said. This is Facebook’s internal data. The truth is surely worse.</p>
<p>President Theodore Roosevelt and Congress <a href=" https://www.fda.gov/about-fda/fda-basics/when-and-why-was-fda-formed">formed</a> the Food and Drug Administration in 1906 precisely because Big Food and Big Pharma failed to protect the general welfare. As its executives <a href="https://www.justjared.com/2021/09/13/instagram-head-adam-mosseri-wife-monica-sport-geometric-outfits-for-met-gala-2021/">parade</a> at the Met Gala in celebration of the unattainable 0.01% of lifestyles and bodies that we mere mortals will never achieve, Instagram’s unwillingness to do what is right is a clarion call for regulation: The FDA must assert its codified right to regulate the algorithm powering the drug of Instagram.</p>
<p>The FDA should consider algorithms a drug impacting our nation’s mental health: The Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act <a href="https://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title21-section321&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim">gives</a> the FDA the right to regulate drugs, defining drugs in part as “articles (other than food) intended to affect the structure or any function of the body of man or other animals.” Instagram’s internal data shows its technology is an article that alters our brains. If this effort fails, Congress and President Joe Biden should create a mental health FDA.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Researchers can study what Facebook prioritizes and the impact those decisions have on our minds. How do we know this? Because Facebook is already doing it — they&#8217;re just burying the results.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The public needs to understand what Facebook and Instagram’s algorithms prioritize. Our government is equipped to study clinical trials of products that can physically harm the public. Researchers can study what Facebook privileges and the impact those decisions have on our minds. How do we know this? Because Facebook is already doing it — they&#8217;re just burying the results.</p>
<p>In November 2020, as Cecilia Kang and Sheera Frenkel report in “<a href="https://www.harpercollins.com/pages/anuglytruth">An Ugly Truth</a>,” Facebook made an emergency change to its News Feed, putting more emphasis on “News Ecosystem Quality” scores (NEQs). High NEQ sources were trustworthy sources; low were untrustworthy. Facebook altered the algorithm to privilege high NEQ scores. As a result, for five days around the election, users saw a “nicer News Feed” with less fake news and fewer conspiracy theories. But Mark Zuckerberg reversed this change because it led to less engagement and could cause a conservative backlash. The public suffered for it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Facebook likewise has studied what happens when the algorithm privileges content that is “good for the world” over content that is “bad for the world.” Lo and behold, engagement decreases. Facebook knows that its algorithm has a remarkable impact on the minds of the American public. How can the government let one man decide the standard based on his business imperatives, not the general welfare?</p>
<p>Upton Sinclair memorably uncovered dangerous abuses in “The Jungle,” which led to a public outcry. The free market failed. Consumers needed protection. The 1906 Pure Food and Drug Act for the first time promulgated safety standards, regulating consumable goods impacting our physical health. Today, we need to regulate the algorithms that impact our mental health. Teen depression has risen <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2019/07/12/a-growing-number-of-american-teenagers-particularly-girls-are-facing-depression/">alarmingly</a> since 2007. Likewise, suicide among those 10 to 24 is up nearly 60% between 2007 and 2018.</p>
<p>It is of course impossible to prove that social media is solely responsible for this increase, but it is absurd to argue it has not contributed. Filter bubbles distort our views and make them more extreme. Bullying online is easier and constant. Regulators must audit the algorithm and question Facebook’s choices.</p>
<p>When it comes to the biggest issue Facebook poses — what the product <em>does to us —</em> regulators have struggled to articulate the problem. Section 230 is correct in its intent and application; the internet cannot function if platforms are liable for every user utterance. And a private company like Facebook loses the trust of its community if it applies arbitrary rules that target users based on their background or political beliefs. Facebook as a company has no explicit duty to uphold the First Amendment, but public perception of its fairness is essential to the brand.</p>
<p>Thus, Zuckerberg has equivocated over the years before belatedly banning Holocaust deniers, Donald Trump, anti-vaccine activists and other bad actors. Deciding what speech is privileged or allowed on its platform, Facebook will always be too slow to react, overcautious and ineffective. Zuckerberg cares only for engagement and growth. Our hearts and minds are caught in the balance.</p>
<p>The most frightening part of “The Ugly Truth,” the passage that got everyone in Silicon Valley talking, was the eponymous memo: Andrew “Boz” Bosworth’s 2016 “The Ugly.”</p>
<p>In the memo, Bosworth, Zuckerberg’s longtime deputy, writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>So we connect more people. That can be bad if they make it negative. Maybe it costs someone a life by exposing someone to bullies. Maybe someone dies in a terrorist attack coordinated on our tools. And still we connect people. The ugly truth is that we believe in connecting people so deeply that anything that allows us to connect more people more often is <em>de facto</em> good.</p></blockquote>
<p>Zuckerberg and Sheryl Sandberg made Bosworth walk back his statements when employees objected, but to outsiders, the memo represents the unvarnished id of Facebook, the ugly truth. Facebook’s monopoly, its stranglehold on our social and political fabric, its growth at all costs mantra of “connection,” is not de facto good. As Bosworth acknowledges, Facebook causes suicides and allows terrorists to organize. This much power concentrated in the hands of one corporation, run by one man, is a threat to our democracy and way of life.</p>
<p>Critics of FDA regulation of social media will claim this is a Big Brother invasion of our personal liberties. But what is the alternative? Why would it be bad for our government to demand that Facebook accounts to the public its internal calculations? Is it safe for the number of sessions, time spent and revenue growth to be the only results that matters? What about the collective mental health of the country and world?</p>
<p>Refusing to study the problem does not mean it does not exist. In the absence of action, we are left with a single man deciding what is right. What is the price we pay for “connection”? This is not up to Zuckerberg. The FDA should decide.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/the-fda-should-regulate-instagrams-algorithm-as-a-drug/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203117</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beware the hidden bias behind TikTok resumes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/beware-the-hidden-bias-behind-tiktok-resumes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/beware-the-hidden-bias-behind-tiktok-resumes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 17:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glassdoor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resume]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hiring processes need to be about letting people put their best foot forward, whether that is in writing or on video.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Nagaraj Nadendla</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/nagarajnadendla">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Nagaraj Nadendla is SVP of development at <a href="https://www.oracle.com/human-capital-management/">Oracle Cloud HCM</a>, where he leads the development of cloud recruitment solutions including Oracle Recruiting and Taleo. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Social media has served as a launchpad to success almost as long as it has been around. The stories of going viral from a self-produced YouTube video and then securing a record deal established the mythology of social media platforms. Ever since, social media has consistently gravitated away from text-based formats and toward visual mediums like video sharing.</p>
<p>For most people, a video on social media won’t be a ticket to stardom, but in recent months, there have been a growing <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/19/technology/tiktok-resumes-jobs.html">number of stories</a> of people getting hired based on videos posted to TikTok. Even LinkedIn has embraced video assets on user profiles with the recent addition of the “<a href="https://blog.linkedin.com/2021/march/30/-bring-your-professional-story-to-life-on-linkedin">Cover Story</a>” feature, which allows workers to supplement their profiles with a video about themselves.</p>
<p>As technology continues to evolve, is there room for a world where your primary resume is a video on TikTok? And if so, what kinds of unintended consequences and implications might this have on the workforce?</p>
<h2>Why is TikTok trending for jobs?</h2>
<p>In recent months, U.S. job openings have risen to an all-time high of <a href="https://apnews.com/article/business-health-coronavirus-pandemic-4c614d89c69b4afd3504a4d92dd574f9">10.1 million</a>. For the first time since the pandemic began, available jobs have exceeded available workers. Employers are struggling to attract qualified candidates to fill positions, and in that light, it makes sense that many recruiters are turning to social platforms like TikTok and video resumes to find talent.</p>
<p>But the scarcity of workers does not negate the importance of finding the right employee for a role. Especially important for recruiters is finding candidates with the skills that align with their business’ goals and strategy. For example, as more organizations embrace a data-driven approach to operating their business, they need more people with skills in analytics and machine learning to help them make sense of the data they collect.</p>
<p>Recruiters have proven to be open to innovation where it helps them find these new candidates. Recruiting is no longer the manual process it used to be, with HR teams sorting through stacks of paper resumes and formal cover letters to find the right candidate. They embraced the power of online connections as LinkedIn rose to prominence and even figured out how to use third-party job sites like GlassDoor to help them draw in promising candidates. On the back end, many recruiters use advanced cloud software to sort through incoming resumes to find the candidates that best match their job descriptions. But all of these methods still rely on the traditional text-based resume or profile as the core of any application.</p>
<p>Videos on social media provide the ability for candidates to demonstrate soft skills that may not be immediately apparent in written documents, such as verbal communication and presentation skills. They are also a way for recruiters to learn more about the personality of the candidate to determine how they’d fit into the culture of the company. While this may be appealing for many, are we ready for the consequences?</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>We’re not ready for the close-up</h2>
<p>While innovation in recruiting is a big part of the future of work, the hype around TikTok and video resumes may actually take us backward. Despite offering a new way for candidates to market themselves for opportunities, it also carries potential pitfalls that candidates, recruiters and business leaders need to be aware of.</p>
<p>The very element that gives video resumes their potential also presents the biggest problems. Video inescapably highlights the person behind the skills and achievements. As recruiters form their first opinions about a candidate, they will be confronted with information they do not usually see until much later in the process, including whether they belong to protected classes because of their race, disability or gender.</p>
<p>Diversity, equity and inclusion (DE&amp;I) concerns have had a major surge in attention over the last couple of years amid heightened awareness and scrutiny around how employers are &#8212; or are not &#8212; prioritizing diversity in the workplace.</p>
<p>But evaluating candidates through video could erase any progress made by introducing more opportunities for unconscious, or even conscious, bias. This could create a dangerous situation for businesses if they do not act carefully because it could open them up to consequences such as damage to their reputation or even something as severe as discrimination lawsuits.</p>
<p>A company with a poor track record for diversity may have the fact that they reviewed videos from candidates used against them in court. Recruiters reviewing the videos may not even be aware of how the race or gender of candidates are impacting their decisions. For that reason, many of the businesses I have seen implement an option for video in their recruiting flow do not allow their recruiters to watch the video until late in the recruiting process.</p>
<p>But even if businesses address the most pressing issues of DE&amp;I by managing bias against those protected classes, by accepting videos there are still issues of diversity in less protected classes such as neurodiversity and socioeconomic status. A candidate with exemplary skills and a strong track record may not present themselves well through a video, coming across as awkward to the recruiter watching the video. Even if that impression is irrelevant to the job, it could still influence the recruiter’s stance on hiring.</p>
<p>Furthermore, candidates from affluent backgrounds may have access to better equipment and software to record and edit a compelling video resume. Other candidates may not, resulting in videos that may not look as polished or professional in the eyes of the recruiter. This creates yet another barrier to the opportunities they can access.</p>
<p>As we sit at an important crossroads in how we handle DE&amp;I in the workplace, it is important for employers and recruiters to find ways to reduce bias in the processes they use to find and hire employees. While innovation is key to moving our industry forward, we have to ensure top priorities are not being compromised.</p>
<h2>Not left on the cutting room floor</h2>
<p>Despite all of these concerns, social media platforms &#8212; especially those based on video &#8212; have created new opportunities for users to expand their personal brands and connect with potential job opportunities. There is potential to use these new systems to benefit both job seekers and employers.</p>
<p>The first step is to ensure that there is always a place for a traditional text-based resume or profile in the recruiting process. Even if recruiters can get all the information they need about a candidate’s capabilities from video, some people will just naturally feel more comfortable staying off camera. Hiring processes need to be about letting people put their best foot forward, whether that is in writing or on video. And that includes accepting that the best foot to put forward may not be your own.</p>
<p>Instead, candidates and businesses should consider using videos as a place for past co-workers or managers to endorse the candidate. An outside endorsement can do a lot more good for an application than simply stating your own strengths because it shows that someone else believes in your capabilities, too.</p>
<p>Video resumes are hot right now because they are easier to make and share than ever and because businesses are in desperate need of strong talent. But before we get caught up in the novelty of this new way of sharing our credentials, we need to make sure that we are setting ourselves up for success.</p>
<p>The goal of any new recruiting technology should be to make it easier for candidates to find opportunities where they can shine without creating new barriers. There are some serious kinks to work out before video resumes can achieve that, and it is important for employers to consider the repercussions before they damage the success of their DE&amp;I efforts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/beware-the-hidden-bias-behind-tiktok-resumes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201423</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenSea admits incident as top exec is accused of trading NFTs on insider information</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/opensea-admits-incident-as-top-exec-is-accused-of-trading-nfts-on-insider-information/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/opensea-admits-incident-as-top-exec-is-accused-of-trading-nfts-on-insider-information/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 17:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distributed computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenSea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The &#8220;eBay of NFTs&#8221; is running into a scandal as it admits one of its employees traded the crypto digital assets using insider information from the platform. Yesterday, a top executive at NFT platform OpenSea was accused of front-running sales on the platform, purchasing pieces from NFT collections before they were featured on the homepage [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The &#8220;eBay of NFTs&#8221; is running into a scandal as it admits one of its employees traded the crypto digital assets using insider information from the platform.</p>
<p>Yesterday, a top executive at NFT platform OpenSea was accused of front-running sales on the platform, purchasing pieces from NFT collections before they were featured on the homepage of the platform. According to Twitter user <a href="https://twitter.com/ZuwuTV">@ZuwuTV,</a> the startup&#8217;s Head of Product was using secret crypto wallets to buy drops before they listed on the main page of OpenSea, selling them shortly after they were highlighted publicly by OpenSea, and funneling the profits back to his main account. Users linked to a handful of transactions from accounts linked back to the executive on the public blockchain including an NFT drop that was, at the time, actively listed on the front page of the platform.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Hey <a href="https://twitter.com/opensea?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@opensea</a> why does it appear <a href="https://twitter.com/natechastain?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@natechastain</a> has a few secret wallets that appears to buy your front page drops before they are listed, then sells them shortly after the front-page-hype spike for profits, and then tumbles them back to his main wallet with his punk on it?</p>
<p>&mdash; Zuwu<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f7e9.png" alt="🟩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f47b.png" alt="👻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f383.png" alt="🎃" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f987.png" alt="🦇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@ZuwuTV) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZuwuTV/status/1437921263394115584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 14, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Today, OpenSea seemed to acknowledge the incident, <a href="https://opensea.io/blog/announcements/employee-information-use-at-opensea/">saying in a blog post</a> that it had &#8220;learned that one of our employees purchased items that they knew were set to display on our front page before they appeared there publicly.&#8221; The company did not identify the employee but said that they were conducting an &#8220;immediate&#8221; review of the incident. The startup, which was recently valued at $1.5 billion after raising a $100 million Series B from Andreessen Horowitz, added in the unsigned blog post that this incident was &#8220;incredibly disappointing.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re conducting a thorough review of yesterday’s incident and are committed to doing the right thing for OpenSea users,&#8221; OpenSea CEO Devin Finzer said in a <a href="https://twitter.com/dfinzer/status/1438122446847201283">tweet</a>.</p>
<p>OpenSea, which did a record $3.4 billion in transaction volume last month, appears not to have had any rules in places preventing employees from using confidential information to buy or sell NFTs on its own platform to its own users. The company detailed that it was now implementing a policy that team members could not buy or sell &#8220;from collections or creators while we are featuring or promoting them,&#8221; and that they are &#8220;prohibited from using confidential information to purchase or sell any NFTs, whether available on the OpenSea platform or not.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Most NFTs are not generally assumed to be securities, despite little official guidance from the SEC on the crypto asset class. Some in the space have questioned whether different mechanics around buying and selling, alongside ongoing rewards structures may be pushing some NFT sales further into securities territory.</p>
<p>&#8220;Many have been enticed by dramatic jumps in the value of new digital assets,&#8221; Senate Banking Committee Chairman Sherrod Brown said in a hearing yesterday &#8212; as transcribed by <a href="https://www.theblockcrypto.com/post/117675/crypto-lending-staking-custody-gensler-sec">The Block</a> &#8212; where the relationship between crypto markets and SEC enforcement was discussed. &#8220;Some professional investors and celebrities make earning millions look easy. But, as we are reminded time and again, it’s never that simple – and too often, someone’s quick profit comes at the expense of workers and entire communities.&#8221;</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve reached out to OpenSea for further comment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Yn51Ws7Dg5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/nft-market-opensea-hits-1-5-billion-valuation/">NFT market OpenSea hits $1.5 billion valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NFT market OpenSea hits $1.5 billion valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/nft-market-opensea-hits-1-5-billion-valuation/embed/#?secret=Yn51Ws7Dg5" data-secret="Yn51Ws7Dg5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/opensea-admits-incident-as-top-exec-is-accused-of-trading-nfts-on-insider-information/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202372</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stamp your Passport to Disrupt for a chance to win these prizes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/stamp-your-passport-to-disrupt-for-a-chance-to-win-these-prizes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/stamp-your-passport-to-disrupt-for-a-chance-to-win-these-prizes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 16:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As you prepare to dive in to three days of TechCrunch Disrupt 2021, be sure to take your passport. No, not the government-issued variety. Our Disrupt Passport lets you collect experiences during the virtual conference and gives you a chance to win some pretty fabulous prizes. Seriously, who wouldn’t want a chance to win these? [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As you prepare to dive in to three days of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a>, be sure to take your passport. No, not the government-issued variety. Our Disrupt Passport lets you collect experiences during the virtual conference and gives you a chance to win some pretty fabulous prizes.</p>
<p>Seriously, who wouldn’t want a chance to win these?</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Grand Prize:</strong> <a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/en-US/x3?color=dark">VanMoof X3 e-bike </a></li>
<li><strong>1st Place:</strong> <a href="https://www.bose.com/en_us/products/headphones/noise_cancelling_headphones/noise-cancelling-headphones-700.html?mc=25_PS_HP_PL_00_GO_&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwg7KJBhDyARIsAHrAXaEj_V4QhQCxvny9lll0iFiMXdU4MIuP1NF3NLiLzvxuTjO1J7ebDbwaAgK-EALw_wcB&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds#v=noise_cancelling_headphones_700_black">Bose Noise Cancelling Headphones </a></li>
<li><strong>2nd Place:</strong> <a href="https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/beam.html">Sonos Beam Sound Bar</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Here’s the deal. The Disrupt Passport (which you can download in the Disrupt virtual venue — and watch a video detailing how to play), contains a series of experiences. Complete all the experiences in just one row and then <strong>send your entry to the TechCrunch team</strong> <strong>by 11:59 pm (PT) on September 23, 2021.</strong></p>
<p>We&#8217;ll select three people who successfully submit their completed passport to win one of the three prizes.</p>
<p>What experiences do you need to do? Nothing more strenuous than what you already plan to do at Disrupt. Take a look at the activities in just one of the Passport’s rows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Meet with a Startup During Startup Alley Crawl: Tuesday</li>
<li>Attend a Breakout Session: Thursday</li>
<li>Schedule and Attend a Meeting with CrunchMatch: Thursday</li>
<li>Take a Photo in the Disrupt Photobooth</li>
<li>Meet with a Sponsor in the Expo</li>
</ul>
<p>All the experiences listed in the Disrupt Passport offer the kind of opportunities that can help you build your startup or expand your portfolio without reinventing the wheel. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=passportpost&amp;display=true">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> is the place to create, collaborate, learn and inspire — and snag cool prizes, too. But you have to have a pass to Disrupt to play. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=passportpost&amp;display=true">Get yours today for less than $100</a> before prices increase next week.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/stamp-your-passport-to-disrupt-for-a-chance-to-win-these-prizes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199461</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Front introduces customer-centric features with deeper CRM integration</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/front-introduces-customer-centric-features-with-deeper-crm-integration/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/front-introduces-customer-centric-features-with-deeper-crm-integration/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 16:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communication platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Front]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Customer communication platform Front is holding an event today to introduce three new features. These new features focus on showing you more information about your customers right from Front’s user interface. If you’re not familiar with Front, the company started as a shared email inbox product so that you can interact with incoming emails as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Customer communication platform <a href="https://front.com">Front</a> is holding an event today to introduce three new features. These new features focus on showing you more information about your customers right from Front’s user interface.</p>
<p>If you’re not familiar with Front, the company started as a shared email inbox product so that you can interact with incoming emails as a team. For instance, if your company uses email lists, such as support@companyname.com, sales@companyname.com or jobs@companyname.com, multiple team members can see incoming emails in Front.</p>
<p>Before replying, you can triage conversations by assigning them to specific team members, discuss the current conversation in the comment section or show your email draft before sending it.</p>
<p>Over time, Front has evolved to integrate more communication channels. You can now use Front for SMS conversations, live chat on your website with your customers, Facebook messages, etc. The company has also refined its product with more powerful features.</p>
<p>For instance, you can set up rules to automate your workflow with simple &#8220;if this then that&#8221; rules. It’s a good way to spread out work across multiple team members and make sure the right person sees the incoming message as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>Today, the company is showcasing features that will be particularly useful for teams that interact with bigger customers, such as sales, support and customer success teams. First, Front users will be able to learn more about the customer they’re interacting with directly from their inbox.</p>
<p>The refreshed context panel works better if the team is interacting with multiple people working for your client. Instead of viewing past conversations with someone in particular, you can view past conversations with everyone working for this client.</p>
<p>Front already integrates with your CRM, such as Salesforce or HubSpot. You can now more easily pull data into the context panel. You can see the name of the account owner, the customer segment and the SLA (service-level agreement) commitment with this customer.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203128" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203128" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203128" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9-Accounts-Contacts-0_00_24_00.png" alt="" width="1024" height="704" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9-Accounts-Contacts-0_00_24_00.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9-Accounts-Contacts-0_00_24_00.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9-Accounts-Contacts-0_00_24_00.png?resize=300,206 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9-Accounts-Contacts-0_00_24_00.png?resize=768,528 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9-Accounts-Contacts-0_00_24_00.png?resize=680,468 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9-Accounts-Contacts-0_00_24_00.png?resize=1536,1056 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9-Accounts-Contacts-0_00_24_00.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203128" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Front</p></div></p>
<p>Second, Front is adding new capabilities for its automated routing feature with deeper integrations with your CRM. For instance, you can find the name of the account owner in your CRM and assign incoming emails to the account owner directly.</p>
<p>If the account owner changes in Salesforce, rules will be automatically updated in Front. You can also fetch annual revenue data from your CRM and set a VIP tag if you’re receiving a message from an important customer.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203129" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203129" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203129" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/10-Account-Rules-0_00_24_20.png" alt="" width="1024" height="704" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/10-Account-Rules-0_00_24_20.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/10-Account-Rules-0_00_24_20.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/10-Account-Rules-0_00_24_20.png?resize=300,206 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/10-Account-Rules-0_00_24_20.png?resize=768,528 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/10-Account-Rules-0_00_24_20.png?resize=680,468 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/10-Account-Rules-0_00_24_20.png?resize=1536,1056 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/10-Account-Rules-0_00_24_20.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203129" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Front</p></div></p>
<p>Finally, Front will soon upgrade the analytics pages. For instance, you can track the team’s performance for a specific account and compare that to the SLA.</p>
<p>These updates position Front as a tool that works better for bigger enterprise clients with expensive B2B contracts. Current Front customers include Shopify, Dropbox, Flexport, Checkout.com, Lydia and Airbnb.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203127" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203127" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203127" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/8-Accounts-Analytics-0_00_23_00.png" alt="" width="1024" height="704" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/8-Accounts-Analytics-0_00_23_00.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/8-Accounts-Analytics-0_00_23_00.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/8-Accounts-Analytics-0_00_23_00.png?resize=300,206 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/8-Accounts-Analytics-0_00_23_00.png?resize=768,528 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/8-Accounts-Analytics-0_00_23_00.png?resize=680,468 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/8-Accounts-Analytics-0_00_23_00.png?resize=1536,1056 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/8-Accounts-Analytics-0_00_23_00.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203127" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Front</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/front-introduces-customer-centric-features-with-deeper-crm-integration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203124</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
