<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 09:34:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Mike Cagney is testing the boundaries of the banking system for himself and others</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/mike-cagney-is-testing-the-boundaries-of-the-banking-system-for-himself-and-others/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/mike-cagney-is-testing-the-boundaries-of-the-banking-system-for-himself-and-others/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 04:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Figure Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Cagney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Founder Mike Cagney is always pushing the envelope, and investors love him for it. Not long sexual harassment allegations prompted him to leave SoFi, the personal finance company that he cofounded in 2011, he raised $50 million for a new lending startup called Figure that has since raised at least $225 million from investors and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Founder Mike Cagney is always pushing the envelope, and investors love him for it. Not long <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/12/technology/sofi-chief-executive-toxic-workplace.html?_r=0">sexual harassment allegations</a> prompted him to leave SoFi, the personal finance company that he cofounded in 2011, he raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/30/sofi-founder-mike-cagney-is-back-with-a-new-startup-and-50-million-in-funding-too/">$50 million</a> for a new lending startup called <a href="https://www.figure.com/#about">Figure</a> that has since raised at least <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20191205005276/en/Figure-Closes-Series-C-Round-of-103-Million-to-Expand-Lending-Products-and-Executive-Hires">$225 million</a> from investors and was valued a year ago at $1.2 billion.</p>
<p>Now, Cagney is trying to do something unprecedented with Figure, which says it uses a blockchain to more quickly facilitate home equity, mortgage refinance, and student and personal loan approvals. The company has applied for a national bank charter in the U.S., wherein it would not take FDIC-insured deposits but it could take uninsured deposits of over $250,000 from accredited investors.</p>
<p>Why does it matter? The approach, <a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:FCyo9xlA1MAJ:https://www.americanbanker.com/news/a-fintechs-novel-bank-charter-application-draws-industrys-ire+&amp;cd=1&amp;hl=en&amp;ct=clnk&amp;gl=us">as American Banker explains it</a>, would bring regulatory benefits. As it reported earlier this week, &#8220;Because Figure Bank would not hold insured deposits, it would not be subject to the FDIC’s oversight. Similarly, the absence of insured deposits would prevent oversight by the Fed under the Bank Holding Company Act. That law imposes restrictions on non-banking activities and is widely thought to be a deal-breaker for tech companies where banking would be a sidelight.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Indeed, if approved, Figure could pave the way for a lot of fintech startups &#8212; and other retail companies that want to wheel and deal in lucrative financial products without the oversight of the Federal Reserve Board or the FDIC &#8212; to nab non-traditional bank charters.</p>
<p>As Michelle Alt, whose year-old <a href="https://www.klaros.com/">financial advisory firm</a> helped Figure with its application, tells AB: &#8220;This model, if it’s approved, wouldn’t be for everyone. A lot of would-be banks want to be banks specifically to have more resilient funding sources.&#8221; But if it’s successful, she adds, &#8220;a lot of people will be interested.”</p>
<p>One can only guess at what the ripple effects would be, though the Bank of Amazon wouldn&#8217;t surprise anyone who follows the company.</p>
<p>In the meantime, the strategy would seemingly be a high-stakes, high-reward development for a smaller outfit like Figure, which could operate far more freely than banks traditionally but also without a safety net for itself or its customers. The most glaring danger would be a bank run, wherein those accredited individuals who are today willing to lend money to the platform at high interest rates began demanding their money back at the same time. (It <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2008/07/13/business/worldbusiness/13iht-indy.4.14456887.html">happens</a>.)</p>
<p>Either way, Cagney might find a receptive audience right now with Brian Brooks, a longtime Fannie Mae executive who served as Coinbase&#8217;s chief legal officer for two years before jumping this spring to the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC), an agency that ensures that national banks and federal savings associations operate in a safe and sound manner.</p>
<p>Brooks was made acting head of the agency in May and green-lit one of the first national charters to go to a fintech, Varo Money, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/fintech-varo-money-gets-green-light-to-become-bank-11596207033">this past summer</a>. In late October, the OCC also granted SoFi <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-sofi-bank-charter/fintech-startup-sofi-gets-preliminary-approval-for-u-s-bank-charter-idUSKBN27D27W">preliminary, conditional approval</a> over its own application for a national bank charter.</p>
<p>While Brooks isn&#8217;t commenting on speculation around Figure&#8217;s application, in July, <a href="https://www.bankingdive.com/news/occ-controller-brian-brooks-special-purpose-charters-unbundling/586155/">during a Brookings Institution event</a>, he reportedly commented about trade groups&#8217; concerns over his efforts to grant fintechs and payments companies charters, saying: &#8220;I think the misunderstanding that some of these trade groups are operating under is that somehow this is going to trigger a lighter-touch charter with fewer obligations, and it&#8217;s going to make the playing field un-level . . . I think it&#8217;s just the opposite.&#8221;</p>
<p>Christopher Cole, executive vice president at the trade group <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.icba.org/">Independent Community Bankers of America</a>, doesn&#8217;t seem persuaded. Earlier this week, he expressed concern about Figure&#8217;s bank charter application to AB, saying he suspects that Brooks &#8220;wants to approve this quickly before he leaves office.”</p>
<p>Brooks&#8217;s days are surely numbered. Last month, he was <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/finance/526425-trump-to-nominate-brooks-as-comptroller-of-the-currency">nominated</a> by President Donald to a full five-year term leading the federal bank regulator and is currently awaiting Senate confirmation. The move &#8212; designed to slow down the incoming Biden administration &#8212; could be undone by President-elect Joe Biden, who can <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/finance/526425-trump-to-nominate-brooks-as-comptroller-of-the-currency">fire the comptroller of the currency at will</a> and appoint an acting replacement to serve until his nominee is confirmed by the Senate.</p>
<p>Still, Cole&#8217;s suggestion is that Brooks still has enough time to figure out a path forward for Figure &#8212; and if its novel charter application is approved, and it stands up to legal challenges &#8212; a lot of other companies, too.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/mike-cagney-is-testing-the-boundaries-of-the-banking-system-for-himself-and-others/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083222</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Slack and Salesforce execs explain their big acquisition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/daily-crunch-slack-salesforce-interview/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/daily-crunch-slack-salesforce-interview/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 23:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083263</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We learn more about Slack&#8217;s future, Revolut adds new payment features and DoorDash pushes its IPO range upward. This is your Daily Crunch for December 4, 2020. The big story: Slack and Salesforce execs explain their big acquisition After Salesforce announced this week that it&#8217;s acquiring Slack for $27.7 billion, Ron Miller spoke to Slack [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We learn more about <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/slack" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="slack">Slack&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> future, Revolut adds new payment features and DoorDash pushes its IPO range upward. This is your Daily Crunch for December 4, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Slack and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/salesforce" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="salesforce">Salesforce <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> execs explain their big acquisition</strong></p>
<p>After Salesforce announced this week that it&#8217;s acquiring Slack for $27.7 billion, Ron Miller spoke to Slack CEO Stewart Butterfield and Salesforce President and COO Bret Taylor to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/why-slack-and-salesforce-execs-think-theyre-better-together/">learn more about the deal</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Butterfield claimed that Slack will remain relatively independent within Salesforce, allowing the team to &#8220;do more of what we were already doing.&#8221; He also insisted that all the talk about competing with Microsoft Teams is &#8220;overblown.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The challenge for us was the narrative,&#8221; Butterfield said. &#8220;They’re just good [at] PR or something that I couldn’t figure out.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/revolut-lets-businesses-accept-online-payments/">Revolut lets businesses accept online payments</a> — With this move, the company is competing directly with Stripe, Adyen, Braintree and Checkout.com.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/otv-closes-new-170-million-fund-and-expands-into-asia/">Health tech venture firm OTV closes new $170M fund and expands into Asia</a> — This year, the firm led rounds in telehealth platforms TytoCare and Lemonaid Health.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/zephr-bdmi-funding/">Zephr raises $8M to help news publishers grow subscription revenue</a> — The startup’s customers already include publishers like McClatchy, News Corp Australia, Dennis Publishing and PEI Media.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/doordash-amps-its-ipo-range-ahead-of-blockbuster-ipo/">DoorDash amps its IPO range ahead of blockbuster IPO</a> — The food delivery unicorn now expects to debut at $90 to $95 per share, up from a previous range of $75 to $85.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/enter-new-markets-and-embrace-a-distributed-workforce-to-grow-during-a-pandemic/">Enter new markets and embrace a distributed workforce to grow during a pandemic</a> — Is this the right time to expand overseas?</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/3-ways-the-pandemic-is-transforming-tech-spending/">Three ways the pandemic is transforming tech spending</a> — All companies are digital product companies now.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/whs-ai-eo-is-bs/">WH’s AI EO is BS</a> — Devin Coldewey is not impressed by the White House&#8217;s new executive order on artificial intelligence.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/chinas-internet-regulator-takes-aim-at-forced-data-collection/">China’s internet regulator takes aim at forced data collection</a> — China is a step closer to cracking down on unscrupulous data collection by app developers.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/gift-guide-games-on-every-platform-to-get-you-through-the-long-covid-winter/">Gift Guide: Games on every platform to get you through the long, COVID winter</a> — It&#8217;s a great time to be a gamer.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/daily-crunch-slack-salesforce-interview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083263</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: 9+ caffeinated gift ideas for your favorite coffee lovers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/gift-guide-9-caffeinated-gift-ideas-for-your-favorite-coffee-lovers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/gift-guide-9-caffeinated-gift-ideas-for-your-favorite-coffee-lovers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 21:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gift guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2020]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2068856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic has meant we leave our homes far less often, and that means fending for ourselves when it comes to coffee. But too many of us have old, cheap coffee makers or worse, pod-based ones at home. Here are the best ways to elevate your coffee game or delight the java lover in your life.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to TechCrunch&#8217;s 2020 Holiday Gift Guide! Need help with gift ideas? We&#8217;re here to help! We&#8217;ll be rolling out gift guides from now through the end of December. </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><em>You can find our other guides right here.</em></a></p>
<p>The pandemic has meant we leave our homes far less often, and that means fending for ourselves when it comes to coffee. But too many of us have old, cheap coffee makers or worse, pod-based ones at home. Here are the best ways to elevate your coffee game or delight the java lover in your life.</p>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic">This article contains links to affiliate partners where available. When you buy through these links, TechCrunch may earn an affiliate commission.</i></p>
<h1>Superior drip coffee makers</h1>
<p>Every grocery store sells a cheap drip coffee maker that does the job adequately, but if anyone is going to use a device every day, it should be something they look forward to, not the bare minimum.</p>
<p>That said, a coffee maker shouldn&#8217;t be an IQ test — you have to operate it before you&#8217;ve had your coffee, after all. I personally find the ones with touchscreens and apps add nothing but new ways to get it wrong. So I tested a few coffee makers that balance quality with simplicity, and after a few weeks of jitters here are my favorites.</p>
<h2><strong>For the industrial design appreciator: OXO 8-cup coffee maker</strong></h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2076136" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="829" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-1.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-1.jpg?resize=150,121 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-1.jpg?resize=300,243 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-1.jpg?resize=768,621 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-1.jpg?resize=680,550 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-1.jpg?resize=1536,1243 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-1.jpg?resize=2048,1657 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-1.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a>Pros</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Compact, well-thought-out design</li>
<li>Lots of actually useful features</li>
<li>Thermal carafe included</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cons</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Single-cup brewing is a bit over-complicated</li>
<li>Could be more coffee-efficient</li>
</ul>
<p>OXO&#8217;s reputation as a kitchen goods designer is well deserved, but I often find their items a bit much for the job. Not so with the 8-cup coffee maker, which manages to balance thoughtful design with simplicity and quality. I can say with confidence: if you aren&#8217;t sure which coffee maker to get&#8230; get this one.</p>
<p>The OXO 8-cup is the (obviously) smaller alternative to the 9-cup, losing the ability to schedule brewing but gaining simpler operation and a single-cup option using a separate, Kalita-compatible basket. The lids of the reservoir and basket area flip up (the latter allowing condensed water to flow safely into the filter) and the basket itself sits securely but pops out easily.</p>
<p>The coffee is uniformly good; I would say as good but slightly less strong than the KBGV below. It flows directly into a thermal carafe with a dedicated hole in the top, simplifying even that part. Pretty much everything about this machine is made to simplify and foolproof itself, making the brewing process extremely reliable.</p>
<p>I honestly struggled to find any complaints, but I would say that the necessity of keeping a second basket that uses a different filter type, then adjusting the various bits so that you can slip the mug in, etc., is arguably more trouble than it&#8217;s worth. But the capability for single-cup brewing is there and doesn&#8217;t take away from the rest at all.</p>
<p>It also recommends somewhat more grounds per cup than the KBGV, not a crazy amount but enough that you&#8217;ll probably get one less pot out of a standard 16 oz bag of coffee.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $170 <a href="https://www.oxo.com/8-cup-coffee-maker.html">from OXO</a></p>
<h2><strong>For the FBI stakeout: Technivorm Moccamaster KBGV</strong></h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2076138" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-2.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-2.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-2.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-2.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-2.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-2.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-2.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-2.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a>Pros</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Streamlined retro-institutional look</li>
<li>Strong, reliable brew</li>
<li>Automatic hot plate</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cons</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Lots of removable parts</li>
<li>Materials unremarkable for the price</li>
</ul>
<p>The KBGV brewed my favorite coffee and in my opinion has the best look, like what you&#8217;d expect in the background of an FBI stakeout field HQ in a 70s movie. Where the OXO is rounded-off and unassuming, designed to disappear in a modern kitchen, the KBGV is bold and shiny.</p>
<p>The coffee it makes is bold, too: reliably strong and flavorful. Its #4 filter process to me was also pretty efficient with grounds.</p>
<p>The squat glass carafe sits on a hot plate that remains on for an hour or so after brewing, which is great but also means you must remember to turn it off — it won&#8217;t start a fire or anything, it&#8217;s just going to sit there being hot.</p>
<p>My main issue with the KBGV is that the reservoir and basket covers just sit on top rather than being on hinges, making the process of brewing involve removing and replacing several pieces. A small complaint, but they, like the carafe lid and basket, are also made of a rather ordinary plastic rather than something more durable. I feel like given the premium price you should be given something a bit more classy and convenient.</p>
<p>The good news is they&#8217;ll be easy to replace if they break, and Technivorm has an excellent warranty.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $330<a href="https://us.moccamaster.com/kbgv-select-polished-silver.html"> from Technivorm</a></p>
<h2><strong>For the &#8216;gram: Ratio 8</strong></h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-3.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2076139" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-3.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-3.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-3.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-3.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-3.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-3.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-3.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-3.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/coffeemakers-3.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a>Pros</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Extremely handsome</li>
<li>Excellent materials</li>
<li>Very simple operation</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cons</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Nothing to keep coffee warm</li>
<li>Quite large!</li>
<li>Very expensive</li>
</ul>
<p>Objectively the most good-looking of the machines here (even if I prefer the quirky charm of the KBGV), the Ratio 8, with its wood and textured metal finish, is obviously meant to be a display piece. And you couldn&#8217;t hide it if you wanted to — this thing is <em>big</em>, and the thick power cord juts straight out of the back, making it difficult to put anywhere but somewhere central.</p>
<p>The machine is basically an automatic Chemex brewer (Chemex makes one of their own that I tried to test but never heard back on), which kind of tells you everything you need to know. Chemex, with its wood-collared, single-piece carafes and luxuriously thick filters, is almost like the BMW of drip coffee, with all that implies. I like it, but I also acknowledge that it&#8217;s a bit over the top. And a machine that does it for you — well!</p>
<p>But as a Chemex brewer goes, it&#8217;s a lovely thing. You get that special extra clarity that the Chemex process brings, and there&#8217;s something wonderful about the way the coffee comes out of those carafes. Operating the machine is a single-button affair, which activates a short bloom period then showers the grounds over time with however much water you put in the reservoir.</p>
<p>I found that the Ratio 8 was best when making a full carafe, as with a half-portion I felt it over-watered and consequently under-extracted what I put in there. Unfortunately that full carafe will have to be consumed with a quickness, as the Ratio 8, despite its size and price, has nothing to keep the coffee warm once it&#8217;s been brewed.</p>
<p>For a showy and unique machine the Ratio 8 is great. But if all you want to do is make great drip, the OXO or KBGV is a much better use of your funds.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$495<a href="https://ratiocoffee.com/products/eight"> from Ratio</a></p>
<h1>More exotic methods</h1>
<p>There are lots of ways to make coffee, and while drip is the easiest and most reliable for most people, the following slightly more unusual options are also viable and perhaps more interesting as gifts.</p>
<h2>FrankOne</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PA150003.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1898483" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PA150003.jpg" alt="PA150003" width="1024" height="689" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PA150003.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PA150003.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PA150003.jpg?resize=300,202 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PA150003.jpg?resize=768,517 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PA150003.jpg?resize=680,458 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PA150003.jpg?resize=1536,1034 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PA150003.jpg?resize=2048,1378 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PA150003.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a>Want to get the first coffee maker to come out of Colombia — you know, coffee central? The <a href="https://frankdepaula.com/">FrankOne </a>is a cool device that quickly makes a pourover-like cup by steeping the grounds then creating a vacuum in the chamber below it, sucking the liquid out but leaving the grounds up top. It works great, operates on a rechargeable battery and is easy to clean (especially if you have a garbage disposal).</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$80<a href="https://frankdepaula.com/frankone-small-coffee-maker-cold-brew-maker"> from FrankDePaula</a></p>
<h2><strong>ROK manual espresso maker</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2082839" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rok-espresso.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2082839" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2082839" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rok-espresso.gif" alt="" width="800" height="484" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2082839" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> ROK</p></div></p>
<p>I avoided the many fancy espresso machines out there for this review mainly for the reason that they are complex, expensive and require considerable upkeep. The ROK is about as simple an espresso maker as you can get, bested only by a stovetop Moka pot.</p>
<p>To work the ROK, you pack your grounds into the included espresso filter and attach it to the machine like any other. Then you pour your hot water into the reservoir up top, raise the arms, and depress them with a slow, steady pressure that forces it through the filter. It really is that simple.</p>
<p>It may not be quite the high-pressure espresso you get from a &#8220;real&#8221; machine, but it&#8217;s quite good, and the process can be repeated to increase the volume and produce something like an americano. The coffee produced by the ROK is a bit like a Moka Pot&#8217;s, but a bit less strong and far less likely to be burnt.</p>
<p>The machine itself is bulletproof — and I mean I think it&#8217;s actually bulletproof. It&#8217;s practically solid metal, though the reservoir and bellows are rubber. Use this to make coffee while camping and then fend off a bear attack.</p>
<p>For a unique, electricity-free coffee experience the ROK is a great option, though not necessarily a practical one.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $189<a href="https://www.rok.coffee/us/home#Products-Desktop"> from ROK</a></p>
<h2>Osma</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2082853" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/osma-coffee.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2082853" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2082853" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/osma-coffee.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="669" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/osma-coffee.jpg 1666w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/osma-coffee.jpg?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/osma-coffee.jpg?resize=300,196 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/osma-coffee.jpg?resize=768,502 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/osma-coffee.jpg?resize=680,444 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/osma-coffee.jpg?resize=1536,1003 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/osma-coffee.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2082853" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Osma</p></div></p>
<p>I haven&#8217;t gotten to test this one yet (though I will), but designer Joey Roth hasn&#8217;t done me wrong yet. This new device from his workshop uses a completely new method of circulating hot water through grounds, making a drip-like cup in a very short time, or cold brew, or tea. If your loved one is a gadget fiend, this is one they probably haven&#8217;t had the chance to covet yet. Technically it uses pods, but they&#8217;re totally biodegradable and you can fill them with your own grounds or leaves.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $185<a href="https://drinkosma.com"> from Osma</a></p>
<h1>Pourover cones</h1>
<p>I&#8217;ve used pourover as my main method of making coffee for years, and it reliably produces the best single cup you can have, though at the cost of being somewhat time-consuming.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/dripper.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2082838" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/dripper.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="436" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/dripper.jpg 1246w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/dripper.jpg?resize=150,64 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/dripper.jpg?resize=300,128 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/dripper.jpg?resize=768,327 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/dripper.jpg?resize=680,290 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/dripper.jpg?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h2>Kalita Wave 185</h2>
<p>Kalita makes a couple sizes of these pourover cones, and although I have happily used my 155 for many years, if I could do it over again I&#8217;d opt for the slightly larger 185, which is more forgiving when you&#8217;re pouring and can brew more than the 16 ounces that is the realistic upper limit of mine.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $36 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000X1AM0Y/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B000X1AM0Y&amp;linkId=32460a58cd4553793b909296495c7bf3">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2>OXO&#8217;s pourover cone with tank</h2>
<p>If hovering by the stove and watering your grounds for the two to three minutes it takes to make a cup is not something you enjoy, <a href="https://www.oxo.com/categories/coffee-tea/brew/coffee-makers/pour-over-coffee-maker-with-water-tank.html#">OXO has a nice little gadget</a> that simplifies things. It&#8217;s basically a pourover cone with a reservoir that sits on top, dripping water through a few tiny holes at a steady rate.</p>
<p>It made a good cup and with minimal fuss, but the capacity is limited, so if you want more than 12 ounces you&#8217;ll have to refill the reservoir.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$16 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01ENK41Q6/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B01ENK41Q6&amp;linkId=2b186288107c19ad72ed22836a0554b8">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2>Kone and other metal filters</h2>
<p>These <a href="https://ablebrewing.com/products/kone-coffee-filter">permanent filters</a> have gotten quite good, and I have one that sits right on top of a cup. No more paper! However I would recommend these only to people who have a garbage disposal or sink that can handle a lot of grounds, because cleaning the filter involves losing a lot of grit down the drain. Occasional deep cleaning is required but it&#8217;s nice to reduce waste even a little bit.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>Around $30-40, depending on brand.</p>
<h1>Coffee subscriptions</h1>
<p>Just as a general note: These types of subscriptions are great, but you need to do a little bit of research or your loved one will end up with a roast they don&#8217;t like. I don&#8217;t want to recommend any in particular, since they all specialize in different things, but aim to prop up independent roasteries and fair trade rather than just getting a steady supply of the same old thing from a major chain.</p>
<p><strong>Some good options:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.drinktrade.com/">Trade Coffee</a> &#8211; reliably recommended</li>
<li><a href="https://www.mistobox.com/">Mistobox</a> &#8211; wider selection</li>
<li><a href="https://www.redbaycoffee.com">Red Bay Coffee</a> &#8211; black-owned business</li>
<li><a href="https://angelscup.com/pages/subscribe">Angel&#8217;s Cup</a> &#8211; blind tasting (no labels)</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gift-guide-2020-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/gift-guide-9-caffeinated-gift-ideas-for-your-favorite-coffee-lovers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2068856</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Wireless headsets from Logitech, Audio-Technica, SteelSeries, HyperX and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/review-wireless-headsets-from-logitech-audio-technica-steelseries-hyperx-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/review-wireless-headsets-from-logitech-audio-technica-steelseries-hyperx-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 20:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audio Technica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyperx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logitech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PS5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SteelSeries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless headphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xbox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2064763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the amount of time you&#8217;re spending at home these days, you deserve a better headset. A wireless one that works with your computer and maybe your console as well, with a mic for calls and great sound for games and movies. Fortunately there are a lot to choose from, and I&#8217;ve tested out your [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With the amount of time you&#8217;re spending at home these days, you deserve a better headset. A wireless one that works with your computer and maybe your console as well, with a mic for calls and great sound for games and movies. Fortunately there are a lot to choose from, and I&#8217;ve tested out your best options.</p>
<p>I asked the leading audio and peripheral companies to send over their flagship wireless headset, with prices ranging from about $100 to $250. Beyond this price range returns diminish swiftly, but right now that&#8217;s the sweet spot for comfort, sound and usability.</p>
<p>For years I&#8217;ve avoided wireless headsets because there were too many compromises, but I&#8217;m pleased to say that the latency has been eliminated and battery life in the ones I reviewed is uniformly excellent. (NB: If the wireless version feels too expensive, you can often get wired ones for $50-100 less.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To test the headphones, I used them all for a variety of everyday tasks, from video calls to movies and music (with only minimal EQing to get a sense of their natural sound) to AAA games and indies. None require an app to work, though some have companion software for LEDs or game profiles. I have a fairly large head and medium-sized ears, for what it&#8217;s worth. All the headphones are rather bulky, though the angle I shot them at individually makes them look huge — you can see in the image up top that they&#8217;re all roughly the same size.</p>
<p>None of these headphones have active noise cancelling, but many offer decent physical isolation to the point where they offer a &#8220;monitor&#8221; feature that pipes in sound from the outside world — useful if you&#8217;re playing a game but waiting for the oven to preheat or something. Only the first set has a built-in mic, the rest have detachable ones of generally solid quality, certainly good enough for streaming and chatting, though for broadcast a separate one would be better. All these headphones use a USB-A style dongle, though the 7P/7X also has a USB-C connector.</p>
<h3>SteelSeries 7P/7X &#8211; $149</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2076127" style="width: 2510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-3.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2076127" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2076127 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-3.jpg" alt="" width="2500" height="1747" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-3.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-3.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-3.jpg?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-3.jpg?resize=768,537 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-3.jpg?resize=680,475 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-3.jpg?resize=1536,1073 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-3.jpg?resize=2048,1431 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-3.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2500px) 100vw, 2500px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2076127" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>The 7P and 7X headsets, designed with the PS5 and Xbox Series X in mind (as well as PC) respectively, are my first and most unreserved recommendation.</p>
<p>The standout feature on these is, to me, a truly surprising sound with an almost disturbingly broad stage and clarity. I almost couldn&#8217;t believe what I was hearing when I put on some familiar tracks I use for reference. This isn&#8217;t a 7.1 simulation or anything like that — but no doubt the gaming focus led to creating a large soundstage. It worked!</p>
<p>I also found the headphones to be very comfortable, with a &#8220;ski goggle&#8221; strap instead of a per-band adjustment that lets them sit very lightly as well as &#8220;remembering&#8221; your setting. The spacious earcups rotate for travel or comfort.</p>
<p>The built-in mic is unobtrusive and stows away nicely, but if you&#8217;re picky about placement it was a bit floppy to adjust. Many of the other headsets have nicer mics that completely detach — maybe that&#8217;s a plus for you, but I tend to lose them.</p>
<p>My main issues with these are that the controls feel cheap and not particularly well laid out. The bottom of the headset is a jumble of ports and buttons and the volume dials don&#8217;t have much travel — it&#8217;s 0 to 100 in one full swipe. (Volume control is independent from system volume.)</p>
<p>The dongle is different from the others in that it is itself USB-C, but with a USB-A cable attached. That&#8217;s good for compatibility, but the cable is three feet long, making it kind of silly to attach to some laptops and whatnot. You could easily get your own short cord, though.</p>
<p>At $150 I think these are an easy recommendation for just about anyone looking at that price range.</p>
<h3>Audio-Technica AT-GWL &#8211; $250</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2076130" style="width: 2510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-5.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2076130" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2076130 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-5.jpg" alt="" width="2500" height="1760" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-5.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-5.jpg?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-5.jpg?resize=300,211 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-5.jpg?resize=768,541 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-5.jpg?resize=680,479 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-5.jpg?resize=1536,1081 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-5.jpg?resize=2048,1442 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-5.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2500px) 100vw, 2500px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2076130" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>The high price on these is partly because they are the wireless version of a headset that also comes wired, so if you want the solid audio performance and comfy fit, you can save some money by going wired.</p>
<p>The sound of the AT-GWLs is rich and naturally has a focus on the upper-mid vocal range, which makes voices in media really pop. I did find the sound a bit confined, which hitting the &#8220;surround&#8221; setting actually helped with. I know that this sort of virtualization has generally been frowned on, but it&#8217;s been a while since these settings have been over the top and distortive. I found surround better for games but not necessarily for music, but it&#8217;s very easy to switch on and off.</p>
<p>The headphones are light and adjusted with traditional, no-nonsense metal bands, with a single pad on the top. I would say they are the lightest-feeling pair I tested, with the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/steelseries" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="steelseries">SteelSeries <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Razer coming in just behind owing to some extra weight and bulk. Despite being compact, the AT-GWLs felt airy but not big. The leather-microfiber combo cups are nice, and I think they&#8217;ll break in well to provide better isolation over time.</p>
<p>Where they fall short is in the interface. First, a note to <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/audio-technica" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="audio-technica">Audio-Technica: <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Turn down the notification noises! Turning the headset on, the mic on or off or hitting the system-independent volume max produces loud, surprising beeps. Too loud!</p>
<p>Second, the buttons and dials are stiff, small and same-feeling. Lifting a hand quickly to turn down the volume (maybe after a huge beep) you may very easily mistake the power switch for the volume dial. The dial also doubles as a button for surround mode, and next to it is a microscopic button to turn on and off the sound of surroundings. It&#8217;s a bit of a jumble — nothing you can&#8217;t get used to, but considering how nice other headsets on this list made their controls, it has to be said.</p>
<h3>HyperX Cloud II wireless &#8211; $100</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2076131" style="width: 2510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-6.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2076131" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2076131 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-6.jpg" alt="" width="2500" height="1739" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-6.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-6.jpg?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-6.jpg?resize=300,209 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-6.jpg?resize=768,534 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-6.jpg?resize=680,473 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-6.jpg?resize=1536,1068 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-6.jpg?resize=2048,1425 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-6.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2500px) 100vw, 2500px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2076131" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/hyperx" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="hyperx">HyperX <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> (owned by Kingston) wasn&#8217;t exactly known for audio until fairly recently, but its previous Cloud headset got the crucial Wirecutter endorsement, and it&#8217;s easy to see why. For less money than any of the other headsets in this roundup, the follow-up to that headset (which I&#8217;m wearing right now) has excellent sound and isolation.</p>
<p>I was surprised to find a soundstage nearly as wide as the 7P/7X, but with more of a focus on the punchy lower register instead of on detail and placement. My music felt big and close, and the atmosphere of games likewise, more immediately present.</p>
<p>The Cloud II&#8217;s controls are simple and effective. The volume dial, tied directly to the system volume, is superb: grippy, with smooth motion and just the right amount of friction, and just-barely-there clicks. There are two good-size buttons, the power one concave and the mic mute (which gives different sounds for muted and active) convex.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unfortunate that they&#8217;re not as comfortable, for me anyway, as the others on this list. The cups (though a bit on the warm side) and band are perfectly fine. It&#8217;s that there&#8217;s little rotation to those cups, meaning there&#8217;s no play to accommodate the shape of your head. I don&#8217;t know, maybe it&#8217;s just my big dome, but they were noticeably tighter at the front of my ear than the back, so I was constantly adjusting or trying to twist them.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll say this: If they add a bit more adjustment to the cups, these would be my default recommendation over the 7P/7X. As exciting as the SteelSeries sound is to me, the Cloud IIs seem more like what people expect, and are $50 cheaper.</p>
<h3>Logitech G-733 &#8211; $130</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2076126" style="width: 2393px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2076126" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2076126 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-2.jpg" alt="" width="2383" height="1636" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-2.jpg 2383w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-2.jpg?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-2.jpg?resize=300,206 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-2.jpg?resize=768,527 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-2.jpg?resize=680,467 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-2.jpg?resize=1536,1055 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-2.jpg?resize=2048,1406 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-2.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2383px) 100vw, 2383px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2076126" class="wp-caption-text">The matte texture of the G733s had a weird interaction with my camera — they don&#8217;t look speckly IRL. Image Credits: Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>These are <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/logitech" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="logitech">Logitech&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> streamer-friendly, color-coordinated, LED-sporting set, but they&#8217;re better than the loud design would suggest.</p>
<p>The sound is definitely gaming-forward, with a definite emphasis on the low end and a very central, present sound that was a lot like the Cloud II.</p>
<p>To be honest, I was not expecting the G733s to be very comfortable — their stiff plastic look suggested they&#8217;d creak, weigh down my ears and crush my noggin. But in fact they&#8217;re really light and quite comfy! There&#8217;s a lot of play in the positions of the earcups. The fit is a little odd in that there&#8217;s a plainly inferior version of the 7P/7X&#8217;s &#8220;ski goggle&#8221; strap that really only has four settings, while the cups slide up and down about two thirds of an inch. It was <em>just</em> enough to accommodate my (again, apparently very large) head.</p>
<p>The mic boom is rather short, and sadly there is no indicator for when the mic is on or off, which is sometimes a minor inconvenience and sometimes a major pain. You can tell from the sound the mute button makes, though.</p>
<p>The volume dial is nice and smooth, though the &#8220;clicks&#8221; are really far apart. I like the texture of it and the mic mute button, the power button not so much. But it works.</p>
<p>The colors may not be to everyone&#8217;s liking, but I have to hand it to Logitech for going all the way. The headset, mic and even the USB dongle are all the same shade, making it much easier to keep track of them in my growing pile of headphones and widgets.</p>
<h3>Logitech Pro-X &#8211; $200</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2076129" style="width: 2510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-4.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2076129" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2076129 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-4.jpg" alt="" width="2500" height="1791" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-4.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-4.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-4.jpg?resize=300,215 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-4.jpg?resize=768,550 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-4.jpg?resize=680,487 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-4.jpg?resize=1536,1100 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-4.jpg?resize=2048,1467 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-4.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2500px) 100vw, 2500px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2076129" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Currently Logitech&#8217;s most premium set of gaming headphones, the Pro-X abandon the bright, plasticky look of its other sets and goes for understated and black.</p>
<p>The sound of the Logitech is big and very clear, with almost a reference feel in how balanced the bands are. I felt more presence in the mid-lows of smart bass-playing than the other sets. There is a &#8220;surround&#8221; feel that makes it feel more like you&#8217;re in a room of well-configured speakers than headphones, something that I think emerges from a de-emphasis of the center channel. The media is &#8220;out there,&#8221; not &#8220;in here.&#8221; It&#8217;s not a bad or a good thing, just distinct from the others.</p>
<p>The controls are about on par with the Cloud II&#8217;s: a nice frictiony volume wheel controlling system volume, a nice mic toggle button and a fairly meaty on-off switch you&#8217;re unlikely to trip on purpose.</p>
<p>Also like the Cloud IIs, there is no rotation to the earcups, making them less comfortable to me than the ATs and SteelSeries, and Logitech&#8217;s cheaper G-733s. A larger head than my own, if that&#8217;s possible, would definitely feel clamped. I do think these would wear in well, but all the same a bit of play would help a lot.</p>
<p>The external material, a satinized matte plastic, looks truly lovely but is an absolute fingerprint magnet. Considering you&#8217;ll be handling these a lot (and let&#8217;s be honest, not necessarily with freshly washed hands), you&#8217;re going to need to wipe them down rather more than any of the others I tested.</p>
<h3>Razer Blackshark V2 Pro &#8211; $180</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2076125" style="width: 2510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2076125" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2076125 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-1.jpg" alt="" width="2500" height="1826" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-1.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-1.jpg?resize=150,110 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-1.jpg?resize=300,219 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-1.jpg?resize=768,561 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-1.jpg?resize=680,497 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-1.jpg?resize=1536,1122 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-1.jpg?resize=2048,1496 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/headphones-review-1.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2500px) 100vw, 2500px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2076125" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>The understated Razer Blackshark V2 Pro soon became my go-to for PC gaming when the SteelSeries set was attached to the PS5.</p>
<p>Their sound is definitely gaming-focused, with extra oomph in the lows and mid-lows, but music didn&#8217;t sound overly shifted in that direction. The soundstage is full but not startlingly so, and everything sounded detailed without being harsh.</p>
<p>The Razers look heavy but aren&#8217;t — it varies day to day but I think they&#8217;re definitely competing for &#8220;most comfortable&#8221; with the A-Ts and SteelSeries. The cups feel spacious and have a nice seal, making for a very isolated listening experience. Adjustment is done with the wires attached to the cups, which is nothing special — I kind of wish this setup would let you adjust the cant as well as the height. The material is like the Logitechs — prone to fingerprints, though a little less so, in my experience.</p>
<p>Their controls are very well designed and laid out, all on one side. The protruding (system-independent) volume knob may seem odd at first but you&#8217;ll love it soon. The one big notch or click indicates exactly 50%, which is super useful for quick &#8220;calibration,&#8221; and turning the knob is smooth yet resistant enough that I never once accidentally changed it. Meanwhile there are conveniently placed and distinguishable buttons for mute and power, and ports for the detachable mic, charge cord and 3.5mm input.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m hard pressed to think of any downsides to the Blackshark except that it doesn&#8217;t work with consoles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/review-wireless-headsets-from-logitech-audio-technica-steelseries-hyperx-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2064763</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 ways the pandemic is transforming tech spending</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/3-ways-the-pandemic-is-transforming-tech-spending/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/3-ways-the-pandemic-is-transforming-tech-spending/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 19:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B2B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coupa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital transformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We don’t believe enterprises or consumers will revert to the old ways of doing things when the pandemic subsides. Welcome to the next phase of tech spending.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Eric Tan</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Eric Tan is Senior Vice President of IT and Business Services <a href="https://www.coupa.com/">Coupa</a>, a leader in business spend management and a former Battery portfolio company.	</div>
	
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Scott Goering</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Scott Goering is VP of Business Development at <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/battery-ventures" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="battery-ventures">Battery Ventures <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Ever since the pandemic hit the U.S. in full force last March, the B2B tech community keeps asking the same questions: Are businesses spending more on technology? What’s the money getting spent on? Is the sales cycle faster? What trends will likely carry into 2021?</p>
<p>Recently we decided to join forces to answer these questions. We analyzed data from the just-released Q4 2020 Outlook of the <a href="https://www.coupa.com/thecoupaBSI/">Coupa Business Spend Index (BSI)</a><u>,</u> a leading indicator of economic growth, in light of hundreds of conversations we have had with business-tech buyers this year.</p>
<p>A former Battery Ventures portfolio company, Coupa* is a business spend-management company that has cumulatively processed <a href="https://investors.coupa.com/static-files/54a36328-5073-4176-abcb-0c450bee9e64">more than $2 trillion in business spending</a>. This perspective gives Coupa unique, real-time insights into tech spending trends across multiple industries.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Tech spending is continuing despite the economic recession &#8212; which helps explain why many startups are raising large rounds and even tapping public markets for capital.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Broadly speaking, tech spending is continuing despite the economic recession &#8212; which helps explain why many tech startups are raising large financing rounds and even tapping the public markets for capital. Here are our three specific takeaways on current tech spending:</p>
<h2>Spending is shifting away from remote collaboration to SaaS and cloud computing</h2>
<p>Tech spending ranks among the hottest boardroom topics today. Decisions that used to be confined to the CIO’s organization are now operationally and strategically critical to the CEO. Multiple reasons drive this shift, but the pandemic has forced businesses to operate and engage with customers differently, almost overnight. Boards recognize that companies must change their business models and operations if they don’t want to become obsolete. The question on everyone’s mind is no longer “what are our technology investments?” but rather, “how fast can they happen?”</p>
<p>Spending on WFH/remote collaboration tools has largely run its course in the first wave of adaptation forced by the pandemic. Now we’re seeing a second wave of tech spending, in which enterprises adopt technology to make operations easier and simply keep their doors open.</p>
<p>SaaS solutions are replacing unsustainable manual processes. Consider Rhode Island’s decision to <a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/curiosity/how-surveys-are-powering-rhode-island-gov-gina-raimondos-fight-against-coronavirus/">shift from in-person citizen surveying to using SurveyMonkey</a>. Many companies are shifting their vendor payments to digital payments, ditching paper checks entirely. Utility provider PG&amp;E is accelerating its digital transformation roadmap from five years to two years.</p>
<p>The second wave of adaptation has also pushed many companies to embrace the cloud, as this chart makes clear:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2083157" style="width: 890px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2083157" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2083157" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image001.png" alt="covid-19 has expanded cloud adoption chart" width="880" height="495" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image001.png 880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image001.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image001.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image001.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image001.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image001.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 880px) 100vw, 880px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2083157" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.battery.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Battery Ventures <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Similarly, the difficulty of maintaining a traditional data center during a pandemic has pushed many companies to finally shift to cloud infrastructure under COVID. As they migrate that workload to the cloud, the pie is still expanding. Goldman Sachs and Battery Ventures data suggest $600 billion worth of disruption potential will bleed into 2021 and beyond.</p>
<p>In addition to SaaS and cloud adoption, companies across sectors are spending on technologies to reduce their reliance on humans. For instance, Tyson Foods<strong> </strong>is investing in and accelerating the adoption of automated technology to process poultry, pork and beef.</p>
<h2>All companies are digital product companies now</h2>
<p>Mention “digital product company” in the past, and we’d all think of Netflix. But now <em>every</em> company has to reimagine itself as offering digital products in a meaningful way.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/3-ways-the-pandemic-is-transforming-tech-spending/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082850</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zephr raises $8M to help news publishers grow subscription revenue</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/zephr-bdmi-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/zephr-bdmi-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 19:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BDMI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zephr]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Zephr has raised $8 million in a new funding round led by Bertelsmann Digital Media Investments (owned by media giant Bertelsmann). The London-headquarted startup&#8217;s customers already include publishers like McClatchy, News Corp Australia, Dennis Publishing and PEI Media. CEO James Henderson told me via email that rather than creating &#8220;a monolithic product that tries to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.zephr.com">Zephr</a> has raised $8 million in a new funding round led by <a href="https://www.bdmifund.com">Bertelsmann Digital Media Investments</a> (owned by media giant Bertelsmann).</p>
<p>The London-headquarted startup&#8217;s customers already include publishers like McClatchy, News Corp Australia, Dennis Publishing and PEI Media. CEO James Henderson told me via email that rather than creating &#8220;a monolithic product that tries to do a bit of everything,&#8221; Zephr is &#8220;focused entirely on the experience and journey for the prospect or customer,&#8221; driving an average 150% increase in conversion rates and 25% increase in subscription revenue within the first six months.</p>
<p>Henderson added, &#8220;By offering the right product, package or message at the right time to the right person, Zephr improves conversion rates, drastically decreases churn and drives new, stable revenue.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To do this, Zephr largely relies on the publisher&#8217;s first-party data about its readers — Henderson said that this data is &#8220;by far the most important and powerful type of data that Zephr both uses and generates.&#8221; But it also takes advantage of contextual data, such as &#8220;time of day, to location, device or consumption patterns.&#8221;</p>
<p>He also noted that Zephr is a no-code tool, allowing non-technical members of the marketing, revenue and product teams to use a drag-and-drop editor to create different customer journeys.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2083186" style="width: 487px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2083186" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2083186" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Feature-RuleFeature-Rule-iPad.jpg?w=477" alt="Zephr" width="477" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Feature-RuleFeature-Rule-iPad.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Feature-RuleFeature-Rule-iPad.jpg?resize=105,150 105w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Feature-RuleFeature-Rule-iPad.jpg?resize=210,300 210w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Feature-RuleFeature-Rule-iPad.jpg?resize=768,1096 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Feature-RuleFeature-Rule-iPad.jpg?resize=477,680 477w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Feature-RuleFeature-Rule-iPad.jpg?resize=35,50 35w" sizes="(max-width: 477px) 100vw, 477px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2083186" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Zephr</p></div></p>
<p>Asked how the pandemic has affected the startup&#8217;s business, Henderson said there were both &#8220;positive and negative indicators,&#8221; with newsrooms seeing record readership but in some cases also freezing spending.</p>
<p>&#8220;As firms prepare for a &#8216;post-pandemic&#8217; world, we are beginning to see our markets seize the opportunity of all these new potential subscribers and invest in subscription models &#8212; and in Zephr.&#8221; he said. &#8220;In publishing and news media, the old model of dominant advertising revenue is on the way out and we are well-placed to capitalize on that interest.&#8221;</p>
<p>The new funding also includes financing from Silicon Valley Bank UK Branch and brings Zephr&#8217;s total funding to $11 million. Previous investors include Knight Capital and Nauta Capital.</p>
<p>According to the company&#8217;s funding announcement, this money will go toward further product development (with a focus on increased personalization), as well as expansion across the United States, Europe and Asia.</p>
<p>“The recent weakness in the advertising market increased pressure for media companies to diversify revenue streams and aim to introduce or optimize subscription models,&#8221; said <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/bertelsmann-digital-media-investments" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="bertelsmann-digital-media-investments">BDMI <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Managing Director Urs Cete in a statement. &#8220;We recognise Zephr’s excellent technology that empowers publishers to galvanise the online subscription opportunity and create customer journeys that are truly unique.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="g3r0InJ35g"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-news-showcase-paywalled-stories/">Google says its News Showcase will add free access to paywalled stories</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google says its News Showcase will add free access to paywalled stories&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-news-showcase-paywalled-stories/embed/#?secret=g3r0InJ35g" data-secret="g3r0InJ35g" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/zephr-bdmi-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083178</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revel pulls electric mopeds after failing to make a dent in Austin&#8217;s car culture</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/revel-pulls-electric-mopeds-after-failing-to-make-a-dent-in-austins-car-culture/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/revel-pulls-electric-mopeds-after-failing-to-make-a-dent-in-austins-car-culture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 18:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shared electric moped startup Revel said Friday that it will shut down its service in Austin later this month. The startup&#8217;s CEO and co-founder Frank Reig didn&#8217;t place the entire blame on the COVID-19 pandemic, which has caused ridership to fall across shared micromobility services as well as public transit, for the company&#8217;s decision. Instead, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Shared electric moped startup <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/revel-d2f5" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="revel-d2f5">Revel <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said Friday that it will shut down its service in Austin later this month.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s CEO and co-founder Frank Reig didn&#8217;t place the entire blame on the COVID-19 pandemic, which has caused ridership to fall across shared micromobility services as well as public transit, for the company&#8217;s decision. Instead, Reig cited the combination of Austin&#8217;s &#8220;deep-rooted&#8221; car culture, which has only become further engrained during COVID. The service will shut down in Austin on December 18.</p>
<p>&#8220;When Revel came to Austin we knew there would be challenges,&#8221; Reig wrote in the statement that was posted on Twitter. &#8220;In addition to having a less dense urban core than our other markets, the city&#8217;s deep-rooted car culture was proven difficult to penetrate, especially during COVID.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">A statement from our CEO &amp; Co-Founder: <a href="https://t.co/Cl5LSgGv5C">pic.twitter.com/Cl5LSgGv5C</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Revel (@_GoRevel) <a href="https://twitter.com/_GoRevel/status/1334879001555447808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;One thing we’ve learned is that Austin, unlike markets that have more robust public transportation infrastructure, is a city that is still very car-dependent, and we have found our electric mopeds do not thrive in a “car culture” environment,&#8221; a company spokesperson said in an email.</p>
<p dir="ltr">COVID was an additional contributing factor. The lack of visitors to the city who could rely on Revel instead of renting and garaging a car, and overall reduction in movement among those who work and live in Austin, exacerbated the market challenges.</p>
<p>Revel, founded in March 2018 by Frank Reig and Paul Suhey, started with a pilot program in Brooklyn and later expanded to Queens, the Bronx and sections of Manhattan. It has been on a fast-paced growth track thanks to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/electric-moped-startup-revel-raises-27-6-million-as-it-eyes-new-markets/">$27.6 million in capital</a> raised October 2019 in a Series A round led by Ibex Investors. The equity round included newcomer Toyota AI Ventures and further investments from Blue Collective, Launch Capital and Maniv Mobility.</p>
<p>Revel <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">expanded to Austin, Miami and Washington, D.C in its first 18 months of operation. In January, the company launched in Oakland and received a permit in July to operate in San Francisco.</span></p>
<p>Revel has had a challenging year, and not just because of the COVID-19 pandemic. The company voluntarily shut down operations in New York on July 28 after several of its users died in crashes. The company restarted its 3,000-strong fleet of mopeds in four boroughs after the city of New York approved its relaunch plan, which included several new features in its app aimed at increasing safety. Revel added training videos, tests and a helmet selfie feature that requires photographic evidence the user is wearing a helmet and a community reporting tool.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/revel-pulls-electric-mopeds-after-failing-to-make-a-dent-in-austins-car-culture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083173</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrimaHealth Credit offers a buy-now, pay-later lending service for elective procedures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/primahealth-credit-offers-a-buy-now-pay-later-lending-service-for-elective-procedures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/primahealth-credit-offers-a-buy-now-pay-later-lending-service-for-elective-procedures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 18:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arizona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit score]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lasik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oklahoma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthodontics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PrimaHealth Credit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083150</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Newport Beach, California-based healthcare lending service PrimaHealth Credit is now pitching point-of-sale lending services for elective medical procedures. Taking the kinds of financial lending services that have been popularized by companies like Klarna and Affirm, PrimaHealth Credit is bringing them into elective surgical space for things like cataract surgery, orthodontic work, dental care or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Newport Beach, California-based healthcare lending service <a href="http://www.primahealthcredit.com/">PrimaHealth Credit</a> is now pitching point-of-sale lending services for elective medical procedures.</p>
<p>Taking the kinds of financial lending services that have been popularized by companies like <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/klarna" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="klarna">Klarna <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Affirm, PrimaHealth Credit is bringing them into elective surgical space for things like cataract surgery, orthodontic work, dental care or LASIK.</p>
<p>&#8220;For many dental, orthodontics, LASIK, and cataract surgery patients, our BNPL product is a ‘last resort’ &#8211; the difference between getting the treatment they need, or not,” said Brendon Kensel, founder and CEO of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/primahealth-credit" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="primahealth-credit">PrimaHealth Credit, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> in a statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company expects that patients will pay somewhere between 25% and 50% of the cost of their treatment up front with repayment durations for the loans ranging between two and four months.</p>
<p>Rates for the loans will range from 19.99% to 24.99% APR with average loan sizes coming in at around $1,800 across dental, orthodontics and LASIK, according to the company.</p>
<p>“Until now, when providers couldn’t approve patients for an existing payment plan, they’d either forego providing them care or take them on anyway, exposing themselves to significant liability as they struggle with adequately assessing creditworthiness and properly servicing and collecting loans,” Kensel said.</p>
<p>The program not only handles loan origination for healthcare practices, but handles the back-office tasks for payment and servicing.</p>
<p>“Our goal as a company is to remove barriers to patient acceptance and help people who have the means but not necessarily the credit score to get the quality care that everyone deserves,&#8221; Kensel said.</p>
<p>Using the PrimaHealth Credit mobile app, patients can receive instant credit decisions and choose the payment plan that works best for them. The company said the service is currently available in <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/arizona" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="arizona">Arizona, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> California, Florida, Oklahoma, and Texas and will be expanded to all 50 states by 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/primahealth-credit-offers-a-buy-now-pay-later-lending-service-for-elective-procedures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083150</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Slack and Salesforce execs think they&#8217;re better together</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/why-slack-and-salesforce-execs-think-theyre-better-together/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/why-slack-and-salesforce-execs-think-theyre-better-together/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 17:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bret Taylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce-Slack deal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewart butterfield]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Salesforce bought Slack earlier this week for $27.7 billion, it was in some ways the end of a startup fairytale. Slack was the living embodiment of the Silicon Valley startup success fantasy. It started as a pivot from a game company, of all things. It raised $1.4 billion, went from zero to a $7 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When <a href="http://salesforce.com">Salesforce</a> bought <a href="http://slack.com">Slack</a> earlier <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">this week for $27.7 billion</a>, it was in some ways the end of a startup fairytale. Slack was the living embodiment of the Silicon Valley startup success fantasy. It <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/30/the-slack-origin-story/">started as a pivot</a> from a game company, of all things. It raised $1.4 billion, went from zero to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/07/slack-raising/">a $7 billion valuation</a> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/19/slack-reportedly-prices-ipo-at-26-per-share/">IPO</a>, checking off every box on the startup founder&#8217;s wish list.</p>
<p>Then quite suddenly this week, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/slack" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="slack">Slack <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> was part of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/salesforce" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="salesforce">Salesforce, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> plucked off the market for an enormous sum of money.</p>
<p>While we might not ever know the back (Slack) room maneuvering that went on to make the deal a reality, it is interesting to note that Slack CEO <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/stewart-butterfield" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="stewart-butterfield">Stewart Butterfield <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> told me in an interview this week that he was not actually trying to sell the company when he approached Salesforce president and COO <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/bret-taylor" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="bret-taylor">Bret Taylor <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> earlier this year. Instead, he wanted to buy something from them.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;I actually talked to Bret in the early days of the pandemic to see if they wanted to sell us Quip because I thought it would be good for us, and I didn&#8217;t really know what their plans were [for it]. He said he&#8217;d get back to me, and then got back to me six months later or so,&#8221; Butterfield said.</p>
<p>At that point, the conversation flipped and the companies began a series of discussions that eventually led to Salesforce acquiring Slack.</p>
<h2>Big money, big expectations</h2>
<p>From the Salesforce perspective, Taylor says that the Slack deal was worth the money because it really allows his company to bring together all the pieces of their platform, one that has expanded over the years from pure CRM to include marketing, customer service, data visualization, workflow and more. Taylor also said that having Slack gives Salesforce a missing communication layer on top of its other products, something especially important when interactions with customers, partners or fellow employees have become mostly digital.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we say we really want Slack to be this next generation interface for Customer 360, what we mean is we&#8217;re pulling together all these systems. How do you rally your teams around these systems in this digital work-anywhere world that we&#8217;re in right now where these teams are distributed and collaboration is more important than ever,&#8221; Taylor said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3kxr2l48Rp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/everyone-has-an-opinion-on-the-27-7b-slack-acquisition/">Everyone has an opinion on the $27.7B Slack acquisition</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Everyone has an opinion on the $27.7B Slack acquisition&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/everyone-has-an-opinion-on-the-27-7b-slack-acquisition/embed/#?secret=3kxr2l48Rp" data-secret="3kxr2l48Rp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Butterfield sees a natural connection between what people do in the course of their work, what machines do behind the scenes in these systems of record and engagement and how Slack can help bridge the gap between humans and machines.</p>
<p>He says that by putting Slack in the middle of business processes, you can begin to eliminate friction that occurs in complex enterprise software like Salesforce. Instead of moving stuff through email, clicking a link, opening a browser, signing in and then finally accessing the tool you want, the approval could be built into a single Slack message.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you have hundreds of those kinds of actions a day, there&#8217;s a real opportunity to increase the velocity, and that has an impact, and not just in the minutes saved by the person doing the approval, but the speed of how the whole business operates,&#8221; Butterfield said.</p>
<h2>Competing with Microsoft</h2>
<p>While neither executive said the deal was about competing with Microsoft, it was likely an underlying reason that the companies decided to join forces. They may prove better together than they are separately, and both have complicated histories with Microsoft.</p>
<p>Slack has had an ongoing battle with Microsoft and its Teams product for years. It <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/22/slack-has-filed-an-antitrust-complaint-against-microsoft-teams-in-the-eu/">filed suit against the company</a> last summer in the EU over what it called unfairly bundling of Teams for free with Office 365. In an interview last year with The Wall Street Journal, Butterfield said that he believes Microsoft sees his company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/24/stewart-butterfield-says-microsoft-sees-slack-as-existential-threat/">as an existential threat</a>. Hyperbole aside, there is tension and competition between the two enterprise software companies.</p>
<p>Salesforce and Microsoft also have a long history, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-salesforce-microsoft/salesforce-sues-microsoft-as-legal-feud-escalates-idUSTRE65O4HT20100625">from lawsuits in the early days</a> to making friends and working together when it makes sense after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/04/after-5-years-microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-has-transformed-more-than-the-stock-price/">Satya Nadella took over in 2014</a>, while still competing hard in the market. It&#8217;s hard not to see the deal in that context.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dLhIzLh1wG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/as-slack-acquisition-rumors-swirl-a-look-at-salesforces-six-biggest-deals/">As Slack acquisition rumors swirl, a look at Salesforce&#8217;s six biggest deals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As Slack acquisition rumors swirl, a look at Salesforce&#8217;s six biggest deals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/as-slack-acquisition-rumors-swirl-a-look-at-salesforces-six-biggest-deals/embed/#?secret=dLhIzLh1wG" data-secret="dLhIzLh1wG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/everyone-has-an-opinion-on-the-27-7b-slack-acquisition/">a recent interview with TechCrunch</a>, Battery Ventures general partner Neeraj Agrawal said the deal was at least partially about catching Microsoft.</p>
<p>&#8220;To get to a market cap of $1 trillion, Salesforce now has to take MSFT head on. Until now, the company has mostly been able to stay in its own swim lane in terms of products,&#8221; Agrawal told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>As for Butterfield, while he saw the obvious competition, he denied the deal was about putting his company in a better position to compete with his rival.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t think that was really an important part of the rationale, at least for me,&#8221; he said, adding &#8220;the competition with Microsoft is overblown. The challenge for us was the narrative. They&#8217;re just good PR or something that I couldn&#8217;t figure out,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>While Butterfield cited a list of large clients in enterprise tech, insurance and banking, the narrative has always been that Slack was favored by developer teams, which is where it initially gained traction. Whatever the reality, with Salesforce, Slack is definitely in a better position to compete with any and all comers in the enterprise communications space, and while it will be part of Salesforce, the two companies also have to figure out how to maintain some separation.</p>
<h2>Keeping Slack independent</h2>
<p>Taylor certainly recognizes that Slack&#8217;s current customers are watching closely to see how they handle the acquisition, and his company will have to walk a fine line between respecting the brand and product independence on one hand, while finding ways to create and build upon existing hooks into Salesforce to allow the CRM giant to take full advantage of its substantial investment.</p>
<p>It won&#8217;t be easy to do, but you can see a similar level of independence in some of Salesforce&#8217;s recent big-money purchases like MuleSoft, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/20/salesforce-is-buying-mulesoft-at-enterprise-value-of-6-5-billion/">it bought in 2018 for $6.5 billion</a>, and Tableau, the company it bought last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/10/salesforce-is-buying-data-visualization-company-tableau-for-15-7b-in-all-stock-deal/">for more than $15 billion</a>. As Butterfield points out, those two companies have clearly maintained their brand identity and independence, and he sees them as role models for Slack.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wKb3LCzZkN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/slacks-stock-climbs-on-possible-salesforce-acquisition/">Slack’s stock climbs on possible Salesforce acquisition</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Slack’s stock climbs on possible Salesforce acquisition&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/slacks-stock-climbs-on-possible-salesforce-acquisition/embed/#?secret=wKb3LCzZkN" data-secret="wKb3LCzZkN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;So there&#8217;s a layer of independence that&#8217;s like that [for Mulesoft and Tableau] because it&#8217;s not going to help anyone call us Chat Cloud or something like that. They paid a lot of money for us, so they want us to do more of what we were already doing,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Taylor, whose opinion matters greatly here, certainly sees it in similar terms.</p>
<p>&#8220;We want to make sure we have a real integrated value proposition, a real integrated platform for developers, but also maintain Slack&#8217;s technology independence, technology agnostic platform and its brand,&#8221; he said.</p>
<h2>Better together</h2>
<p>As for the companies coming together, both men see a lot of potential here to merge Slack communications with Salesforce&#8217;s enterprise software prowess to make something better, and Taylor sees Slack helping link the two with workflows and automations.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you think about automation, it&#8217;s event driven, these long-running processes, automations. If you look at what people are doing with the Slack platform, it&#8217;s essentially incorporating workflows and bots and all these things. The combination of the Salesforce platform where I think we have the best automation intelligence capabilities with the Slack platform is incredible,&#8221; Taylor said.</p>
<p>The challenge these two men now face as they move forward with this acquisition, and all of the expectations inherent in a deal this large, is making it work. Salesforce has a lot of experience with large acquisitions, and they have handled some well, and some not so well. It&#8217;s going to be imperative for both companies that they get this right. It&#8217;s now up to Taylor and Butterfield to make sure that happens.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bcxKYRGv7r"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">Salesforce buys Slack in a $27.7B megadeal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce buys Slack in a $27.7B megadeal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/embed/#?secret=bcxKYRGv7r" data-secret="bcxKYRGv7r" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/why-slack-and-salesforce-execs-think-theyre-better-together/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083109</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revolut lets businesses accept online payments</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/revolut-lets-businesses-accept-online-payments/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/revolut-lets-businesses-accept-online-payments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 16:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fintech startup Revolut is launching its own acquiring solution. With this move, the company is competing directly with Stripe, Adyen, Braintree or Checkout.com. This is an in-house product and not just a fresh coat of paint on an existing solution. As a reminder, Revolut already offers business accounts. It lets you send and receive international [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Fintech startup <a href="https://www.revolut.com">Revolut</a> is launching its own <a href="https://www.revolut.com/business/online-payments">acquiring solution</a>. With this move, the company is competing directly with Stripe, Adyen, Braintree or Checkout.com. This is an in-house product and not just a fresh coat of paint on an existing solution.</p>
<p>As a reminder, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/revolut" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="revolut">Revolut <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> already offers <a href="https://www.revolut.com/business/">business accounts</a>. It lets you send and receive international payments, and exchange funds in multiple currencies. You also can order debit cards to spend money from your Revolut account directly.</p>
<p>With Revolut’s acquiring solution, the company is going one step further, as you can now accept card payments from your customers. Revolut supports 14 currencies and settles payments on your Revolut Business account the next day.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>When it comes to fees, you get a small allowance of free card payment processing fees <a href="https://www.revolut.com/business/business-account-plans">depending on your plan</a>. Above that limit, you pay 1.3% on card transactions from customers based in Europe and the U.K. For other cards, you pay 2.8% on all transactions — there’s no free allowance.</p>
<p>This is slightly cheaper than Stripe, which costs 1.4% + £0.20 for European cards and 2.9% + £0.20 for non-European cards. Of course, companies like Stripe have been optimizing their payments infrastructure for many years. Right now, Stripe supports more payment methods, more currencies, advanced fraud prevention features, etc.</p>
<p>After you’ve created your merchant account, Revolut offers plugins for WooCommerce, Prestashop and Magento. You can also use the Merchant API to add a checkout widget on your custom website.</p>
<p>If you’re a freelancer and you just need to send a couple of invoices per month, you can also generate <a href="https://www.revolut.com/business/payment-links">payment links</a>. The recipient can then pay from a web page hosted by Revolut.</p>
<p>The main advantage of Revolut’s acquiring solution is that it’s integrated with Revolut Business. You can see payments and banking in the same interface, you don’t need to alternate between your Stripe account and your bank account to reconcile transaction data.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TvA9OmGRfx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/24/revolut-extends-series-d-round-to-580-million-with-80-million-in-new-funding/">Revolut extends Series D round to $580 million with $80 million in new funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Revolut extends Series D round to $580 million with $80 million in new funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/24/revolut-extends-series-d-round-to-580-million-with-80-million-in-new-funding/embed/#?secret=TvA9OmGRfx" data-secret="TvA9OmGRfx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It could work particularly well for B2B businesses that don’t handle a ton of transactions and don’t want to set up a separate payments solution. Let’s see what customers think of the API when they start using it.</p>
<p>Online payments are available for business customers in the U.K., Austria, Belgium, Denmark, France, Germany, Ireland, Italy, Netherlands, Poland, Portugal, Spain and Sweden. The rest of the European Economic Area should get the feature soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/revolut-lets-businesses-accept-online-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083117</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DoorDash amps its IPO range ahead of blockbuster IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/doordash-amps-its-ipo-range-ahead-of-blockbuster-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/doordash-amps-its-ipo-range-ahead-of-blockbuster-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 15:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DoorDash filed a fresh S-1/A, providing the market with a new price range for its impending IPO. The American food delivery unicorn now expects to debut at $90 to $95 per share, up from a previous range of $75 to $85. That&#8217;s a bump of 20% on the low end and 12% on the upper [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/doordash" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="doordash">DoorDash <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> filed a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1792789/000119312520309968/d752207ds1a.htm">fresh S-1/A</a>, providing the market with a new price range for its impending IPO.</p>
<p>The American food delivery unicorn now expects to debut at $90 to $95 per share, up from a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/doordash-aims-to-add-11-billion-to-its-valuation-during-public-offering/">previous range of $75 to $85.</a> That&#8217;s a bump of 20% on the low end and 12% on the upper end of its IPO range.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>DoorDash still anticipates 317,656,521 shares outstanding after its IPO, giving the company a new, non-diluted valuation range between $28.6 billion and $30.2 billion. On a fully diluted basis, the company&#8217;s valuation rises to more than $35 billion.</p>
<p>For the on-demand giant, the upgrade is enormously positive news. Not only will its valuation stretch even further above its most recent private price &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/after-ipo-delays-doordash-confirms-400m-raise/">around $16 billion, set this summer</a> &#8212; but DoorDash will also raise even more money than it previously anticipated. That war chest will be welcome when a vaccine becomes widely available and food consumption habits could shift.</p>
<p>DoorDash will raise as much as $3.135 billion in its IPO, according to the filing.</p>
<p>After mulling over the company&#8217;s updated valuation from its new SEC filing, I&#8217;ve decided there are three things worth calling out and discussing. Let&#8217;s get into them.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s Friday, so to make our analysis as easy as possible I&#8217;ve broken it into discrete sections for your perusal. Let&#8217;s go!</p>
<h2>A path to profitability is important</h2>
<p>DoorDash&#8217;s most profitable quarters that we are aware of were its two most recent. During the June 30 quarter, the company saw positive net income of $23 million off revenues of $675 million. In the September 30 quarter, on the back of even more revenue growth, DoorDash lost a modest $42 million against $879 million in top line.</p>
<p>Those two quarters contrast with the first quarter of 2020 when DoorDash lost a far-greater $129 million against a far-smaller revenue result of $362 million, and Q4 2019 when the figures were a $134 million loss and revenues of just $298 million.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/doordash-amps-its-ipo-range-ahead-of-blockbuster-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083067</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enter new markets and embrace a distributed workforce to grow during a pandemic</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/enter-new-markets-and-embrace-a-distributed-workforce-to-grow-during-a-pandemic/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/enter-new-markets-and-embrace-a-distributed-workforce-to-grow-during-a-pandemic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 14:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommuting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We hope this guide gives founders and C-suite executives some food for thought in forming a plan for their international growth — and a pause for thought on those considering too bold an approach.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sarah Cole</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://linkedin.com/in/sarah-cole-7b3a2b36/">Sarah Cole</a> is a senior associate in <a href="https://www.taylorwessing.com/">Taylor Wessing</a>'s Silicon Valley office. She advises mostly North American technology and life sciences companies on their investments into the UK and Europe, including on European launches, cross-border M&amp;A, venture capital and other growth company investment work.	</div>
	
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mark Barron</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://linkedin.com/in/mark-barron-56014a/">Mark Barron</a> is the head of <a href="https://www.taylorwessing.com/">Taylor Wessing</a>'s market-leading technology and life sciences inward investment team, and advises North American companies on how to translate their domestic success to new jurisdictions and cultures and to thrive as global businesses.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Many companies will not see the uncertainty of a global pandemic as the perfect moment to go international, but for others (particularly in healthcare, online communications, and workplace mobility) the market is stronger than ever and companies are having to respond quickly internationally to both service existing clients and take advantage of the growth in demand.</p>
<p>We and our team at <a href="https://www.taylorwessing.com/en">Taylor Wessing</a> advise 50 to 75 venture-backed North American companies each year on setting up in Europe or Asia. We’ve helped companies such as TaskRabbit, Lime, Glossier, InVision and many others translate their domestic success to new jurisdictions and cultures and to thrive as global businesses.</p>
<p>This is a practical guide to international expansion with the challenges of the current time in mind. It&#8217;s a quick-read providing some practical tips and sharing best practices from peer companies to help you come out of the pandemic with a strong international presence. A great deal of this advice is evergreen and will serve you well whatever the circumstances may be.</p>
<p>In particular, we&#8217;ll cover the rise (and risks) of distributed workforces — a way for CEOs to hire the best talent anywhere in the world. This has taken on new significance with the boom in remote working as one of several options for CEOs looking for strategic growth during and after COVID.</p>
<h2>Is this the right time to expand overseas?</h2>
<p>Ten years ago, the timing question was much simpler. Founders would first of all focus on developing a product and winning over their domestic market, funded through their Series A and B rounds, and then go on to raise their Series C round, which investors would expect to be used to push into new markets.</p>
<p>Since then, with the age of the smartphone in full swing and international direct ordering ubiquitous, opportunities to sell into new markets appeared far earlier in a company&#8217;s growth and there is no longer a canned strategy for timing your international expansion.</p>
<p>The current circumstances have exaggerated this trend. There are many challenges in traditional sectors, but also many new market opportunities quickly appearing in healthcare and other technology sectors with founders wanting to move quickly into new markets.</p>
<p>Although it may be tempting to just get a few sales people on the ground to go for it, we would still recommend laying some groundwork and making some key decisions before diving in. For example: ensuring management can give sufficient time and attention to the new market; tweaking your product to comply with local regulations; reworking your sales approach.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			If you are early-stage, tread carefully. Our belief is that the Series B round is still the earliest a founder or board should consider international expansion.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</span></p>
<p>If you are early-stage, tread carefully. Our belief is that the Series B round is still the earliest a founder or board should consider international expansion. The companies we&#8217;ve worked with who have moved earlier than the B round will generally end up realizing it&#8217;s too early. They&#8217;ll end up pressing pause, or making a full strategic exit, tail between legs.</p>
<p>International expansion is a matter of focus, as well as financial resources. Once you&#8217;re selling into a new market, everyone in the business needs to be thinking internationally, including the CEO, CFO, general counsel, the board, engineers and staff. It can stretch everyone before there are the necessary resources in place to cope.</p>
<h2>Decision made: How do you get going quickly?</h2>
<p>Even in the best of times our advice would be to not experiment or push the boundaries when it comes to your international strategy, do that elsewhere in your business. You should follow the path <em>most</em> travelled at this stage. This is especially true in the current climate. If you&#8217;re thinking of doing something new, something your peers haven&#8217;t done before, we should have a conversation first.</p>
<p>Whichever market you&#8217;ve chosen, there are some universal first steps (although they might vary slightly between jurisdictions). For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>If you have a permanent establishment for tax purposes (i.e., the local tax authorities consider you established enough to be paying income tax and corporation tax), work on the basis that you&#8217;ll need to incorporate a company or register a local branch.</li>
<li>Consider flexible options when it comes to taking on people (more on this below). Remember that in all cases local employment contracts will be needed (subject to the use of PEOs – see below).</li>
<li>Perhaps most importantly, local agreements transferring IP ownership will be needed (see next chapter).</li>
<li>There will also be some local filings (e.g., tax, corporate, payroll) where you will need a local service provider such as an accountant and payroll provider.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Common international expansion traps … and how to avoid them<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/enter-new-markets-and-embrace-a-distributed-workforce-to-grow-during-a-pandemic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082709</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grab-Singtel and Ant Group win digital bank licenses in Singapore</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/grab-singtel-and-ant-group-win-digital-bank-licenses-in-singapore/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/grab-singtel-and-ant-group-win-digital-bank-licenses-in-singapore/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 13:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ant group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[singtel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Singapore on Friday granted four firms, including Ant Group and Grab, licenses to run digital banks in the Southeast Asian country, in a move that would allow the tech giants to expand their financial services offerings. The nation’s central bank, Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS), said it applied a “rigorous, merit-based process” to select a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Singapore on Friday granted four firms, including <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/ant-group" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="ant-group">Ant Group <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/grabtaxi" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="grabtaxi">Grab, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> licenses to run digital banks in the Southeast Asian country, in a move that would allow the tech giants to expand their financial services offerings.</p>
<p>The nation’s central bank, Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS), said it applied a “rigorous, merit-based process” to select a strong slate of digital banks. As these digital banks start their pilot operations, MAS said it will review whether more companies could be granted this license.</p>
<p>A total of 21 firms, including TikTok-parent firm ByteDance, had applied to get a digital license, of which 14 met the eligibility criteria, MAS <a href="https://www.mas.gov.sg/news/media-releases/2020/mas-announces-successful-applicants-of-licences-to-operate-new-digital-banks-in-singapore">said</a>. Tech giants see a major opportunity in expanding to financial services as a way to supercharge their revenue in the rapidly growing region.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The other two licenses went to an entity wholly owned by internet giant Sea, and a consortium of Greenland Financial Holdings, Linklogis Hong Kong and Beijing Cooperative Equity Investment Fund Management.</p>
<p>Like traditional banks, Grab-<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/singtel" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="singtel">Singtel <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Sea will be able to offer customers banking accounts, debit and credit cards and other services. Digital wholesale banks &#8212; the licenses of which went to Ant-owned entity and Greenland Financial consortium &#8212; will serve small and medium-sized businesses. None of them will be required to have a physical presence.</p>
<p>“We expect them to thrive alongside the incumbent banks and raise the industry’s bar in delivering quality financial services, particularly for currently underserved businesses and individuals,” said MAS MD Ravi Menon in a statement. A handful of countries, including the U.K., India and Hong Kong, have streamlined their regulations in recent years to grant tech companies the ability to operate as digital banks.</p>
<p>Ride-hailing firm Grab and telecom operator Singtel <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/30/grab-and-singtel-team-up-to-apply-for-a-digital-full-bank-license-in-singapore/">formed a consortium last year</a> to apply for the digital full bank license. Their combined experience and expertise “will further our goal to empower more people to gain better control of their money and achieve better economic outcomes for themselves, their businesses and families,” said Anthony Tan, Group CEO &amp; co-founder of Grab, in a statement Friday.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vkzwxB0URn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/30/grab-and-singtel-team-up-to-apply-for-a-digital-full-bank-license-in-singapore/">Grab and Singtel team up to apply for a digital full bank license in Singapore</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Grab and Singtel team up to apply for a digital full bank license in Singapore&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/30/grab-and-singtel-team-up-to-apply-for-a-digital-full-bank-license-in-singapore/embed/#?secret=vkzwxB0URn" data-secret="vkzwxB0URn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“Over the years, Ant Group has accumulated substantial experience and proven success, especially in China where we work with partner financial institutions to serve the needs of SMEs,” Ant Group said in a statement. “We look forward to building stronger and deeper collaborations with all participants in the financial services industry in Singapore.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/grab-singtel-and-ant-group-win-digital-bank-licenses-in-singapore/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083051</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SunCulture wants to turn Africa into the world&#8217;s next bread basket, one solar water pump at a time</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/sunculture-wants-to-turn-africa-into-the-worlds-next-bread-basket-one-solar-water-pump-at-a-time/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/sunculture-wants-to-turn-africa-into-the-worlds-next-bread-basket-one-solar-water-pump-at-a-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 13:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agriculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[east africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethiopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nairobi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senegal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar Power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SunCulture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tanzania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The world&#8217;s food supply must double by the year 2050 to meet the demands of a growing population, according to a report from the United Nations. And as pressure mounts to find new crop land to support the growth, the world&#8217;s eyes are increasingly turning to the African continent as the next potential global bread [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The world&#8217;s food supply <a href="https://www.un.org/press/en/2009/gaef3242.doc.htm#:~:text=Food%20production%20must%20double%20by%202050%20to%20meet%20the%20demand,a%20panel%20discussion%20on%20%E2%80%9CNew">must double by the year 2050</a> to meet the demands of a growing population, according to a report from the United Nations. And as pressure mounts to find new crop land to support the growth, the world&#8217;s eyes are increasingly turning to the African continent as the next potential global bread basket.</p>
<p>While Africa has 65% of the world&#8217;s remaining uncultivated arable land, according to the African Development Bank, the countries on the continent face significant obstacles as they look to boost the productivity of their agricultural industries.</p>
<p>On the continent, 80% of families depend on agriculture for their livelihoods, but only 4% use irrigation. Many families also lack access to reliable and affordable electricity. It&#8217;s these twin problems that Samir Ibrahim and his co-founder at <a href="https://sunculture.com/">SunCulture</a>, Charlie Nichols, have spent the last eight years trying to solve.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Armed with a new financing model and purpose-built small solar-powered generators and water pumps, Nichols and Ibrahim have already built a network of customers using their equipment to increase incomes by anywhere from five to 10 times their previous levels by growing higher-value cash crops, cultivating more land and raising more livestock.</p>
<p>The company also just closed on $14 million in funding to expand its business across Africa.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have to double the amount of food we have to create by 2050, and if you look at where there are enough resources to grow food &#8212; all signs point to Africa. You have a lot of farmers and a lot of land, and a lot of resources,&#8221; Ibrahim said.</p>
<p>African small farmers face two big problems as they look to increase productivity, Ibrahim said.<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/apeel-gets-more-cash-to-fight-food-insecurity-in-emerging-markets-with-its-food-preserving-tech/"> One is access to markets</a>, which alone is a huge source of food waste, and the other is food security because of a lack of stable growing conditions exacerbated by climate change.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="z7F6zgsV8C"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/apeel-gets-more-cash-to-fight-food-insecurity-in-emerging-markets-with-its-food-preserving-tech/">Apeel gets more cash to fight poverty and food insecurity in emerging markets with its food-preserving tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apeel gets more cash to fight poverty and food insecurity in emerging markets with its food-preserving tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/apeel-gets-more-cash-to-fight-food-insecurity-in-emerging-markets-with-its-food-preserving-tech/embed/#?secret=z7F6zgsV8C" data-secret="z7F6zgsV8C" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As one small farmer <a href="https://www.economist.com/special-report/2020/03/26/african-countries-must-get-smarter-with-their-agriculture">told The Economist</a> earlier this year, “The rainy season is not predictable. When it is supposed to rain it doesn’t, then it all comes at once.”</p>
<p>Ibrahim, who graduated from New York University in 2011, had long been drawn to the African continent. His father was born in Tanzania and his mother grew up in <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/kenya" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="kenya">Kenya <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and they eventually found their way to the U.S. But growing up, Ibrahim was told stories about East Africa.</p>
<p>While pursuing a business degree at NYU Ibrahim met Nichols, who had been working on large-scale solar projects in the U.S., at an event for budding entrepreneurs in New York.</p>
<p>The two began a friendship and discussed potential business opportunities stemming from a paper Nichols had read about renewable energy applications in the agriculture industry.</p>
<p>After winning second place in a business plan competition sponsored by NYU, the two men decided to prove that they should have won first. They booked tickets to Kenya and tried to launch a pilot program for their business selling solar-powered water pumps and generators.</p>
<p>Conceptually solar water-pumping systems have been around for decades. But as the costs of solar equipment and energy storage have declined, the systems that leverage those components have become more accessible to a broader swath of the global population.</p>
<p>That timing is part of what has enabled <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/sunculture-2" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="sunculture-2">SunCulture <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> to succeed where other companies have stumbled. &#8220;We moved here at a time when [solar] reached grid parity in a lot of markets. It was at a time when a lot of development financiers were funding the nexus between agriculture and energy,&#8221; said Ibrahim.</p>
<p>Initially, the company sold its integrated energy generation and water-pumping systems to the middle income farmers who hold jobs in cities like Nairobi and cultivate crops on land they own in rural areas. These &#8220;telephone farmers&#8221; were willing to spend the $5,000 required to install SunCulture&#8217;s initial systems.</p>
<p>Now, the cost of a system is somewhere between $500 and $1,000 and is more accessible for the 570 million farming households across the word &#8212; with the company&#8217;s &#8220;pay-as-you-grow&#8221; model.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a spin on what&#8217;s become a popular business model for the distribution of solar systems of all types across Africa. Investors have poured nearly $1 billion into the development of off-grid solar energy and retail technology companies like M-kopa, Greenlight Planet, d.light design, ZOLA Electric and SolarHome, according to Ibrahim. In some ways, SunCulture just extends that model to agricultural applications.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PGM3eQyTdO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/the-sun-exchange-raises-3m-for-crypto-driven-solar-power-in-africa/">The Sun Exchange raises $3M for crypto-driven solar power in Africa</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Sun Exchange raises $3M for crypto-driven solar power in Africa&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/the-sun-exchange-raises-3m-for-crypto-driven-solar-power-in-africa/embed/#?secret=PGM3eQyTdO" data-secret="PGM3eQyTdO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We have had to bundle services and financing. The reason this particularly works is because our customers are increasing their incomes four or five times,&#8221; said Ibrahim. &#8220;Most of the money has been going to consuming power. This is the first time there has been productive power.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SunCulture&#8217;s hardware consists of 300-watt solar panels and a 440-watt-hour battery system. The batteries can support up to four lights, two phones and a plug-in submersible water pump. </span></p>
<p>The company&#8217;s best-selling product line can support irrigation for a two-and-a-half acre farm, Ibrahim said. &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">We see ourselves as an entry point for other types of appliances. We’re growing to be the largest solar company for Africa.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>With the $14 million in funding, from investors including <span style="font-weight: 400;">Energy Access Ventures (EAV), Électricité</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">de France (EDF), Acumen Capital Partners (ACP) and Dream Project Incubators (DPI), SunCulture will expand its footprint in</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Kenya, Ethiopia, Uganda, Zambia, Senegal, Togo and Cote D’Ivoire, the company said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ekta Partners acted as the financial advisor for the deal, while CrossBoundary provided</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">additional advisory support, including an analysis on the market opportunity and competitive</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">landscape, under the United States Agency for International Development (USAID)’s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kenya</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Investment Mechanism Program</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/sunculture-wants-to-turn-africa-into-the-worlds-next-bread-basket-one-solar-water-pump-at-a-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China&#8217;s internet regulator takes aim at forced data collection</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/chinas-internet-regulator-takes-aim-at-forced-data-collection/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/chinas-internet-regulator-takes-aim-at-forced-data-collection/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 08:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083015</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China is a step closer to cracking down on unscrupulous data collection by app developers. This week, the country&#8217;s cybersecurity watchdog began seeking comment on the range of user information that apps from instant messengers to ride-hailing services are allowed to collect. The move follows in the footstep of a proposed data protection law that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">China is a step closer to cracking down on unscrupulous data collection by app developers. This week, the country&#8217;s cybersecurity watchdog <a href="http://www.cac.gov.cn/2020-12/01/c_1608389002456595.htm">began seeking comment</a> on the range of user information that apps from instant messengers to ride-hailing services are allowed to collect.</p>
<p>The move follows in the footstep of a <a href="https://www.chinalawtranslate.com/en/personal-information-protection-draft/">proposed data protection law</a> that was released in October and is currently under review. The comprehensive data privacy law is set to be a &#8220;milestone&#8221; if passed and implemented, <a href="https://www.chinadaily.com.cn/a/202010/13/WS5f85968ea31024ad0ba7e715.html">wrote</a> the editorial of China Daily, the Chinese Communist Party&#8217;s official mouthpiece. The law is set to restrict data practices not just by private firms but also among government departments.</p>
<p>&#8220;Some leaking of personal information has resulted in economic losses for individuals when the information is used to swindle the targeted individual of his or her money,&#8221; said the party paper. &#8220;With increasingly advanced technology, the collection of personal information has been extended to biological information such as an individual&#8217;s face or even genes, which could result in serious consequences if such information is misused.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Apps in China often force users into surrendering excessive personal information by declining access when users refuse to consent. The draft rules released this week take aim at the practice by defining the types of data collection that are &#8220;<a href="http://www.cac.gov.cn/2020-12/01/c_1608389002247944.htm">legal, proper and necessary</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to the draft, &#8220;necessary&#8221; data are those that ensure the &#8220;normal operation of apps&#8217; basic functions.&#8221; As long as users have allowed the collection of necessary data, apps must grant them access.</p>
<p>Here are a few examples of what&#8217;s considered &#8220;necessary&#8221; personal data for different types of apps, as translated by <a href="https://www.chinalawtranslate.com/en/app-necessary-data/">China Law Translate</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Navigation: location</li>
<li>Ride-hailing: the registered user&#8217;s real identity (normally in the form of one&#8217;s mobile phone number in China) and location information</li>
<li>Messaging: the registered user&#8217;s real identity and contact list</li>
<li>Payment: the registered user&#8217;s real identity, the payer/payee&#8217;s bank information</li>
<li>Online shopping: the registered user&#8217;s real identity, payment details, information about the recipient like their name, address and phone number</li>
<li>Games: the registered user&#8217;s real identity</li>
<li>Dating: the registered user&#8217;s real identity, and the age, sex and marital status of the person looking for marriage or dating</li>
</ul>
<p>There are also categories of apps that are required to grant users access without gathering any personal information upfront: live streaming, short video, video/music streaming, news, browsers, photo editors and app stores.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that while the draft provides clear rules for apps to follow, it gives no details on how they will be enforced or how offenders will be punished. For instance, will app stores incorporate the benchmark into their approval process? Or will internet users be the watchdog? It remains to be seen.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ip85PC67lQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/china-presents-global-standard-for-data-security/">China presents &#8216;global standard for data security&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China presents &#8216;global standard for data security&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/china-presents-global-standard-for-data-security/embed/#?secret=ip85PC67lQ" data-secret="ip85PC67lQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/chinas-internet-regulator-takes-aim-at-forced-data-collection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083015</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YC-backed LemonBox raises $2.5M bringing vitamins to Chinese millennials</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/lemonbox-2-5-million-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/lemonbox-2-5-million-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 03:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lemonbox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panda Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Like many overseas Chinese, Derek Weng gets shopping requests from his family and friends whenever he returns to China. Some of the most wanted imported products are maternity items, cosmetics and vitamin supplements. Many in China still uphold the belief that &#8220;imported products are better.&#8221; The demand gave Weng a business idea. In 2018, he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Like many overseas Chinese, Derek Weng gets shopping requests from his family and friends whenever he returns to China. Some of the most wanted imported products are maternity items, cosmetics and vitamin supplements. Many in China still uphold the belief that &#8220;imported products are better.&#8221;</p>
<p>The demand gave Weng a business idea. In 2018, he founded <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/lemonbox" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="lemonbox">LemonBox <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> to sell American health supplements to Chinese millennials like himself via online channels. The company soon <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/13/lemonbox-raises-2-million/">attracted seed funding from Y Combinator</a> and just this week, it announced the completion of a pre-A round of $2.5 million led by Panda Capital and followed by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/y-combinator" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="y-combinator">Y Combinator <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>.</p>
<p>LemonBox tries to differentiate itself from other import businesses on two levels &#8212; affordability and personalization. Weng, who previously worked at Walmart, where he was involved in the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/20/walmart-sells-yihaodian-its-chinese-e-commerce-marketplace-to-alibaba-rival-jd-com/">retail giant&#8217;s China import business</a>, told TechCrunch that he&#8217;s acquainted with a lot of American supplement manufacturers and is thus able to cut middleman costs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;In China, most supplements are sold at a big markup through pharmacies or multi-level marketing companies like Amway,&#8221; Weng said. &#8220;But vitamins aren&#8217;t that expensive to produce. Amway and the likes spend a lot on marketing and sales.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2083004" style="width: 670px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2083004" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2083004 " src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/951607041281_.pic_.jpg" alt="" width="660" height="495" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/951607041281_.pic_.jpg 1440w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/951607041281_.pic_.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/951607041281_.pic_.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/951607041281_.pic_.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/951607041281_.pic_.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/951607041281_.pic_.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2083004" class="wp-caption-text">Inside LemonBox&#8217;s fulfillment center (Image: LemonBox)</p></div></p>
<p>LemonBox designed a WeChat-based lite app, where users receive product recommendations after taking a questionnaire about their health conditions. Instead of selling by the bottle, the company customizes user needs by offering daily packs of various supplements.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you are a vegetarian and travel a lot, and the other person smokes a lot, [your demands] are going to be very different. I wanted to customize user prescriptions using big data,&#8221; explained Weng, who studied artificial intelligence in business school.</p>
<p>A monthly basket of 30 B-complex tablets, for instance, costs 35 yuan ($5) on LemonBox. Amway&#8217;s counterpart product, a bottle of 120 tablets, asks for 229 yuan on JD.com. That&#8217;s about 57 yuan ($9) for 30 tablets.</p>
<p>Selling cheaper vitamins is just a means for LemonBox to attract consumers and gather health insights into Chinese millennials, with which the company hopes to widen its product range. Weng declined to disclose the company&#8217;s customer size, but claimed that its user conversion rate is &#8220;higher than most e-commerce sites.&#8221;</p>
<p>With the new proceeds, LemonBox is opening a second fulfillment center in the Shenzhen free-trade zone after its Silicon Valley-based one. That&#8217;s to provide more stability to its supply chain as the COVID-19 pandemic disrupts international flights and cross-border trade. Moreover, the startup will spend the money on securing health-related certificates and adding Japan to its sourcing regions.</p>
<h2>Returnees adapt</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2079197" style="width: 315px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2079197" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2079197 " src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/41271606710965_.pic_.jpg" alt="" width="305" height="542" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/41271606710965_.pic_.jpg 750w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/41271606710965_.pic_.jpg?resize=84,150 84w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/41271606710965_.pic_.jpg?resize=169,300 169w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/41271606710965_.pic_.jpg?resize=382,680 382w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/41271606710965_.pic_.jpg?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 305px) 100vw, 305px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2079197" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot of Lemonbox&#8217;s WeChat-based store</p></div></p>
<p>In the decade or so when Weng was living in the U.S., the Chinese internet saw drastic changes and gave rise to an industry largely in the grip of Alibaba and Tencent. Weng realized he couldn&#8217;t simply replicate America&#8217;s direct-to-customer playbook in China.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the U.S., you might build a website and maybe an app. You will embed your service into Google, Facebook or Instagram to market your products. Every continent is connected with one other,&#8221; said Weng.</p>
<p>&#8220;In China, it&#8217;s pretty significantly different. First off, not a lot of people use web browsers, but everyone is on mobile phones. Baidu is not as popular as Google, but everybody is using WeChat, and WeChat is isolated from other major traffic platforms.&#8221;</p>
<p>As such, LemonBox is looking to diversify beyond its WeChat store by launching a web version as well as a store through Alibaba&#8217;s Tmall marketplace.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s a lot of learning to be done. It&#8217;s a very humbling experience,&#8221; said Weng.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eOjIM3HvU2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/20/walmart-sells-yihaodian-its-chinese-e-commerce-marketplace-to-alibaba-rival-jd-com/">Walmart sells Yihaodian, its Chinese e-commerce marketplace, to Alibaba rival JD.com</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Walmart sells Yihaodian, its Chinese e-commerce marketplace, to Alibaba rival JD.com&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/20/walmart-sells-yihaodian-its-chinese-e-commerce-marketplace-to-alibaba-rival-jd-com/embed/#?secret=eOjIM3HvU2" data-secret="eOjIM3HvU2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/lemonbox-2-5-million-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079188</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Health tech venture firm OTV closes new $170 million fund and expands into Asia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/otv-closes-new-170-million-fund-and-expands-into-asia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/otv-closes-new-170-million-fund-and-expands-into-asia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 02:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OTV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OTV (formerly known as Olive Tree Ventures), an Israeli venture capital firm that focuses on digital health tech, announced it has closed a new fund totaling $170 million. The firm also launched a new office in Shanghai, China to spearhead its growth in the Asia Pacific region. OTV currently has a total of 11 companies [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.otv.vc/">OTV</a> (formerly known as Olive Tree Ventures), an Israeli venture capital firm that focuses on digital health tech, announced it has closed a new fund totaling $170 million. The firm also launched a new office in Shanghai, China to spearhead its growth in the Asia Pacific region.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/olive-tree-ventures" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="olive-tree-ventures">OTV <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> currently has a total of 11 companies in its portfolio. This year, it led rounds in telehealth platforms TytoCare and Lemonaid Health, and its other investments include genomic machine learning platform Emedgene; microscopy imaging startup Scopio; and at-home cardiac and pulmonary monitor Donisi Health. OTV has begun investing in more B and C rounds, with the goal of helping companies that have already validated products deal with regulations and other issues as they expand.</p>
<p>OTV focuses on digital health products that have the potential to work in different countries, make healthcare more affordable and fill gaps in overwhelmed healthcare systems.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wik1PRO9tl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/tyto-care-raises-50-million-as-it-looks-to-buy-and-build-new-services-during-covid-19-demand-surge/">Tyto Care raises $50 million as it looks to buy and build new services during COVID-19 demand surge</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tyto Care raises $50 million as it looks to buy and build new services during COVID-19 demand surge&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/tyto-care-raises-50-million-as-it-looks-to-buy-and-build-new-services-during-covid-19-demand-surge/embed/#?secret=wik1PRO9tl" data-secret="wik1PRO9tl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Jose Antonio Urrutia Rivas will serve as OTV’s head of Asia Pacific, managing its Shanghai office and helping the firm&#8217;s portfolio companies expand in China and other Asian countries. This brings OTV’s offices to a total of four, with other locations in New York, Tel Aviv and Montreal. Before joining OTV, Rivas worked at financial firm LarrainVial as its Asian market director.</p>
<p>OTV was founded in 2015 by general partners Mayer Gniwisch, Amir Lahat and Alejandro Weinstein. OTV partner Manor Zemer, who has worked in Asian markets for over 15 years and spent the last five living in Beijing, told TechCrunch that the firm decided it was the right time to expand into Asia because &#8220;digital health is already highly well-developed in many Asia-Pacific countries, where digital health products complement in-person healthcare providers, making that region a natural fit for a venture capital firm specializing in the field.&#8221;</p>
<p>He added that OTV &#8220;wanted to capitalize on how the COVID-19 pandemic has thrust the internationalized and interconnected nature of the world’s healthcare infrastructures into the limelight, even though digital health was a growth area long before the pandemic.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XJ73oG1WNL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/16/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-digital-health/">Where top VCs are investing in digital health</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Where top VCs are investing in digital health&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/16/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-digital-health/embed/#?secret=XJ73oG1WNL" data-secret="XJ73oG1WNL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/otv-closes-new-170-million-fund-and-expands-into-asia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WH&#8217;s AI EO is BS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/whs-ai-eo-is-bs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/whs-ai-eo-is-bs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White House]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An executive order was just issued from the White House regarding &#8220;the Use of Trustworthy Artificial Intelligence in Government.&#8221; Leaving aside the meritless presumption of the government&#8217;s own trustworthiness and that it is the software that has trust issues, the order is almost entirely hot air. The EO is like others in that it is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">An executive order was <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/executive-order-promoting-use-trustworthy-artificial-intelligence-federal-government/">just issued</a> from the White House regarding &#8220;the Use of Trustworthy Artificial Intelligence in Government.&#8221; Leaving aside the meritless presumption of the government&#8217;s own trustworthiness and that it is the <em>software</em> that has trust issues, the order is almost entirely hot air.</p>
<p>The EO is like others in that it is limited to what a president can peremptorily force federal agencies to do — and that really isn&#8217;t very much, practically speaking. This one &#8220;directs Federal agencies to be guided&#8221; by nine principles, which gives away the level of impact right there. Please, agencies — be guided!</p>
<p>And then, of course, all military and national security activities are excepted, which is where AI systems are at their most dangerous and oversight is most important. No one is worried about what NOAA is doing with AI — but they are very concerned with what three-letter agencies and the Pentagon are getting up to. (They have their own, self-imposed rules.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The principles are something of a wish list. AI used by the feds must be:</p>
<blockquote><p>lawful; purposeful and performance-driven; accurate, reliable, and effective; safe, secure, and resilient; understandable; responsible and traceable; regularly monitored; transparent; and accountable.</p></blockquote>
<p>I would challenge anyone to find <em>any</em> significant deployment of AI that is all of these things, anywhere in the world. Any agency claims that an AI or machine learning system they use adheres to all these principles as they are detailed in the EO should be treated with extreme skepticism.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not that the principles themselves are bad or pointless — it&#8217;s certainly important that an agency be able to quantify the risks when considering using AI for something, and that there is a process in place for monitoring their effects. But an executive order doesn&#8217;t accomplish this. Strong laws, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/massachusetts-votes-to-pass-statewide-police-ban-on-facial-recognition/">likely starting at the city and state level</a>, have already shown what it is to demand AI accountability, and though a federal law is unlikely to appear any time soon, this is not a replacement for a comprehensive bill. It&#8217;s just too hand-wavey on just about everything. Besides, many agencies already adopted &#8220;principles&#8221; like these years ago.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BpAOlCW92M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/facial-recognition-ban-portland-oregon/">Portland passes expansive city ban on facial recognition tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Portland passes expansive city ban on facial recognition tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/facial-recognition-ban-portland-oregon/embed/#?secret=BpAOlCW92M" data-secret="BpAOlCW92M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The one thing the EO does in fact do is compel each agency to produce a list of all the uses to which it is putting AI, however it may be defined. Of course, it&#8217;ll be more than a year before we see that.</p>
<p>Within 60 days of the order, the agencies will choose the format for this AI inventory; 180 days after that, the inventory must be completed; 120 days after that, the inventory must be completed and reviewed for consistency with the principles; plans to bring systems in line with them the agencies must &#8220;strive&#8221; to accomplish within 180 further days; meanwhile, within 60 days of the inventories having been completed they must be shared with other agencies; then, within 120 days of completion, they must be shared with the public (minus anything sensitive for law enforcement, national security, etc.).</p>
<p>In theory we might have those inventories in a month, but in practice we&#8217;re looking at about a year and a half, at which point we&#8217;ll have a snapshot of AI tools from the previous administration, with all the juicy bits taken out at their discretion. Still, it might make for interesting reading depending on what exactly goes into it.</p>
<p>This executive order is, like others of its ilk, an attempt by this White House to appear as an active leader on something that is almost entirely out of their hands. To develop and deploy AI should certainly be done according to common principles, but even if those principles could be established in a top-down fashion, this loose, lightly binding gesture that kind-of, sort-of makes some agencies have to pinky-swear to think real hard about them isn&#8217;t the way to do it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Kgb2uj20av"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/microsofts-brad-smith-says-company-will-not-sell-facial-recognition-tech-to-police/">Microsoft&#8217;s Brad Smith says company will not sell facial recognition tech to police</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft&#8217;s Brad Smith says company will not sell facial recognition tech to police&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/microsofts-brad-smith-says-company-will-not-sell-facial-recognition-tech-to-police/embed/#?secret=Kgb2uj20av" data-secret="Kgb2uj20av" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/whs-ai-eo-is-bs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082917</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joe White MBE appointed new UK Consul-General in SF, with new Technology Envoy role</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/joe-white-mbe-appointed-new-uk-consul-general-in-sf-with-new-technology-envoy-role/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/joe-white-mbe-appointed-new-uk-consul-general-in-sf-with-new-technology-envoy-role/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneur first]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joe white]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joe White MBE — a general partner of Entrepreneur First, a Greylock-backed early-stage deep tech fund — is leaving after being appointed as Her Majesty’s Consul-General, San Francisco, and Technology Envoy to the United States in a new, combined and powerful, role for the U.K. government. One of the key figures from the last two [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/joe-white-2">Joe White MBE</a> — a general partner of <a href="https://www.joinef.com/">Entrepreneur First</a>, a Greylock-backed early-stage deep tech fund — is leaving after being appointed as Her Majesty’s Consul-General, San Francisco, and Technology Envoy to the United States in a new, combined and powerful, role for the U.K. government.</p>
<p>One of the key figures from the last two decades of the tech industry in the U.K., most recently White has been co-chair of <a href="https://gbxglobal.org/">GBx</a>, a curated network of British entrepreneurs; a non-executive director for the U.K.’s Behavioural Insights Team where he advised on social impact technology products; and a former co-founder of <a href="https://www.moonfruit.com/">Moonfruit</a>, a website and e-commerce platform hosting 7 million sites, which was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/05/15/moonfruit-finally-exits-for-29-million-in-cash-to-re-energise-yell/">acquired by Yell.com</a> in 2012. He received an MBE from HM Queen in 2017 for Services to Technology Businesses.</p>
<p>White brings to the Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office (FCDO) huge experience as an entrepreneur and VC. The appointment is also a first for the U.K. White’s role as HM Consul-General has been combined with that of the new role of Technology Envoy to the United States. TechCrunch understands that this will involve high-level activity not just in San Francisco but also in Washington, DC, as tech goes up the political agenda under the new Biden presidency.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>White&#8217;s combined role will lead the Consulate, manage relationships in the northwest of the U.S., support the U.K. Ambassador to the U.S. on areas of shared U.K.-U.S. interest, including technology and entrepreneurship, and support Her Majesty&#8217;s Trade Commissioner in “promoting and enhancing the U.K. as partner of choice in trade, investment and research and development.”</p>
<p>In a statement, White said: “It is an honour to represent the UK at this critical time, and a pleasure to support our world-renowned tech sector which continues to go from strength to strength. I am looking forward to working closely with UK government tech teams in the US and in the UK, to further our growing and important relationship with the US tech community.”</p>
<p>Foreign Secretary Dominic Raab added: “The UK and the US are the largest investors in each other’s economies and this important appointment further underlines our commitment to the tech sector. I am delighted Joe will take on this enhanced role as we look to build back better and support an innovative post-pandemic global economy.”</p>
<p>White will take up his appointment later this year. He will report to Dame Karen Pierce DCMG, Her Majesty’s Ambassador to the United States of America.</p>
<p><strong>TechCrunch Comment: </strong></p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/joe-white-2" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="joe-white-2">Joe White <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> just hit a quadruple. He is the right man, in the right place, with the right experience, at the right time.</p>
<p>He’s a former entrepreneur, investor and has worked on both sides of &#8220;the pond&#8221;, so knows the U.K. and European tech scene as well as Silicon Valley. He has deep connections in all those ecosystems. And it can’t hurt that his wife, Wendy Tan White MBE, is vice president at X, (formerly Google X), Alphabet&#8217;s moonshot company, and co-founded Moonfruit with him. Furthermore, White is no stranger to the worlds of politics and diplomacy. His father, Michael White, was The Guardian newspaper&#8217;s political editor for many years.</p>
<p>Under Prime Minister David Cameron, the U.K. government was a keen exponent of the tech industry. Brexit cooled its ire in recent years, but the current chancellor, Rishi Sunak, has proved his interest by creating the U.K.’s Future Fund, hailed as a big success during the COVID period.</p>
<p>The U.K. and U.S. not only have a shared history, but they also have shared industries. The U.K. has been the traditional launching pad for U.S. startups into Europe. Likewise, Silicon Valley is now awash with British-born entrepreneurs and investors. But with tensions around the actions of U.S. Big Tech in the U.K. (the &#8220;Online Harms&#8221; legislation is aimed at social platforms), controversies over tax and global security issues all on the agenda, it’s right that the Consul General role in SF is bolstered by this new Tech Envoy moniker.</p>
<p>Silicon Valley is also about to get a fellow tech entrepreneur into one of the highest roles the U.K. government can bestow overseas. There could hardly be a better person for the job.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/joe-white-mbe-appointed-new-uk-consul-general-in-sf-with-new-technology-envoy-role/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Google fires co-lead of its Ethical AI team</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/google-fires-ethical-ai-co-lead/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/google-fires-ethical-ai-co-lead/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 23:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Timnit Gebru]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082942</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google fires a leading researcher, Stripe launches a new banking service and WarnerMedia shakes up the theatrical business model. This is your Daily Crunch for December 3, 2020. The big story: Google fires co-lead of its Ethical AI team Timnit Gebru, a leading researcher in the field of ethics and artificial intelligence, tweeted last night [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> fires a leading researcher, Stripe launches a new banking service and WarnerMedia shakes up the theatrical business model. This is your Daily Crunch for December 3, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Google fires co-lead of its Ethical AI team</strong></p>
<p>Timnit Gebru, a leading researcher in the field of ethics and artificial intelligence, tweeted last night that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/googles-co-lead-of-ethical-ai-team-says-she-was-fired-for-sending-an-email/">Google fired her in response to a message she sent to an internal email list</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Casey Newton obtained <a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/the-withering-email-that-got-an-ethical">the email in question</a>, in which Gebru expressed frustration with her treatment at Google and disappointment at its diversity and inclusion efforts: &#8220;We just had a Black research all hands with such an emotional show of exasperation. Do you know what happened since? Silencing in the most fundamental way possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>Google declined to comment, except to point to an email from Jeff Dean, the head of Google Research, in which he said Gebru had threatened to resign unless certain conditions were met. (&#8220;I hadn’t resigned — I had asked for simple conditions first and said I would respond when I’m back from vacation,&#8221; Gebru said.)</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/youtube-introduces-new-features-to-address-toxic-comments/">YouTube introduces new feature to address toxic comments</a> — The feature appears when users are about to post something offensive in a video’s comments section and warns them to “Keep comments respectful.”</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/developers-can-now-enroll-in-apples-small-business-program-for-reduced-app-store-fees/">Developers can now enroll in Apple’s ‘Small Business Program’ for reduced App Store fees</a> — Just a few weeks back, we learned that Apple would be launching a program to reduce its fees from 30% to 15% for developers earning less than $1 million per year from the App Store.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/androids-winter-update-adds-new-features-to-gboard-maps-books-nearby-share-and-more/">Android’s winter update adds new features to Gboard, Maps, Books, Nearby Share and more</a> — One of the more fun bits in the winter update will be a dramatic expansion of the Emoji Kitchen.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/stripe-announces-embedded-business-banking-service-stripe-treasury/">Stripe announces embedded business banking service Stripe Treasury</a> — The company is partnering with banks to offer a banking-as-a-service API.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/everlywell-raises-175-million-to-expand-virtual-care-options-and-scale-its-at-home-health-testing/">Everlywell raises $175M to expand virtual care options and scale its at-home health testing</a> — Earlier this year, Everlywell launched an at-home COVID-19 test collection kit, the first test of its kind to receive an emergency authorization from the FDA.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/vsco-acquires-mobile-app-trash-to-expand-into-a-i-powered-video-editing/">VSCO acquires mobile app Trash to expand into AI-powered video editing</a> — The deal will see Trash’s technology integrated into the VSCO app.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/vcs-who-want-better-outcomes-should-use-data-to-reduce-founder-team-risk/">VCs who want better outcomes should use data to reduce founder team risk</a> — Using an objective, data-backed process to evaluate teams will help VCs make better investment decisions.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/this-is-a-good-time-to-start-a-proptech-company/">This is a good time to start a proptech company</a> — At least, it&#8217;s a good time according to Colton Pace of Fika Ventures.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/boost-roi-with-intent-data-and-personalized-multichannel-marketing-campaigns/">Boost ROI with intent data and personalized multichannel marketing campaigns</a> — More mass email blasts are not going to get you the connections with prospects you crave.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/warner-bros-hbo-max-simultaneous-release/">All of Warner Bros.’ theatrical movies will get simultaneous releases on HBO Max next year</a> — This includes movies like “Godzilla vs. Kong,” “Mortal Kombat,” “In the Heights,” “Space Jam: A New Legacy” “The Suicide Squad,” “Dune,” the “Sopranos” prequel “The Many Saints of Newark” and “The Matrix 4.”</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/nasa-selects-four-companies-for-moon-material-collection-as-it-seeks-to-set-precedent-on-private-sector-outer-space-mining/">NASA selects four companies for moon material collection as it seeks to set precedent on private sector outer space mining</a> — The four companies all have rides booked on future commercial lunar lander missions.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/bill-gates-just-released-a-plan-for-us-leadership-on-climate-change-including-35b-in-funding/">Bill Gates just released a plan for US leadership on climate change, including $35B in funding</a> — Gates wrote that we &#8220;need to revolutionize the world’s physical economy.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/google-fires-ethical-ai-co-lead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082942</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
