<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 05:13:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>China lays out &#8216;rectification&#8217; plan for Jack Ma&#8217;s fintech empire Ant</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/ant-group-financial-clampdown/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/ant-group-financial-clampdown/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 05:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ant Financial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ant group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ant+]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xtransfer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090864</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What a whirlwind holiday for Jack Ma and his fintech empire. The People&#8217;s Bank of China, the country&#8217;s central bank, summoned Ant Group for regulatory talks on December 26th, announcing a sweeping plan for the fintech firm to &#8220;rectify&#8221; its regulatory violations. The meeting came less than two months after China&#8217;s financial authorities abruptly halted [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">What a whirlwind holiday for Jack Ma and his <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/aax-b20d" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="aax-b20d">fintech <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> empire. The People&#8217;s Bank of China, the country&#8217;s central bank, summoned Ant Group for regulatory talks on December 26th, announcing a sweeping plan for the fintech firm to &#8220;rectify&#8221; its regulatory violations.</p>
<p>The meeting came less than two months after China&#8217;s financial authorities abruptly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/china-postpones-ants-colossal-ipo-after-closed-door-talk-with-jack-ma/">halted</a> what could have been a record-setting initial public offering of Ant over the firm&#8217;s regulatory compliance issues. The company, which started out as a payments processor for Alibaba&#8217;s online marketplaces and spun out in 2011, lacked a sound governance structure, defied regulatory requirements, illegally engaged in arbitrage, excluded competitors using its market advantage and hurt consumer rights, <a href="http://www.pbc.gov.cn/goutongjiaoliu/113456/113469/4153479/index.html">said</a> the central bank.</p>
<p>Concurrently, Jack Ma&#8217;s e-commerce giant Alibaba is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/alibaba-antitrust-probe/">under investigation</a> by China&#8217;s top market regulator over alleged monopolistic behavior.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7riTWQAubq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/alibaba-antitrust-probe/">China&#8217;s e-commerce titan Alibaba hit with antitrust probe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China&#8217;s e-commerce titan Alibaba hit with antitrust probe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/alibaba-antitrust-probe/embed/#?secret=7riTWQAubq" data-secret="7riTWQAubq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The banking authority laid out a five-point compliance agenda for Ant, which is controlled by Alibaba&#8217;s billionaire founder Jack Ma. The fintech company should return to its roots in payments and bring more transparency to transactions; obtain the necessary licenses for its credit businesses and protect user data privacy; establish a financial holding company and ensure it holds sufficient capital; revamp its credit, insurance, wealth management and other financial businesses according to the law; and step up compliance for its securities business.</p>
<p>Following the closed-door meeting, Ant <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/bJk4wIywi_aqk4pGD1IZHg">said</a> it has established an internal &#8220;rectification workforce&#8221; to work on all the regulatory requirements.</p>
<p>The shakeup could take months to carry out and likely <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/ant-group-ipo-suspension/ants-ipo-fiasco-set-to-clip-its-wings-and-dent-its-value-idUSKBN27K1SS">dent Ant&#8217;s valuation</a>, which surpassed $300 billion around the time it was scheduled to go public. For instance, the government recently announced plans to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/china-lending/update-1-china-issues-draft-rules-to-regulate-online-micro-lending-business-idUSL1N2HP035">raise the bar</a> for third-party technology platforms like Ant to provide loans to consumers, a segment that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/tencent-vs-alibaba-ant-fintech/">made up about 35%</a> of Ant&#8217;s annual revenue. The proposed change, which is part of Beijing&#8217;s effort to control the country&#8217;s debt risks, also sets a new requirement for online microlenders to provide at least 30% of the loan they fund jointly with banks, which could put pressure on Ant&#8217;s cash flow.</p>
<p>Some remain optimistic about Ant&#8217;s future. &#8220;[Ant] creates a lot of value. If you take the long view, the temporary suspension of its IPO has a limited impact on its business,&#8221; Bill Deng, founder of cross-border payments operator <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/xtransfer">Xtransfer</a> and a former executive at Ant, said to TechCrunch.</p>
<p>&#8220;From the regulator&#8217;s standpoint, [Ant&#8217;s] lending size is getting so big that it has extended beyond the old regulatory perimeters. To some extent, it has also encroached on the core interests of traditional financial players,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>The clampdown on Ant has no doubt sent a warning to the rest of the industry. In a surprising move, JD.com&#8217;s fintech unit, a challenger to Ant, <a href="https://www.caixinglobal.com/2020-12-22/jdcoms-fintech-unit-reshuffles-executives-ahead-of-ipo-101642174.html">appointed its former chief compliance officer</a> to steer the fintech firm as the new chief executive officer.</p>
<p>Tencent also has a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/tencent-vs-alibaba-ant-fintech/">sprawling fintech business</a>, but it may not receive the same level of scrutiny because the social and gaming giant is &#8220;not nearly as aggressive&#8221; as Ant, said a partner of Tencent&#8217;s overseas fintech business who asked not to be named.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/ant-group-financial-clampdown/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090864</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian startups raised $9.3 billion in 2020</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/indian-startups-raised-9-3-billion-in-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/indian-startups-raised-9-3-billion-in-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 03:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dailyhunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jio Platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oyo rooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paytm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PolicyBazaar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Razorpay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unacademy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urban Ladder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zomato]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The coronavirus pandemic &#8212; and a handful of other factors &#8212; slowed dealmaking for startups in India this year. Compared to their record $14.5 billion fundraise last year, Indian startups are ending 2020 with about $9.3 billion. This is the first time since 2016 that startups in India, one of the world’s largest startup communities, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The coronavirus pandemic &#8212; and a handful of other factors &#8212; slowed dealmaking for startups in India this year.</p>
<p>Compared to their <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/29/indian-tech-startups-funding-amount-2019/">record $14.5 billion fundraise last year</a>, Indian startups are ending 2020 with about $9.3 billion. This is the first time since 2016 that startups in India, one of the world’s largest startup communities, has raised less than $10 billion in a year, according to consultancy firm Tracxn.</p>
<p>The number of deals fell from 1,185 last year to 1,088 in 2020. There were fewer larger sized rounds, too. Rounds with dealsize $100 million or larger fell from 26 in 2019 to 20 (these rounds delivered $3.6 billion this year, compared to $7.5 billion last year), and similarly rounds with dealsize $50 million to $100 million fell from 27 to 13. (The figures do not include investments in telecom giant Jio Platforms, which alone raised over $20 billion this year.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Despite the slowdown, Indian startups saw substantial rebound in the second half of this year. In the first half, startups in the world’s second largest internet market had raised just $4.2 billion from about 461 deals, said Tracxn.</p>
<p>Other than the coronavirus, which has impacted startups worldwide, another factor that impacted the dealmaking was absence of &#8212; or reduced participation from &#8212; some of the biggest investors.</p>
<p>Chinese giants such as Alibaba &#8212; and its affiliate Ant Group &#8212; and Tencent wrote <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/26/chinas-alibaba-wont-invest-in-indian-startups-for-at-least-six-months-report-says/">fewer checks this year</a> to Indian startups <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/18/to-avoid-hostile-takeovers-amid-covid-19-india-mandates-approvals-on-chinese-investments/">amid tension</a> between the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/india-bans-pubg-and-over-100-additional-chinese-apps/">two neighboring nations</a>. SoftBank also delivered less capital as many of its high-profile portfolio firms including Paytm, Oyo Rooms, and Ola did not raise money.</p>
<p>But the virus also accelerated growth of some startups. Byju’s is now <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/07/silver-lake-leads-500-million-round-in-indias-byjus/">valued at over $11 billion</a>, up from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/07/indian-education-startup-byjus-raises-200m-from-general-atlantic/">$8 billion in January this year</a>. Unacademy, another high-profile startup in the online learning space, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/indias-online-learning-platform-unacademy-raises-150-million-at-1-45-billion-valuation/">raised two rounds</a> at the height of the pandemic, increasing its valuation from about $500 million in February this year to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/tiger-global-invests-in-india-unacademy-at-2-billion-valuation/">over $2 billion</a>.</p>
<p>Bond, a firm started by Mary Meeker and other high-profile investors, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/mary-meekers-bond-invests-in-indian-online-learning-giant-byjus/">backed Byju’s this year</a>. Bond believes that Byju’s will be worth over $30 billion in three years, a person who was briefed by the investment firm told TechCrunch. Several startups in India <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/chargebee-raises-55-million-to-help-businesses-move-to-subscriptions/">operating on a SaaS model</a> and catering to customers worldwide also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/15/sales-readiness-platform-mindtickle-raises-100-million-led-by-softbank-vision-fund-2/">picked up momentum this year</a>.</p>
<p>11 Indian startups including RazorPay, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/unacademy" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="unacademy">Unacademy, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> DailyHunt, and Glance became a unicorn this year. (On a side note, Google and Facebook wrote several checks to Indian firms this year. Google <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/google-leads-145-million-investment-in-indias-glance/">backed Glance and DailyHunt last week</a>, while Facebook <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/facebook-backs-indian-education-startup-unacademy/">invested in Unacademy</a>. Both the firms also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/india-approves-googles-4-5-billion-deal-with-reliances-jio-platforms/">invested in Jio Platforms this year</a>.)</p>
<p>&#8220;I am old enough (unfortunately!) to have seen the 2001 and 2008 downturns so when Covid hit and there were stories of doom and gloom everywhere, I remembered what I saw happening in the past downturns — a beginning of a new generation of teams who built the next generation of companies,&#8221; said Vaibhav Domkundwar, founder and managing partner at Better Capital. Better Capital, which backs early stage startups in India, wrote 43 investment and follow-on checks this year.</p>
<p>M&amp;A activities also accelerated this year. Byju’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/indias-byjus-acquires-whitehat-jr-for-300-million/">acquired WhiteHat Jr for $300 million</a>, while Unacademy <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/06/unacademy-prepladder-india/">acquired PrepLadder</a>, which offers courses aimed at medical students, for $50 million in July. It also led an investment round of $5 million to acquire a majority stake in Mastree.</p>
<p>Reliance Industries acquired online pharmacy Nedmeds and, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/14/reliance-retail-buys-urban-ladder-for-24-4-million/">in a fire sale, Urban Ladder</a>.</p>
<p>But for the first time, Indian startups are on the verge of seeing another kind of exit. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/zomato" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="zomato">Zomato, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/flipkart" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="flipkart">Flipkart, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Policybazaar are among some startups that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/10/indias-zomato-raises-100m-from-tiger-global-says-it-is-planning-to-file-for-ipo-next-year/">plan to go public next year</a>. Analysts at Bernstein have identified Paytm, Byju’s, PhonePe, and Delhivery among those who could also go public by 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/indian-startups-raised-9-3-billion-in-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090865</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: Get Back</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/gillmor-gang-get-back/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/gillmor-gang-get-back/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 19:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today we sat on the deck with our daughter Ella and her boyfriend Nick. Knowing of my fascination with all things Beatles, Nick gave me a Japanese 45 of Get Back flipped with Don’t Let Me Down. His gift coincided with a 5 minute cut of material from a newly authorized production of a new [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/EogHfkW0zbw?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Today we sat on the deck with our daughter Ella and her boyfriend Nick. Knowing of my fascination with all things Beatles, Nick gave me a Japanese 45 of Get Back flipped with Don’t Let Me Down. His gift coincided with a 5 minute cut of material from a newly authorized production of a new version of Get Back, the film. A short history follows.</p>
<p>In the waning days of The Beatles’ partnership, the band decided to return to a more slimmed down production style, minus overdubs and plus a live feel. After original sessions in Twickenham Studios, the group decamped to the basement of their Apple headquarters and a hastily rebuilt studio courtesy of their usual producer, George Martin and loaned equipment from EMI Studios.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In the years since Sgt. Pepper, Beatles records had begun to retreat from their highly produced studio experiments. The most recent double album, The Beatles (commonly known as the White Album) was largely recorded in single takes, driving a wedge between the group and their producer that fostered a two week holiday where Martin turned the production over to his assistant.</p>
<p>The multiple takes also exacerbated growing tensions between the band members, as hundreds of attempts to perfect Paul McCartney songs like Ob-La-Di, Ob-La-Da drove Lennon further into his heroin experiments with Yoko Ono. Bickering drove Ringo Starr to quit for two weeks before being lured back with flowers draping his drum kit; George Harrison invited Eric Clapton in to a session in a successful attempt to put the rest on their best behavior. This gambit worked again with Billy Preston in the Get Back sessions four months later in January 1969.</p>
<p>It may be hard to understand the context of these tensions in a world beset with a global pandemic and the worst president in the history of the free world, but this was the middle of the Vietnam War and the first term of Richard Nixon. His landslide reelection in 1972 would preclude the voters turning him out of office, and the Watergate scandal that drove him to resign was only just beginning to unfold. Compare the emotional turmoil of four rock musicians to today’s terror at the actions of an unhinged autocrat being removed from office in what seems like an endless thirty days. But it really sucked then as now.</p>
<p>Part of the problem was the disquieting anxiety on the part of the postwar boomer generation that we didn’t really deserve the respect we weren’t getting from straight society. The silent majority of our parents and peers sneered at our experiments of free love and drug-induced “insights.” The counter culture we labeled ourselves was as lonely a place to be as the Deplorables of 2016. We had no power, no real leaders, and nowhere to go but down when Woodstock collapsed into Altamont, assassination, and addiction.</p>
<p>So we didn’t know what we were talking about and yet here we were owning the ceramics we broke. Our heroes in London were on top of the world, and they couldn’t stand each other. What to do? Let’s make a movie of how we really are. On the plus side, there was real alchemy between these four young men. Even though sick of each other, they loved the results of what they found together. Lennon was haughty but funny, McCartney pleasant but coiled like a big cat. Ringo was Everyman, with an actor’s surprise at his luck and proud of his true role of ignition switch.</p>
<p>Harrison is the crucible, where the steel is forged. In interviews after the breakup and narrating during, George seems to be the one who realizes the true value of the partnership even as he explodes it with solo success. The backlog of his material spilled out in his first album, so successful that its chart topping drove McCartney and Lennon to try and keep up for the next 8 years until Lennon’s death.</p>
<p>Yet of all the others, he was the one to recognize the value, the responsibility, of keeping the door open for what they had together. When Lennon recorded his vicious assault on McCartney, How Do You Sleep, George not only played on the record but provided the emotional power with a surging slide guitar lead he’d only developed when the group was done. During the White Album sessions that produced some of Lennon’s best work, he suggested Lennon change the title from Maharishi to Sexy Sadie to lose the personal attack on the guru for what may have turned out to be a jealous setup by another of the group’s coterie.</p>
<p>In the film fragment released for Christmas 2020, Harrison is seen kicking off Get Back, the first time you can really see the role George played in the propulsion of the track. As with many players, you can best understand this when he drops out for a retake or a tempo adjustment led by Paul; the absence of the guitarist shows how central he is to the mix. In the only footage released prior to this new material, Harrison seemed subdued on the roof concert version of the track. He reportedly was opposed to doing a live concert in general, and only agreed to go out on the roof when Lennon finally committed.</p>
<p>It’s this context that is so striking in the new material. The tensions within the group can be seen not only for the inevitability of their collapse but also their courage to be filmed and displayed for all to consume. As a persistent fan of the band and all of its dynamics at the core of the century, the new footage comes across like The Godfather and its sequels. Like Godfather II, the Beatles studio phase once they abandoned live performance in 1966 transcended their initial success in a way that essentially invented the modern Hollywood business of sequels.</p>
<p>The return to live phase that began with the White Album and continued through the Get Back sessions resolved itself with the last Beatles recording of Abbey Road. In this way the Get Back film apparently includes early recordings of material from Abbey Road as well as Harrison and McCartney tracks never finished by the group. Unlike the Let It Be film that emerged as a director’s cut of the breakdown of the group pre-Abbey Road, this new Get Back film will likely serve as a document of the final phase of the group in both defeat and resolution.</p>
<p>The last Beatles recording of all four plus Billy Preston produced I Want You (She’s So Heavy), the long bluesy track that ends side one of Abbey Road. It’s a tantalizing glimpse into the future that never was of the greatest group there ever was. Like Francis Ford Coppola’s reimagining of the the last Godfather sequel, Get Back is a coda to the tragic highs and lows of the time that was the Sixties. At the time, it was impossible to imagine where we could go from there. Today, we share that same feeling of despair, but perhaps, the hope of what the future could bring.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><em>from the <a href="https://gillmorgang.substack.com"> Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/frank-radice" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="frank-radice">Frank Radice, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/michael-markman-6388" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="michael-markman-6388">Michael Markman, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/keith-teare" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="keith-teare">Keith Teare, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/denis-pombriant" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="denis-pombriant">Denis Pombriant, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/brent-leary" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="brent-leary">Brent Leary, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/steve-gillmor" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="steve-gillmor">Steve Gillmor <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>. Recorded live Friday, December 18, 2020.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><a href="https://gillmorgang.substack.com">Subscribe to the Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> &#8230; and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/gillmor-gang-get-back/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090849</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What startups can learn from this dumpster fire year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/26/what-startups-can-learn-from-this-dumpster-fire-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/26/what-startups-can-learn-from-this-dumpster-fire-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups Weekly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Want this newsletter in your inbox every Saturday morning? Sign up here. Remember when it was news that venture capitalists were open for business? Or when Zoom investing was only done by that one guy in Ann Arbor (ha, I kid!)? These past few months have felt busier than ever, with no holiday slowdown in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Want this newsletter in your inbox every Saturday morning? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here.</a></em></p>
<p>Remember when it was news that venture capitalists were open for business? Or when Zoom investing was only done by <a href="https://twitter.com/TurnerNovak">that one guy in Ann Arbor </a>(ha, I kid!)? These past few months have felt busier than ever, with no holiday slowdown in sight when it comes to startup growth, hot IPOs and new financings.</p>
<p>Even with a distracting bull market, I wanted to reflect and see how the youngest startups are faring. <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex Wilhem</a> and I dove into data, provided by Pitchbook, to see if the next <strong>DoorDashes</strong> and <strong>Airbnbs</strong> are getting their first financings.</p>
<p>The answer is that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/us-seed-stage-investing-flourished-during-pandemic/">seed investing flourished but in a complicated way</a>. COVID-19 shook up which startups were considered attractive by private investors. And that changeup came at risk to certain sectors and people.</p>
<p>Here’s how two investors <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/us-seed-stage-investing-flourished-during-pandemic/">explained the dynamics</a>:</p>
<h3><strong>Freestyle’s Jenny Lefcourt:</strong></h3>
<blockquote><p>I think seed prices are being driven up by the larger [venture] firms playing earlier and feeling like <strong>they cannot afford to miss the next DoorDash. </strong>I think the larger firms have so much capital to put to work and feel they are better off burning some [cash] at seed for the upside of being in the right [startups] where they can <strong>double, triple, 10x down on their winners</strong>.</p></blockquote>
<h3><strong>Eniac Ventures’ Nihal Mehta: </strong></h3>
<blockquote><p>Because you can’t meet in person, investors felt way more comfortable investing in ‘proven’ entrepreneurs that had <strong>pre-existing connections to their social circle.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>The long-term ramifications of this tunnel vision means that female founders lost out during this time, since social circles in venture capital are largely white and male. From a sector perspective, e-commerce and edtech have had an easy time raising, but at the cost of travel and hospitality.</p>
<p>The data brings a sort of dissonance to startup-land: Even though seed investing has never looked more busy and fruitful, this is good news for some, and bad news for others. It’s a healthy reminder that a boom and bust can be true at the same time.</p>
<p>How’s that for a 2020 sign-off? We’ll be off next week but in the meantime, two bits of homework: take advantage of this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/holiday-sale-save-10-on-extra-crunch-membership/">Extra Crunch holiday sale</a> and send me tips and thoughts to <a href="mailto:natasha.mascarenhas@techcrunch.com">natasha.mascarenhas@techcrunch.com</a> or tweet me <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">@nmasc_</a> in between your holiday treats.</p>
<p>I’ll chat with you all in the New Year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1944326" style="width: 711px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1944326" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-1944326" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GettyImages-655824660.jpeg" alt="Waves of sheets of paper that mimic fire" width="701" height="468" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GettyImages-655824660.jpeg 2119w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GettyImages-655824660.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GettyImages-655824660.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GettyImages-655824660.jpeg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GettyImages-655824660.jpeg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GettyImages-655824660.jpeg?resize=1536,1026 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GettyImages-655824660.jpeg?resize=2048,1368 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GettyImages-655824660.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 701px) 100vw, 701px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1944326" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Getty Images</p></div></p>
<h2>Edtech’s biggest challenge in 2021</h2>
<p>No sector has had a year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/to-win-post-pandemic-edtech-needs-to-start-thinking-big/">quite like edtech</a>. The sector attracted $10 billion in funding globally, and remote learning went from a tool to a necessity.</p>
<p>Here are my favorite edtech stories I wrote this year:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/edtech-investors-are-panning-for-gold/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Edtech investors are panning for gold</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/30/teachers-are-leaving-schools-will-they-come-to-startups-next/">Teachers are leaving schools. Will they come to startups next?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/edtech-is-surging-and-parents-have-some-notes/">Edtech is surging, and parents have some notes </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/09/edtech-startups-prepare-to-become-not-just-a-teaching-tool-but-a-necessity/">Edtech startups prepare to become ‘not just a teaching tool but a necessity’ </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/will-edtech-empower-or-erase-the-need-for-higher-education/"> Will edtech empower or erase the need for higher education</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Finally, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/to-win-post-pandemic-edtech-needs-to-start-thinking-big/">in my end of year op-ed for TechCrunch</a>, I propose that the ubiquity of remote learning surely brought a boom to new users, but it may have in fact limited the sector’s ability to innovate in lieu of fast, easy scale.</p>
<p>Here’s my biggest tip for the year ahead:</p>
<blockquote><p>For edtech in 2020, flexible and scrappy was a survival tactic that led to profits, growth and most of all, aha moments that technology was needed in the way we learn. Now, as we enter the rest of the decade, the sector will have to shake off its short-term-fix mentality to evolve from tunnel vision to wide-pan ambition.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1817409" style="width: 755px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1817409" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-1817409" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/bulb-on-off1.gif" alt="light bulb flickering on and off" width="745" height="419" /><p id="caption-attachment-1817409" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Bryce Durbin / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<h2><strong>A $16B checkbook for space startups </strong></h2>
<p>Funding for space startups is defying odds &#8211; which is the poetic flair we need once in a while. As part of our TC Sessions: Space 2020 event, a number of TechCrunch reporters dove deep into what kind of money is going into &#8230; the space.</p>
<ul>
<li>Some think that space startup funding didn’t slow, despite the economic downturn, because of government involvement <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/despite-economic-downturn-space-startup-funding-defies-gravity/ ">providing a budget buffer</a>.</li>
<li>The man who handles the money for the Air Force’s $16 billion checkbook wants startups to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/the-us-wants-startups-to-get-a-piece-of-the-16-billion-spent-on-space-tech/">slide into the DMs</a>.</li>
<li>Three VCs talk about space junk, sustainability, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/3-vcs-discuss-space-junk-and-what-else-theyre-betting-on-right-now/">the merits of space manufacturing</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chris Boshuizen</strong> of the venture firm <strong>DCVC</strong> and a co-founder of <strong>Planet Labs</strong> notably said:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>We don’t yet live in the sci-fi future, where you can just fly up, grab a piece of debris and bring it back. That’s really, really hard — I think probably five years away — but something we want to support and see happen.</em></p></blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_2089782" style="width: 739px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2089782" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2089782" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/uncle-sam-space-force.jpg" alt="Image of Uncle Sam floating in space with the Space Force logo above his left shoulder." width="729" height="410" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/uncle-sam-space-force.jpg 3367w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/uncle-sam-space-force.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/uncle-sam-space-force.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/uncle-sam-space-force.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/uncle-sam-space-force.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/uncle-sam-space-force.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/uncle-sam-space-force.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/uncle-sam-space-force.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 729px) 100vw, 729px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2089782" class="wp-caption-text">Image of Uncle Sam floating in space with the Space Force logo above his left shoulder.</p></div></p>
<h2><strong>Remembering the startups we lost in 2020 </strong></h2>
<p>Building a startup is always difficult, but the pandemic was a plot twist that led to a not-so-happy ending for many companies this year. So, as part of an annual TechCrunch tradition, we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/remember-the-startups-we-lost-in-2020/">paid homage to the startups we lost in 2020. </a></p>
<p>Here are my takeaways:</p>
<ul>
<li>This is not a fun list. Failure is hard, but you can learn a thing or two when you sort through the ashes. For example? Big names, big plans, and a boatload of money isn&#8217;t a replacement for actually making money.</li>
<li>List includes <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">short-form video app <strong>Quibi</strong>, to lawyer tech startup <strong>Atrium</strong>, to a slew of travel startups which fell apart as the virus dragged on. </span></li>
<li>While some businesses chalked up failure to COVID-19, the cracks and fundamental business flaws were often peeking through far before the pandemic began.<br />
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2064948 aligncenter" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/quibi-destroyed.jpg" alt="" width="738" height="415" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/quibi-destroyed.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/quibi-destroyed.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/quibi-destroyed.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/quibi-destroyed.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/quibi-destroyed.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/quibi-destroyed.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/quibi-destroyed.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/quibi-destroyed.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 738px) 100vw, 738px" /></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Around TechCrunch</strong></h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/gift-guide-techcrunchs-favorite-things-of-2020/">TechCrunch’s Favorite Things of 2020</a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/gift-guide-last-minute-gift-ideas/">Gift Guide: Last-minute subscriptions to keep the gifts going all year</a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/techcrunchs-top-stories-of-2020/ ">Video: TechCrunch editors choose their top stories of 2020</a></strong></p>
<h2><strong>Across the week</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Seen on TechCrunch</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/snoop-doggs-casa-verde-capital-closes-on-100-million-as-the-cannabis-industry-bounces-back/">Snoop Dogg’s Casa Verde Capital closes on $100 million as the cannabis industry bounces back</a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/activism-platform-actionable-helps-users-be-proactive-about-the-causes-they-love/ ">Activism platform actionable helps users be proactive about the causes they love</a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/letterhead-wants-to-be-the-shopify-of-email-newsletters/">Letterhead wants to be the Shopify of email newsletters</a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href=" https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/telegram-to-launch-an-ad-platform-as-it-approaches-500-million-users/ ">Telegram, nearing 500 million users, to begin monetizing the app</a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/the-biden-administration-can-change-the-world-with-new-crypto-regulations/ ">The Biden administration can change the world with new crypto regulations</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>Seen on Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/with-a-50b-run-rate-in-reach-can-anyone-stop-aws/ ">With a $50B run rate, can anyone stop AWS? </a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href=" https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-after-2020s-epic-ma-spree/ ">Looking ahead after 2020s epic M&amp;A spree</a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/dear-sophie-whats-ahead-for-u-s-immigration-in-2021/">Dear Sophie: What’s ahead for US immigration in 2021?</a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/the-built-environment-will-be-one-of-techs-next-big-platforms/ ">The built environment will be one of tech’s next big platforms</a></strong></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kWcfbpHuKH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/give-the-gift-of-extra-crunch-for-25-off/">Give the gift of Extra Crunch for 25% off</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Give the gift of Extra Crunch for 25% off&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/give-the-gift-of-extra-crunch-for-25-off/embed/#?secret=kWcfbpHuKH" data-secret="kWcfbpHuKH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2><strong>@EquityPod</strong></h2>
<p>Finally, Equity is ending the year with two holiday episodes. This week, we&#8217;ve got <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/equity-venture-capital-surprise-2020/">reflections on this dumpster fire year.</a> I teamed up with <a href="https://twitter.com/DannyCrichton"> Danny</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/CGates123">Chris</a> and<a href="https://twitter.com/alex"> Alex</a> to just sit back and think about this eventful year. We also got five venture capitalists who we got to leave us their notes as well.</p>
<p>The goal for this episode was to sit down and think<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/equity-venture-capital-surprise-2020/"> a year that no one could have ever predicted</a>, but with a specific angle, as always, on venture capital and startups.</p>
<p>We asked about the biggest surprise, non-portfolio companies to watch, and trends they got wrong and right. There was also banter on Zoom investing (Alex came up with Zesting, not me) and startup pricing.</p>
<p><em>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/26/what-startups-can-learn-from-this-dumpster-fire-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090793</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Original Content podcast: &#8216;The Mandalorian&#8217; season two goes deep into Star Wars mythology</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/26/original-content-mandalorian-season-two/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/26/original-content-mandalorian-season-two/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 14:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Original Content podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Mandalorian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the walt disney company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;The Mandalorian&#8221; just wrapped up its second season on Disney+, with an action-packed and surprise-filled finale. In many ways, it feels like a seamless continuation of the first season&#8217;s storylines, with the titular bounty hunter searching for a Jedi who can take responsibility for the alien moppet known to the internet as Baby Yoda, while [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;The Mandalorian&#8221; just wrapped up its second season on Disney+, with an action-packed and surprise-filled finale.</p>
<p>In many ways, it feels like a seamless continuation of the first season&#8217;s storylines, with the titular bounty hunter searching for a Jedi who can take responsibility for the alien moppet known to the internet as Baby Yoda, while the pair is pursued by the sinister Moff Gideon.</p>
<p>But as we explain on the latest episode of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/original-content-podcast/">the Original Content podcast</a>, where <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/17/original-content-mandalorian/">the first season</a> of &#8220;The Mandalorian&#8221; felt accessible to anyone, regardless of their level of Star Wars fandom, season two deepens its ties to the rest of the fictional universe.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That includes bringing in live action versions of characters from the animated &#8220;Clone Wars&#8221; series, as well as setting up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-investor-day/">the many other Star Wars shows</a> that are in the works for Disney+. This approach prompted very different responses from your podcast hosts — Darrell was delighted since he understood all the Ester Eggs, Jordan was exhausted trying to keep up and Anthony was happy to let many of the references go over his head.</p>
<p>At least the show&#8217;s other virtues remain intact, with enjoyably grungy and tactile space opera settings, spectacular big budget battles and an adorable baby Jedi.</p>
<p>In addition to reviewing &#8220;The Mandalorian,&#8221; we also discuss HBO Max&#8217;s arrival on Roku (which somehow prompts Anthony to explain his disappointment in the new Christopher Nolan movie &#8220;Tenet&#8221;), and Darrell and Jordan offer their latest thoughts on &#8220;The Bachelorette.&#8221;</p>
<p>You can listen to our review in the player below, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/original-content/id1271763098" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">subscribe using Apple Podcasts</a> or find us in your podcast player of choice. If you like the show, please let us know by leaving a review on Apple. You can also <a href="https://twitter.com/originalcontent">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="mailto:originalcontent@techcrunch.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">send us feedback directly</a>. (Or suggest shows and movies for us to review!)</p>
<p>And if you&#8217;d like to skip ahead, here&#8217;s how the episode breaks down:<br />
0:00 Intro<br />
4:14 HBO Max/&#8221;Tenet&#8221; discussion<br />
13:35 &#8220;The Bachelorette&#8221; discussion<br />
28:42 &#8220;The Mandalorian&#8221; Season 2 review<br />
50:40 &#8220;The Mandalorian&#8221; spoiler discussion</p>
<p><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/4ec7b619-4fd6-4e3d-8ee4-36e0d9f99c07?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/26/original-content-mandalorian-season-two/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090815</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Music made 2020 better, but we failed to make 2020 better for musicians</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/25/music-made-2020-better-but-we-failed-to-make-2020-better-for-musicians/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/25/music-made-2020-better-but-we-failed-to-make-2020-better-for-musicians/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revenue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Are you okay?” I don’t have a good answer to the question. Knowing full well that I’m talking back to an algorithm &#8212; even one asking the same question of everyone with a different band mad-libbed in &#8212; doesn’t soften the blow. Am I? Are we? Is anyone, really? In this case, it’s referring to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">“Are you okay?”</p>
<p>I don’t have a good answer to the question. Knowing full well that I’m talking <a href="https://pudding.cool/2020/12/judge-my-spotify/">back to an algorithm</a> &#8212; even one asking the same question of everyone with a different band mad-libbed in &#8212; doesn’t soften the blow. Am I? Are we? Is anyone, really?</p>
<p>In this case, it’s referring to Waxahatchee. I mean, yeah, I totally listened to a lot of Waxahatchee this year. Waxahatchee is good. Saint Cloud was one of my favorite albums of the year. Katie Crutchfield’s music doesn’t exist in the Elliott Smith, Leonard Cohen bin for me. It’s not time to send up the signal flares when you see the band all over my <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/spotify" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="spotify">Spotify <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> social feed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Spotify roasting AI that’s been making the rounds this week is a fun exercise in music snobbery. It also may be brushing against some larger truth here. Something I think we all considered at least in passing this year when Spotify offered its annual “Wrapped” year in review.</p>
<p>What’s the soundtrack to the worst year, ever? What do we listen to while the world burns? In 2009, a former CNN intern stumbled across a video tape in the archives labeled with the title, <a href="https://jalopnik.com/this-is-the-video-cnn-will-play-when-the-world-ends-1677511538">&#8220;Turner Doomsday Video.”</a> The minute-long video features a band playing, &#8220;Nearer My God To Thee,” believed to be the final song played by the band on the Titanic. It carried the explicit instructions, “HFR [Hold for Release] till end of the world confirmed.”</p>
<p>Barring any sort of last-minute surprise, it seems likely we’ll make it through 2020 shy of a full-on apocalypse (in spite of, perhaps, the best efforts of some). But for me, Spotify’s year in review was a testament to hell year, just as my Apple Watch exercise bars saw a zeroing out in late-March and April, as the pandemic bore down on my home of Queens, New York and I dealt with some personal health issues.</p>
<p>What was pitched as a celebratory aggregation of my listening habits over the previous 12 months exited the machine as a testament to the long stretches of time where engaging with music felt like an impossibility. Ambient music and post-rock got me listening again when lyrics seemed like too much to process. And I’m sure I’m not alone in having listened to some comfort tracks with an alarming frequency.</p>
<p>Looking back is a useful reminder of the role music played in what undoubtedly qualifies as the worst year to date for many. It would be an overstatement to suggest that music saved my life in 2020, but it certainly cushioned the blow of one too many emotional gut punches.</p>
<p>“Music can lift us out of depression or move us to tears – it is a remedy, a tonic, orange juice for the ear,” the late-neurologist, Oliver Sacks wrote. “But for many of my neurological patients, music is even more – it can provide access, even when no medication can, to movement, to speech, to life. For them, music is not a luxury, but a necessity.”</p>
<p>Louis Armstrong put it even more succinctly: “music is life itself.”</p>
<p>It’s a cruel irony that, in a year when music has meant so much to so many, most musicians have struggled to make ends meet. The musical field certainly isn’t unique in that respect this year, but their struggles have been pronounced in an era when streaming revenues offer fractions of cents what musicians make in record sales, and touring has become the most important revenue stream for all but the biggest names. For the past 10 months, that all but dried up.</p>
<p>“The pandemic utterly decimated the live-music industry,” Wilco frontman Jeff Tweedy <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/jeff-tweedy-on-covid-19and-its-impact-on-live-music-11608062400">noted in a recent interview</a>. “There’s been almost an entire year now of absolutely zero revenue.”</p>
<p>In May, a <a href="https://www.nme.com/news/music/19-per-cent-of-musicians-are-considering-abandoning-their-careers-due-to-lack-of-government-support-during-coronavirus-2670463">survey from the Musician’s Union</a> noted that 19% of musicians said they might end up giving up their careers due to the impact of COVID-19. Seven months later, one wonders whether that figure might have been optimistic.</p>
<p>Tweedy adds, “There will be places to play. But the landscape won’t ever look the same. I imagine that a lot of the more intimate music venues will be gone, just like a lot of small businesses and restaurants.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FMW1bEG5Ne"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/bandcamp-fridays-will-continue-through-next-may/">Bandcamp Fridays will continue through next May</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bandcamp Fridays will continue through next May&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/bandcamp-fridays-will-continue-through-next-may/embed/#?secret=FMW1bEG5Ne" data-secret="FMW1bEG5Ne" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Bandcamp has been a beacon for many. The service’s “Bandcamp Fridays,” which waive its revenue cut, have raised $40 million to date. The site has promised to continue offering the feature at least through May of next year.</p>
<p>This year’s struggles have served to highlight concerns over streaming royalties. Spotify has understandably been the focal point for this conversation, all while the company has spent hundreds of millions to bolster its podcast programming. CEO Daniel Ek didn’t do himself any favors in July when he noted, “Some artists that used to do well in the past may not do well in this future landscape, where you can’t record music once every three to four years and think that’s going to be enough.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5MkpZcrJcp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/justice-at-spotify-demands-better-compensation-and-increased-transparency-for-musicians/">Justice at Spotify demands better compensation and increased transparency for musicians</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Justice at Spotify demands better compensation and increased transparency for musicians&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/justice-at-spotify-demands-better-compensation-and-increased-transparency-for-musicians/embed/#?secret=5MkpZcrJcp" data-secret="5MkpZcrJcp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In October, Justice at Spotify rep (and Galaxie 500 member) Damon Kurkowski told me “[R]esponse from certain corners of the industry has been as cold as we expected: ‘You’re just musicians and don’t understand business,’ is the basic gist of it. To which I would say: The problem we are calling attention to is precisely that musicians have been left out of the conversation! We always come last in payment and in consultation — even though our work is what the streaming business is built on.”</p>
<p>The struggle to survive on music is nothing new, of course. Jazz genius Thelonious Monk famously had a benefactor in Baroness Pannonica de Koenigswarter. But just because we’ve failed musicians in the past doesn’t mean we can’t and shouldn’t do better.</p>
<p>Am I okay? I’m still not sure, but listening to music seems to help.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/25/music-made-2020-better-but-we-failed-to-make-2020-better-for-musicians/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090823</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Alibaba faces antitrust probe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/daily-crunch-alibaba-faces-antitrust-probe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/daily-crunch-alibaba-faces-antitrust-probe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 23:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chinese authorities investigate an e-commerce giant, Google may be tightening its grip on research and VCs weigh in on the year&#8217;s biggest surprises. This is your (briefer than usual) Daily Crunch for December 24, 2020. The big story: Alibaba faces antitrust probe China&#8217;s State Administration for Market Regulation said that it&#8217;s investigating the e-commerce giant [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chinese authorities investigate an e-commerce giant, Google may be tightening its grip on research and VCs weigh in on the year&#8217;s biggest surprises. This is your (briefer than usual) Daily Crunch for December 24, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Alibaba faces antitrust probe</strong></p>
<p>China&#8217;s State Administration for Market Regulation said that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/alibaba-antitrust-probe/">it&#8217;s investigating the e-commerce giant</a> over a policy that forces merchants to sell exclusively with Alibaba and skip rival platforms JD.com and Pinduoduo.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Alibaba will actively cooperate with the regulators on the investigation,” the company said in a statement. “Company business operations remain normal.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Chinese authorities have already called off the initial public offering of Alibaba affiliate Ant Group, and the company has now received another &#8220;meeting notice&#8221; from regulators.</p>
<p><strong>Holiday grab bag</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/google-reportedly-tightens-grip-on-research-into-sensitive-topics/">Google reportedly tightens grip on research into ‘sensitive topics’</a> — Reuters, citing researchers at the company and internal documents, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-alphabet-google-research-focus-idUSKBN28X1CB">reports</a> that Google has implemented new controls in the last year, including an extra round of inspection for papers on certain topics.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/equity-venture-capital-surprise-2020/">Five VCs discuss what surprised them the most in 2020</a> — The latest episode of Equity reflects on a year that no one could have predicted.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/gift-guide-last-minute-gift-ideas/">Gift Guide: Last-minute subscriptions to keep the gifts going all year</a> — They’re easy to order at the very last minute, easy to give from afar and they’ll spread the gifting fun out over weeks and months.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/the-built-environment-will-be-one-of-techs-next-big-platforms/">The built environment will be one of tech’s next big platforms</a> — An in-depth look at Sidewalk Labs&#8217; abandoned Toronto waterfront project.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/us-seed-stage-investing-flourished-during-pandemic/">US seed-stage investing flourished during pandemic</a> — According to a TechCrunch analysis of PitchBook data and a survey of venture capitalists, a few trends became clear.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/reading-between-the-lines-how-data-will-optimize-your-developers-annual-reviews/">Use Git data to optimize your developers’ annual reviews</a> — Three metrics can help you understand true performance quality.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/daily-crunch-alibaba-faces-antitrust-probe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090821</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Not even 5G could rescue smartphone sales in 2020</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/not-even-5g-could-rescue-smartphone-sales-in-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/not-even-5g-could-rescue-smartphone-sales-in-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 20:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5g]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone sales]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This was going to be the year of 5G. It was going to be the year the next-generation wireless technology helped reverse some troubling macro trends for the industry &#8212; or at the very least helped stem the bleeding some. But the best laid plans, and all that. With about a week left in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This was going to be the year of 5G. It was going to be the year the next-generation wireless technology helped reverse some troubling macro trends for the industry &#8212; or at the very least helped stem the bleeding some.</p>
<p>But the best laid plans, and all that. With about a week left in the year, I think it’s pretty safe to say that 2020 didn’t wind up the way the vast majority of us had hoped. It’s a list that certainly includes the lion’s share of smartphone makers. Look no further than a recent report published by Gartner to answer the question of just how bad 2020 was for smartphone sales.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5lcsBg4fCd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/29/gartner-q3-smartphone-sales-down-5-7-to-366m-slicing-covid-19-declines-in-q1-q2/">Gartner: Q3 smartphone sales down 5.7% to 366M, slicing COVID-19 declines in Q1, Q2</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gartner: Q3 smartphone sales down 5.7% to 366M, slicing COVID-19 declines in Q1, Q2&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/29/gartner-q3-smartphone-sales-down-5-7-to-366m-slicing-covid-19-declines-in-q1-q2/embed/#?secret=5lcsBg4fCd" data-secret="5lcsBg4fCd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It was so bad that a 5.7% global decline year-over-year for the third quarter constituted good news. In a normal year, that wouldn’t qualify as good news for too many industries outside of wax cylinder and asbestos sales. But there are few standards by which 2020 was a normal year, so now we’ll take some respite in the fact that a 5.7% drop was a considerably less pronounced drop than the ~20% we saw in Qs 1 and 2.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rhTK1DMb3E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/27/smartphone-sales-declined-again-in-q2-surprising-no-one/">Smartphone sales declined again in Q2, surprising no one</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Smartphone sales declined again in Q2, surprising no one&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/27/smartphone-sales-declined-again-in-q2-surprising-no-one/embed/#?secret=rhTK1DMb3E" data-secret="rhTK1DMb3E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VVIsQOxD1B"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/01/smartphone-sales-expected-to-drop-2-5-globally-this-year/">Smartphone sales expected to drop 2.5% globally this year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Smartphone sales expected to drop 2.5% globally this year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/01/smartphone-sales-expected-to-drop-2-5-globally-this-year/embed/#?secret=VVIsQOxD1B" data-secret="VVIsQOxD1B" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Some context before we get into the whys here. A thing that’s important to note up front is that mobile wasn’t one of those industries where everything was smooth sailing before everything got upended by a pandemic. In 2019 I wrote a not insignificant number of stories with headlines like “Smartphone sales expected to drop 2.5% globally this year” and “Smartphone sales declined again in Q2, surprising no one.” And even those stories were a continuation of trends from a year prior.</p>
<p>The reasons for the decline should be pretty familiar by now. For one thing, premium handsets got expensive, routinely topping out over $1,000. Related to that, phones have gotten good. Good news for consumers doesn’t necessarily translate to good news for manufacturers here, as upgrade cycles have slowed significantly from their traditional every two years (also an artifact of the carrier subscription model). Couple that with economic hardships, and you’ve got a recipe for slowed growth.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="y68ycXDHFN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/12/5g-devices-were-less-than-1-of-us-smartphone-purchases-in-2019/">5G devices were less than 1% of US smartphone purchases in 2019</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5G devices were less than 1% of US smartphone purchases in 2019&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/12/5g-devices-were-less-than-1-of-us-smartphone-purchases-in-2019/embed/#?secret=y68ycXDHFN" data-secret="y68ycXDHFN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This March, I wrote an article titled “5G devices were less than 1% of US smartphone purchases in 2019.” There was, perhaps, a certain level of cognitive dissonance there, after many years of 5G hype. There are myriad factors at play here. First, there just weren’t a ton of different 5G models available in the States by year’s end. Second, network rollout was far from complete. And, of course, there was no 5G iPhone.</p>
<p>I concluded that piece by noting:</p>
<blockquote><p>Of course, it remains to be seen how COVID-19 will impact sales. It seems safe to assume that, like every aspect of our lives, there will be a notable impact on the number of people buying expensive smartphones. Certainly things like smartphone purchases tend to lessen in importance in the face of something like a global pandemic.</p></blockquote>
<p>In hindsight, the answer is “a lot.” I’ll be the first to admit that when I wrote those words on March 12, I had absolutely no notion of how bad it was about to get and how long it would last (hello month nine of lockdown). In the earliest days, the big issue globally was on the supply side. Asia (China specifically) was the first place to get hit and the epicenter of manufacturing buckled accordingly. Both China and its manufacturing were remarkably fast to get back online.</p>
<p>In the intervening months, demand has taken a massive hit. Once again, there are a number of reasons for this. For starters, people aren’t leaving their homes as much &#8212; and for that reason, the money they’ve allotted to electronics purchases has gone toward things like PCs, as they’ve shifted to a remote work set-up. The other big issue here is simple economics. So many people are out of work and so much has become uncertain that smartphones have once again been elevated to a kind of luxury status.</p>
<p>There are, however, reasons to be hopeful. It seems likely that 5G will eventually help right things &#8212; though it’s hard to say when. Likely much of that depends on how soon we’re able to return to “normal” in 2021. But for now, there’s some <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/apple-iphone-12-supercycle-may-be-happening-after-all-new-data-shows/">positive to be seen in early iPhone sales</a>. After Apple went all in on 5G this year, the new handset (perhaps unsurprisingly) topped sales for all other 5G handsets for the month of October, according to analysts.</p>
<p>The company will offer a more complete picture (including the ever-important holiday sales) as part of its earnings report next month. For now, at least, it seems that thing are finally heading in the right direction. That trend will, hopefully, continue as the new year sees a number of Android launches.</p>
<p>Perhaps 2021 will be the year of 5G &#8212; because 2020 sure wasn’t.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/not-even-5g-could-rescue-smartphone-sales-in-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090802</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk says SpaceX to double launch pad usage for Starship tests, Super Heavy flights coming in a &#8216;few months&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/elon-musk-says-spacex-to-double-launch-pad-usage-for-starship-tests-super-heavy-flights-coming-in-a-few-months/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/elon-musk-says-spacex-to-double-launch-pad-usage-for-starship-tests-super-heavy-flights-coming-in-a-few-months/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 18:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gulf of Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyperloop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Years Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacex starship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090788</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX is set to significantly ramp up its Starship development program in the new year, in more ways than one. SpaceX CEO and founder Elon Musk noted on Twitter on Thursday that the company will seek to make use of both of its two launch pads at its development facility in Boca Chica, Texas with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-exploration-technologies" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-exploration-technologies">SpaceX <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is set to significantly ramp up its Starship development program in the new year, in more ways than one. SpaceX CEO and founder Elon Musk noted on Twitter on Thursday that the company will seek to make use of both of its two launch pads at its development facility in Boca Chica, Texas with prototype rockets set up on each, and that it will begin flight testing its Super Heavy booster (starting with low-altitude &#8220;hops&#8221;) as quickly as &#8220;a few months&#8221; from now.</p>
<p>Recently, SpaceX set up its SN9 prototype of Starship (the ninth in the current series) at Pad B at its Texas testing facility, which is on the Gulf of Mexico. SN9 will be next to undergo active testing, after SpaceX successfully flew its predecessor SN8 to an altitude of around 40,000 feet, and then executed a crucial belly flop maneuver that will be used to help control the powered landing of the production version. SN8 was destroyed when it touched down harder than expected, but SpaceX still achieved all its testing goals with the flight &#8212; and more.</p>
<p>SN9 will now undergo ground tests before hopefully doing its own flight test later on. That&#8217;ll provide the team with even more valuable data to carry on to further tests &#8212; with the ultimate goal of eventually achieving orbit with a Starship prototype vehicle. Musk&#8217;s<a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1342062363105759232"> tweet that two prototypes</a> will be stood up next to each other on Pad A and Pad B at the Boca Chica site could indicate the pace of these test flights might speed up, to match the fast clip at which SpaceX is constructing new rocket iterations.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Meanwhile, news that Super Heavy could be undergoing testing soon is also reason to get excited about 2021 for SpaceX and Starship. Super Heavy is the booster that SpaceX will eventually use to fly Starship for orbital launches, and to eventually help propel it to deep space &#8212; for destinations including Mars. Super Heavy will be around 240 feet tall, and will include 28 Raptor engines to provide it with the lift capacity needed to break Earth&#8217;s gravity when it&#8217;s stacked with a Starship loaded down with cargo.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uUo8doXvCv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/spacex-flies-its-starship-rocket-to-40000-feet-just-misses-the-landing-in-explosive-finale/">SpaceX flies its Starship rocket to 40,000 feet, just misses the landing in explosive finale</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX flies its Starship rocket to 40,000 feet, just misses the landing in explosive finale&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/spacex-flies-its-starship-rocket-to-40000-feet-just-misses-the-landing-in-explosive-finale/embed/#?secret=uUo8doXvCv" data-secret="uUo8doXvCv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/elon-musk-says-spacex-to-double-launch-pad-usage-for-starship-tests-super-heavy-flights-coming-in-a-few-months/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090788</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Use Git data to optimize your developers’ annual reviews</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/reading-between-the-lines-how-data-will-optimize-your-developers-annual-reviews/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/reading-between-the-lines-how-data-will-optimize-your-developers-annual-reviews/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 17:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommuting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Summarizing the performance of 10, 20 or 50 developers over the past 12 months, offering personalized advice and having the facts to back it up — is no small task.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Alex Circei</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/alexcircei">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexcircei/">Alex Circei</a> is CEO and co-founder of <a href="https://waydev.co/">Waydev</a>, a Git analytics tool that measures engineers' performance automatically.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/if-you-care-about-remote-employees-start-tracking-their-performance/">If you care about remote employees, start tracking their performance</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The end of the year is looming and with it one of your most important tasks as a manager. Summarizing the performance of 10, 20 or 50 developers over the past 12 months, offering personalized advice and having the facts to back it up — is no small task.</p>
<p>We believe that the only unbiased, accurate and insightful way to understand how your developers are working, progressing and — last but definitely not least — how they’re feeling, is with data. Data can provide more objective insights into employee activity than could ever be gathered by a human.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			It’s still very hard for many managers to fully understand that all employees work at different paces and levels.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Consider this: Over two-thirds of employees say they would put more effort into their work if they felt more appreciated, and 90% want a manager who&#8217;s fair to all employees.</p>
<p>Let’s be honest. It’s hard to judge all of your employees fairly if you’re (1) unable to work physically side-by-side with them, meaning you’ll inevitably have more contact with the some over others (e.g., those you’re more friendly with); and (2) you’re relying on manual trackers to keep on top of everyone’s work, which can get lost and take a lot of effort to process and analyze; (3) you expect engineers to self-report their progress, which is far from objective.</p>
<p>It’s also unlikely, especially with the quieter ones, that on top of all that you’ll have identified areas for them to expand their talents by upskilling or reskilling. But it’s that kind of personal attention that will make employees feel appreciated and able to progress professionally with you. Absent that, they’re likely to take the next best job opportunity that shows up.</p>
<p>So here’s a run down of why you need data to set up a fair annual review process; if not this year, then you can kick-start it for 2021.</p>
<h2>1. Use data to set next year’s goals</h2>
<p>The best way to track your developers’ progress automatically is by using Git Analytics tools, which track the performance of individuals by aggregating historical Git data and then feeding that information back to managers in minute detail.</p>
<p>This data will clearly show you if one of your engineers is over capacity or underworked and the types of projects they excel in. If you’re assessing an engineering manager and the team members they’re responsible for have been taking longer to push their code to the shared repository, causing a backlog of tasks, it may mean that they’re not delegating tasks properly. An appropriate goal here would be to track and divide their team’s responsibilities more efficiently, which can be tracked using the same metrics, or cross-training members of other teams to assist with their tasks.</p>
<p>Another example is that of an engineer who is dipping their toe into multiple projects. Indicators of where they’ve performed best include churn (we’ll get to that later), coworkers repeatedly asking that same employee to assist them in new tasks and of course positive feedback for senior staff, which can easily be integrated into Git analytics tools. These are clear signs that next year, your engineer could be maximizing their talents in these alternative areas, and you could diversify their tasks accordingly.</p>
<p>Once you know what targets to set, you can use analytics tools to create automatic targets for each engineer. That means that after you’ve set it up, it will be updated regularly on the engineer’s progress using indicators directly from the code repository. It won’t need time-consuming input from either you or your employee, allowing you both to focus on more important tasks. As a manager you’ll receive full reports once the deadline of the task is reached and get notified whenever metrics start dropping or the goal has been met.</p>
<p>This is important — you’ll be able to keep on top of those goals yourself, without having to delegate that responsibility or depend on self-reporting by the engineer. It will keep employee monitoring honest and transparent.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">2. Three Git metrics can help you understand true performance quality</h2>
<p>The easiest way for managers to “conclude” how an engineer has performed is by looking at superficial output: the number of completed pull requests submitted per week, the number of commits per day, etc. Especially for nontechnical managers, this is a grave but common error. When something is done, it doesn’t mean it’s been done well or that it is even productive or usable.</p>
<p>Instead, look at these data points to determine the actual quality of your engineer’s work:</p>
<ol>
<li>Churn is your number-one red flag, telling you how many times someone has modified their code in the first 21 days after it has been checked in. The more churn, the less of an engineer&#8217;s code is actually productive, with good longevity. Churn is a natural and healthy part of the software development process, but we’ve identified that any churn level above the normal 15%-30% indicates that an engineer is struggling with assignments.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/reading-between-the-lines-how-data-will-optimize-your-developers-annual-reviews/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090573</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US seed-stage investing flourished during pandemic</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/us-seed-stage-investing-flourished-during-pandemic/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/us-seed-stage-investing-flourished-during-pandemic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pandemic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pre-seed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seed]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you didn’t think much about seed in 2020, you’re not alone. Late, huge rounds consumed most of the media’s oxygen, leaving smaller startups to compete for scraps of attention.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As the United States entered its first wave of COVID-19 lockdowns, there were wide expectations in startup land <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/07/vcs-warn-coronavirus-will-impact-fundraising-for-the-next-2-quarters/">that a reckoning had arrived</a>. But the expected comeuppance of high-burn, high-growth startups fueled by cheap capital provided by venture capitalists <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/founders-fund-confirms-3-billion-in-new-capital-across-two-funds/">raising</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/09/index-raises-1-2b-growth-fund-and-800m-to-invest-in-emerging-startups/">ever-larger funds</a>, failed to arrive.</p>
<p>Instead, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/04/saas-earnings-rise-as-pandemic-pushes-companies-more-rapidly-to-the-cloud/">very opposite came to pass</a>.</p>
<p>Layoffs happened <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/30/the-second-wave-of-unicorn-layoffs-is-brutal/">swiftly and aggressively</a> during the early months of the pandemic era. But by the middle of Q2, venture activity had warmed and third quarter dealmaking felt <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/extension-rounds-help-some-startups-play-offense-during-covid-19/">swift and competitive</a>, with some investors describing it as the hottest summer in recent years.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Venture capital as an asset class has survived the pandemic’s stress test.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>But somewhat lost amongst the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/how-robinhood-and-chime-raised-2b-in-the-last-year/">splashy megarounds</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/unpacking-the-c3-ai-ipo-filing/">high-interest IPOs</a> that can dominate the news cycle were seed-stage startups. The raw little companies that represent the grist that will shape itself into the next set of giants.</p>
<p>TechCrunch explored what happened in seed investing to uncover what was missed amidst the storm and fury of late-stage startup activity. According to a TechCrunch analysis of <a href="https://pitchbook.com/">PitchBook data</a> and a survey of venture capitalists, a few trends became clear.</p>
<p>First, the pattern of <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/more-supergiant-seed-rounds-are-sprouting-up/">rising seed-check sizes</a> seen in prior years continued despite the tumultuous business climate. Second, more expensive and larger seed deals were not only caused by excessive capital present in the private markets. Instead, COVID-19 shook up which startups were considered attractive by private investors. And the changeup did not necessarily raise their number.</p>
<p>Let’s dig into the data and see what it can teach us about this wild year. Then we’ll hear from <a href="https://eniac.vc/">Eniac Ventures</a>’ <a href="https://twitter.com/nihalmehta">Nihal Mehta</a>, <a href="https://freestyle.vc/">Freestyle’s</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/jennylefcourt">Jenny Lefcourt</a>,<a href="https://www.pear.vc/"> Pear VC’s</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/marhershenson?lang=en">Mar Hershenson</a> and <a href="https://contrarycap.com/">Contrary Capital’s</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/etarczynski?lang=en">Eric Tarczynski</a> about what they saw in 2020 while writing a chunk of the checks that our data encompasses.</p>
<h2>The American seed market in 2020</h2>
<p>If you didn’t think much about seed in 2020, you’re not alone. Late, huge rounds <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/how-unicorns-helped-venture-capital-get-later-and-bigger/">consumed most of the media’s oxygen</a>, leaving smaller startups to compete for scraps of attention. There was so much late-stage activity &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/late-stage-deals-made-q3-2020-a-standout-vc-quarter-for-us-based-startups/">around 90 $100 million or larger rounds in Q3, for example</a> &#8212; it was difficult for smaller investments to command attention.</p>
<p>But despite living in the background, the dollars invested into seed-stage startups in the United States had an up-and-down year that was fascinating:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2090284" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090284" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2090284 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/seed-2020.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/seed-2020.jpg 1018w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/seed-2020.jpg?resize=150,88 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/seed-2020.jpg?resize=300,177 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/seed-2020.jpg?resize=768,453 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/seed-2020.jpg?resize=680,401 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/seed-2020.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090284" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> PitchBook</p></div></p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/seed-2" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="seed-2">Seed <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> dollar volume fell as Q1 progressed, reaching a 2020 nadir in April, the start of Q2. But as May arrived, the pace at which investors put money into seed-stage startups accelerated, recovering to January levels &#8212; which is to say, pre-pandemic &#8212; by June. The COVID dip, for seed, then, was a short-term affair.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/us-seed-stage-investing-flourished-during-pandemic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090277</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Grid sees machine learning as the brains behind the utility business of the future</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/national-grid-sees-machine-learning-as-the-brains-behind-the-utility-business-of-the-future/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/national-grid-sees-machine-learning-as-the-brains-behind-the-utility-business-of-the-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 14:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electrical grid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Grid Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart grid]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If the portfolio of a corporate venture capital firm can be taken as a signal for the strategic priorities of their parent companies, then National Grid has high hopes for automation as the future of the utility industry. The heavy emphasis on automation and machine learning from one of the nation&#8217;s largest privately held utilities [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If the portfolio of a corporate venture capital firm can be taken as a signal for the strategic priorities of their parent companies, then <a href="https://www.nationalgridus.com/Default.aspx">National Grid</a> has high hopes for automation as the future of the utility industry.</p>
<p>The heavy emphasis on automation and machine learning from one of the nation&#8217;s largest privately held utilities with a customer base numbering around 20 million people is significant. And a sign of where the industry could be going.</p>
<p>Since its launch, National Grid&#8217;s venture firm, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lisa-m-lambert-141448/">National Grid Partners</a>, has invested in 16 startups that featured machine learning at the core of their pitch. Most recently, the company backed AI Dash, which uses machine learning algorithms to analyze satellite images and infer the encroachment of vegetation on National Grid power lines to avoid outages.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Another recent investment, Aperio, uses data from sensors monitoring critical infrastructure to predict loss of data quality from degradation or cyberattacks.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mlcJaDuL6v"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/07/aperio-raises-a-4-5m-seed-round-to-protect-power-plants-from-hackers/">Aperio raises a $4.5M seed round to protect power plants from hackers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Aperio raises a $4.5M seed round to protect power plants from hackers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/07/aperio-raises-a-4-5m-seed-round-to-protect-power-plants-from-hackers/embed/#?secret=mlcJaDuL6v" data-secret="mlcJaDuL6v" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Indeed, of the $175 million in investments the firm has made, roughly $135 million has been committed to companies leveraging machine learning for their services.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;AI will be critical for the energy industry to achieve aggressive decarbonization and decentralization goals,&#8221; said Lisa Lambert, the chief technology and innovation officer at National Grid and the founder and president of National Grid Partners.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">National Grid started the year off slowly because of the COVID-19 epidemic, but the pace of its investments picked up and the company is on track to hit its investment targets for the year, Lambert said.</p>
<p>Modernization is critical for an industry that still mostly runs on spreadsheets and collective knowledge that has locked in an aging employee base, with no contingency plans in the event of retirement, Lambert said. It&#8217;s that situation that&#8217;s compelling National Grid and other utilities to automate more of their business.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“Most companies in the utility sector are trying to automate now for efficiency reasons and cost reasons. Today, most companies have everything written down in manuals; as an industry, we basically still run our networks off spreadsheets, and the skills and experience of the people who run the networks. So we&#8217;ve got serious issues if those people retire. Automating [and] digitizing is top of mind for all the utilities we’ve talked to in the Next Grid Alliance.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">To date, a lot of the automation work that&#8217;s been done has been around basic automation of business processes. But there are new capabilities on the horizon that will push the automation of different activities up the value chain, Lambert said.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“ ML is the next level &#8212; predictive maintenance of your assets, delivering for the customer. Uniphore, for example: you’re learning from every interaction you have with your customer, incorporating that into the algorithm, and the next time you meet a customer, you’re going to do better. So that’s the next generation,&#8221; Lambert said. &#8220;Once everything is digital, you&#8217;re learning from those engagements &#8212; whether engaging an asset or a human being.&#8221;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Lambert sees another source of demand for new machine learning tech in the need for utilities to rapidly decarbonize. The move away from fossil fuels will necessitate entirely new ways of operating and managing a power grid. One where humans are less likely to be in the loop.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“In the next five years, utilities have to get automation and analytics right if they’re going to have any chance at a net-zero world &#8212; you’re going to need to run those assets differently,&#8221; said Lambert. &#8220;Windmills and solar panels are not [part of] traditional distribution networks. A lot of traditional engineers probably don’t think about the need to innovate, because they’re building out the engineering technology that was relevant when assets were built decades ago &#8212; whereas all these renewable assets have been built in the era of OT/IT.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/national-grid-sees-machine-learning-as-the-brains-behind-the-utility-business-of-the-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090593</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five VCs discuss what surprised them the most in 2020</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/equity-venture-capital-surprise-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/equity-venture-capital-surprise-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 14:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garry tan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sarah kunst]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2089822</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast (now on Twitter!), where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. Today is our holiday look-back at the year, bringing not only our own Danny and Natasha and Chris and Alex into the mix, but also five venture capitalists who we got to leave us their [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/ffc04dd2-887d-4a90-816f-b5cbdafb0cfa?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast (<a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">now on Twitter!</a>), where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>Today is our holiday look-back at the year, bringing not only our own <a href="https://twitter.com/DannyCrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/CGates123">Chris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> into the mix, but also five venture capitalists who we got to leave us their notes as well. The goal for this episode was to reflect on a year that no one could have ever predicted, but with a specific angle, as always, on venture capital and startups.</p>
<p>We asked about the biggest surprise, non-portfolio companies to watch, and trends they got wrong and right. There was also banter on Zoom investing (Alex came up with Zesting, but we&#8217;re taking suggestions if anyone comes up with a better moniker) and startup pricing.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s who we asked to call into our super Fancy Equity Hotline:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/sarahkunst">Sarah Kunst</a>, Cleo Capital</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/TurnerNovak">Turner Novak</a>, Gelt</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/LolitaTaub">Lolita Taub</a>, The Community Fund</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/garrytan">Garry Tan</a>, Initialized</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/donutsdidthis">Iris Choi</a>, Floodgate</li>
</ul>
<p>Thanks to them all for participating, and of course you, our dear Equity listeners, for a blockbuster year for the podcast.</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts.</i></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/equity-venture-capital-surprise-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2089822</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The built environment will be one of tech&#8217;s next big platforms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/the-built-environment-will-be-one-of-techs-next-big-platforms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/the-built-environment-will-be-one-of-techs-next-big-platforms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 13:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[REEF Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sidewalk Infrastructure Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sidewalk labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart cities]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From the beginning, the plan for Sidewalk Labs (a subsidiary of Alphabet and &#8212; by extension &#8212; a relative of Google) to develop a $1.3 billion tech-enabled real estate project on the Toronto waterfront was controversial. Privacy advocates had justified concerns about the Google-adjacent company&#8217;s ability to capture a near-total amount of data from the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">From the beginning, the plan for <a href="https://www.sidewalklabs.com/">Sidewalk Labs</a> (a subsidiary of Alphabet and &#8212; by extension &#8212; a relative of Google) to develop a $1.3 billion tech-enabled real estate project on the Toronto waterfront was controversial.</p>
<p>Privacy advocates had justified concerns about the Google-adjacent company&#8217;s ability to capture a near-total amount of data from the residents of the development or any city-dweller that wandered into its high-tech panopticon.</p>
<p>But <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/alphabet" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="alphabet">Alphabet, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/sidewalk-labs" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="sidewalk-labs">Sidewalk Labs&#8217; <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> leadership and even Canada&#8217;s popular prime minister, Justin Trudeau, had high hopes for the project.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Startups working in real estate technology managed to nab a record $3.7 billion from investors in the first quarter of the year.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>“Successful cities around the world are wrestling with the same challenges of growth, from rising costs of living that price out the middle class, to congestion and ever-longer commutes, to the challenges of climate change. Sidewalk Labs scoured the globe for the perfect place to create a district focused on solutions to these pressing challenges, and we found it on Toronto’s Eastern Waterfront — along with the perfect public-sector partner, Waterfront Toronto,&#8221; said Sidewalk Labs chief executive Dan Doctoroff, the former deputy mayor of New York, <a href="https://storage.googleapis.com/sidewalk-toronto-ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/13214335/Sidewalk-Toronto-Press-Release.pdf">in a statement announcing the launch in 2017</a>. &#8220;This will not be a place where we deploy technology for its own sake, but rather one where we use emerging digital tools and the latest in urban design to solve big urban challenges in ways that we hope will inspire cities around the world.&#8221;</p>
<p>From Sidewalk Labs&#8217; perspective, the Toronto project would be an ideal laboratory that the company and the city of Toronto could use to explore the utility and efficacy of the latest and greatest new technologies meant to enhance city living and make it more environmentally sustainable.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s stated goal, back in 2017 was &#8220;to create a place that encourages innovation around energy, waste and other environmental challenges to protect the planet; a place that provides a range of transportation options that are more affordable, safe and convenient than the private car; a place that embraces adaptable buildings and new construction methods to reduce the cost of housing and retail space; a place where public spaces welcome families to enjoy the outdoors day and night, and in all seasons; a place that is enhanced by digital technology and data without giving up the privacy and security that everyone deserves.&#8221;</p>
<p>From a purely engineering perspective, integrating these new technologies into a single site to be a test case made some sense. From a community development perspective, it was a nightmare. Toronto residents began to see the development as little more than a showroom for <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1t12UqYl5SA">a slew of privacy-invading innovations</a> that Sidewalk could then spin up into companies &#8212; or a space where startup companies could test their tech on a potentially unwitting population.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/1t12UqYl5SA?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>So when the economic implications of the global COVID-19 pandemic started to become clear back in March of this year, it seemed as good a time as any for Sidewalk Labs to shutter the project.</p>
<p>&#8220;[As] unprecedented economic uncertainty has set in around the world and in the Toronto real estate market, it has become too difficult to make the 12-acre project financially viable without sacrificing core parts of the plan we had developed together with Waterfront Toronto to build a truly inclusive, sustainable community,&#8221; <a href="https://medium.com/sidewalk-talk/why-were-no-longer-pursuing-the-quayside-project-and-what-s-next-for-sidewalk-labs-9a61de3fee3a">Doctoroff said in a statement</a>. &#8220;And so, after a great deal of deliberation, we concluded that it no longer made sense to proceed with the Quayside project.&#8221;<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/the-built-environment-will-be-one-of-techs-next-big-platforms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085994</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bristol&#8217;s Brightpearl raises $33M Series C round led by Sage to boost its platform for retailers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/bristols-brightpearl-raises-33m-series-c-round-led-by-sage-to-boost-its-platform-for-retailers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/bristols-brightpearl-raises-33m-series-c-round-led-by-sage-to-boost-its-platform-for-retailers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 13:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brightpearl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Brightpearl, which allows retailers to streamline their operations thus boosting sales, has raised $33 million in funding to scale its business. This Series C round was led by Sage, which has put $23 million into the U.K. company. Previous backers Cipio Partners, Notion Capital and Verdane also participated, putting in $10 million. The Bristol, U.K.-based startup [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.brightpearl.com/">Brightpearl</a>, which allows retailers to streamline their operations thus boosting sales, has <a href="https://twitter.com/BrightpearlHQ/status/1342073610169683969">raised $33 million</a> in funding to scale its business. This <a href="https://www.brightpearl.com/press-and-media/press-releases/sage-and-brightpearl-announce-partnership-to-accelerate-digital-transformation-for-retail-customers">Series C round</a> was led by Sage, which has put <a href="https://www.sage.com/investors/investor-downloads/press-releases/2020/12/sage-and-brightpearl-announce-partnership/">$23 million into the U.K. company</a>. Previous backers Cipio Partners, Notion Capital and Verdane also participated, putting in $10 million.</p>
<p>The Bristol, U.K.-based startup has a platform for financial management, CRM, fulfillment, inventory and sales order management, purchasing and supplier management, warehousing and logistics.</p>
<p>Sage now takes a seat on <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/pearl-systems" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="pearl-systems">Brightpearl’s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> board. In a statement it said: “Together, Sage and Brightpearl will help retail and e-commerce customers take advantage of best-of-breed cloud finance and retail management solutions, supporting them on their digital journey. <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The partnership with Brightpearl is consistent with Sage’s broader strategy to invest in complementary high growth cloud-based software applications.” </span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Brightpearl has existing partnerships with Shopify, eBay and Amazon.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Derek O’Carroll, the chief executive of Brightpearl, said in a statement: “We are delighted to build this new relationship with Sage to further support our retail customers and accelerate the strong presence that Sage and Brightpearl have in the UK and US. Brightpearl’s solution brings significant benefits by automating retail processes so global merchants can save time and deliver outstanding and rapid end-to-end customer experiences.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/bristols-brightpearl-raises-33m-series-c-round-led-by-sage-to-boost-its-platform-for-retailers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090764</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China&#8217;s e-commerce titan Alibaba hit with antitrust probe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/alibaba-antitrust-probe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/alibaba-antitrust-probe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 02:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ant Financial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ant+]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack ma]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090746</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China&#8217;s top market watchdog has begun a probe into Alibaba over alleged anti-competition practices at the e-commerce firm, the latest of Beijing&#8217;s efforts to curb the country&#8217;s ever-expanding internet titans. The State Administration for Market Regulation said Thursday in a brief statement that it is investigating Alibaba over its &#8220;choosing one from two&#8221; policy, in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">China&#8217;s top market watchdog has begun a probe into Alibaba over alleged anti-competition practices at the e-commerce firm, the latest of Beijing&#8217;s efforts to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/china-literature-alibaba-fined/">curb the country&#8217;s ever-expanding internet titans</a>.</p>
<p>The State Administration for Market Regulation said Thursday in a brief <a href="http://www.samr.gov.cn/xw/zj/202012/t20201224_324638.html">statement</a> that it is investigating Alibaba over its &#8220;choosing one from two&#8221; policy, in which merchants are forced to sell exclusively on Alibaba and skip rivaling platforms JD.com and Pinduoduo.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today, Alibaba Group has received notification from the State Administration for Market Regulation that an investigation has been initiated into the Company pursuant to the Anti-Monopoly Law. Alibaba will actively cooperate with the regulators on the investigation,&#8221; Alibaba said in a statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Company business operations remain normal.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1qRCWhcqS5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/china-antitrust-rules-on-internet-industry/">China proposes antitrust law ahead of Singles&#8217; Day shopping spree</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China proposes antitrust law ahead of Singles&#8217; Day shopping spree&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/china-antitrust-rules-on-internet-industry/embed/#?secret=1qRCWhcqS5" data-secret="1qRCWhcqS5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Alibaba&#8217;s shares tumbled more than 8% on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange on Thursday.</p>
<p>On the same day, state-backed Xinhua <a href="http://www.xinhuanet.com/fortune/2020-12/24/c_1126900017.htm">reported</a> that Ant Group, Alibaba&#8217;s affiliate, has been summoned by a group of finance authorities to discuss its &#8220;compliance&#8221; work. Ant, which operates the popular Alipay e-wallet and works as an intermediary for financial services and customers, has pledged to take measures to curb debt risks after Chinese <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">authorities abruptly </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/china-postpones-ants-colossal-ipo-after-closed-door-talk-with-jack-ma/">called off</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> its colossal initial public offering last month.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;Today, Ant Group received a meeting notice from regulators. We will seriously study and strictly comply with all regulatory requirements and commit full efforts to fulfill all related work,&#8221; the firm <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/nxNILHzQytiglFoKHtB22A">said</a> in a statement.</p>
<p>Some argue that the clampdown is a long time coming for China&#8217;s internet giants, which have been allowed to grow under a relatively loose regulatory environment. The Alibaba case is a &#8220;significant step&#8221; in China&#8217;s anti-monopolistic regulations on the internet industry, said an opinion piece published in the official newspaper of China&#8217;s ruling Communist Party. Assuaging worries that stricter regulations could deal a blow to the industry, the piece said the probe into Alibaba &#8220;is beneficial to restoring orders and promoting long-term, healthy development of the platform economy.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8qbDk5Ug3i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/china-literature-alibaba-fined/">China fines Alibaba, Tencent&#8217;s e-book subsidiary over anti-trust violations</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China fines Alibaba, Tencent&#8217;s e-book subsidiary over anti-trust violations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/china-literature-alibaba-fined/embed/#?secret=8qbDk5Ug3i" data-secret="8qbDk5Ug3i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/alibaba-antitrust-probe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090746</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google reportedly tightens grip on research into &#8216;sensitive topics&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/google-reportedly-tightens-grip-on-research-into-sensitive-topics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/google-reportedly-tightens-grip-on-research-into-sensitive-topics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 01:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Timnit Gebru]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google is currently under fire for apparently pushing out a researcher whose work warned of bias in AI, and now a report from Reuters says others doing such work at the company have been asked to &#8220;strike a positive tone&#8221; and undergo additional reviews for research touching on &#8220;sensitive topics.&#8221; Reuters, citing researchers at the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is currently under fire for apparently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/googles-co-lead-of-ethical-ai-team-says-she-was-fired-for-sending-an-email/">pushing out a researcher whose work warned of bias in AI</a>, and now <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-alphabet-google-research-focus-idUSKBN28X1CB">a report from Reuters</a> says others doing such work at the company have been asked to &#8220;strike a positive tone&#8221; and undergo additional reviews for research touching on &#8220;sensitive topics.&#8221;</p>
<p>Reuters, citing researchers at the company and internal documents, reports that Google has implemented new controls in the last year, including an extra round of inspection for papers on certain topics and seemingly an increase in executive interference at later stages of research.</p>
<p>That certainly appears to have been the case with Dr. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/timnit-gebru" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="timnit-gebru">Timnit Gebru, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> an AI researcher at Google whose resignation seems to have been forced under confusing circumstances following friction between her and management over work that her team was doing. (I&#8217;ve asked Gebru and Google for comment on the story.)</p>
<p>
		<div class="embed breakout" id="vidible_div_0" data-pid="56faf851e4b0d3dcac2e081a" data-bcid="564f313b67b6231408bc51ee" data-video="5bac337dbf4885293903f4f0"></div>
		<span><script type="text/javascript" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunch-2017/features/shortcodes/vidible-callback-js.php?id=0"></script></span>
		</p>
<p>Among the &#8220;sensitive&#8221; topics, according to an internal web page seen by Reuters, are: &#8220;the oil industry, China, Iran, Israel, COVID-19, home security, insurance, location data, religion, self-driving vehicles, telecoms and systems that recommend or personalize web content.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s clear that many of these issues are indeed sensitive, though advising researchers to take care when addressing them seems superfluous considering the existence of ethics boards, peer review and other ordinary controls on research. One researcher who spoke to Reuters warned that this sort of top-down interference from Google could soon get &#8220;into a serious problem of censorship.&#8221;</p>
<p>This is in addition to the fundamental issue of vital research being conducted under the auspices of a company for which it may or may not be in their interest to publish. Naturally large private research institutions have existed for nearly as long as organized scientific endeavor, but companies like Facebook, Google, Apple, Microsoft and others exert an enormous influence over fields like AI and have good reason to avoid criticism of lucrative technologies while shouting their usefulness from every rooftop.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mILUY7qUcv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/google-ceo-says-company-will-review-events-leading-up-to-dr-timnit-gebrus-departure/">Google CEO says company will review events leading up to Dr. Timnit Gebru&#8217;s departure</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google CEO says company will review events leading up to Dr. Timnit Gebru&#8217;s departure&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/google-ceo-says-company-will-review-events-leading-up-to-dr-timnit-gebrus-departure/embed/#?secret=mILUY7qUcv" data-secret="mILUY7qUcv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/google-reportedly-tightens-grip-on-research-into-sensitive-topics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090715</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: Last-minute subscriptions to keep the gifts going all year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/gift-guide-last-minute-gift-ideas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/gift-guide-last-minute-gift-ideas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 23:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2020]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SURPRISE! It's December 23rd. How? Because time doesn't make sense anymore and last week was really a month ago and April was yesterday.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to TechCrunch’s 2020 Holiday Gift Guide! Need help with gift ideas? We’re here to help! </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><em>You can find our other guides right here.</em></a></p>
<p>SURPRISE! It&#8217;s December 23rd. How? Because time doesn&#8217;t make sense anymore and last week was really a month ago and April was yesterday.</p>
<p>Last-minute shopping is always pretty dreadful, but this year particularly so. No one should be dropping their social distancing practices just to battle crowds for a twice-returned air fryer. Online retailers, meanwhile, have been warning of shipping delays since before December even started.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Fortunately, subscription boxes and services exist. They&#8217;re easy to order at the very last minute, easy to give from afar and they&#8217;ll spread the gifting fun out over weeks and months.</p>
<p>Need some ideas? Here&#8217;s some inspiration:</p>
<h2>For the puzzle/escape room fan: Hunt A Killer</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2090690" style="width: 514px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090690" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2090690" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Hunt-a-killer.png?w=504" alt="" width="504" height="500" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Hunt-a-killer.png 504w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Hunt-a-killer.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Hunt-a-killer.png?resize=300,298 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Hunt-a-killer.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Hunt-a-killer.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Hunt-a-killer.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Hunt-a-killer.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Hunt-a-killer.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 504px) 100vw, 504px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090690" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Hunt A Killer</p></div></p>
<p>THERE&#8217;S BEEN A (fictional) MURDER!</p>
<p>You&#8217;ve been contacted by a detective who needs your help, and your job is to figure out whodunnit through the process of elimination. Each month brings another slice of the story via a box filled with puzzles, newspaper clippings, audio recordings, props and other clues that lead you to the criminal.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve done a few of these sets with family, and we&#8217;ve very much enjoyed them as a way to lose ourselves in a fictional world for a few hours. It&#8217;s paced in such a way that no single box is a commitment of more than an hour or two, so you can just drop back in whenever you&#8217;ve got the time. You can also expedite the next month&#8217;s box if you don&#8217;t want to wait, which is great.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.huntakiller.com">Varies, but the six-month prepay option gets you one full game for around $165.</a></p>
<h2>For the crafters and scrapbookers: Pipsticks</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2090691" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090691" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2090691" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pipsticks.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="279" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pipsticks.jpg 1020w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pipsticks.jpg?resize=150,61 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pipsticks.jpg?resize=300,123 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pipsticks.jpg?resize=768,315 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pipsticks.jpg?resize=680,279 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pipsticks.jpg?resize=50,20 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090691" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Pipsticks</p></div></p>
<p>Got a friend whose childhood love for stickers never faded? Pipsticks will send them a bundle of (really, really nice!) stickers each month. They&#8217;ve got a &#8220;Kids Club&#8221; plan meant specifically for the little ones, or a &#8220;Pro Club&#8221; pack for anyone looking to buff up their journaling/scrapbooking/crafting sticker collection.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.pipsticks.com">Starts at $12 per month</a></p>
<h2>For the dog owners: Barkbox</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2090692" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090692" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2090692" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/barkbox.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="386" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/barkbox.jpg 766w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/barkbox.jpg?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/barkbox.jpg?resize=300,170 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/barkbox.jpg?resize=680,386 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/barkbox.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090692" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Barkbox</p></div></p>
<p>Spoiling dogs is fun. Barkbox brings &#8217;em a constant rotation of treats and toys, all tailored around each month&#8217;s theme, like &#8220;Dogsgiving&#8221; in November or &#8220;Lick or Treat&#8221; back in October. Boxes are tailored to the size of the dog, and they&#8217;ve got a slightly pricier &#8220;Super Chewer&#8221; box with ultra-durable picks for dogs that chomp right through anything you put in front of them.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.barkbox.com">Starts at $23 per month</a></p>
<h2>For the highly caffeinated: Coffee subscriptions</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2003668" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2003668" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2003668" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/GettyImages-450769547.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/GettyImages-450769547.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/GettyImages-450769547.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/GettyImages-450769547.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/GettyImages-450769547.jpg?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/GettyImages-450769547.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/GettyImages-450769547.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2003668" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tetra Images <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>There&#8217;s a whole world of coffee to explore out there, but it&#8217;s way too easy to pick up whatever bag looks pretty and stick with that brand until the end of time. Got a friend that&#8217;s been buying the same red plastic tub of grounds for 10 years? Encourage them to branch out a bit!</p>
<p>There are so, <em>so</em> many options for coffee subscriptions, but a few that our team has tried and can vouch for are: <a href="https://www.yesplz.coffee">YesPlz</a>, <a href="https://www.drinktrade.com">Trade Coffee</a>, <a href="https://www.mistobox.com">Mistobox</a>, <a href="https://www.redbaycoffee.com">Red Bay Coffee</a> and <a href="https://angelscup.com/pages/subscribe">Angel&#8217;s Cup</a></p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> Varies</p>
<h2>For the one who wants to read more: Book of the Month</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2090694" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090694" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2090694" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/BOTM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="426" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/BOTM.jpg 758w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/BOTM.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/BOTM.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/BOTM.jpg?resize=680,426 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/BOTM.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090694" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Book of the Month</p></div></p>
<p>They vet the books, you read them. Each month you pick from one of five genre-spanning options and it&#8217;s dropped at your door. Running short on time and haven&#8217;t finished last month&#8217;s pick, or just not into this month&#8217;s selections? You can skip a month quite easily.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong> <a href="https://www.bookofthemonth.com">Starts at $50 for three months of books</a></p>
<h2>For the new human (and their parents): Lovevery Play Kits</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2090720" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Lovevery.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="295" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Lovevery.jpg 1237w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Lovevery.jpg?resize=150,65 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Lovevery.jpg?resize=300,130 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Lovevery.jpg?resize=768,333 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Lovevery.jpg?resize=680,295 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Lovevery.jpg?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Got a friend with a newborn and have no idea what to get them? Lovevery takes the subscription box concept and breaks it down month-by-month for the first stretch of a kid&#8217;s life. The newborn box, for example, focuses on high contrast items and things that&#8217;ll make tummy time a little more fun, whereas later boxes bring in toys that help with finer motor skills like stacking and grasping. They also offer boxes for toddlers, introducing concepts like rhyming, matching and counting. The boxes are a bit pricey, but the company makes huge efforts to keep things sustainable and baby safe.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong><a href="https://gifting.lovevery.com/home">Around $80 per box</a></p>
<h2>For the TechCrunch reader: Extra Crunch</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1781845" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/extra-crunch-featured-image.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="361" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/extra-crunch-featured-image.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/extra-crunch-featured-image.jpg?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/extra-crunch-featured-image.jpg?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/extra-crunch-featured-image.jpg?resize=768,408 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/extra-crunch-featured-image.jpg?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/extra-crunch-featured-image.jpg?resize=1536,816 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/extra-crunch-featured-image.jpg?resize=2048,1088 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/extra-crunch-featured-image.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Shameless plug time! Extra Crunch is our membership program, where we&#8217;re able to go deep on topics like hiring, building a company and picking the right investors. We regularly host Extra Crunch Live sessions where we chat with some of the biggest names in the industry and field questions from the audience, and our EC-1 series gives readers a rare view into the formation and strategies of some of the fastest growing companies around. We just launched a gifting option — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/ec-gifting/">check it out here</a>!</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/ec-gifting/">$75 per year</a></p>
<h2>For the one with good handwriting: Maido in a Box</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2090697" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090697" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2090697" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mai-do.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="545" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mai-do.jpg 699w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mai-do.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mai-do.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mai-do.jpg?resize=680,545 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mai-do.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090697" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Kinokuniya</p></div></p>
<p>My handwriting is a joke, but I still absolutely love a good pen. One of my favorite stores to just wander around — back when that was a thing we could do — is Maido. Owned by the Japanese bookstore chain Kinokuniya, Maido offers up a carefully curated collection of pens and stationary in a way that&#8217;s exhaustive but not overwhelming.</p>
<p>With the pandemic greatly limiting aimless retail store exploration, Maido has started producing monthly themed boxes where they bring their best goods to you. I&#8217;ve ordered a few of these so far, and each box has been just wonderful. If you&#8217;ve got a friend that has ever spent 20 minutes talking about their favorite pen, this one&#8217;s for them.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://usa.kinokuniya.com/featured-stationery-maido-in-a-box">$35</a></p>
<h2>For the would-be green thumb: Succulent Studios</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2090699" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090699" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2090699" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/succulent.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="277" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/succulent.jpg 691w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/succulent.jpg?resize=150,61 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/succulent.jpg?resize=300,122 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/succulent.jpg?resize=680,277 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/succulent.jpg?resize=50,20 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090699" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Succulent Studios</p></div></p>
<p>I love plants! Sadly, I also tend to kill plants pretty much immediately. I was very proud this year to grow a whole FOUR grape tomatoes before my tomato plant fell over and died. What the hell am I supposed to do with four grape tomatoes?</p>
<p>As a result, our house and yard are filled with all of the succulents we can find — they&#8217;re super pretty and, thankfully, incredibly hard to kill. A lot of ours came from Succulent Studio, a service that does a wonderful job of finding new plants (with fun names like Lime Sparkler and Superbum) and delivering them safely to your door. If one does happen get beat up en route, they&#8217;ll teach you how to revive it&#8230; or, failing that, they&#8217;ll replace it.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://succulent.studio">$16.50 for two plants a month</a></p>
<h2>For the folks who like wine: MORE WINE</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1963351" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1963351" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-1963351" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-946327882.jpeg?w=680" alt="A bottle of wine escaping from a gift box. Still life." width="680" height="474" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-946327882.jpeg 2074w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-946327882.jpeg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-946327882.jpeg?resize=300,209 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-946327882.jpeg?resize=768,535 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-946327882.jpeg?resize=680,474 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-946327882.jpeg?resize=1536,1071 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-946327882.jpeg?resize=2048,1428 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-946327882.jpeg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1963351" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>As with coffee, there are SO many different wines to try and so many different services that want to help you try them all. It&#8217;s tough to narrow it down, but there are plenty of services with proven track records. <a href="https://www.winc.com">Winc</a> has you take a quiz that aims to analyze your tastes and pair accordingly. <a href="https://www.cellarswineclub.com">Cellars Wine Club</a> lets you pick a theme (Imports? Sweet? Sparkling? Reds only?) <a href="https://www.getvinebox.com">Vinebox</a> sends wine by the glass in cute little test tube lookin&#8217; vials so you don&#8217;t have to commit to a whole bottle. TechCrunch&#8217;s own Darrell Etherington likes <a href="https://gargoylewineclub.com/products/wine-club">Gargoyle Wine Club</a>, with the caveat that it only ships to Canada.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> Varies, but generally around $60-80 per box.</p>
<h2>For the traveler who can&#8217;t travel right now: Try the World</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2090701" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090701" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2090701" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/try-the-world.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="295" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/try-the-world.jpg 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/try-the-world.jpg?resize=150,65 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/try-the-world.jpg?resize=300,130 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/try-the-world.jpg?resize=680,295 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/try-the-world.jpg?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090701" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Try the World</p></div></p>
<p>One of my favorite parts about traveling is wandering into a local grocery store and trying all of the regional staples — all of the snacks, candies and other goodies I&#8217;ve never seen at home. That sort of exploration isn&#8217;t super feasible in 2020, a year when many of us haven&#8217;t even left our own state.</p>
<p>As its name suggests, Try the World brings all of those goodies from around the globe straight to your doorstep. I&#8217;ve had boxes contain regional-favorite hot sauces, teas, spices, mustards and more. The only catch? If you find something you love, finding where to buy more can be tough.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.trytheworld.com">Starts at $40 a month</a></p>
<h2>For the snazzy dresser: Gentleman&#8217;s Box</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2090708" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gentlemans-box.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="433" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gentlemans-box.jpg 797w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gentlemans-box.jpg?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gentlemans-box.jpg?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gentlemans-box.jpg?resize=768,490 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gentlemans-box.jpg?resize=680,433 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gentlemans-box.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>As written by our Editorial Director Henry Pickavet, who I can confirm is often dressed much more nicely than me:</p>
<blockquote><p>I consider myself to be a fairly decent dresser. I tend to lean on ties, tie bars, pocket squares and the like to spruce up a button-down or a gray jacket.</p>
<p>But the choices! The sheer number of accessories, color schemes and levels of fancy can be overwhelming. Which is why I was pretty excited when I came across Gentleman’s Box.</p>
<p>Each month, I receive a small box that includes five to six items: a tie and a pair of socks, as well as a combination of a random mix of a number of other things that alternate from month to month, such as a tie bar, cuff links, a lapel pin and a pocket square. I’ve also received a few watches, a few pairs of sunglasses, a wallet, a tray for odds and ends and money clip. Fancy, right?</p>
<p>Each box also comes with an editorially curated booklet that includes details about how the selections of the month fit together, as well as pictures from customers showing their wares in the wild. I look forward to the end of the pandemic for a number of reasons, and on that list is to be able to go out again and get my dapper on.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>Depending on what you&#8217;re looking for, <a href="https://gentlemansbox.com/">ranges from $35 to $100+ per box</a></p>
<h2>For the gamer: An all-you-can-play service on their platform of choice</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2090705" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090705" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2090705" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="304" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox.jpg 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox.jpg?resize=150,67 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox.jpg?resize=300,134 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox.jpg?resize=768,344 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox.jpg?resize=680,304 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/xbox.jpg?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090705" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Microsoft</p></div></p>
<p>Why give &#8217;em just one game when you can give them access to <em>tons</em> of games? A lot of the big names in gaming all have Netflix-style on-demand games services now, and they&#8217;re actually pretty dang solid. Sony has PS Now (check out Horizon Zero Dawn, Hollow Knight and the God of War series if you haven&#8217;t already), and Microsoft has Xbox Game Pass (Gears 5! MotoGP 20! Celeste!). Even Apple is getting in on the fun with Apple Arcade — if you dive in there, be sure to check out Beyond a Steel Sky, one of our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/gift-guide-techcrunchs-favorite-things-of-2020/">favorite things of 2020.</a></p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong><a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/ps-now/">PS Now</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/xbox-game-pass">Xbox Game Pass</a> are both $10 per month (but cheaper if you prepay), while <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-arcade/">Apple Arcade</a> is $5 per month</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FJAbEEGGFN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/gift-guide-techcrunchs-favorite-things-of-2020/">Gift Guide: TechCrunch&#8217;s Favorite Things of 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gift Guide: TechCrunch&#8217;s Favorite Things of 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/gift-guide-techcrunchs-favorite-things-of-2020/embed/#?secret=FJAbEEGGFN" data-secret="FJAbEEGGFN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gift-guide-2020-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/gift-guide-last-minute-gift-ideas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090681</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Telegram prepares to monetize</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/daily-crunch-telegram-prepares-to-monetize/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/daily-crunch-telegram-prepares-to-monetize/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 23:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pavel Durov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Telegram will introduce ads, TikTok&#8217;s parent company is moving into drug discovery and President Trump continues his battle against Section 230. This is your Daily Crunch for December 23, 2020. The big story: Telegram prepares to monetize Telegram founder Pavel Durov said the messaging app will introduce advertising next year on public one-to-many channels. Durov [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/telegram" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="telegram">Telegram <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> will introduce ads, TikTok&#8217;s parent company is moving into drug discovery and President Trump continues his battle against Section 230. This is your Daily Crunch for December 23, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Telegram prepares to monetize</strong></p>
<p>Telegram founder <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/pavel-durov" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="pavel-durov">Pavel Durov <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said the messaging app will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/telegram-to-launch-an-ad-platform-as-it-approaches-500-million-users/">introduce advertising next year</a> on public one-to-many channels. Durov wrote on his Telegram channel the ad platform will be &#8220;one that is user-friendly, respects privacy and allows us to cover the costs of server and traffic.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He also pointed to premium stickers as another way that Telegram could monetize, while emphasizing that existing features will remain free and that he does not support showing ads in private chats.</p>
<p>In addition to discussing the company&#8217;s monetization plans, Durov said that Telegram is &#8220;approaching&#8221; 500 million users.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/nikolas-stock-crashes-after-announcing-cancelation-of-contract-with-republic-services-for-2500-garbage-trucks/">Nikola’s stock crashes after announcing cancelation of contract with Republic Services for 2,500 garbage trucks</a> — This is the latest deal to unravel for Nikola as it tries to patch up following recent devastating reports.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/bytedance-ai-drug/">TikTok parent ByteDance hiring for AI drug discovery team</a> — &#8220;We are looking for candidates to join our team and conduct cutting-edge research in drug discovery and manufacturing powered by AI algorithms,&#8221; the company said in a job posting.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/weride-200-million-funding/">Chinese autonomous driving startup WeRide bags $200M in funding</a> — The new funding will see WeRide joining hands with Yutong, a 57-year-old company, to make autonomous-driving minibuses and city buses.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/voyager-space-holdings-to-acquire-majority-stake-in-commercial-space-leader-nanoracks/">Voyager Space Holdings to acquire majority stake in commercial space leader Nanoracks</a> — Nanoracks provided the Bishop Airlock that was installed on the International Space Station.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/honk-introduces-a-real-time-ephemeral-messaging-app-aimed-at-gen-z/">Honk introduces a real-time, ephemeral messaging app aimed at Gen Z</a> — Instead of sending texts off into the void and hoping for a response, friends on Honk communicate via messages that are shown live as you type.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/dear-sophie-whats-ahead-for-u-s-immigration-in-2021/">Dear Sophie: What’s ahead for US immigration in 2021?</a> — Sophie Alcorn weighs in on what&#8217;s next for U.S. visas and green cards.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-after-2020s-epic-ma-spree/">Looking ahead after 2020’s epic M&amp;A spree</a> — This year, four deals involving chip companies totaled over $100 billion on their own.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-to-2021-venture-fundraising-liquidity-and-the-everything-bubble/">Heading into 2021: Venture fundraising, liquidity and the everything bubble</a> — Alex Wilhelm&#8217;s final column of the year.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/trump-ndaa-veto-section-230/">Trump vetoes major defense bill, citing Section 230</a> — President Trump has vetoed the $740 million National Defense Authorization Act, a major bill that allocates military funds each year.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/ripples-xrp-cryptocurrency-crashes-following-announcement-of-sec-suit/">XRP cryptocurrency crashes following announcement of SEC suit against Ripple</a> — The XRP token’s value has declined more than 42% in the past 24 hours.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/taskrabbit-resets-passwords-suspicious-activity-network/">TaskRabbit is resetting customer passwords after finding ‘suspicious activity’ on its network</a> — The company later confirmed the activity was a credential stuffing attack, where existing sets of exposed or breached usernames and passwords are matched against different websites to access accounts.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/daily-crunch-telegram-prepares-to-monetize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090656</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump vetoes major defense bill, citing Section 230</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/trump-ndaa-veto-section-230/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/trump-ndaa-veto-section-230/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 21:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Section 230]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The battle over big tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following through on his previous threat, President Trump has vetoed the $740 million National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA), a major bill that allocates military funds each year. In tweets early this month, Trump said he would sink the NDAA if it wasn&#8217;t altered to include language &#8220;terminating&#8221; Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act, an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Following through on his <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/trump-section-230-ndaa/">previous threat</a>, President Trump has vetoed the $740 million National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA), a major bill that allocates military funds each year.</p>
<p>In tweets early this month, Trump said he would sink the NDAA if it wasn&#8217;t altered to include language &#8220;terminating&#8221; Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act, an essential and previously obscure internet law that the president has had in his crosshairs for the better part of the year.</p>
<p>&#8220;Your failure to terminate the very dangerous national security risk of Section 230 will make our intelligence virtually impossible to conduct without everyone knowing what we are doing at every step,&#8221; Trump said in a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/presidential-veto-message-house-representatives-h-r-6395/">statement</a> on the veto. It&#8217;s not clear what the president meant, or what he was referring to in criticizing the military funding bill as a &#8221; &#8216;gift&#8217; to China and Russia.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Section 230, which is a liability shielding gift from the U.S. to “Big Tech” (the only companies in America that have it &#8211; corporate welfare!), is a serious threat to our National Security &amp; Election Integrity. Our Country can never be safe &amp; secure if we allow it to stand&#8230;..</p>
<p>&mdash; Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1333965375193624578?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The president cited &#8220;bipartisan calls&#8221; for a Section 230 repeal in his decision, in spite of the NDAA&#8217;s overwhelming bipartisan support in Congress and the fact that Section 230 reform was never seriously considered in the unrelated military spending bill. Trump also claimed that Section 230 &#8220;facilitates the spread of foreign disinformation online,&#8221; a threat that the president, who frequently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/trump-flu-covid-misinformation-facebook-and-twitter/">spreads dangerous misinformation online</a>, has historically expressed little concern for.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cBnMFUPl62"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/trump-section-230-ndaa/">Trump&#8217;s odd new attack on Section 230 is probably doomed</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Trump&#8217;s odd new attack on Section 230 is probably doomed&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/trump-section-230-ndaa/embed/#?secret=cBnMFUPl62" data-secret="cBnMFUPl62" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Section 230 became a hot topic in 2020 as lawmakers, states and the federal government made major moves to rein in the tech industry&#8217;s biggest, most powerful companies. The law protects internet companies from liability for the content they host and is widely credited with opening the doors for internet companies big and small to grow their online business over the years.</p>
<p>Looking for leverage over tech platforms that policed his content, Trump zeroed in on Section 230 — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/trump-twitter-executive-order-social-media/">and Twitter in particular</a> — early this year. In May, the president signed an unusual but largely toothless <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/trump-social-media-executive-order/">executive order</a> attacking tech&#8217;s liability shield. &#8220;The choices Twitter makes when it chooses to edit, blacklist, shadowban are editorial decisions, pure and simple,” Trump said when he signed the order.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OA3JjOFD1Q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/trump-twitter-executive-order-social-media/">Going to war with Twitter, Trump threatens critical social media legal protections</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Going to war with Twitter, Trump threatens critical social media legal protections&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/trump-twitter-executive-order-social-media/embed/#?secret=OA3JjOFD1Q" data-secret="OA3JjOFD1Q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Trump&#8217;s position on Section 230 and the NDAA was never particularly tenable. While the NDAA is a massive piece of legislation, the kind that rolls up many disparate things, altering it to somehow repeal Section 230 was never on the table. It&#8217;s also hard to overstate the unpopularity of the position the president has staked out here. The NDAA funds many parts of the military beyond combat and this year&#8217;s bill includes pay raises for the troops and additional health support for Vietnam veterans.</p>
<p>Trump&#8217;s views on Section 230 are similarly extreme, even relative to many other members of his party. While there is support for changing Section 230 on both sides of the aisle, Congress is far from a consensus on what needs to change and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/section-230-hearing-big-tech/">complex bipartisan reform effort</a> is ongoing. Throwing Section 230 out altogether is very unlikely to be the end result of whatever kind of reform Congress comes up with in the coming year.</p>
<p>The House plans to convene on Monday to override the president&#8217;s exercise of veto powers, an effort that would require a two-thirds majority in both houses of Congress. The House approved the NDAA earlier this month with a veto-proof 355-78 vote, including broad support from the vast majority of House Republicans. The Senate passed the legislation along to the president with a <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/12/11/senate-passes-defense-bill-444579">similarly strong bipartisan 84-13 vote</a> in favor of the bill on December 11.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yofp5lu8Dx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/section-230-hearing-big-tech/">Section 230 will be on the chopping block at the next big tech hearing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Section 230 will be on the chopping block at the next big tech hearing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/section-230-hearing-big-tech/embed/#?secret=yofp5lu8Dx" data-secret="yofp5lu8Dx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-battle-over-big-tech/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/battle-over-big-tech-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/trump-ndaa-veto-section-230/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090640</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
