<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 09:31:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Fintechs in Africa continue to overshadow all other startups in funding gained</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/fintechs-in-africa-continue-to-overshadow-all-other-startups-in-funding-gained/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/fintechs-in-africa-continue-to-overshadow-all-other-startups-in-funding-gained/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Njanja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 09:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mpesa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year 2021 saw more and bigger deals closed in Africa, as tech startups across the continent raised close to $5 billion. This amount was double the previous year’s investment, and nine times what was raised five years ago, an indication of how much the startup scene has transformed over the last few years. Fintechs [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The year 2021 saw more and bigger deals closed in Africa, as tech startups across the continent raised </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/african-tech-took-center-stage-in-2021/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">close to $5 billion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This amount was double the previous year’s investment, and</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/another-record-breaking-year-african-tech-start-ups-raised-collon/?trackingId=6ncsYxVeIpYLqWvU8n6CNg%3D%3D"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">nine</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> times what was raised five years ago, an indication of how much the startup scene has transformed over the last few years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fintechs dominated the fundraising, accounting for nearly $3 billion, or two thirds of all the investment realized by startups across the continent last year, a </span><a href="https://briter-bridges.typeform.com/africa-2021?typeform-source=briterbridges.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">report </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">by markets insights firm Briter Bridges shows. This amount was also more than double the </span><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-06/fintech-bright-spot-africa-plays-catch-up-in-bumper-funding-year?sref=gni836kR"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$1.35 billion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> investment that fintechs in Africa raised in 2020, and triple the amount in 2019.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Among the largest beneficiaries of the fintech capital were <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/african-fintech-opay-valued-at-2b-in-softbank-vision-fund-2-led-400m-funding/">Opay</a>, which raised $400 million in  Series C funding, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/african-payments-company-flutterwave-raises-170m-now-valued-at-over-1b/">Flutterwave</a>, which got $170 million in a Series C round, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/south-african-digital-bank-tymebank-lands-109m-from-uk-and-phillippines-investors/">TymeBank</a>, which raised $180 million in Series B. Jumo and MNT Halan raised $120 million rounds, as digital payments gateway MFS Africa gained $100 million. This was as Zepz (formerly WorldRemit) raised $292 million in Series E financing, while <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/chipper-cash-gets-2b-valuation-with-150m-extension-round-led-by-ftx/">Chipper Cash</a> raised</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">$250 million</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> , <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/tala-grabs-145m-to-offer-more-financial-services-in-emerging-markets/">Tala</a> $145 million as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/06/sequoia-heritage-stripe-and-others-invest-200m-in-african-fintech-wave-at-1-7b-valuation/">Wave</a> sealed $200 million in funding.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252619" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And, given the incremental funding for fintechs in Africa over the years, capital injected into these startups is only likely to increase with deepening mobile phone usage and internet penetration. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile subscriber penetration across the continent is predicted to increase by four percentage points to hit 615 million &#8211; </span><a href="https://www.gsma.com/mobileeconomy/sub-saharan-africa/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">half of the continent’s population</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; by 2025 according to the GSM Association. It is also poised for greater growth as the adoption of lending, digital payments, banking and insurance services grows. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Financial Technology Partners, an investment banking firm focused exclusively on fintech, in a past review of the sector in Africa </span><a href="https://ftpartners.docsend.com/view/kg7dbcj"><span style="font-weight: 400;">said</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the continent, with its rapidly growing population, some of the fastest-growing economies and an underdeveloped financial services ecosystem, presents an attractive opportunity for fintechs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“While the payment space begins to see scale-ups such as Flutterwave, Chipper, MFS Africa, Cellulant, Jumo playing alongside global, established providers such as Visa, Mastercard, and Stripe, the next few years are likely to (in fact, we already do) see increased movements across other fintech verticals, from lending to KYC, SME management software, and decentralised finance. This, and greater M&amp;A activity, as the ecosystem moves towards maturity and consolidation,” Director at Briter Bridges, Dario Giuliani told TechCrunch.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2252903" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2252903" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2252903" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BriterBridges.png" alt="" width="1024" height="609" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BriterBridges.png 1568w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BriterBridges.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BriterBridges.png?resize=300,179 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BriterBridges.png?resize=768,457 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BriterBridges.png?resize=680,405 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BriterBridges.png?resize=1536,914 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BriterBridges.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2252903" class="wp-caption-text">Deals by stage in Africa over the years. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Briter Bridges</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Startups specializing in digital/mobile payments have received the greatest financing over the years followed by banking/lending startups and insurtechs.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The latest </span><a href="https://ftpartners.docsend.com/view/kg7dbcj"><span style="font-weight: 400;">data</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> shows digital payments space in Africa has also experienced the greatest growth in terms of funding received and total transactions volume </span><a href="https://ftpartners.docsend.com/view/kg7dbcj"><span style="font-weight: 400;">over the last decade</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> when compared to other sub-sectors within the fintech space. The growth experienced by fintechs is against the backdrop of the increasing phone ownership and a deepening penetration of mobile money technology and the internet – all of which have made it possible to bypass the sometimes restrictive traditional banking infrastructure.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Innovations around mobile money and digital payments have allowed for the processing of payments online and offline through USSD or STK commands, over apps or using NFC technology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Africa has a massive underbanked and unbanked population, but its growing middle class, increasing mobile penetration and improving communications infrastructure make it uniquely conducive to fintech innovation and mobile financial services,” said Financial Technology Partners.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Emerging fintech services have banked the unbanked, driving up financial inclusion as their uptake solves some of the greatest pain points experienced by businesses and individuals– like sending and receiving money, and accepting payments. Startups in the remittance space like Wari, sureRemit and Paga, have, for example, made it possible for African residents to receive money from overseas easily and affordably. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1982071" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1982071" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1982071" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/89664713_gettyimages-74504527.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/89664713_gettyimages-74504527.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/89664713_gettyimages-74504527.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/89664713_gettyimages-74504527.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/89664713_gettyimages-74504527.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/89664713_gettyimages-74504527.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/89664713_gettyimages-74504527.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1982071" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Opportunities for growth</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Africa is regarded as the world’s second-fastest growing and profitable payments and banking market after Latin America, according to </span><a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/mckinsey/industries/financial%20services/our%20insights/african%20retail%20bankings%20next%20growth%20frontier/roaring-to-life-growth-and-innovation-in-african-retail-banking-web-final.ashx"><span style="font-weight: 400;">this</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> McKinsey study, and this only means that the fintech sector is likely to continue to attract investors tapping on the increasing growth opportunities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The continent is already a global leader in mobile money adoption, accounting for the bulk of the mobile money transactions made in 2020 – a year that saw the number of mobile money accounts rise by </span><a href="https://www.gsma.com/mobilefordevelopment/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GSMA_State-of-the-Industry-Report-on-Mobile-Money-2021_Full-report.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">43%</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  Mobile money success across the continent is likely due to ease in access brought by advancements in telecommunications technology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For instance, M-Pesa, a mobile money service by East Africa’s biggest telco, Safaricom, does not require internet connectivity for its customers to send and receive money, as well as to pay utility bills &#8211; the wallet turns subscribers’ phone numbers into a sort of proxy for bank accounts. The service recently surpassed voice to become Safaricom’s top earner after the platform’s revenues hit $745 million for the financial year ending March 2021.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Across the region (especially in Kenya) M-Pesa has served as an anchor for a raft of new services that are coming online. In 2012, for example, Safaricom laid the ground for the adoption of lending apps when it first launched M-Shwari &#8211; a mobile-based savings and loans product. Many more lending apps have since emerged in the market including Silicon Valley backed Tala and Branch. These now-popular l</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/kenya-cracks-down-on-digital-lenders-over-data-privacy-issues/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ending apps</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> use customers&#8217; mobile money transaction history to determine the amount of instant credit to extend to borrowers – monies that are then deposited in customers&#8217; mobile money wallets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Such lending and banking startups have made credit accessible to a majority of people with no credit scores, and who were previously cut out by formal financial institutions due to a lack of banking history data.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Insurtechs have also over the last few years thrived with the birth of innovative products that are affordable, allowing micropayments, and covering growing risks including those brought by climate change. Innovative products around insurtech have also encouraged the uptake of insurance products – even though the penetration across sub-Saharan Africa (with an exception of South Africa) remains low compared to other regions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While investments grew in 2021, the bulk of the funding went to a small number of startups. Analysis by Briter, which includes data from both disclosed and undisclosed deals, shows that an estimated $3 billion of the total amount raised went to 20 companies, as over 700 other startups raised nearly $2 billion.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/fintechs-in-africa-continue-to-overshadow-all-other-startups-in-funding-gained/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252619</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LG&#8217;s best-selling OLED TVs get an upgrade for the new year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/lg-oled-tv-at-ces/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/lg-oled-tv-at-ces/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 05:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oled]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oled tv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LG has had a pretty incredible winning streak with its OLED televisions the past couple of years. LG&#8217;s C1 has been the flat screen to beat, so there&#8217;s little surprise that the company&#8217;s 2022 lineup caught our (virtual) attention at CES this year. It seems like the company is content leaving well enough alone, with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">LG has had a pretty incredible winning streak with its OLED televisions the past couple of years. <a href="https://www.lg.com/us/tvs/lg-oled65c1pub-oled-4k-tv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LG&#8217;s C1</a> has been the flat screen to beat, so there&#8217;s little surprise that the company&#8217;s 2022 lineup caught our (virtual) attention at CES this year. It seems like the company is content leaving well enough alone, with a relatively minor update to the best-selling televisions, adding some additional screen sizes and some additional smarts to the family.</p>
<p>OLED tech isn&#8217;t new; Sony showed off a version of an OLED television with dismal resolution and a bank-destroying price tag <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2007/11/15/very-expensive-sony-oled-tv-ready-for-pre-ordering/">back in 2007</a>. In recent years, the tech has accelerated, putting it within the range of middle-class wallets. The OLED technology in question does away with the need for the back-light found in older LED-lit LCD panels. Instead of a large light source that&#8217;s beamed through an array of little color pixels, in the OLED tech each individual pixel is a little light-emitting diode. This means that when an individual pixel is off, it is not emitting any light at all, giving astonishing amounts of contrast and positively jaw-dropping color gamut. Because of the lacking backlight, TV manufacturers can also get fancy with the packaging; the thinner form factor means rollable or bendable TV screens become possible.</p>
<p>LG&#8217;s TVs have collected well-deserved CES Innovation Awards eight years running, and the company was positively beaming with excitement as it showed off the newest visions for the future of television.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252729" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company showed off two new series of televisions &#8212; the G2 and C2 series, both using upgraded OLED technology to create even better visuals. LG claims that this enables the displays to deliver higher brightness with greater clarity and detail, all of which should result in even more realistic images beamed into your eye-holes at home.<a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2022-OLED-evo-C2_77-inch_Product05-e1641250731704.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2252748" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2022-OLED-evo-C2_77-inch_Product05-e1641250731704.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="663" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2022-OLED-evo-C2_77-inch_Product05-e1641250731704.jpg 1170w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2022-OLED-evo-C2_77-inch_Product05-e1641250731704.jpg?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2022-OLED-evo-C2_77-inch_Product05-e1641250731704.jpg?resize=300,194 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2022-OLED-evo-C2_77-inch_Product05-e1641250731704.jpg?resize=768,497 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2022-OLED-evo-C2_77-inch_Product05-e1641250731704.jpg?resize=680,440 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2022-OLED-evo-C2_77-inch_Product05-e1641250731704.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>LG&#8217;s 2022 77-inch C2 with evo OLED technology. It probably looks better in person. (<strong>Image Credits:</strong> LG)LG’s 2022 G2 series introduces a new 83-inch model and the world’s very first 97-inch OLED displays. The new sizes are introduced alongside the three other sizes (55&#8243;, 65&#8243; and 77&#8243;) already available in the lineup. The LG G2 series gets a design refresh with a snazzy looking flush-to-the-wall mounting option the company calls &#8220;Gallery Design&#8221;.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the C2 series gets a total of six display sizes for this year&#8217;s starting lineup. It adds a small 42-inch version, which is great for smaller rooms or for console or computer gaming. On top of the newcomer, there are 48-, 55-, 65-, 77- and 83-inch options.</p>
<p>Also new for 2022 is a shiny new user experience based on LG&#8217;s webOS 22. Among other things, the software includes personalizable profiles so the various users of the TVs can configure their settings, which streaming services they prefer, and get customized content recommendations based on their viewing histories and such.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>There are a number of incremental upgrades on the display side as well, as the company maintains it has further improved its already class-leading color rendition, brightness and a flicker-free experience. LG also doubles down on its gaming cred; it is the first OLED TV to support <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/products/g-sync-monitors/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nvidia G-SYNC Compatibility</a>, and the company reminds us that its displays are the first 8K OLED TV to enable full-on 8K gaming with Nvidia&#8217;s top-of-the-range <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/graphics-cards/30-series/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RTX 30-Series graphics cards</a>, along with an array of gaming-specific settings and presets available through the company&#8217;s Game Optimizer menu.</p>
<p>No doubt the reviews will be bubbling forth before long, so keep your eyes peeled for those in the next few weeks and months. If you somehow managed to stay clear of CES in Las Vegas, and you have a beyond-usual interest in LG and its shiny new announcements, you can <a href="http://www.LG.com/CES2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">check out LG&#8217;s virtual exhibition booth</a> from 8 am PST on January 4th, 2022.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/lg-oled-tv-at-ces/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252729</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Samsung’s budget flagship Galaxy S21 FE arrives next week, starting at $699</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/samsungs-budget-flagship-galaxy-s21-fe-arrives-next-week-starting-at-699/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/samsungs-budget-flagship-galaxy-s21-fe-arrives-next-week-starting-at-699/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 02:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[samsung galaxy s21 fe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2251982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CES, in general, isn’t much of a phone show. That certainly applies to Samsung, which tends to save its big mobile news for Mobile World Congress, a month or two from now. Instead, the event is more about big things: TVs, washing machines, etc. Over the past few years, however, the electronics giant has used [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">CES, in general, isn’t much of a phone show. That certainly applies to Samsung, which tends to save its big mobile news for Mobile World Congress, a month or two from now. Instead, the event is more about big things: TVs, washing machines, etc.</p>
<p>Over the past few years, however, the electronics giant has used the show as a platform for launching its budget flagship &#8212; again, just ahead of the launch of its…flagship-flagship S series. Over the years, Samsung has toyed around with various names for the product, including the “Lite,” before settling on “FE” &#8212; short for “Fan Edition.” Seems last year&#8217;s device was a big success for the company. It notes, &#8220;Since its launch in Q4 2020, Galaxy S20 FE sold 10 million units in just over a year, making it one of Samsung’s best-selling Galaxy smartphones over the past year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2251991" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2251991" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2251991" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-7.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-7.jpg 6566w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-7.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-7.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-7.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-7.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-7.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-7.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-7.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2251991" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Samsung</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2251982" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Ultimately, the company no doubt landed on the notion that naming a device “Lite” was really leading with the fact that the product was “less than,” from a spec standpoint. So it’s positioning these devices as a kind of fan service &#8212; offering some of the luxuries of the higher-priced devices, while dulling some of the bleeding edges in the name of keeping costs down.</p>
<p>For the newly announced Galaxy S21 FE 5G, that’s a starting price of $699 (roughly one dollar per letter of the product’s name). That’s the same price point the company hit with last year’s S20 &#8212; and $100 more than Google’s Pixel 6, which has catapulted to the top of the list of affordable flagships (apologies if the flagship and budget distinctions get sort of nebulous here).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2251990" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2251990" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2251990" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-17.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-17.jpg 6566w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-17.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-17.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-17.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-17.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-17.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-17.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-17.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2251990" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Samsung</p></div></p>
<p>“We saw an incredible response to the Galaxy S20 FE and Galaxy S21 lineup,&#8221; says Samsung&#8217;s TM Roh in a release. &#8220;So we applied the same approach with S21 FE 5G, equipping it with the premium features that matter most to our loyal Galaxy fans — because we’re focused on delivering a smartphone that meets their most important needs.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The handset sports a 6.4-inch display with a 120Hz refresh rate, powered by Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 888 processor, as its successor, the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1, is starting rollout on flagships from companies like Xiaomi. There’s a triple camera system with a 12-megapixel main, 32-megapixel ultrawide and 12-megapixel telephoto. The system comes with either 6 or 8GB of RAM and 128 or 256GB of storage, along with a solid 4,500mAh battery. And, of course, as the name implies, there’s 5G on-board.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2251992" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2251992" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2251992" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-19.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-19.jpg 6432w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-19.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-19.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-19.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-19.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-19.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-19.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Galaxy-S21-FE_Lifestyle-Product-19.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2251992" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Samsung</p></div></p>
<p>The design borrows plenty of cues from the standard S21, though the premium build has been swapped out for a lower-cost plastic construction. The S21 FE starts shipping January 11.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/samsungs-budget-flagship-galaxy-s21-fe-arrives-next-week-starting-at-699/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2251982</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Liquid Death lands $75M more to expand the brand</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/liquid-death-lands-75-million-more-in-funding-including-to-roll-out-flavored-water/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/liquid-death-lands-75-million-more-in-funding-including-to-roll-out-flavored-water/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 01:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liquid Death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live-nation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Cessario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mike jones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252735</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Liquid Death, a water brand that began life in 2018 with a funny video to first test the concept, has grown deadly serious about its growth prospects. The L.A.-based outfit, which sells canned mountain water from the Alps that will &#8220;murder your thirst,&#8221; has just landed $75 million in Series C funding led by the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://liquiddeath.com/">Liquid Death</a>, a water brand that began life in 2018 with a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jYkKBXqqunE">funny video</a> to first test the concept, has grown deadly serious about its growth prospects. The L.A.-based outfit, which sells canned mountain water from the Alps that will &#8220;murder your thirst,&#8221; has just landed $75 million in Series C funding led by the startup studio Science, which helped launch the company and now owns a &#8220;strong minority&#8221; position. (Says Science cofounder Mike Jones, &#8220;I wish we owned more.&#8221;)</p>
<p>We talked earlier today with Liquid Death&#8217;s cofounder and CEO, Mike Cessario, a West Coast agency creative-turned-entrepreneur, about the company&#8217;s growth. Seemingly, there is a lot to boast about. According to Cessario, Liquid Death is now carried in more than 29,000 locations throughout the U.S. including Whole Foods, Target, Safeway and 7-Eleven stores, and revenue reached nearly $45 million last year, up from $3 million in 2019 when the company sold its first can.</p>
<p>He thinks there is a lot of room to grow from here, including through flavored waters that Liquid Death is beginning to roll out with names that suit the brand&#8217;s punk-metal ethos. Its first three products? Berry It Alive, Severed Lime, and Mango Chainsaw.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252735" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Cessario has long credited the firm&#8217;s growth with its grimly funny phrasing, along with its packaging, arguing that aluminum is more recyclable than plastic (though, of course, no single-use container is great for the environment).</p>
<p>Still, he&#8217;s particularly proud of Liquid Death&#8217;s organic growth strategy, one that has enabled the outfit to compete and even thrive in a world rife with other water brands. Indeed, asked how much Liquid Death spends on marketing compared with other beverage brands, Cessario insisted there is no comparison.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t know what other water brands spend, but we&#8217;re not going to have Coca-Cola or Pepsi-like budgets to spend. We don&#8217;t have $300 million to throw at something, so every piece of marketing that we make has to be interesting or entertaining so that people organically spread it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Some of these marketing pieces come together quickly, he said, in two weeks or less when &#8220;an idea comes out of nowhere.&#8221; Other times, a marketing piece can be a six-month-long process. Take a stunt last summer by Liquid Death and one of its handful of celebrity investors, Tony Hawk, who teamed up to sell 150 skateboard decks whose ink included <a href="https://liquiddeath.com/pages/hawkblood">some blood from Hawk</a>. The decks sold out quickly, said Cessario, but making the decks, as well as lining up a phlebotomist who could &#8220;legally draw blood and was willing to be on camera&#8221; took some time, he said with a laugh.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In an even more extreme gimmick, Cessario had the face of an avid Liquid Death customer <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVBDn5HgkRK/">tattooed on his arm</a>.</p>
<p>As for how the company&#8217;s strategy changes now that it has more products to push, Cessario told us that the focus remains squarely on building a brand &#8220;that&#8217;s about making healthy beverages as fun or more fun than junk food and alcohol brands.&#8221; Because its demographic skews younger and male, and because &#8220;young kids and most men have more of a palette for sweeter things,&#8221; observes Cessario, that means new drinks, which Cessario said are sweetened by agave nectar and feature just three grams of sugar and 20 calories per drink. (&#8220;We aren&#8217;t catering to people who are obsessing over every last calorie,&#8221; he noted.)</p>
<p>In the meantime, there are evidently plenty of places in the U.S. that have yet to discover the brand. Pointing to a beverage industry metric called ACV (for all-commodity volume) that represents the total annual sales volume of retailers, Cessario said that Fiji water has 90% ACV whereas Liquid Death was approaching just 9% at the end of 2021.</p>
<p>A sweeter deal with Amazon may well boost that percentage. Specifically, said Cessario, Liquid Death recently passed an important metric that Amazon uses to decide when to start selling a product wholesale, meaning Liquid Death no longer gets charged for every case of water that it sells through Amazon but instead is selling water directly to the e-commerce giant, which then sells the water directly to its customers at a reduced price &#8212; and has sent sales soaring, said Cessario.</p>
<p>It matters, he continued.&#8221;For a lot of food and beverage brands, Amazon is often their biggest sales channel.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other investors in Liquid Death&#8217;s new round include Live Nation, PowerPlant Partners, Access Capital, and Nomad Ventures.</p>
<p>Altogether, Liquid Death has now raised $125 million altogether and is valued by its backers at $525 million, it says.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/liquid-death-lands-75-million-more-in-funding-including-to-roll-out-flavored-water/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252735</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VC Joe Lonsdale&#8217;s tweets about &#8216;woke&#8217; tech diversity spark investor pushback</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/vc-joe-lonsdales-tweets-about-woke-tech-diversity-spark-investor-pushback/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/vc-joe-lonsdales-tweets-about-woke-tech-diversity-spark-investor-pushback/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 01:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[8VC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[controversy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Lonsdale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week, in response to someone who tweeted that VCs were racist, venture capitalist and entrepreneur Joe Lonsdale attributed disparities in venture capital investing to “average black culture.” “A real view: average black culture needs to step it up and stop having as many kids born out of wedlock (statistical indicator of underperformance) / who [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last week, in response to someone who tweeted that VCs were racist, venture capitalist and entrepreneur <a href="https://twitter.com/JTLonsdale" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Joe Lonsdale</a> attributed disparities in venture capital investing to “average black culture.”</p>
<p>“A real view: average black culture needs to step it up and stop having as many kids born out of wedlock (statistical indicator of underperformance) / who don’t value education or spend as much time on homework,” wrote Lonsdale in the now-deleted series of tweets.</p>
<p>The opining of Lonsdale, who co-founded Palantir and runs the early-stage venture firm 8VC, prompted swift criticism from a number of tech investors, many of whom called on Lonsdale’s advisors and limited partners &#8212; which include the likes of Yahoo founder Jerry Yang, Box CEO Aaron Levie and actor Leonardo DiCaprio &#8212; to speak out against the entrepreneur&#8217;s actions.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252795" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In one tweet with a screenshot of Londsale’s tweets, Bessemer partner <a href="https://twitter.com/TheValuesVC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Elliott Robinson</a> wrote, “[I]t’s not VCs like [Joe Lonsdale] that hold the tech ecosystem and society back. It’s the hundreds of LPs, co-Investors, Founders, and decision makers that remain silent because: they do not care, they are scared [or] they agree. I feel bad for him/them to live like that. Its sad.”</p>
<p>Stealth-mode general partner<a href="https://twitter.com/lolitataub" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Lolita Taub</a>, who formerly invested via Backstage Capital and the Community Fund, told anyone who agrees with Londsale’s “racist commentary” to unfollow her.</p>
<p>Lightship Capital GP <a href="https://twitter.com/BrianBrackeen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Brian Brackeen</a> meanwhile said <a href="https://twitter.com/BrianBrackeen/status/1476547564073676800" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in a tweet</a> that “any LP of his is complicit” and that “there is no shame in being him in SF. The culture there is to accept people like him. Diversity in tech can’t improve until we diversify the geography.”</p>
<p>Lonsdale responded to a request for further context, saying to TechCrunch via e-mail that he was “jumping on a flight” but that “somebody edited a screenshot and took a tweet totally out of context in order to cause outrage.” He further added that “the people attacking me have political motivations. You will note they are almost entirely on the far left and prefer divisive attacks vs working towards positive solutions together.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He insists that context surrounding the statements was lost from his original thread.</p>
<p>“I commented how past racism likely caused issues with some cultures today that we need to discuss and address, and given how terrible some of the things these communities experienced in the past were &#8211; red lining, Jim Crow, and so many terrible past issues &#8211; it isn&#8217;t necessarily fair to blame 100% of problems today on racism.”</p>
<p>Lonsdale also added that he has “invested millions of dollars in black founders and in relevant philanthropic causes and proudly work with a lot of advisors from these communities and we continue to do more to reach out to talent from these backgrounds and to partner. As i have stated, it&#8217;s not only dumb to discriminate, but if anything if somebody comes from a tough background and still manages to succeed &#8211; that means they are likely to be resilient, which means they are an even better founder to back. I am eager to continue to back talented black founders.”</p>
<p>When asked about the Black founders that Lonsdale has invested in, a spokesperson for Lonsdale responded saying it &#8220;doesn&#8217;t seem appropriate to list names and force [anyone] to answer questions&#8221; given how Lonsdale&#8217;s &#8220;notes were taken out of context.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lonsdale has a highly successful business track record, but a record, too, of troubled personal dealings. In addition to Palantir and 8VC, Lonsdale has co-founded a line of companies, including Addepar, OpenGov, Affinity, Epirus, Esper, Swiftscale Bio, Resilience Bio, Hearth and LIT, which recently <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/tiger-global-to-invest-in-joe-lonsdales-newest-fintech-venture?rc=ajsw4d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">received a $50 million investment from Tiger Global.</a></p>
<p>He has been the main character in a number of controversies, including a breakup with <a href="https://fortune.com/2015/11/10/what-caused-formation-8-to-split-and-what-comes-next/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">earlier investing partners</a> and a high-profile lawsuit filed by a former Stanford student <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/11/02/high-profile-lawsuit-against-vc-joe-lonsdale-now-dropped/">that was later dropped</a>.</p>
<p>More recently, <a href="https://twitter.com/JTLonsdale/status/1453399478254379008?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1453399478254379008%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Ffox2now.com%2Fnews%2Fdads-who-take-6-months-of-paternity-leave-are-losers-tech-investor-says%2F" target="_blank" rel="noopener">he called</a> “any man in an important position who takes 6 months of leave for a newborn…a loser.”</p>
<p>Lonsdale &#8212; whose venture firm has been successful in its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/16/joe-lonsdale-moves-forward-with-8vcs-new-fund-and-more/">fundraising efforts</a> despite public controversy &#8212; has been attempting to clarify his earlier position since taking it last Friday. Later that same day, for example, he tweeted: “Worth clarifying: you can be against divisive and &#8216;woke&#8217; nonsense, and I am. But we should still appreciate the positive parts of our culture and wisdom of the 21st century &#8211; that it’s important to be aware of past racism, kind, inclusive, and against actual racism of all sorts.”</p>
<p>“I don&#8217;t necessarily expect TC to give me a fair hearing &#8211; a sensational article attacking and making [people] think somebody is racist and getting angry is what you are taught to do in journalism these days &#8211; but I hope you&#8217;ll consider representing this view fairly,” Lonsdale said in an e-mailed statement to TechCrunch.</p>
<p>In a competitive and cash-rich fundraising market, Lonsdale’s controversial comments could attract negative attention to his venture firm and make founders less inclined to accept his money. Indeed, Block Party founder <a href="https://twitter.com/triketora">Tracy Chou</a> claimed on Twitter that even before making his latest comments, Lonsdale had spoken to her Y Combinator batch and she described his comments on stage as “terribly distasteful.”</p>
<p>“It sucks that even after everything he’s trotted out by the establishment as an exemplar and to give advice,”<a href="https://twitter.com/triketora/status/1476355529970786304" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> she tweeted.</a></p>
<p>In the meantime, Lonsdale may find it harder to partner with the venture industry’s small but growing number of Black investors. Fund manager <a href="https://twitter.com/DelJohnsonVC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Del Johnson</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/spencergtyson" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Spencer Tyson</a>, an associate at Revere VC, are among many investors who took to Twitter to dissect Lonsdale’s comments in the aftermath, and their frustration was plain. Tyson tweeted: “What you, and many others, fail to realize is that there is a difference between &#8216;woke&#8217; culture and BLACK culture,” he said. “We’re not your rich liberal friends you argue with at dinner parties… You attacked BLACK culture.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Ladies gentlemen, folks of all ages. I present to you my thesis: <a href="https://t.co/yVDFZ5B9IS">https://t.co/yVDFZ5B9IS</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Del Johnson (@DelJohnsonVC) <a href="https://twitter.com/DelJohnsonVC/status/1476333898535632896?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 29, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>For now, Lonsdale is continuing in his efforts to recontextualize his earlier statements. “The data suggests that there are structural issues (likely caused by past racism) holding people back and causing disparity, not racism by VCs,” Lonsdale tweeted<a href="https://twitter.com/JTLonsdale/status/1476590029828857858"> in a separate response. </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/vc-joe-lonsdales-tweets-about-woke-tech-diversity-spark-investor-pushback/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252795</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exotel raises $40M for its full-stack customer engagement platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/exotel-raises-40-million-for-its-full-stack-customer-engagement-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/exotel-raises-40-million-for-its-full-stack-customer-engagement-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 01:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blume ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exotel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gupshup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steadview Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Exotel said on Tuesday it has raised $40 million in a financing round, just three months after securing $35 million in funding, as the Bangalore-based startup demonstrates growth for its full-stack customer engagement platform in emerging markets. Steadview Capital led the startup’s Series D round. Exotel, which counts Blume Ventures and IIFL Asset Management among its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Exotel said on Tuesday it has raised $40 million in a financing round, just three months after securing $35 million in funding, as the Bangalore-based startup demonstrates growth for its full-stack customer engagement platform in emerging markets.</p>
<p>Steadview Capital led the startup’s Series D round. Exotel, which counts Blume Ventures and IIFL Asset Management among its backers, has raised about $100 million in a mix of debt and equity rounds in the last 12 months.</p>
<p><a href="https://exotel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Exotel</a> offers its clients a full-stack platform with offerings such as contact center, APIs, voice and chat bots, to engage with their customers through touch points such as web chat, co-browsing and videos.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252802" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Indian ride-hailing giant Ola uses Exotel’s platform to send text messages to its customers. Food delivery giant Swiggy relies on the startup to mask the phone numbers when the delivery partner makes a call to the customer. Relationship managers at HDFC Bank, a large bank in India, use Exotel to engage with customers with a savings account.</p>
<p>This engagement “involves bringing together disconnected channels, bots, applications with siloed customer data across teams,” said Shivakumar Ganesan, co-founder and chief executive of Exotel. “For the first time we are enabling this over the cloud with our full-stack platform.”</p>
<p>The startup operates in a space that has attracted the attention of several major giants, such as Microsoft, Amazon, Twilio, Salesforce and Zoom in recent years as organizations scramble to build or acquire tools to create one-store service centers.</p>
<p>But Exotel has two clear differentiating factors in the otherwise crowded field, said Ganesan in an interview with TechCrunch. The startup focuses on serving customers in emerging markets and, unlike many of its global competitors, it offers a wide range of services.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Practically everyone in India is our customer,” he said. The startup, which has also expanded to Southeast Asia and the Middle East in recent years, has amassed over 4,000 customers, some of which it gained after its recent acquisitions of cloud center platform Ameyo and conversational AI startup Cogno AI. Bajaj Allianz, City Mall, KrazyBee, Shadowfax and TCS started to use Exotel&#8217;s platform in the last 12 months.</p>
<p>Ganesan attributed some of its recent growth to the pandemic, which he said has made communication technology a “source of life” for several enterprises and businesses in banking, fintech and auto industries.</p>
<p>&#8220;The importance of having effective communication strategy is increasing over time and Exotel executed this successfully by powering communication to almost all internet unicorns in India,&#8221; said Puneet Kumar, managing director at Steadview Capital, in a statement. &#8220;We like their vision of building an end-to-end communication stack to enable enterprises to engage intelligently with customers and are thrilled to be part of their next growth phase.&#8221;</p>
<p>The startup, which employs more than 1,000 employees, today generates an annualized recurring revenue of $50 million. It aims to grow this figure to $200 million as it broadens its offerings and wins more customers. It&#8217;s also looking to hire about 200 people by the end of the year.</p>
<hr />
<p>Karthik Reddy of Blume <a href="https://blume.vc/exotel-the-bootstrap-champ-10yearsofblume/">shared the story</a> of how his firm chased to invest in Exotel, which he described as &#8220;one of the buzziest&#8221; deals it had won at the time. The blog post from last year also recounts the struggle the super hot startup faced in its lukewarm years.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;There was a lot of visibility for the company in digital and traditional media as it kept building beyond the odds. Then there was some regulatory scare. Good press can alert various competitors – from large telcos to larger funded companies. Others in the sector too got similar scares. The company had to double down on ensuring that they were well above board and procured whatever licenses it needed. The bank balance dipped to 14 lacs at a point in 2014-15.</p>
<p>Investors would show excitement and then shirk away. Over 6 years, between 2012 and 2018, we lost count of near miss term sheets, half-hearted term sheets (e.g.”we will invest $3 mill contingent on another $3 mill being committed by a co-lead”), merger and acquisition offers from everyone, Indian competitors to Asian telcos to American giants.</p>
<p>Clearly, the segment was considered interesting enough that we needed to see a desi Twilio emerge.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/exotel-raises-40-million-for-its-full-stack-customer-engagement-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252802</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Withings launches an even smarter scale to measure you from top to toe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/withings-body-scan/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/withings-body-scan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 01:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart scales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[withings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2251569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Your bathroom scales have been capable of telling you more than your weight for a while, and Withings is one of the companies leading the charge on that front (since 2009). Today, the company announced its Withings Body Scan, which continues the company&#8217;s bid for being your measure-all-the-things-about-yourself brand of choice. In addition to weight, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Your bathroom scales have been capable of telling you more than your weight for a while, and <a href="https://www.withings.com/us/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Withings</a> is one of the companies leading the charge on that front (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2009/09/30/your-weight-for-a-wi-fi-scale-is-over-get-it/">since 2009</a>). Today, the company announced its Withings Body Scan, which continues the company&#8217;s bid for being your measure-all-the-things-about-yourself brand of choice. In addition to weight, the $299 slate of glass promises to measure an ECG, segmental body composition, and keep an eye on your nerve activity.</p>
<p>Because the scale is promising at-home ECG, the device has to go through a more rigorous FDA approval process. The same process caused a lengthy delay in the company&#8217;s ScanWatch &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/withings-scanwatch-review/">which offers an on-wrist ECG feature</a> &#8212; making it to U.S. shores, compared to its European launch.</p>
<p>The new Body Scan adds a few funky new features to the otherwise familiar-looking scale from Withings. The product, which contains four weight sensors, promises body weight accuracy to within 50 grams (or, for a 200-pound person, accuracy to an impressive 0.025%). The device also has 14 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indium_tin_oxide" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ITO electrodes</a> within the platform and four stainless steel electrodes in a retractable handle. Together, those sensors gather data for the six-lead ECG and segmental body composition analysis.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2251569" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Body Scan promises daily analysis of data associated with health conditions, including heart rate, &#8220;vascular age,&#8221; and the aforementioned ECG measurement. The flurry of electrodes means that Body Scan can pull off some fun party tricks, including using multi-frequency Bioelectrical Impedance Analysis to measure overall body composition. Beyond the standard body fat percentage you may have seen on its old scale, the Body Scan can also measure water percentage, visceral fat, muscle and bone mass. It further promises to be able to offer more granular readings for individual body parts, including torso, arms and legs.</p>
<p>Seen in the context of the company&#8217;s other product offerings, including under-mattress sleep trackers, smart blood pressure cuffs, body temperature sensors and its growing line of smart health fitness sensors, the Body Scan is an obvious brand extension.</p>
<p>On top of the hardware products, Withings is extending its in-app health coaching. The company enables its users to access coaching, clinical specialists and personalized nutrition, and exercise plans help them reach their health goals. The app also lets users export a health snapshot with historical data, which will be particularly useful for people who like to take a more active role in their health alongside their nutritionists, trainers and health professionals.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/withings-body-scan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2251569</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elizabeth Holmes convicted of 4 of 11 fraud counts in Theranos trial</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/elizabeth-holmes-verdict-guilty-theranos-fraud/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/elizabeth-holmes-verdict-guilty-theranos-fraud/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Betsy DeVos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elizabeth holmes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holmes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Mattis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Years Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pfizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rupert Murdoch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stanford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theranos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walgreens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Elizabeth Holmes has been found guilty of defrauding investors as founder and CEO of Theranos. After four months of court proceedings and seven days of deliberations, the jury has reached a verdict that will have lasting implications in Silicon Valley and beyond. The former youngest and wealthiest female self-made billionaire was tried for two counts [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Elizabeth Holmes has been found guilty of defrauding investors as founder and CEO of Theranos. After four months of court proceedings and seven days of deliberations, the jury has reached a verdict that will have lasting implications in Silicon Valley and beyond.</p>
<p>The former <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbespr/2015/05/27/forbes-announces-inaugural-list-of-americas-50-richest-self-made-women/?sh=4ab0aca824c1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">youngest and wealthiest</a> female self-made billionaire was tried for two counts of conspiracy to commit wire fraud and nine counts of wire fraud. Holmes was found guilty of conspiring to defraud investors, as well as defrauding investors from the DeVos family, hedge fund manager Brian Grossman and former estate and trust attorney Dan Mosely. She was not found guilty of charges related to defrauding patients.</p>
<p>The jury did not reach a verdict on three wire fraud counts involving Black Diamond executive Chris Lucas, Hall Group executive Bryan Tolbert and money manager Alan Eisenman, who all testified in the trial. Judge Edward Davila found a <a href="https://twitter.com/doratki/status/1478168539618070529" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mistrial</a> on these three counts. Prosecutor Jeffrey Schenk said he will confer with the Department of Justice, then tell the court next week how the government wishes to proceed.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2250549" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Holmes founded Theranos in 2003 after dropping out of Stanford. She pitched investors and partners on technology that would revolutionize the healthcare system &#8212; instead of drawing blood intravenously and waiting days for test results, her technology would prick a tiny bit of blood and instantly conduct dozens of tests on it. Soon she was the CEO of a company with a $10 billion valuation, but there was one problem: the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/theranos-lab-chief-says-he-found-blood-testing-technology-didnt-work-11613602822" target="_blank" rel="noopener">technology didn&#8217;t work</a>.</p>
<p>Theranos has been defunct since 2018, but Holmes&#8217; criminal trial only began this fall after delays due to the pandemic and the birth of Holmes&#8217; child. Over 11 weeks, the prosecution constructed the case that Holmes knowingly defrauded investors, questioning witnesses like former U.S. Secretary of Defense James Mattis, whistleblower Erika Cheung, Theranos patients, investors, medical professionals and journalists.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Even though Theranos&#8217; technology didn&#8217;t actually accomplish what the company claimed it did, Holmes said that she thought she was telling the truth &#8212; she even alleged that the </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/11/23/technology/elizabeth-holmes-trial-theranos?name=styln-elizabeth-holmes-trial&amp;region=TOP_BANNER&amp;block=storyline_menu_recirc&amp;action=click&amp;pgtype=LegacyCollection&amp;variant=show&amp;is_new=false" target="_blank" rel="noopener">slideshows</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> she presented to investors were made by scientists and engineers. But the prosecution managed on some counts to convince the jury that Holmes knowingly misled investors and partners &#8212; one piece of evidence showed that Theranos used Pfizer&#8217;s logo in an <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/15/technology/elizabeth-holmes-trial-theranos-takeaways.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unauthorized manner</a> while negotiating a partnership with Walgreens. A former senior product manager at Theranos, Daniel Edlin <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/22/technology/elizabeth-holmes-trial-takeaways.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">testified</a> that Theranos sometimes faked demonstrations of their technology in front of investors. When billionaire investor Rupert Murdoch had his blood tested, Theranos removed abnormal results before sending out the reports, Edlin said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">In a big twist for the high-profile trial, Holmes </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/theranos-founder-elizabeth-holmes-testifies-in-her-own-criminal-trial/">took the stand herself</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> to argue that her failure as a startup founder doesn&#8217;t mean she committed fraud. In a key moment, </span>Holmes alleged that Theranos COO Ramesh &#8220;Sunny&#8221; Balwani abused her.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Balwani, who faces a separate trial next year, was Holmes&#8217; boyfriend in secret. They met when Holmes was 18 and Balwani was 37 &#8212; she moved in with him the year after she dropped out of Stanford. She also said during the trial that she was raped as a Stanford student, which is part of why she didn&#8217;t finish her degree. She &#8220;decided [she] was going to build a life by building this company.&#8221; She detailed Balwani&#8217;s controlling behavior, including a written document that dictated her daily schedule, including what she ate, when she slept and how she dressed. She said, &#8220;He was so disappointed in my mediocrity and he was trying to teach me how to be better.&#8221;</p>
<p>The jury deliberated for seven days, even <a href="https://twitter.com/BobbyAllyn/status/1473433208574263297" target="_blank" rel="noopener">asking</a> if they were allowed to take jury instructions home to review. They also asked to re-listen to some audio clips of Holmes&#8217; calls with investors, which had been presented as evidence, yet deliberations continued into the new year.</p>
<p>On the seventh day of deliberations<strong>,</strong> the jury submitted its third note to the judge, saying that it could not reach an unanimous verdict on three of the 11 counts. The prosecution suggested that Judge Davila read the jury an instructional document on what to do in the case of a deadlocked jury. Holmes&#8217; defense disagreed, saying that these <a href="https://twitter.com/doratki/status/1478078212139798537" target="_blank" rel="noopener">instructions</a> could be seen as coercive, but the judge proceeded to deliver the instructions. He also <a href="https://twitter.com/doratki/status/1478081965697994762" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reminded</a> the jury that Holmes would be presumed innocent until proven guilty. Four hours later, the jury submitted another note stating that its members could still not reach an unanimous verdict on three charges. Shortly after, they presented their verdict on the eight other counts.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not unexpected for the deliberations in a prominent white-collar trial to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-28/in-many-blockbuster-white-collar-trials-jurors-took-their-time?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">take this long</a>. The jury deliberated for five days before arriving at a verdict in Ghislaine Maxwell&#8217;s recent four-week trial; she was found <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/dec/30/ghislaine-maxwell-what-happens-next-charges-sentencing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">guilty</a> of five of six charges. In 2007, former press tycoon Conrad Black was of fraud convicted after <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/14/business/13cnd-black.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12 days</a> of jury deliberations in a 14-week trial.</p>
<p>The trial&#8217;s verdict sends a message to tech founders that it&#8217;s not okay to lie about your technology &#8212; especially not when it affects the health of real people. But it sends a mixed message that she was found not guilty of the counts related to defrauding patients. Beyond that, the case showed how important due diligence is for investors and partners collaborating with startups. Notably, Theranos&#8217; investors weren&#8217;t the usual-suspect venture capital firms. Rather, her funding came from individuals like former Secretary of Education Betsy DeVos, billionaire media mogul Rupert Murdoch, former Secretary of State Henry Kissinger and the Walton family, among other wealthy elites. Some evidence showed that these investors were willing to give Theranos money even when Holmes evaded their more probing questions.</p>
<p>But the investors&#8217; misplaced belief in Holmes wasn&#8217;t the only thing propelling the faulty Theranos tech forward. Theranos and other diagnostics companies have exploited <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/now/theranos-faulty-blood-tests-got-122724789.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">regulatory loopholes</a> that allow devices that are not yet FDA approved to reach the market.</p>
<p>There is <a href="https://twitter.com/doratki/status/1478172574420975624">not yet</a> a date set for Holmes&#8217; sentencing hearing. The prosecution <a href="https://twitter.com/doratki/status/1478169425383669760" target="_blank" rel="noopener">will not</a> ask Holmes to be detained today, but <a href="https://twitter.com/doratki/status/1478171908596281347" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> that the government wants either cash or property to secure her bond.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Theranos isn&#8217;t quite a thing of the past yet. Balwani awaits his own criminal fraud trial next year. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eREE6owHHm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/theranos-founder-elizabeth-holmes-testifies-in-her-own-criminal-trial/">Theranos founder Elizabeth Holmes testifies in her own criminal trial</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Theranos founder Elizabeth Holmes testifies in her own criminal trial&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/theranos-founder-elizabeth-holmes-testifies-in-her-own-criminal-trial/embed/#?secret=eREE6owHHm" data-secret="eREE6owHHm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/elizabeth-holmes-verdict-guilty-theranos-fraud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250549</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The coming reckoning: Showing ROI from threat intelligence</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/the-coming-reckoning-showing-roi-from-threat-intelligence/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/the-coming-reckoning-showing-roi-from-threat-intelligence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[espionage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[threat intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252450</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For threat intelligence teams, it appears old habits die hard. Many remain in the government intel mindset, focused on funneling data to the security operations center (SOC).]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Chris Jacob</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chris-jacob-80ba0b/">Chris Jacob</a> serves as global vice president, Threat Intelligence Engineers at <a href="https://www.threatq.com/">ThreatQuotient</a> and previously held leadership roles at SourceFire, Fidelis Cybersecurity and Webroot.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Threat intelligence has been a part of cyber defense processes in the private sector for nearly a decade now. Many threat intelligence teams were initially composed of classically trained intel operators from the public sector, where they focused on gathering data to thwart national security threats. And as these teams grew and adjusted to protecting against customer data breaches and disruptions to services, growing pains associated with working in a corporate environment were to be expected.</p>
<p>Expectations are changing, though. Security operations is maturing, and as threats have continued to evolve, enterprises have made significant investments in security infrastructure. C-suites and boards are increasingly involved in security decision-making, and <a href="https://www.einnews.com/pr_news/551270774/global-cybersecurity-spending-to-exceed-1-75-trillion-from-2021-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener">studies show</a> that they are doubling down on security investments, which are expected to rise to $458.9 billion in 2025 from $262.4 billion in 2021.</p>
<p>But with increased investment comes scrutiny and rigorous competition for dollars across IT and security teams. However, for threat intelligence teams, it appears old habits die hard. Many remain in the government intel mindset, focused on funneling data to the security operations center (SOC) and have limited experience in extending threat intelligence to other parts of the business, communicating the resulting value and justifying the investment required.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Delivering curated threat intelligence to more teams that need it, enabled with bi-directional integration, will allow CISOs and their team to prove threat intelligence is far from a cost center.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>After nearly a decade of threat intelligence going corporate, a reckoning is coming. It’s time for CISOs and threat intel teams to start working together and prove that threat intelligence is not a cost center, but drives value across all security operations.</p>
<p>As threat intel teams mature, here are three recommendations to help create a shift in mindset and demonstrate the full value it provides.</p>
<h2>Think of the threat intel team as the providers of a product<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/the-coming-reckoning-showing-roi-from-threat-intelligence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252450</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fintech-focused Ribbit Capital raises $1.15B in seventh fund, according to SEC filing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/fintech-focused-ribbit-capital-raises-1-15b-in-seventh-fund-according-to-sec-filing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/fintech-focused-ribbit-capital-raises-1-15b-in-seventh-fund-according-to-sec-filing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 23:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ribbit Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252751</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ribbit Capital, a venture firm best known for its fintech investments, has raised $1.15 billion in new capital in what appears to be a close of its seventh fund, according to a filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC).  The new fund, dubbed Ribbit Capital VII LP, is believed to be the final [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ribbit Capital, a venture firm best known for its fintech investments, has raised $1.15 billion in new capital in what appears to be a close of its seventh fund, according to a </span><a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1851162/000185116222000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">filing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new fund, dubbed </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ribbit Capital VII LP, is believed to be the final close of the fund. The amount is significantly higher than the </span><a href="https://www.venturecapitaljournal.com/ribbit-capital-targets-750m-for-seventh-fund/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$750 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the firm was said to be raising in March of 2021. It is also more than double the</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/12/fintech-investment-powerhouse-ribbit-capital-aims-for-420-million-with-its-latest-fund/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> $420 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it raised in its sixth fund in January of 2020.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since its 2012 inception, Ribbit Capital had previously raised about $1.3 billion in capital, according to </span><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/ribbit-capital" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crunchbase</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It has invested (and seen exits) in what are some of the world’s largest fintechs today, including Coinbase, Nubank, Affirm and Robinhood.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252751" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to this fund, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ribbit’s managing partner </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/meyermalka/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meyer &#8220;Micky&#8221; Malka</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">is listed as director of an entity called Bullfrog Capital LP. According to a 2020 filing associated with that Palo Alto-based venture capital firm, Bullfrog intended to raise $500 million from limited partners. A new filing indicates that the entity actually ended up raising $1.15 billion as well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TechCrunch reached out to Ribbit and Malka for comment but had not heard back at the time of writing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2021 was a busy year for Ribbit, which also made a number of investments in Latin America, even leading several deals in the region. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, </span><a href="https://www.justos.com.br/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Justos</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a startup that says it will be the first insurance company in Brazil to use data when determining rates, in October raised </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/24/brazilian-insurtech-justos-raises-35-8m-in-ribbit-capital-led-series-a/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a $35.8 million Series A round of funding</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> led by Ribbit. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The firm has not only been active in North America and LatAm. In March 2021, it led a </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/28/ajaib-raises-65m-series-a-extension-led-by-ribbit-capital-increasing-the-rounds-total-to-90m/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$65 million extension</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for Indonesian investment app </span><a href="https://ajaib.co.id/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ajaib</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/fintech-focused-ribbit-capital-raises-1-15b-in-seventh-fund-according-to-sec-filing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252751</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GAF Energy&#8217;s easy-install solar shingles aim to outshine Tesla roofs and traditional panels</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/gaf-energys-easy-install-solar-shingles-aim-to-outshine-tesla-roofs-and-traditional-panels/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/gaf-energys-easy-install-solar-shingles-aim-to-outshine-tesla-roofs-and-traditional-panels/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 23:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaf energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar shingles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Putting solar panels on the roof is increasingly realistic for the average homeowner, but they tend to be specialized, aftermarket affairs or else whole-roof replacements. GAF Energy, a division of the roofing giant, claims its new solar shingles are simple enough to install that no special equipment or knowledge is required, making home renewable energy [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Putting solar panels on the roof is increasingly realistic for the average homeowner, but they tend to be specialized, aftermarket affairs or else whole-roof replacements. GAF Energy, a division of the roofing giant, claims <a href="https://www.gaf.energy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its new solar shingles</a> are simple enough to install that no special equipment or knowledge is required, making home renewable energy that much more accessible.</p>
<p>Solar shingles are not themselves new, but tend to be a bit more complicated of an installation than just riveting a panel to the roof with a few inches of space underneath. Instead, they replace the shingles themselves, acting as both roofing material and solar panel array.</p>
<p>Many of our readers will be familiar with Tesla&#8217;s foray into this space, the imaginatively named Solar Roof, which uses solar shingles but, like others, needs a special team and is basically a whole-roof replacement. If you only wanted to replace a damaged patch with 30 square feet of panels, Tesla isn&#8217;t an option, and other solar shingles might not be able to be installed by your local roofer.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252737" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>GAF Energy hopes to change that with its Timberline Solar, announced today at CES, which it says can be installed by any roofer with a nail gun. GAF Energy president Martin DeBono described the shingle as &#8220;the only product to integrate solar technology into existing roofing processes and materials to yield a full-fledged solar roof, enabling mainstream deployment of clean energy via traditional roofing channels.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2252765" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/timberline-solar-2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2252765" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2252765" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/timberline-solar-2.jpg" alt="Roofers install a solar shingle on a roof." width="1024" height="693" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/timberline-solar-2.jpg 1152w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/timberline-solar-2.jpg?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/timberline-solar-2.jpg?resize=300,203 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/timberline-solar-2.jpg?resize=768,520 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/timberline-solar-2.jpg?resize=680,460 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/timberline-solar-2.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2252765" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> GAF Energy</p></div></p>
<p>You might wonder why, if you&#8217;re already going to the trouble of getting solar installed on your roof, you don&#8217;t just roll with it and get the specialist. It&#8217;s going to be expensive anyway, right? It&#8217;s true in a way, but the cost is coming down for every aspect of getting a solar roof, and every dollar shaved off makes it realistic for a few more customers (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/">as Aurora Solar&#8217;s COO Sam Adeyemo observed to me last year</a>). Not only that, but specialists tend to congregate in population centers, meaning folks in rural areas, where solar might actually be more practical, face higher costs and lower availability.</p>
<p>The company noted that its solar shingles install just like regular roof shingles, except for exposing the electrical contacts on the upward side so they can be easily accessed (don&#8217;t worry — the whole thing is as weatherproof as a regular roof too). You can even walk on them when it&#8217;s time to clean the gutters. The company is the first to receive UL&#8217;s new &#8220;building-integrated photovoltaic (BIPV) solar roofing certification,&#8221; UL 7103.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s just another step from solar roofs being an expensive, complex option to a normal one available to anyone, and maybe even one that will pay itself off in time.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/gaf-energys-easy-install-solar-shingles-aim-to-outshine-tesla-roofs-and-traditional-panels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252737</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Connecting the dots on diversity in cybersecurity recruitment</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/connecting-the-dots-on-diversity-in-cybersecurity-recruitment/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/connecting-the-dots-on-diversity-in-cybersecurity-recruitment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 23:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief information security officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To tackle the cybersecurity skills shortage, we need to recruit from a wider, more diverse talent pool.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mandy Andress</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/elastic">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mandyandress">Mandy Andress</a> is the chief information security officer at <a href="https://www.elastic.co/">Elastic</a>, an enterprise search company, and has more than 25 years of experience in information risk management and security.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/13/pushing-for-an-apolitical-workplace-is-immoral-and-unrealistic/">Pushing for an &#8216;apolitical&#8217; workplace is immoral (and unrealistic)</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Critical thinking and problem-solving are considered vital attributes for the cybersecurity professional — so it’s time our industry applied those capabilities to connect the dots between the skills shortage and lack of diversity.</p>
<p>There’s no question that recruiting talent in sufficient numbers right now is a growing challenge — but it’s one that I believe a more inclusive talent pipeline would help to alleviate.</p>
<p>In its <a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Research/2021/ISC2-Cybersecurity-Workforce-Study-2021.ashx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cybersecurity Workforce Study 2021</a>, industry body (ISC)<sup>2</sup> found that 2.7 million information security jobs remain unfilled worldwide. While this number is down from 3.1 million in 2020, we’re a long way from where we need to be. In the face of increased digitization and a rising tide of attacks, the current cybersecurity workforce of 4.2 million people globally needs to grow 65% to keep up with the demand for its skills.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2250680" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In other words, we’re going to need to draw from a wider talent pool to plug the gaps. But as researchers from Washington, D.C.-based think tank the Aspen Institute point out in their <a href="https://www.aspeninstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Diversity-Equity-and-Inclusion-in-Cybersecurity_9.921.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Diversity, Equity and Inclusion in Cybersecurity report</a>, diversity efforts to date “have not addressed the overwhelming white-ness and male-ness of the cybersecurity field.” Estimates suggest that only 4% of U.S. cybersecurity workers self-identify as Hispanic, 9% as Black and 24% as women, the report noted.</p>
<p>It’s clear that our industry faces serious future risks if it doesn’t find ways to recruit new talent to fill the growing number of vacancies. But more than that, its current lack of diversity poses <em>more</em> immediate risks because company systems aren’t homogeneous, and neither are potential assailants.</p>
<p>The authors of <a href="https://nam12.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fsecureservercdn.net%2F166.62.108.22%2F5kb.d9b.myftpupload.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2020%2F01%2FICIT-Brief-The-Business-Value-of-a-Diverse-InfoSec-Team.pdf&amp;data=04%7C01%7CIndia.Heady%40revereteam.com%7C9dc790746cf84aace5c308d9b4f4d535%7Cb824bfb3918e43c2bb1cdcc1ba40a82b%7C0%7C0%7C637739788197382292%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000&amp;sdata=JljMbk2dzxV%2FnqvJNljbpUsDmDH1MzVhfwv2GrEpi40%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Business Value of a Diverse Infosec Team</a> from the cybersecurity think tank Institute for Critical Infrastructure Technology make this point forcefully: “Homogeneous experiences and perspectives yield less success compared to problem-solving done by teams with varied backgrounds.”</p>
<p>Proactive cybersecurity strategies, by contrast, aggregate a multitude of perspectives, which brings the benefit of innovation, problem-solving and consensus-building.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>Shifting the narrative</h2>
<p>As the chief information security officer (CISO) at search-powered solutions company Elastic, I believe that individual information security leaders can do a great deal to shift the narrative, at least within their organizations. What this takes is a hefty dose of fresh thinking when it comes to recruitment.</p>
<p>The cybersecurity team I lead as an LGBTQIA+ female CISO includes people who represent the array of human nature when it comes to neurodiversity, sexual orientation, gender identity, race and age. The picture is just as varied when it comes to background, educational pathway and industry experience.</p>
<p>But let me be clear: Diversifying the cybersecurity talent pipeline is not just a numbers game for me. I’m not just focused on onboarding in sufficient numbers to run a fully staffed team. It’s also about improving the quality of that team and the work we perform.</p>
<p>Put simply, a more diverse cybersecurity team is a better cybersecurity team. In a multidisciplinary field like this, different perspectives are critical. When threats and tactics change around us daily, the diverse viewpoints on my team help counter complacency by bringing new thinking to situations. Our adversaries, after all, are continuously trying new tactics, finding new ways to bypass controls and identify vulnerabilities. My team’s different perspectives bring a more disruptive “hacker mindset” to our work in countering attacks.</p>
<p>Our industry’s overreliance on specialists with the “right” qualifications and educational backgrounds might actually be a weakness — a point of view reinforced for me by David Epstein’s 2019 book, “Range: Why Generalists Triumph in a Specialized World.” Epstein argues that generalists with wide-ranging interests are more creative, more agile and able to make connections that their more specialized peers can’t see, especially in complex and unpredictable fields — a description that is a good fit for cybersecurity.</p>
<p>The value of diverse thinking within my current team is evident in the ongoing data protection certification process that we perform for customers. For this key compliance process, diversity is our strength, because our team can quickly get beyond “the way things have always been done” and find better, more efficient and — critically — safer ways to meet changing compliance objectives.</p>
<p>Another example where I’ve seen a clear-cut advantage of diverse thinking is from my team’s approach to supporting our fully distributed workforce. Being a distributed company by design, with almost 80% of our employees working remotely, demands that my team think differently when it comes to data privacy and protection. Our constant innovation in supporting secure remote working meant we were already prepared in this area when the pandemic hit, while cybersecurity teams at other companies were still struggling to make the leap.</p>
<h2>Taking action</h2>
<p>What matters most, of course, is transforming words into action. For me, it helps that I work for an organization that prioritizes inclusivity and acceptance for all employees in its <a href="https://www.elastic.co/about/our-source-code" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Source Code</a>.</p>
<p>This gives managers and employees alike a clear set of cues as to who we are as an organization and who we aspire to be, telling employees: “<a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/culture-someone-like-me-mandy-andress-on-security-at-elastic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Just come as you are</a>.” By creating an environment that is inclusive for all employees, through a commitment to equal pay, emphasis on internal hiring and prioritizing skills over location, we can hire and retain the best talent wherever they reside.</p>
<p>This year, our company&#8217;s aspirational DEI goals include a 40% hiring rate target for women or non-binary individuals, with a 30% hiring rate target for technical roles &#8212; globally. And for underrepresented groups, our hiring rate target in the U.S. is 35%, with 27% for technical roles.</p>
<p>With that backing, I’ve personally taken positive steps to ensure that Elastic increases diversity in its cybersecurity talent pipeline. So here are my pointers for other information security leaders:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Broaden the scope of qualifications.</strong> Look beyond traditional schooling and minimum career experience to see skills, qualifications, experiences and capabilities gained from shorter programs, online certificates, other jobs and participation in cybersecurity communities that support core foundational understanding of systems and their vulnerabilities.<br />
Some of the most successful teams that I’ve built over the years have not only come from a variety of IT backgrounds, such as systems architecture, business analysis and project management but from outside of the IT discipline entirely. For example, I hired a former emergency medical technician who moved into healthcare fraud analysis before joining my team. Former lawyers have brought attention to detail. People with a marketing background have proved adept at tackling customer data privacy challenges with empathy, while those from the financial sector bring new thinking to compliance issues.<br />
But what they all have in common, and what has made them strong additions to my infosec teams, is their curiosity, a willingness to question, and excitement to learn and try new things. These transferable experiences are just as important, if not <em>more</em> important, than specific skills.</li>
<li><strong>Encourage underrepresented groups.</strong> Add language that explicitly states your interest in groups often left out of hiring pools, such as women, people of color and members of the LGBTQIA+ community. Job descriptions should make explicit that the company fosters a welcoming environment for everyone and encourages personal and professional development of its cybersecurity talent.<br />
For example, I have recruited for an intern program recently immigrated individuals who do not have the standard security qualifications. Most of these recruits quickly moved into full-time roles and outperformed cybersecurity veterans. I have also taken steps to work more closely with local community colleges on sourcing graduates and with recruitment specialists who focus on supplying more diverse candidates for cybersecurity roles, such as <a href="https://cybersn.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberSN</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Make your hiring process accessible.</strong> Many would-be applicants are discouraged if the hiring process isn’t adapted for those with <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/culture-why-accessibility-matters-to-someone-like-me" target="_blank" rel="noopener">accessibility needs</a>. We’ve worked to ensure that everything from our recruiting site to our internal digital properties and tools follows international guidelines and translates to a positive environment for all candidates and employees.<br />
Anonymized hiring is an important part of this process. I regularly review resumes with the identifying information stripped to ensure that unconscious bias plays no part when we’re making judgments on job candidates.</li>
</ul>
<p>Cybersecurity teams need people with diverse life experiences, education and skills, so our recruitment efforts need to reach a far wider audience. If they don’t, we risk overlooking talent and excluding viewpoints that could be instrumental in delivering on our mission as an industry. If we allow that to happen and continue instead to compete for the increasingly sparse talent that fits nicely with age-old biases, we’ll only have ourselves to blame.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/connecting-the-dots-on-diversity-in-cybersecurity-recruitment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250680</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: No-code app development platform Abstra raises $2.3M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/daily-crunch-no-code-app-development-platform-abstra-raises-2-3m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/daily-crunch-no-code-app-development-platform-abstra-raises-2-3m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 23:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to Daily Crunch for January 3, 2022! It’s a new year, but that doesn’t mean we’re going to reinvent the wheel. This newsletter is going to stick to its tried-and-true format, so expect few surprises and <em>lots</em> of news.</p>
<p>Before we start, a big thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/grg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Greg</a> for taking over while I was off. Now, to work! —<a href="http://twitter.com/alex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alex</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252673" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/please-effect-a-golf-clap-as-apples-value-reaches-3-trillion/"><strong>Apple’s value touches the $3T mark:</strong></a><strong> </strong>It’s easy to forget just how big the biggest tech companies are. The numbers simply scale past our ability to understand them. U.S. tech behemoth Apple made that point in spades today by briefly becoming worth <em>three trillion USD</em>. It’s a little hard to sum up just how much money that is, but it’s enough money that if you distributed the sum to all current Americans it would <a href="https://www.wolframalpha.com/input/?i=3+trillion+divided+by+the+population+of+the+united+states" target="_blank" rel="noopener">work out to around $9,000</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/brazils-abstra-lands-accenture-as-a-customer-and-2-3m-to-help-teams-make-apps-with-its-no-code-tool/"><strong>Abstra raises $2.3M for no-code apps:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The boom in no- and low-code services in recent years is partly thanks to demand for traditional developers outstripping supply, and technology itself advancing to allow the method of development to, well, work. Brazil’s Abstra’s latest round further indicates that the no- and low-code phenomenon is a global affair.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/twitter-completes-sale-of-mopub-to-applovin-for-1-05-billion/"><strong>Twitter completes MoPub sale:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The October-announced sale of Twitter’s MoPub service to AppLovin, a deal worth $1.05 billion, is now complete. MoPub is a mobile advertising platform, but Twitter is not done with ads. The company intends to keep building its in-house ad tech now that the deal is done, TechCrunch reports.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>The new year is already paying drama dividends, with the latest coming from an investor and the former CEO of Twitter. You see, Chris Dixon doesn’t agree with Jack Dorsey’s criticisms of non-Bitcoin crypto companies. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/your-mom-owns-web-2-0/">You can imagine the fun that we are having with this</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/smarter-health-gets-5-15m-sgd-to-reduce-healthcare-costs-in-southeast-asia/">Smarter Health raises $3.8M for better healthcare data sharing:</a> </strong>If you have ever had to port your own data for your healthcare providers, you are aware of how much fun it is. None. That’s how much. Happily Smarter Health is working on the issue in Singapore, working to allow for a “smoother exchange of data between different parties in the healthcare system, improving patient care and reducing administrative costs.”</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/the-station-tusimple-loses-the-driver-nikola-settles-and-transpo-predictions-for-2022/"><strong>What’s ahead for wheels?</strong></a><strong> </strong>The TechCrunch transit desk has a great look back at 2021 and a forecast for 2022. If you care about e-scooters, autonomous driving or anything related, we have you covered.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/02/aimmo-grabs-12m-series-a-to-advance-data-labeling-technology/"><strong>AIMMO raises $12M Series A for data labeling:</strong></a> AI is neat but needs lots of data to function. And to get that data, sometimes you have to do lots of tagging. Startups are taking this problem on, including Scale AI. AIMMO, a South Korean startup, has a neat take on the work varietal and, now, a full bank account.</li>
</ul>
<p>And because you deserve a treat for making it through the first working day of the year: The “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/31/cheugiest-tech-moments-of-2021/">Cheugiest tech moments of 2021</a>” from three of TechCrunch’s best.</p>
<p>If you need even more diversion, TechCrunch also has stories today <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/reflect-orb-biofeedback-ball/">on zen balls</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/the-fish-is-driving-again/">driving fish</a>.</p>
<h2>When fundraising, New Zealand startup founders should play the &#8220;Kiwi card&#8221;</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2251260" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/31/when-fundraising-new-zealand-startup-founders-should-play-the-kiwi-card/"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2251260" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2251260 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-86070581.jpg" alt="Kiwi crossing sign and Ngauruhoe Volcano, Tongariro National Park, North Island, New Zealand" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-86070581.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-86070581.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-86070581.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-86070581.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-86070581.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-86070581.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2251260" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Jami+Tarris" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jami Tarris <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>In the final article in a series about New Zealand, Rebecca Bellan <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/31/when-fundraising-new-zealand-startup-founders-should-play-the-kiwi-card/">spoke to four stakeholders</a> to learn more about how foreign investment and a fund of funds program are juicing up the nation&#8217;s burgeoning startup ecosystem:</p>
<ul>
<li>Peter Beck, CEO/CTO Rocket Lab</li>
<li>Cecilia Robinson, founder and co-CEO, Tend Health</li>
<li>Phoebe Harrop, principal, Blackbird Ventures</li>
<li>Robbie Paul, CEO, Icehouse Ventures</li>
</ul>
<p>“While starting on a rock at the bottom of the world comes with challenges, there are plenty of advantages, too,&#8221; said Paul, who advises native founders to &#8220;play the Kiwi card.&#8221;</p>
<p>Almost one of every five New Zealanders lives abroad, and that diaspora has helped the nation build a great deal of international goodwill. &#8220;It’s an easy conversation starter and chances are most interesting people offshore have some sort of affinity or connection to New Zealand,&#8221; Paul said.</p>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/why-delivery-hero-is-acquiring-a-majority-stake-in-spanish-delivery-company-glovo/"><strong>Why is Delivery Hero buying more of Glovo?</strong></a><strong> </strong>The latter company previously said that it wanted to stay indie and go public. And yet it was recently announced that Delivery Hero would acquire a majority stake in the business. TechCrunch digs into what might have happened.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/seriously-its-time-to-get-rid-of-that-classic-blackberry-for-real-now/"><strong>BlackBerry’s network is done:</strong></a> You really, <em>really</em> have to get rid of your BlackBerry. Why? Because the company “will end access to legacy services” tomorrow, which means no “key features like data, phone calls, SMS and 911 access.” It is time. At long last. All seven of you who still use a BlackBerry.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend software consultants who have expertise in UI/UX, website development, mobile development and more! If you’re a software consultant, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl?typeform-source=techcrunch.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/daily-crunch-no-code-app-development-platform-abstra-raises-2-3m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252673</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AWS will buy a SaaS company, and other 2022 enterprise predictions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/aws-will-buy-a-saas-company-and-other-2022-enterprise-predictions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/aws-will-buy-a-saas-company-and-other-2022-enterprise-predictions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Selipsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andy Jassy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bret Taylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cell phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[co CEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marc Benioff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulesoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tableau]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year end predictions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It's always a sticky business predicting what's going to happen in tech, because who knows what's going on behind the scenes or what's coming next.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s always a sticky business predicting what&#8217;s going to happen in tech, because who knows what&#8217;s going on behind the scenes or what&#8217;s coming next.</p>
<p>Would you have thought, for instance, that Salesforce would spend almost $28 billion <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">to buy Slack</a> at the end of 2020? Or that in 2021, Jeff Bezos <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/jeff-bezos-will-no-longer-be-ceo-of-amazon-as-of-later-this-year/">would step back at Amazon</a> with a domino effect of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/what-andy-jassys-promotion-to-amazon-ceo-could-mean-for-aws/">Andy Jassy moving into his role</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/tableau-ceo-adam-selipsky-is-returning-to-aws-to-replace-andy-jassy-as-ceo/">Adam Selipsky coming back</a> after a stint at Tableau to take Jassy&#8217;s old job running AWS?</p>
<p>I sure didn&#8217;t see that coming, and I&#8217;m betting most people didn&#8217;t. The tech world moves so quickly, it&#8217;s often hard to keep up.</p>
<p>We weren&#8217;t using <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/the-irrational-exuberance-of-web3/">the terms metaverse and web3</a> (complete with lowercase spelling), and then quite suddenly in 2021, we were. If you told me that the blockchain was going to come back in a big way in 2021, or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-changes-its-corporate-branding-to-meta/#:~:text=Facebook%20creator%20Mark%20Zuckerberg%20announced,our%20company%20is%20now%20Meta.">Facebook would change its name</a> to Meta, I would have laughed in your face. Yet, here we are.</p>
<p>So let&#8217;s admit that there are things that we can&#8217;t possibly predict, but it seems it&#8217;s a part of my job to rear back and throw out some predictions. I would like to think that mine are based on my careful observation of the world I cover in the enterprise, rather than some random musings, but if I&#8217;m being honest, it&#8217;s probably a combination.</p>
<p>So with that in mind, and the usual caveats, here are my predictions for the coming year:</p>
<ul>
<li>Speaking of web3, companies (and especially governments) will learn just how difficult it is to retrofit brittle legacy systems to accept digital currency. There will need to be some sort of reckoning to either modernize or let it go for the time being, most likely the latter. Updating systems is challenging and expensive, and it&#8217;s hard to see governments spending the money to do it to accommodate digital currency, which is still in its infancy. Pew recently reported that <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2021/11/11/16-of-americans-say-they-have-ever-invested-in-traded-or-used-cryptocurrency/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">just 16% of Americans</a> have traded, invested or used crypto currencies.</li>
<li>While we&#8217;re at it, even though the hype is out of control, I&#8217;m betting that most companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/10/face-computers-slowly-find-their-place-in-business/">will continue to adopt AR/VR slowly</a> in the enterprise in 2022. Just as in the past before the term &#8220;metaverse&#8221; started trending, there will be some experimental dabbling in areas where it makes sense, but most people will realize they don&#8217;t want to do their work with VR hardware on their face all day. And, it&#8217;s also expensive to create content.</li>
<li>With <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/30/bret-taylor-has-been-promoted-to-salesforce-co-ceo/">Bret Taylor getting promoted to co-CEO of Salesforce</a> this year, the next logical step is for him to take over as solo CEO, and let Marc Benioff follow Bezos into the chairman&#8217;s role, where he can concentrate more on his charity work. Benioff has been the face of the company for over 20 years, and he may want to finally step back from that grinding responsibility and enjoy his wealth.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/aws-will-buy-a-saas-company-and-other-2022-enterprise-predictions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248941</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlackBerry phones once ruled the world, then the world changed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/blackberry-phones-once-ruled-the-world-then-the-world-changed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/blackberry-phones-once-ruled-the-world-then-the-world-changed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[john chen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research-in-motion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s easy to forget now in the age of Apple and Android, but at one time, BlackBerry owned the business smartphone market. You could have your Motorolas and your Nokias and your Samsungs, but for business, BlackBerry was it. Stalwart. Secure. Functional. As TechCrunch reported this morning, BlackBerry is shutting down its remaining services, and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s easy to forget now in the age of Apple and Android, but at one time, BlackBerry owned the business smartphone market. You could have your Motorolas and your Nokias and your Samsungs, but for business, BlackBerry was it. Stalwart. Secure. Functional.</p>
<p>As TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/seriously-its-time-to-get-rid-of-that-classic-blackberry-for-real-now/?tpcc=tcplustwitter">reported this morning</a>, BlackBerry is shutting down its remaining services, and users running BlackBerry devices with BlackBerry OS 7.1 and BlackBerry 10 &#8212; and you have to wonder just how many there were left &#8212; will no longer have access to data or even the once famous BlackBerry messaging service, among other things. It&#8217;s all getting shut off tomorrow.</p>
<p>As that fateful shutdown day approaches, it may be hard to understand just how ubiquitous the BlackBerry was before iPhone and Android came along, and just how precipitous its market share drop was. People loved their BlackBerrys with the combination of external keyboard and messaging service as a way to communicate with colleagues outside of the office. For better or worse, the BlackBerry ushered in the mobile era for many business people.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252581" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Comscore tracked mobile market share data back when BlackBerry reached the height of its power in 2010 as the top smartphone platform with 43%. It would be the high water mark for the company. (Note that these numbers measure the platform ubiquity and not units sold.)</p>
<table style="width: 100%;" border="" cellpadding="5">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Month/Year</td>
<td>Market Share (as measured by top smartphone platforms)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="https://www.comscore.com/Insights/Press-Releases/2010/3/comScore-Reports-January-2010-U.S.-Mobile-Subscriber-Market-Share" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jan 2010</a></td>
<td>43%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="https://www.comscore.com/Insights/Press-Releases/2011/3/comScore-Reports-January-2011-US-Mobile-Subscriber-Market-Share" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jan 2011</a></td>
<td>30.4%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="https://www.comscore.com/por/Insights/Press-Releases/2012/3/comScore-Reports-January-2012-US-Mobile-Subscriber-Market-Share" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jan 2012</a></td>
<td>15.2%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="https://www.comscore.com/Insights/Press-Releases/2013/3/comScore-Reports-January-2013-U.S.-Smartphone-Subscriber-Market-Share" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jan 2013</a></td>
<td>5.9%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>As you can see, BlackBerry phones went from top of the smartphone heap to single digits in the blink of an eye, losing large swaths of market share as it got completely disrupted by Apple and Android touchscreens. BlackBerry eventually reacted to these changes, <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/rimm-announces-new-blackberry-bold-and-torch-phones-2011-8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">releasing the BlackBerry Torch in 2011</a>, but it was far too little and far too late. Plus in a classic case of disruption theory, the people who loved the external keyboard never really took to the BlackBerry touch screen.</p>
<p>One other move among many included teaming with Microsoft in 2011 to make Bing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2011-05-03-microsoft-rim-announce-collaboration-bing-to-power-blackberry.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the default search engine on BlackBerry</a> phone, which in retrospect feels like a bit of a desperation move, but at the time was viewed more positively that the company was trying things. Whatever they tried, though, it didn&#8217;t work.</p>
<p>As the company&#8217;s fortunes plunged, they <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/the-man-who-answered-the-call-to-save-blackberry/2016/05/20/8799b86c-1b93-11e6-8c7b-6931e66333e7_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hired John Chen as CEO</a> in 2013, who began the process of shifting the company from phones to security software.</p>
<p>Why security? Well, because BlackBerry always had a reputation as being rock-solid when it came to security, so it seemed like a reasonable pivot. The company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/28/blackberry-bows-out-of-making-its-own-hardware/">announced the change officially in 2016</a>. Today, the company focuses entirely on selling security software to enterprises and governments. It has a modest market cap of around $5 billion, but it&#8217;s still around.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SuYi2I7mpw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/28/blackberry-yes-blackberry-is-making-a-comeback-as-a-software-company/">BlackBerry, yes BlackBerry, is making a comeback as a software company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BlackBerry, yes BlackBerry, is making a comeback as a software company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/28/blackberry-yes-blackberry-is-making-a-comeback-as-a-software-company/embed/#?secret=SuYi2I7mpw" data-secret="SuYi2I7mpw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As my colleague Brian Heater pointed out in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/seriously-its-time-to-get-rid-of-that-classic-blackberry-for-real-now/?tpcc=tcplustwitter">today&#8217;s article</a>, there are still BlackBerry-style devices out there, but they don&#8217;t run the old BB operating system:</p>
<blockquote><p>There are, of course, plenty of options out there — though OnwardMobility, which promised a 5G BlackBerry-branded device is currently still MIA, in spite of promising an announcement in 2021. There’s always the OSOM device, which sports its own Canadian pedigree. Though, again, that privacy-focused product won’t be announced until Mobile World Congress at the end of next month.</p></blockquote>
<p>But the beloved BlackBerry, once the constant companion of business people and politicians is going to be left to history, another device disrupted by the next big thing.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IplxOgtzYw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/06/02/bye-bye-blackberry/">Will The Last BlackBerry User Turn Off The Flashing LED Light?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will The Last BlackBerry User Turn Off The Flashing LED Light?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/06/02/bye-bye-blackberry/embed/#?secret=IplxOgtzYw" data-secret="IplxOgtzYw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/blackberry-phones-once-ruled-the-world-then-the-world-changed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252581</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The fish is driving again</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/the-fish-is-driving-again/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/the-fish-is-driving-again/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 20:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ben gurion university]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Truly there is nothing new under the sun if, when one learns that a goldfish can drive, the immediate response is &#8220;again?&#8221; But while today&#8217;s icthyological innovation may bear superficial, scale-deep if you will, similarity to fish-driven vehicles of yesteryear, there is an important new aspect: in this case, the goldfish has actually learned to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Truly there is nothing new under the sun if, when one learns that a goldfish can drive, the immediate response is &#8220;again?&#8221; But while today&#8217;s icthyological innovation may bear superficial, scale-deep if you will, similarity to fish-driven vehicles of yesteryear, there is an important new aspect: in this case, the goldfish has actually <em>learned</em> to drive.</p>
<p>First, for those of you that weren&#8217;t paying attention in 2014, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YbNmL6hSNKw&amp;t=23s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">there was indeed a goldfish that drove around a little tank</a>, to the delight of the still-innocent world. Using a webcam mounted above the tank, an object detection algorithm tracked the position of the fish and moved the cart on which it was mounted in the direction the goldfish swam in. (I can&#8217;t believe I remembered this — I can&#8217;t remember my own address.)</p>
<p>Fun, right? But ultimately more of a piscine parlor trick than a serious scientific endeavor. After all, the fish was just swimming around its tank, oblivious to the world and mechanism that moved it about the room.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252631" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Now, however, researchers from Ben-Gurion University in Israel have taken it one step further. Using a remarkably similar mechanism, they also detect the position of a goldfish in a tank, and direct the &#8220;Fish Operated Vehicle (FOV)&#8221; in the direction of the sector it swims to.</p>
<p>But here is where the stories diverge. The researchers then set the goldfish to various tasks that required <em>actively navigating</em> its vehicle around the larger, non-aquatic world. For instance, the fish would start in the center of a room and be given a reward if it went to a red stripe on the side.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I am excited to share a new study led by Shachar Givon &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/MatanSamina?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MatanSamina</a> w/ Ohad Ben Shahar: Goldfish can learn to navigate a small robotic vehicle on land. We trained goldfish to drive a wheeled platform that reacts to the fish’s movement (<a href="https://t.co/ZR59Hu9sib">https://t.co/ZR59Hu9sib</a>). <a href="https://t.co/J5BkuGlZ34">pic.twitter.com/J5BkuGlZ34</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Ronen Segev (@ronen_segev) <a href="https://twitter.com/ronen_segev/status/1477889582398164994?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 3, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Despite the common wisdom that goldfish are particularly lacking in the brains department, they&#8217;re actually capable of learning and remembering fairly complex behaviors and situations. But there&#8217;s no reason to assume that the creature would be able to understand the more abstract concept of space represented by its tank moving through a larger world by some external means.</p>
<p>Yet as the researchers put it in the abstract to <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0166432821005994" target="_blank" rel="noopener">their paper in Behavioural Brain Research</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>[The fish] were able to operate the vehicle, explore the new environment, and reach the target regardless of the starting point, all while avoiding dead-ends and correcting location inaccuracies. These results demonstrate how a fish was able to transfer its space representation and navigation skills to a wholly different terrestrial environment.</p></blockquote>
<p>This suggests that the way even creatures on the order of goldfish get around is not some kind of hard-coded aquatic movement circuit but something more universal, perhaps one that evolved earlier and at a more basic level than we think. Just how abstract or universal is yet to be determined, but it&#8217;s an interesting result to be sure.</p>
<p>More importantly, however, it means there&#8217;s a pretty good chance that you&#8217;ll be able to get a mobile terrarium for your fish, iguana, skink, perhaps even your tarantula, allowing it the freedom of the house without actually letting it slither or scuttle everywhere. (Incidentally, if this idea appeals to you, you might enjoy the story <a href="http://www.sfsfss.com/stories/Blish,%20James%20-%20%5BNovelette%5D%20Surface%20Tension%20%5Bv1.0%5D.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&#8220;Surface Tension,&#8221; by James Blish</a>.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/the-fish-is-driving-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252631</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>These balls tell you how zen you are</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/reflect-orb-biofeedback-ball/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/reflect-orb-biofeedback-ball/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 20:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reflect]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s all good and well to be able to sit cross-legged on a mountain top and feel at one with the universe &#8212; but how do you know if you are doing it right or not? For beginner meditators who aren&#8217;t sure how they are &#8220;meant&#8221; to feel in their bodies there&#8217;s Reflect&#8217;s Orb product, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s all good and well to be able to sit cross-legged on a mountain top and feel at one with the universe &#8212; but how do you know if you are doing it right or not? For beginner meditators who aren&#8217;t sure how they are &#8220;meant&#8221; to feel in their bodies there&#8217;s <a href="https://www.meetreflect.com/orb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reflect&#8217;s Orb product</a>, which was launched during this year&#8217;s virtual CES shenanigans. Entrapped in their home base of Israel, I spoke to the company from the bustling and &#8212; fittingly &#8212; far more laid back metropolis of Tel Aviv, rather than the one-armed-bandit-laden post-apocalyptic hellscape that is Las Vegas.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re not targeting Zen Buddhist monks, or those who can sit cross-legged on top of the mountain and meditate for hours; they have their shit together,&#8221; jokes Shiri Perciger, CMO at Reflect. &#8220;They don&#8217;t need us &#8212; but we have had users try it who have never meditated before. We&#8217;ve also had expert yoga teachers and mindfulness coaches. Almost anyone who tried it finds value in our product.&#8221;</p>
<p>The value of Reflect&#8217;s Orb, the company says, is in the real-time biofeedback that&#8217;s shown on the device itself. As the company explains it, bio-feedback is the self-monitoring of your physiology in real time, using the company&#8217;s device. It enables you to gain insights into your internal processes and learn to regulate them. For example, if you use an Apple Watch, you may have noticed that the watch reminds you to breathe precisely at the moment you need it most. The &#8220;breathe&#8221; feature on the Apple Watch exemplifies the basic principles of biofeedback and highlights the importance of breath to improve wellness. The watch measures something (although, to my knowledge, Apple has never explicitly stated what triggers a &#8220;breathe&#8221; alert on your watch), and periodically reminds you to breathe for a bit. The goal is to bring you back to a place of peace. Orb takes biofeedback and makes the process more explicit.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252494" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;Biofeedback can be used for many things, including measuring and reporting stress and anxiety. We measure what&#8217;s going on in your body, and we show it to you in real time. The goal is to make you aware of things that usually you&#8217;re unaware of &#8212; things that happen unconsciously in your body all the time,&#8221; explains Noga Sapir, CEO at Reflect. &#8220;We are measuring things like heart rate and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heart_rate_variability" target="_blank" rel="noopener">heart rate variability (HRV)</a>, which is a very good predictor of stress. We also measure <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electrodermal_activity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">electrodermal activity (EDA)</a>. Both change in response to stress, and the idea behind biofeedback is that we show you a dynamic, constant feed of what&#8217;s going on. From there, you can begin to influence it. First by being aware of it, and then by seeing what works in this feedback loop. We give you the tools to first be aware of what your body is going through, and then to influence it in a way that will calm you.&#8221;</p>
<p>The device itself is a soft, cloth-covered ball that you hold in two hands. It has six electrodes where your fingers rest, and a light ring that reports back in real time how calm you are. The idea is that by adjusting your seating position, feeling your body and adjusting your breathing patterns, you can see how your body reacts to the various calming techniques. The light ring indicates how relaxed you are.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2252554" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Noga-Sapir-CEO.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2252554" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2252554" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Noga-Sapir-CEO.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="638" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Noga-Sapir-CEO.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Noga-Sapir-CEO.jpg?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Noga-Sapir-CEO.jpg?resize=300,187 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Noga-Sapir-CEO.jpg?resize=768,479 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Noga-Sapir-CEO.jpg?resize=680,424 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Noga-Sapir-CEO.jpg?resize=1536,957 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Noga-Sapir-CEO.jpg?resize=2048,1276 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Noga-Sapir-CEO.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2252554" class="wp-caption-text">Noga Sapir, CEO at Reflect, showing off the Orb (<strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.meetreflect.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reflect</a>)</p></div></p>
<p>The device itself is independent of your phone, and doesn&#8217;t need to be connected to anything. When you are connected to a network, the orb uploads your data to the cloud and makes it available to you via a mobile app, but you can also use it offline. Take it to a literal or proverbial mountain top and breathe. When the device reconnects it phones home so you can get detailed information about how your relaxation session went.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Reflect is entering a competitive and somewhat crowded market. The <a href="https://choosemuse.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Muse headband</a> measures brain activity and gives feedback on sleep and meditation practices. <a href="https://zendomeditation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zendo Meditation</a> also connects to your head to measure how deeply you find peace. Another product in this space is the <a href="https://www.hellocore.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Core meditation trainer</a>, which has a similar form factor &#8212; a ball with electrodes &#8212; that measures HRV and other biofeedback for meditation purposes. The company maintains that it has a unique enough selling point to carve out a healthy user base, and to take on its competitors head-on.</p>
<p>&#8220;Muse does something similar with neurofeedback, and Core rely on their meditation library, but don&#8217;t do live biofeedback. Both of these solutions need to be connected to an app,&#8221; explains Sapir, &#8220;We want the Reflect Orb to be an experience you can take anywhere with you wherever you go. We think the real-time biofeedback approach is better, in that it really allows you to build your awareness of the body and brings your focus. For me personally, it is very important that there <em>is</em> a mobile app, and that it gives you all the data you need, but when you use Reflect, you just use Reflect. There are meditation apps, and there is a lot of technology built into our phones, but it&#8217;s kind of paradoxical because phones are stressful for a lot of us. I just wanted to put the phone away and just focus on this tactile and visual experience.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Orb is priced at $229, but the company has the product available for preorder <a href="https://www.meetreflect.com/product/reflect/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">priced at a discounted $199</a> for now. The team told me it is planning to start shipping in February this year.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/reflect-orb-biofeedback-ball/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252494</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Please effect a golf clap as Apple&#8217;s value reaches $3 trillion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/please-effect-a-golf-clap-as-apples-value-reaches-3-trillion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/please-effect-a-golf-clap-as-apples-value-reaches-3-trillion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 19:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CrunchBase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wealth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We lose sight of the fact that the tech giants are just that: huge. Their scale is a bit hard to parse, frankly, as their wealth is effectively uncountable.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple&#8217;s rapid valuation ascent of the last few years came to a head today as the Cupertino-based hardware-and-software company reached the $3 trillion market cap threshold, according to <a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Google Finance</a> data.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s some quibbling among different data providers, but the <a href="https://twitter.com/bdsams/status/1478076141030285313">consensus</a> is that Apple managed to reach a $3 trillion valuation during intraday trading, despite some pegging the company at a mere $2.99 trillion.</p>
<p>Notably, the gap between $3.00 trillion and $2.99 trillion is <em>$10 billion</em>, so it&#8217;s not like the difference is chump change. Regardless, Apple has set a new high-water mark for corporate value in our time. Mazel.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252610" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>So what?</h2>
<p>The fact that a single technology company &#8212; any single company, really &#8212; is worth $3 trillion may not astound you if you have become accustomed to financial headlines that deal with large numbers. But it is, in fact, a big deal.</p>
<p>Some context will help. Back <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/morning-report-hunt-3-trillion/">in May 2017</a>, I noted that &#8220;tech’s Big 5&#8221; were approaching &#8220;the $3 trillion market cap watermark&#8221; with a combined value of $2.97 trillion. They finally <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/techs-5-biggest-players-now-worth-3-trillion/">reached that dollar figure</a> later that year in July. The next year, we noted that the same basket of companies was <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/the-big-5-worth-4-trillion-heading-into-earnings/">now worth $4 trillion</a>, a material jump from their prior values.</p>
<p>You know what has happened since: The pandemic revalued tech companies, giving them far more value per dollar of revenue than before. The impact of COVID on tech companies was perhaps most pronounced among pure software companies, but the largest U.S. tech companies did just fine, as we can see today in Apple&#8217;s accomplishment of being worth $3 trillion <em>on its own</em>, the same value as Apple, Amazon, Meta (née Facebook), Microsoft and Alphabet <em>combined</em> a half-decade ago.</p>
<p>The $3 trillion figure is notable for another reason. It&#8217;s also what the then-current crop of unicorns was worth back in mid-2021, <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/unicorn-startup-investors-2021-tiger-global/">per Crunchbase news math</a>. CB Insights <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research-unicorn-companies">says that they are worth $3.1 trillion now</a>. More simply, Apple is worth as much as every unicorn <em>combined</em>. That&#8217;s a lot!</p>
<p>We lose sight of the fact that the tech giants are just that: huge. Their scale is a bit hard to parse, frankly, as their wealth is effectively uncountable.</p>
<p>A lot of science-fiction discusses futures in which corporations are ascendant and able to act as nation-states either implicitly or explicitly. It always felt like a stretch in my imagination. But now with Apple hitting the $3 trillion mark on its own, perhaps the authors were really oracles after all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/please-effect-a-golf-clap-as-apples-value-reaches-3-trillion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252610</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 views: Pay attention to these startup theses in 2022</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/3-views-pay-attention-to-these-startup-theses-in-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/3-views-pay-attention-to-these-startup-theses-in-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 18:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alex wilhelm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[as-a-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business model]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dynamic pricing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forbes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natasha mascarenhas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pricing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red hat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software engineers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas, Alex Wilhelm and Anna Heim explain their perspectives on the startup models we can expect to see in 2022.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In retrospect, the rise of software as a service (SaaS) is obvious. But for years, the idea that software would not only be hosted by providers instead of purchased by customers, and rented, instead of owned outright, was far from anyone&#8217;s mind.</p>
<p>SaaS has cemented its place in the epicenter of startup and Big Tech life, but it’s already being disrupted by the usage-based pricing movement. More startups are offering their services via a developer hook or API, and charging for customer usage over, say, a set number of seats for a predetermined period of time.</p>
<p>Not everyone is sold on the on-demand move, but the competition for the software business model of the future underscores the point that tech models never rule the roost forever. So, what’s the next thesis that we will look back on? It may be more complicated than &#8220;a crypto strategy,&#8221; but we have thoughts on what will become the de facto startup model and strategy.</p>
<p>To explore the concept, <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Natasha Mascarenhas</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/alex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alex Wilhelm</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/abracarioca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anna Heim</a> took the time to write up their expectations for 2022’s startup theses. Naturally, our notes cover a bit more than just business models, but as the beating heart of every startup is its model, the money element comes into play in all of our perspectives.</p>
<h2>Alex: 2022 is when open source will become the de facto startup model</h2>
<p>I’ve spoken with lots of founders over the years, and while I do have a more business focus than an early-stage bent, I do get to chat with founders building the early blocks of their businesses on a regular basis.</p>
<p>What hit me this year, especially toward the latter half, was just how frequently I ran into bright folks building businesses that had an open source component.</p>
<p>We all know that open source isn’t new as a business concept. Red Hat was founded in the tech equivalent of the neolithic era and has done well throughout its life. But startups building companies atop open source code are taking up a greater portion of their industry than before, and I think I know why. Or at least I have a hunch.</p>
<p>It’s about control, basically.</p>
<p>Software was once something that you bought. Actually, if you go back far enough, you can find examples of early PC manufacturers offering full software suites with their hardware, but that model died off as the world realized that open platforms were the way forward. From there, software bumbled along as a thing that consumers and corporations could buy.</p>
<p>&#8220;Buy&#8221; is the key word here. Folks bought closed source code from companies, and then ran it on their own systems, either personal or mainframe. Then, the cloud came along, and hosted software took off. Here again, however, the code was still largely closed source. You didn’t get a copy of Slack’s code per se, but you could rent access to its service for your team.</p>
<p>As software transformed from a series of discrete sales to a stream of recurring payments, SaaS took off, and investors cheered it on. This brings us almost to the modern moment, but not quite. On-demand pricing began to supplant SaaS as the de facto sales model of the software world — as Anna notes below — with Twilio as its champion, just as Salesforce was once for the SaaS market.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/3-views-pay-attention-to-these-startup-theses-in-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250079</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your mom owns Web 2.0</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/your-mom-owns-web-2-0/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/your-mom-owns-web-2-0/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 18:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Dixon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack dorsey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marc Andreessen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I promise that this is not all a tech elite rubber-noodle fight. The drama, instead, highlights an interesting issue that venture capital has with the web3 world.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We&#8217;ve been gifted another episode of &#8220;Tech versus Tech: Crypto Edition&#8221; today.</p>
<p>The argument among the tech elite about just who owns what in the Web 2.0 and web3 worlds continued this weekend. And once again the dustup featured former Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey and a16z, the investing firm best known in recent years for its capital deployments into the blockchain domain.</p>
<p>Dorsey, after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/29/jack-reportedly-stepping-down-from-twitter-ceo-role/">pulling the rip cord from his perch atop Twitter</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/01/square-is-changing-its-name-to-block/">rebranding his fintech firm Square</a> to the more crypto-friendly &#8220;Block,&#8221; has decided to talk more publicly about his views.</p>
<p>And views he has. The well-known tech exec is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/05/jack-dorsey-dials-in-on-his-dream-job-bitcoin-missionary/">a known Bitcoin fan</a>, which you might think would slot in nicely with a16z&#8217;s general crypto bullishness.</p>
<p>It does not.</p>
<h2>Jack, web3 and who owns what</h2>
<p>We dug into the early Dorsey-versus-a16z arguments <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/bitcoin-is-religion-web3-is-greed/">here</a> but will provide a summary for those of you who would prefer something brief.</p>
<p>Dorsey&#8217;s ideas surrounding Bitcoin are centered around his belief in decentralization as a good. Bitcoin is a reasonably decentralized system. Its founder is out of the picture, it is owned by no single entity and its community has managed to keep working on the project despite it lacking a traditional leader or external investment.</p>
<p>How does that contrast with web3, the blockchain projects that also trumpet the power and importance of decentralization? Dorsey thinks that web3 is, in fact, centralized due to ownership &#8212; control &#8212; accruing in the hands of external investors, a16z among them. This is because, unlike with Bitcoin, web3 companies are busy hoovering up venture capital at a rate that is frankly staggering, meaning that many decentralized projects are racking up large external investors in their central holding companies &#8212; centralization squared, I suppose.</p>
<p>Dorsey&#8217;s complaints about ownership, web3 and the role of external capital in funding so much of the crypto market came to a head in a series of tweets posted between December 20 and 22, with the well-known Twitter user taking potshots at venture capital in crypto more generally, and a16z in particular.</p>
<p>One example for flavor:</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">You don’t own “web3.”</p>
<p>The VCs and their LPs do. It will never escape their incentives. It’s ultimately a centralized entity with a different label. </p>
<p>Know what you’re getting into…</p>
<p>&mdash; jack<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/26a1.png" alt="⚡" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@jack) <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1473139010197508098?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 21, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Them&#8217;s fighting words.</p>
<p>So what happened most recently? Well, a16z denizen and prolific Twitter blocker Chris Dixon took a shot <em>back</em> at Dorsey&#8217;s argument yesterday with the following:</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/your-mom-owns-web-2-0/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252510</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
