<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 10:20:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Taxdoo raises $64M to expand from tax compliance to a wider set of financial tools for e-commerce companies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/taxdoo-raises-64m-to-expand-from-tax-compliance-to-a-wider-set-of-financial-tools-for-e-commerce-companies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/taxdoo-raises-64m-to-expand-from-tax-compliance-to-a-wider-set-of-financial-tools-for-e-commerce-companies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 10:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automation technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hamburg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Curtius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taxdoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visionaries Club]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248616</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With e-commerce becoming increasingly globalized, a company called Taxdoo, which builds API-based tools to help e-commerce companies with tax compliance and other accounting needs, is announcing a round of funding: $64 million, a Series B that the Hamburg-based startup will be using to expand further across Europe and to build what it describes as the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With e-commerce becoming increasingly globalized, a company called <a href="https://www.taxdoo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Taxdoo</a>, which builds API-based tools to help e-commerce companies with tax compliance and other accounting needs, is announcing a round of funding: $64 million, a Series B that the Hamburg-based startup will be using to expand further across Europe and to build what it describes as the financial operating system for e-commerce businesses.</p>
<p class="p5">&#8220;We&#8217;re already helping customers shave off hours of manual [sales tax] work, and with newer features like pro forma invoices for tax compliance, we’ve built a lot of adjacent features,&#8221; said CEO Christian Königsheim in an interivew. &#8220;The long-term vision is that we want to enable our customers to have their financial data accelerate their growth rather than holding them back. We want to give them competitive edge by automating tedious tasks, so that they don&#8217;t have to pay that much attention to compliance and regulation. We see this as a financial operating system for commerce.&#8221;</p>
<p>The funding is being led by Tiger Global &#8212; part of the VC&#8217;s very aggressive foray into backing European startups &#8212; with previous backers Accel, Visionaries Club, and 20VC also participating. Taxdoo last announced funding less than a year ago &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/taxdoo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a $21 million Series A</a> &#8212; so this brings the total raised by it now to $84 million. I understand from sources close to the company that the valuation is now just north of $350 million.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248616" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Co-founded by three economics PhDs &#8212; Matthias Allmendinger, Roger Gothmann and Christian Königsheim &#8212; the three were doing research into VAT. They saw how complex sales tax regimes were for average merchants to follow, but they also identified that there was probably a way to solve that with automation technology.</p>
<p>The three have been very hands-on with how the company has developed and grown that vision: I mentioned to Königsheim that when he was talking to me it sounded like he was reading out his company&#8217;s press release &#8212; <em>not</em> what you want to happen when you&#8217;re interviewing someone! But it turned out that he actually wrote that press release himself, hence the identical cadence and diction. (I joked that he might have others on the team dedicated to doing that kind of work these days, he replied that he saw it as his &#8220;victory lap&#8221; after working so hard on closing the round.)</p>
<p>Taxdoo very much made its name around providing a set of APIs that European e-commerce companies, or really any organization doing business online, could use to calculate VAT (sales tax) and to track it to meet accounting compliance requirements. It currently works with over 1,700 marketplaces, online merchants, and enterprises, integrating with the platforms that they use in turn to sell online. (These include ERP providers like Xentral, as well as e-commerce site builders like Shopify, payment platforms like Afterbuy and marketplaces like eBay and Amazon.)</p>
<p>As e-commerce has continued to grow, so too have both the complexity of accounting around it, and the scrutiny of the space by financial regulators.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>On the accounting side, one of Taxdoo&#8217;s tools, for example, allows companies to automatically query and pull out transaction data needed to calculate VAT (some transactions are exempt, so that makes it more complicated). Another can pull records and send them for individual filing across different countries or tax juridictions.</p>
<p>On the regulatory front, new rules coming into force have presented more opportunities for Taxdoo to expand its own scope of services. Its APIs now include, in addition to a wider set of VAT calculators, tools to manage accounting and invoicing. It also has opened its platform so that third-party developers can build their own tools on top of Taxdoo for customers to use to fit their specific needs (Xentral is an example of one of the developers building apps on top of Taxdoo to make it easier to use the two platforms together).</p>
<p class="p3">This is dry work, and for many definitely not the most visible part of building an e-commerce business, but it&#8217;s essential, and hard, to get right. This also makes the company an attractive partner &#8212; or even target &#8212; for ambitious fintech companies that are building one-stop shops to service online businesses with all of their payment and financial needs. (Case in point, Stripe has made acquisitions and launched a new suite of services aimed to help calculate sales tax for its customers. It seems that a logical next step would be to dive deeper into accounting around those tax calculations.)</p>
<p>“Taxdoo is tackling the largest pain points faced today by e-commerce merchants and marketplaces,&#8221; said John Curtius, partner at Tiger Global, in a statement. &#8220;Taxdoo&#8217;s team uniquely combines deep expertise in e-commerce, automation, tax, accounting, and finance — along with a pervasive customer centricity. We’re excited to support Taxdoo in building the Financial Operating System for e-commerce.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/taxdoo-raises-64m-to-expand-from-tax-compliance-to-a-wider-set-of-financial-tools-for-e-commerce-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248616</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ventures Platform announces first close of its $40M pan-African fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/ventures-platform-announces-first-close-of-its-40m-pan-african-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/ventures-platform-announces-first-close-of-its-40m-pan-african-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 10:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Draper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[african]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[andela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kola Aina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lagos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Seibel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paystack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SeedCamp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital Firms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ventures Platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zambia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Activity around African venture capital firms raising funds continues to increase as we head towards the end of the year. In the latest development, Abuja- and Lagos-based Ventures Platform is today announcing the first close of its $40 million pan-African fund. The fund, founded by one of Nigeria’s most active early-stage investors, Kola Aina, has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Activity around African venture capital firms raising funds continues to increase as we head towards the end of the year. I</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">n the latest development, Abuja- and Lagos-based <a href="https://venturesplatform.com/">Ventures Platform</a> is today announcing the first close of its $40 million pan-African fund.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fund, founded by one of Nigeria’s most active early-stage investors, <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/kola-aina-vp">Kola Aina</a>, has made 69 investments since 2016</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Ventures Platform&#8217;s news is also coming a day after another pan-African VC firm 4DX Ventures secured the final close of its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/4dx-ventures-closes-second-fund-with-60m-adds-dikembe-mutombo-as-senior-advisor/">$60 million fund</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aina, the firm’s founding and general partner, said he used his own money for the first set of investments made by the firm</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Then, Ventures Platform experimented with an accelerator model, where it gave a standardized check of $20,000 to pre-seed to seed-stage startups in exchange for 10% equity.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248348" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2017, Ventures Platform took outside capital for the first time by forming syndicates. Within this two-year period, some</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of the startups it invested in included Piggyvest, Paystack, Kudi and Thrive Agric</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">wanted to perfect our style of finding high-performing companies early before they become obvious and backing them with everything we bring to the table from our experience as operators ourselves,” Aina told TechCrunch over a call. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We didn’t want to go out and try to fundraise when we didn’t </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">really</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have evidence that we could make money out of this.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ventures Platform became one of the local investors that cashed out from Paystack’s $200 million+ exit to Stripe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. With a few other secondary exits under its belt, Aina said he felt this was the perfect time for the firm “to go to the market and raise its first institutional fund.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though the first close of Ventures Platform’s first institutional fund </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is undisclosed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Aina noted that “it is a sizeable amount</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.” </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interestingly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the limited partners (LPs) involved are Nigerian- and African-based, which is a testament to the growth in the size of local investors’ checks in funding the region’s most innovative companies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paystack CEO Shola Akinlade is one of these LPs. Others include the Nigeria Sovereign Investment Authority (NSIA); UAC Nigeria, one of Nigeria’s oldest companies; VFD Group; and global investors such as Y Combinator CEO Michael Seibel and Adam Draper.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">proud that for this first close, a large part of our capital came from local funding. I gave a TED Talk titled ‘who would own our future unicorns’ and I’m so proud of this because it seems Africans are answering loud and clear that we would own them too. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So this was a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">nice mix of Nigerian corporates, family offices, institutions, as well as global investors</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aina mentioned that it took a conscious effort to accept only local capital for its first close. And while a few investors from Europe, the U.S. and Asia took part, he said they would feature </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">heavily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (including institutional investors and DFIs) in the second close, which will occur early next year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It was very deliberate. For us, it was strategic, getting local capital for our first close. I mean, the second close, as you will see, will be from global fund of funds and DFIs where we’ve got commitments. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, ultimately</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as much as foreign capital is critical, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it’s an interest of foreign capital to be in bed with local capital from a derisking standpoint.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ventures Platform sees itself as a thesis-centred fund. Aina said the fund’s thesis </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is centred</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> around funding market-creating innovations that solve non-consumption and create innovative new ways to deliver goods and services or services to low-income markets. The firm </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is focused</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on six core verticals: fintech, edtech, agritech and food science, healthtech and bioscience, enterprise SaaS and digital infrastructure.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because the pan-African firm relied on syndicate and proprietary capital funds in the earlier stages of its lifecycle, it couldn’t take on follow-on rounds in its portfolio companies, including the likes of Tiger-backed Mono and SeamlessHR.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These startups have </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">cumulatively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> raised more than $500 million in follow-on rounds, and Aina notes that his firm is keen on participating now that it has secured the first close of this fund.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We have a pretty robust pipeline of companies that we’ll be looking at across the continent, as well as our portfolio companies that have raised new rounds of financing. We’re looking for interesting companies that fit our thesis and what’s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">compelling now is that we have a follow on capital to fund them,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ventures Platform </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">primarily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> focused on pre-seed and seed with an average check size of $50,000, but this fund provides the opportunity to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">participate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Series A deals. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now the firm will be able to write more than $1 million to companies (including follow-on rounds) over their life cycle</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Abuja-based venture capital firm is also deepening activity in other regions outside Nigeria &#8212; Kenya’s MarketForce and Tambua Health, Zambia’s Union54 and Egypt’s MoneyHash. It plans to invest more in these regions and Francophone Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of the firm’s 69 companies, 30% have passed through Y Combinator. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aina says that while part of this success can be attributed to Y</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">C being a partner, he believes his firm has a knack for picking quality companies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6D15yNTPE8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/one-of-nigerias-high-profile-angel-investors-is-launching-a-fund-for-african-startups/">One of Nigeria&#8217;s high-profile angel investors is launching a fund for African startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;One of Nigeria&#8217;s high-profile angel investors is launching a fund for African startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/one-of-nigerias-high-profile-angel-investors-is-launching-a-fund-for-african-startups/embed/#?secret=6D15yNTPE8" data-secret="6D15yNTPE8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Only a few venture capital firms in the Nigerian and African tech ecosystem can boast similar YC stats with Ventures Platform</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. For startups, being part of these firms’ portfolios represents a marker of success, but some VC critics believe these sorts of numbers are inevitable for firms that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">employ</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “pray and spray” tactics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aina defends his firm, saying that as an “early-stage discovery fund,” Ventures Platform’s role involves identifying many companies to back early and invest in subsequent rounds of few. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> every fund has its strategy. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ultimately</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, because of the stage at which we invest, a key part of our strategies is to fund a large batch of companies at the pre-seed stage, and what you see is that funnel would narrow as time goes on. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">With this new fund, we now can double down on our winners, which is good for the companies and also good for us at the point of exit</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ventures Platform said it would onboard well-known figures across African tech as venture partners as part of a move to deepen its expertise further. The first and only disclosed partner for now is Seni Sulyman, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the former vice president of global operations at Andela and CEO of BlackOps, a talent marketplace for African venture builders and operators</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/ventures-platform-announces-first-close-of-its-40m-pan-african-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248348</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>German revenue-based financing platform Re:cap raises $111.5M Seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/german-revenue-based-financing-platform-recap-raises-111-5m-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/german-revenue-based-financing-platform-recap-raises-111-5m-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 09:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entreé Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[felix capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fintech startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project A Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seed money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underwriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Re:cap, a non-dilutive funding platform in a similar vein to Pipe.com and Capchase but based in Europe, has closed a Seed financing round of $111.5 million, in a mix of growth capital and liquidity for the revenue-based financing platform. re:cap’s first product is now officially going live, following a pre-seed funding in May of this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.re-cap.com/">Re:cap</a>, a non-dilutive funding platform in a similar vein to Pipe.com and Capchase but based in Europe, has closed a Seed financing round of $111.5 million, in a mix of growth capital and liquidity for the revenue-based financing platform. re:cap’s first product is now officially going live, following a pre-seed funding in May of this year.</p>
<p>The growth capital has come from pan-European VCs Felix Capital and Project A Ventures, with participation from existing investor Entrée Capital. The new capital will be invested into further expansion of the team as well as product and entering new European markets from its launch base of Germany. Initially focused on SaaS businesses, it has plans to move into other verticals.</p>
<p>The company was founded by Paul Becker (CEO) and Jonas Tebbe (CPO), who previously built the <a href="https://www.liqid.de/">LIQID</a> fintech startup.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248621" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>re:cap allows recurring revenue businesses to fund their growth, but without needing to dilute ownership via VC or taking on debt, with the ability to convert up to 50% of their ARR into instant, non-dilutive upfront cash. At the same time, institutional investors can invest directly in the recurring revenues of software companies.</p>
<p>Paul Becker, Co-founder and CEO of re:cap said: &#8220;Our funding platform will revolutionize the way software companies finance themselves today. But focusing on software companies is just the beginning: all financing solutions can be rebuilt with the information available in the digital age. Our ambition is for re:cap to become the European champion in this category.”</p>
<p>Joseph Pizzolato of Felix Capital said: “re:cap’s speed of execution in their first months has been tremendous. Both their financing solution and their technology with fully automated underwriting and transaction processing are setting standards. Based on their experience and expertise, the team around Paul and Jonas brings all the prerequisites to build a European category leader.”</p>
<p>“Today’s newly emerging tech players need money fast to finance and scale their business. re:cap has developed a great new digital funding platform for software companies to finance their business with the right investors quickly. We were the first major investor in Paul’s and Jonas&#8217; previous company, LIQID, and have great confidence in the team to build something game-changing”, said Uwe Horstmann, General Partner at Project A.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Speaking to me over a call Becker added: “We operate in a similar fashion to Pipe, less so Capchase. The main difference is that we are live in Germany and we did it at a record pace. So speed for execution is important. We were able to get a lot of liquidity on the market at launch, $100M, so way more than other players when they launched. We basically have a mature product at launch, with deeper underwriting and automation, that works for institutional investors.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We mainly target on SAAS and software or companies with a tech component, but we’re also servicing consumer subscription companies. We mainly go after companies with recurring revenue models, enabling us to underwrite the companies. In Germany it is a little tougher to think about regulation and privacy, so if you don’t have that then you are screwed,” he added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/german-revenue-based-financing-platform-recap-raises-111-5m-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248621</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google&#8217;s Africa Investment Fund makes first investment in Uganda&#8217;s SafeBoda</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/googles-africa-investment-fund-makes-first-investment-in-ugandas-safeboda/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/googles-africa-investment-fund-makes-first-investment-in-ugandas-safeboda/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 09:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Africa Investment Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beenext]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[east africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gojek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SafeBoda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[west africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248609</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Internet giant Google announced today that it has made the first investment from its Africa Investment Fund in Ugandan super app SafeBoda. The undisclosed investment comes two months after Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai announced the tech giant’s intentions to commit $1 billion over the next five years in “tech-led initiatives”, which includes a $50 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Internet giant Google announced today that it has made the first investment from its Africa Investment Fund in Ugandan super app <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/the-motorcycle-ride-hailing-wars-in-nigeria-and-uganda-is-safebodas-to-lose/">SafeBoda</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The undisclosed investment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> comes two months after Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai announced the tech giant’s intentions to</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/google-confirms-1b-investment-into-africa-including-subsea-cable-for-faster-internet/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">commit $1 billion over the next five years</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in “tech-led initiatives”, which includes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/google-sets-up-50m-fund-to-invest-in-african-startups/">a $50 million Africa Investment Fund</a> targeted at early- and growth-stage startups on the continent. He made this known at the Google for Africa event in October.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before launching the fund, Google proved helpful in startups’ journeys via its Google for Startups Accelerator Africa program. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248609" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The accelerator </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">program has supported more than 80 startups in seed to Series A stages with equity-free mentorship and resources. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Collectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, they have raised over $100 million in venture capital. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Google also recently launched Black Founders Fund, a non-dilutive $3 million fund allocated to 50 startups yearly. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NEZhR3whEk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/google-sets-up-50m-fund-to-invest-in-african-startups/">Google sets up $50M fund to invest in African startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google sets up $50M fund to invest in African startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/google-sets-up-50m-fund-to-invest-in-african-startups/embed/#?secret=NEZhR3whEk" data-secret="NEZhR3whEk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fintech startups and those from Nigeria, Kenya, Egypt and South Africa get looked at the most by venture capitalists. Last year, fintech startups accounted for 25% of the VC funding which flowed into Africa, while startups from the Big Four received more than half of the continent’s total funding. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VC firms and institutional fund managers who have spoken with TechCrunch recently say they want to bridge this funding gap by investing in overlooked regions and sectors on the continent. Nitin Gajria, t</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">he managing director of sub-Saharan Africa, Google, is one such and he expressed these sentiments </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">when the company announced the Africa Investment Fund in October. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are not restricting ourselves to certain verticals. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are focusing on investments where </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">we believe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that Google could add value,” the managing director said in October</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. “If there are founders building interesting products solving real challenges in Africa, that would fall </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">squarely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> within our investment thesis.”</span></p>
<p>Though Google’s investment in SafeBoda <span style="font-weight: 400;">serves as an early reminder of Gajria’s statement,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> startups from the Big Four markets will likely fill the fund’s portfolio in the next couple of years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Ugandan startup launched as a two-wheel ride-hailing platform before embarking on a super app plan two years ago</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, it offers rides, parcel delivery, food and shop, payments, savings and other financial services to over 1 million customers in Uganda and its second market, Nigeria. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company counts more than 25,000 drivers who have completed over 40 million orders in both markets</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SafeBoda has rarely announced any of its funding rounds since its </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">inception</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2017, but people who know the company’s dealings say it has raised over $20 million. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its investors include GoVentures of Gojek, Allianz X, Transsion Holdings, Beenext, Unbound and Justin Kan</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SafeBoda said the investment from Google’s Africa Investment Fund will help “drive its growth in Uganda and Nigeria, scaling its transportation-led app to offer new payment and financial services solutions for its expanding set of customers: passengers, drivers and merchants.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“SafeBoda welcomes Google to their community and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are excited</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to continue to drive innovation in informal transportation and payments in the boda boda (East Africa) or okada (West Africa) industry,” said co-founder </span>Ricky Rapa Thomson in a statement.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This vital industry is the lifeblood of Africa’s cities and powers economic development</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. SafeBoda </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is thrilled</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that leading global companies such as Google see the importance of backing startups working towards these goals.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TechCrunch reached out to Google for more details on the deal and future investments</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>Gajria, <span style="font-weight: 400;">in a statement, said, “I am thrilled about our first investment from the $50M Africa Investment Fund that we announced two months ago. This is part of our ongoing commitment to tech startups in Africa. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am of the firm belief that no one is better placed to solve Africa’s biggest problems than Africa’s young developers and entrepreneurs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We look forward to announcing </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">subsequent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> investments in other startups.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="v2Km6QTG1s"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/the-motorcycle-ride-hailing-wars-in-nigeria-and-uganda-is-safebodas-to-lose/">The motorcycle ride-hailing wars in Nigeria and Uganda are SafeBoda&#8217;s to lose</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The motorcycle ride-hailing wars in Nigeria and Uganda are SafeBoda&#8217;s to lose&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/the-motorcycle-ride-hailing-wars-in-nigeria-and-uganda-is-safebodas-to-lose/embed/#?secret=v2Km6QTG1s" data-secret="v2Km6QTG1s" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/googles-africa-investment-fund-makes-first-investment-in-ugandas-safeboda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248609</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>La Belle Vie raises $28 million to build an online supermarket from scratch</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/la-belle-vie-raises-28-million-to-build-an-online-supermarket-from-scratch/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/la-belle-vie-raises-28-million-to-build-an-online-supermarket-from-scratch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bam Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[instant groceries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[instant grocery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[La Belle Vie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick commerce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup La Belle Vie announced that it has raised a $28.2 million (€25 million) Series B round led by Left Lane and Quadrille Capital, with existing investor Capagro also participating. The company operates an online grocery store in the Paris area. Online grocery delivery services and so-called quick-commerce startups are quite trendy. In fact, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.labellevie.com">La Belle Vie</a> announced that it has raised a $28.2 million (€25 million) Series B round led by Left Lane and Quadrille Capital, with existing investor Capagro also participating. The company operates an online grocery store in the Paris area.</p>
<p>Online grocery delivery services and so-called quick-commerce startups are quite trendy. In fact, it has become an incredibly crowded space. In Paris alone, people can order groceries from Cajoo, Gorillas, Flink, Getir, Zapp and Gopuff (following <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/after-acquiring-dija-and-fancy-instant-grocery-startup-gopuff-launches-in-the-uk-en-route-to-european-expansion/">Dija’s acquisition</a>) — I’m probably forgetting a name or two.</p>
<p>But La Belle Vie has been around since 2015. It has acquired quite a lot of experience when it comes to logistics, inventory management and unit economics.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248149" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>La Belle Vie originally started with a focus on fresh products, such as vegetables, fruits, meat, fish and cheese. You could order anything you would find in a local outdoor food market. And it’s true that supermarket chains have often neglected that segment with their online order service.</p>
<p>Over time, La Belle Vie has expanded its offering with packaged goods and many of the items that you would find in a supermarket. The company has signed a partnership with Système U.</p>
<p>In many ways, La Belle Vie feels like an online supermarket. There are offers and an editorialized selection of products. For instance, you can buy 12 oysters for €4.99 right now. This is the kind of offer you would find in the central aisle of a supermarket.</p>
<p>Right now, La Belle Vie offers 17,000 products, including 4,000 different fresh products. The company can deliver your order in less than 3 hours across the Ile-de-France region. It has 500 employees and processes 15,000 orders per week.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While it feels perfectly fine to wait a couple of hours to get your groceries, La Belle Vie isn’t standing still. The company wants to compete directly with quick-commerce startups. It has launched a new brand called <a href="https://www.bamcourses.com">Bam Courses</a>.</p>
<p>The new service is limited to Paris and a selection of 2,500 products. Orders are dispatched from one of La Belle Vie’s seven distribution hubs in Paris and the company tries to deliver orders within 15 minutes.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very proud of the path [co-founder] Alban [Wienkoop] and I have taken. Since day one, we have been obsessed with profitability, with extremely tight control of our margins and supply chain, but also with the social aspect, with the employment of over 600 people on permanent contracts. La Belle Vie is a wonderful human adventure and we are thrilled to be supported in our growth by international and French investors that are as prestigious as they are experienced,” co-founder and CEO Paul Lê said in a statement.</p>
<p>Before today’s funding round, the company had raised a $6.2 million (€5.5 million) round in 2018 and and a $13.1 million (€11.6 million) round in 2020. Up next, the startup plans to expand to other major cities in France.</p>
<p>While Getir and Gopuff have been around for a while, most quick-commerce startups have been founded in the past year or two. The fact that La Belle Vie has been around for a while is a clear advantage as it has gained some experience over the past few years.</p>
<p>There’s a big question mark in the instant grocery delivery space. What happens if VC firms stop financing gigantic funding rounds, like Flink’s recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/flink-the-berlin-based-instant-grocery-startup-is-now-valued-at-2-85b-after-raising-750m-in-a-round-led-by-doordash/">$750 million round</a>? It’s hard to predict whether customers will stick around once promo codes dry up and service quality goes down. With its slow and steady approach, La Belle Vie has more visibility on its customer base and future performance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/la-belle-vie-raises-28-million-to-build-an-online-supermarket-from-scratch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248149</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Phylagen, which tracks indoor microbiomes, says it&#8217;s right now &#8220;racing to meet demand&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/phylagen/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/phylagen/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 05:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3m]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakout Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cultivian Sandbox Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phylagen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solazyme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two years into a worldwide pandemic, outfits around the globe are wrestling with how to resume their in-person operations safely. Consider that Apple just scrapped its office-return deadline, while Google, which plans to require its workforce to return to its offices three times a week at some point next year, made it clear to employees [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Two years into a worldwide pandemic, outfits around the globe are wrestling with how to resume their in-person operations safely. Consider that Apple just <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-15/apple-delays-return-to-office-until-date-yet-to-be-determined">scrapped</a> its office-return deadline, while Google, which plans to require its workforce to return to its offices three times a week at some point next year, made it clear to employees yesterday that if they don&#8217;t get vaccinated, they will eventually lose their jobs. &#8220;Our vaccination requirements are one of the most important ways we can keep our workforce safe and keep our services running,&#8221; said Google in a <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/12/14/google-employees-to-lose-pay-if-dont-comply-with-vaccination-policy.html">statement</a> to CNBC:</p>
<p>Still, even vaccinated individuals can become infected with variants of the highly contagious coronavirus. Enter <a href="https://phylagen.com/">Phylagen</a>, a low-flying, seven-year-old, San Francisco-based company that says it&#8217;s able to combine microbial genomics and data analytics to answer the question of whether a physical space has played host to someone with Covid-19.</p>
<p>How does it do it? In broad strokes, Phylagen employs a network of sensors, swabs, and sample collectors who put the materials into packages twice a week, then ship them to a centralized lab. Phylagen then promises data within 72 hours about whether sick people have carried germs inside a building &#8212; which it divides into floors and zones for tracking purposes &#8212; or whether the building&#8217;s air is safe to breathe.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247469" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company calls it &#8220;enterprise pathogen monitoring as a service,&#8221; and its feasibility has long fascinated founder and CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jessicalgreen/">Jessica Green</a>, a former biology professor who is formally trained as both a civil engineer and a microbiome scientist.</p>
<p>It was a lonely obsession until recently, however. As Green explains it: &#8220;We spend 90% of our time indoors and know nothing about what we&#8217;re breathing in, even while during this very conversation, we&#8217;ll both emit millions of micro organisms and inhale hundreds and thousands of viruses, bacteria, and molds that [can have] really severe consequences for our health and well-being.&#8221; While she &#8220;knew this decades ago,&#8221; she adds, the public&#8217;s understanding has &#8220;come to fruition with this pandemic.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pIBhksbHy4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/charity_dean/">Disease-related risk management is now a thing, and this young startup is at the forefront</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Disease-related risk management is now a thing, and this young startup is at the forefront&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/charity_dean/embed/#?secret=pIBhksbHy4" data-secret="pIBhksbHy4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Phylagen wasn&#8217;t always so focused on the air we breath. From its earliest days until some time last spring, the company operated in what&#8217;s called the supply chain track-and-trace market, a segment that businesses use to ensure that their products have followed an expected path toward their final destination. (Detours can mean products have been tampered with, which can ruin a company&#8217;s reputation or even lead to deadly consequences, especially when it comes to pharmaceuticals.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Green suggests there was interest in the product as a means to track Covid as the pandemic took hold, but as it became clearer that the virus was spreading through aerosols and not surfaces, Phylagen pivoted completely to another application of Phylagen&#8217;s  technology. It began to use its learnings &#8212; and its ever-growing database of microorganisms &#8212; not for traceability applications, but instead to enter buildings, capture the microorganisms found there, then digitize the information and push it out to customers.</p>
<p>Apparently, there are a growing number of them. While Green declined to name specific clients, saying only that Phylagen is working closely with numerous big tech companies and commercial real estate companies, she said the business, cofounded by  Harrison Dillon &#8212; he previously cofounded the industrial biotech firm Solazyme &#8212; is going like gangbusters heading into 2022.</p>
<p>Revenue, she says, has grown 10 times year over year. The company has 40 employees up from 20. Phylagen plans to double headcount again, in fact, aided by strategic funding the company quietly raised this past summer from Johnson Controls, a publicly traded European conglomerate that produces fire, HVAC, and security equipment for buildings.</p>
<p>Altogether, Phylagen has raised $30 million to date, including from 3M, Breakout Ventures, and Cultivian Sandbox.</p>
<p>Of course, questions remain, including whether Phylagen can outmaneuver rivals that are springing up in the space.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are emerging competitors because this is the new normal,&#8221; acknowledges Green. &#8220;Everybody is going to be demanding healthy indoor air, and there are currently very antiquated ways of measuring indoor air quality, and no affordable, reliable ways to test for anything biological that&#8217;s air-related.&#8221;</p>
<p>Phylagen&#8217;s own processes may seem antiquated to those who don&#8217;t want to wait 72 hours for results from either the labs that Phylagen owns (it has one in San Francisco and another in Manhattan) or with which it partners. After all, given how quickly the coronavirus is still spreading, two or three days might sound to some potential customers like an eternity.</p>
<p>Green suggests that window will shrink soon enough. &#8220;In the next generation [of testing], everything will be automated and on site. Imagine a CO2 sensor or Nest thermostat that gives information on temperature and relative humidity. There is a clear path to being able to detect DNA and RNA that is airborne in a similar way, and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re working toward.&#8221;</p>
<p>Certainly, if Phylagen fulfills its potential, its opportunities look, well, significant. For one thing, Phylagen can test for much more than Covid-19 and says that allergens are also on its road map.</p>
<p>Beyond its commercial possibilities, there is also the home. Already, early investor 3M appears to be champing at the bit to develop data-driven consumer products. It even began selling a <a href="https://news.3m.com/2021-09-27-Scotch-Brite-TM-and-Phylagen-Introduce-the-First-Consumer-Home-Cleanliness-Test-Kit">home cleanliness kit</a> in September using Phylagen&#8217;s technology, though judging by the kit&#8217;s <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09C7BHYF4?tag=commconn_us_45_101393-20&amp;linkCode=ogi&amp;th=1&amp;psc=1&amp;smid=A3JWKAKR8XB7XF">price</a> on Amazon &#8212; it costs roughly $180 &#8211;it&#8217;s too expensive for most homeowners to consider at this point and is more of a trial balloon.</p>
<p>In the meantime, Green insists that the company remains entirely focused for now on its enterprise customers, in part because it doesn&#8217;t have time to consider other products, not anytime soon.</p>
<p>&#8220;The main thing to take away from that [3M] product is that we can really make any menu of organisms that we want to test for,&#8221; she says. &#8220;But the most relevant and the largest market opportunity and the biggest market need right now is the commercial building space.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s more a function of what we&#8217;re able to keep up with,&#8221; she adds. &#8220;Right now, We&#8217;re racing to meet demand.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/phylagen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247469</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reddit files confidentially to go public</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/reddit-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/reddit-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 03:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steve huffman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wikis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In August, Reddit raked in a hefty $410 million financing led by Fidelity, valuing it at $10 billion. It had plans to close out the round, a Series F, at $700 million at the time. The company&#8217;s CEO Steve Huffman told the New York Times that Fidelity&#8217;s investment would give it more time to decide [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In August, Reddit raked in a hefty $410 million financing led by Fidelity, valuing it at $10 billion. It had plans to close out the round, a Series F, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/reddit-is-raising-up-to-700m-in-series-f-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">at $700 million at the time</a>.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s CEO Steve Huffman <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/12/technology/reddit-new-funding.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told the New York Times</a> that Fidelity&#8217;s investment would give it more time to decide when and how to go public.</p>
<p>Now the news is out that the 16-year-old site has confidentially submitted a draft registration statement with the Securities and Exchange Commission to go public, the company <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/reddit-announces-confidential-submission-of-draft-registration-statement-related-to-proposed-public-offering-301446048.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> Wednesday evening.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248561" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Reddit has not yet determined how many shares to offer or the price range for its initial public offering.</p>
<p>There were signs that the well-financed company was readying for an IPO. In March, it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/reddit-is-raising-up-to-700m-in-series-f-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the hiring of its first-ever CFO, Drew Vollero, who previously worked on Snap’s IPO.</p>
<p>Reddit has raised $1.3 billion in funding so far, according to <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/reddit" target="_blank" rel="noopener">public information</a>.</p>
<p>The content aggregating behemoth has faced mounting challenges such as presenting itself as a home for communities while trying to police hate speech. A subreddit earlier this year played a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/sec-issues-statement-on-past-weeks-turbulent-market-activity-prompted-by-reddit-fueled-gamestop-run/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pivotal role</a> in massive market rallies for companies like GameStop and AMC.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In 2019, Tencent&#8217;s leading role in Reddit&#8217;s $300 million Series D stoked fears that censorship would befall the community site. My colleague Jon at the time <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/12/tencent-reddit-nononono/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">disputed the speculation</a>.</p>
<p>The hype on Reddit has contributed to its financial success. In Q2, Reddit broke <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/reddit-is-raising-up-to-700m-in-series-f-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$100 million in advertising revenue</a>. At last count in August, the site attracted 50 million daily visitors and hosted 100,000 active subreddits.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JLcXfAYqSA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/reddit-is-raising-up-to-700m-in-series-f-funding/">Reddit is raising up to $700M in Series F funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Reddit is raising up to $700M in Series F funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/reddit-is-raising-up-to-700m-in-series-f-funding/embed/#?secret=JLcXfAYqSA" data-secret="JLcXfAYqSA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/reddit-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248561</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beijing court rules bitcoin mining contract &#8216;void&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/beijing-court-rules-bitcoin-mining-contract-void/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/beijing-court-rules-bitcoin-mining-contract-void/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 02:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual currency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As crypto investors widely know, China has declared all cryptocurrency transactions illegal and outlawed crypto mining activities. Lately, a court decision further reasserted the government&#8217;s attitude to stifle any bitcoin mining activity possible. On December 15, the court of Beijing&#8217;s Chaoyang District heard a contract dispute over delayed returns from bitcoin mining and ruled that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As crypto investors widely know, China has declared all <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/24/china-says-all-cryptocurrency-related-transactions-are-illegal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cryptocurrency transactions illegal</a> and outlawed crypto mining activities. Lately, a court decision further reasserted the government&#8217;s attitude to stifle any bitcoin mining activity possible.</p>
<p>On December 15, the court of Beijing&#8217;s Chaoyang District heard a contract dispute over delayed returns from bitcoin mining and ruled that the service contract was &#8220;void&#8221;, according to a <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/xjlqO0s6jXjtIVGgqu0bqQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">notice</a> from the court.</p>
<p>The plaintiff took to the court after the defendant, a mining company it contracted, failed to pay it 278.1654976 Bitcoins, which is worth roughly $18 million as of December 15.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248537" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>This marks the first time a Beijing court has declared bitcoin mining contracts null, the notice said. Following the ruling, the court urged relevant authorities in Sichuan, an energy-rich province where mining mentioned by the case took place, to &#8220;purge&#8221; any such remaining activity.</p>
<p>The court ruling, while not surprising, could discourage overseas companies from doing business with Chinese crypto firms. Though China has deemed all crypto transactions, trading and investment illegal, many crypto firms still keep engineering and operational forces in the country while touting services to overseas customers.</p>
<p>China began weighing crypto mining bans as early as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/09/china-considers-ban-crypto-mining/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2019</a> and started to seriously ramp up enforcement in 2021. Virtual <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">currency mining is &#8220;energy-intensive, produces high carbon emissions and contributes little to the economy,&#8221; said a September <a href="http://www.news.cn/english/2021-09/24/c_1310207561.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">notice</a> from the National Development and Reform Commission, China&#8217;s state planner, and such activities &#8220;should be eliminated.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The signed contract, the Beijing court said, &#8220;is void because it undermines social and public interests.&#8221; As such, its related rights and interests &#8220;should not be protected by the law&#8221; and the parties involved &#8220;should bear the consequences&#8221; of their actions.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="poqHHOMY6y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/24/china-says-all-cryptocurrency-related-transactions-are-illegal/">China says all cryptocurrency-related transactions are illegal and must be banned</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China says all cryptocurrency-related transactions are illegal and must be banned&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/24/china-says-all-cryptocurrency-related-transactions-are-illegal/embed/#?secret=poqHHOMY6y" data-secret="poqHHOMY6y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/beijing-court-rules-bitcoin-mining-contract-void/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248537</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>General Catalyst leads $7M investment in AR startup selling NFT jetpacks</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/general-catalyst-invests-7m-in-ar-startup-selling-nft-jetpacks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/general-catalyst-invests-7m-in-ar-startup-selling-nft-jetpacks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avatar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distributed computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guy oseary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sound ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After months of NFT mania and Facebook&#8217;s recent name change to Meta, it&#8217;s fair to say that &#8220;metaverse&#8221; chatter has reached a fever pitch. And while crypto investors are buying up avatars and digital swaths of land in hopes that a digital universe will spring up around these projects, it&#8217;s unclear which projects &#8212; if [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After months of NFT mania and Facebook&#8217;s recent name change to Meta, it&#8217;s fair to say that &#8220;metaverse&#8221; chatter has reached a fever pitch. And while crypto investors are buying up avatars and digital swaths of land in hopes that a digital universe will spring up around these projects, it&#8217;s unclear which projects &#8212; if any &#8212; will stand the test of time.</p>
<p>Institutional investors are also making their bets on the NFT &#8220;metaverse.&#8221; Crypto startup <a href="https://jadu.ar/nft/hoverboards">Jadu</a>, which has made millions of dollars selling pixelated NFT jetpacks and hoverboards, has scored $7 million in venture funding from General Catalyst with additional funding from Coinbase Ventures, The VR Fund, Sound Ventures and Guy Oseary, among others.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s virtual accessories can be used with other 3D avatars including Larva Labs&#8217; Meebits and other wildly pricey NFTs like CyberKongz and DeadFellaz. The avatars can be viewed and raced around in the company&#8217;s AR app The Mirrorverse, which the company hopes to eventually turn into a full-fledged Pokémon GO-like game.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248461" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Over the weekend, the company sold 6,666 NFT hoverboards for $4.4 million worth of the Ethereum cryptocurrency.</p>
<p>The NFT space has attracted plenty of ridicule throughout the year, though proponents believe that the digital goods are more than meet the eye and allow creators to get attention and bankroll projects that they might otherwise have a tough time financing. Jadu CEO Asad J. Malik says that appetite for NFTs is overwhelming, but that they&#8217;re focused on building their broader platform for the time being.</p>
<p>&#8220;We can milk people right now, like there&#8217;s enough interest if we want we could say we&#8217;re releasing some avatar and we&#8217;re going to do like 1 ETH mints, and we can probably like make $20-30 million like that, but that&#8217;s not sustainable and that&#8217;s distracting,&#8221; Malik tells TechCrunch. &#8220;We have enough money, we&#8217;re going to build out the AR stuff. That&#8217;s really what we want to get ahead of everyone else on, like actual good AR gameplay, and NFTs are just kind of a process of being able to do that.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ywruV7vKJc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/crypto-giant-dapper-labs-takes-its-next-shot-with-genies-nft-platform-the-warehouse/">Crypto gaming giant Dapper Labs takes its next shot with Genies NFT platform &#8216;The Warehouse&#8217;</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Crypto gaming giant Dapper Labs takes its next shot with Genies NFT platform &#8216;The Warehouse&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/crypto-giant-dapper-labs-takes-its-next-shot-with-genies-nft-platform-the-warehouse/embed/#?secret=ywruV7vKJc" data-secret="ywruV7vKJc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/general-catalyst-invests-7m-in-ar-startup-selling-nft-jetpacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248461</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bold visions and solid fundamentals are driving investor interest in space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/bold-visions-and-solid-business-fundamentals-are-driving-investor-interest-in-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/bold-visions-and-solid-business-fundamentals-are-driving-investor-interest-in-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Space Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bessemer's Tess Hatch, Sequoia's Shaun Maguire and Hemisphere Ventures' Lisa Rich shared their thoughts on the active year that just passed and on what's coming next.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Investors are excited about the opportunities in the space market that are being unlocked by exit events and continued interest and private investment in the biggest and most successful space companies, including SpaceX. During a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a> panel discussion on the growth-stage investment outlook for startups, Bessemer&#8217;s Tess Hatch, Sequoia&#8217;s Shaun Maguire and Hemisphere Ventures&#8217; Lisa Rich shared their thoughts on the active year that just passed and on what&#8217;s coming next.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve shared highlights from the discussion below, followed by a video of the full discussion, &#8220;Backing the Brightest.&#8221;</p>
<p>First, in terms of the year that just passed, SPACs obviously played a big role in space startups and generating liquidity for investors.</p>
<p>Hatch:</p>
<blockquote><p>It&#8217;s bringing liquidity back to the investors that invested in those space companies years ago, I think looking back, Skybox, which was one of the first venture backed companies that had an exit was sold to Google for about half a billion dollars in 2014, after it was created in 2010. And not many venture capitalists were investing in space at the time, but they heard half-a-billion four years later— those are good ROI and a short time horizon for my LPs. Then basically every VC invested in one or two space companies, but from 2014 until this year, there weren&#8217;t many liquidity events in the industry.</p></blockquote>
<p>Maguire:</p>
<blockquote><p>You know, I think direct IPOs are still the gold standard, and a lot of the most marquee companies will try to do that. But SPACs are a very powerful tool in the toolkit, and it&#8217;s great to have another path toward liquidity. And in general, I think SPACs are better suited for deep tech companies than for like, enterprise SaaS companies, just where there&#8217;s oftentimes it&#8217;s hard to tell long-term stories with a traditional IPO process, whereas it&#8217;s much easier with SPACs.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/bold-visions-and-solid-business-fundamentals-are-driving-investor-interest-in-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248142</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hyundai’s Mobile Eccentric Droid tries hard to live up to its name</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/hyundais-mobile-eccentric-droid-tries-hard-to-live-up-to-its-name/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/hyundais-mobile-eccentric-droid-tries-hard-to-live-up-to-its-name/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m going to hand it to Hyundai. The company is building some weird robotics, and I’m mostly here for it. In addition to the more straightforward car-building fare you’d expect, the auto giant has also given us a walking car robot or two, some wild drones and whatever this thing is. All in all, Boston [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I’m going to hand it to Hyundai. The company is building some weird robotics, and I’m mostly here for it. In addition to the more straightforward car-building fare you’d expect, the auto giant has also given us a<a href="https://www.hyundai.com/worldwide/en/brand/technology-with-a-human-heart" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> walking car robot or two</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/hyundai-shrinks-its-walking-car-robot-to-carry-cargo-get-rides-from-drones/">some wild drones</a> and <a href="https://www.hyundainews.com/en-us/releases/3242" target="_blank" rel="noopener">whatever this thing is</a>.</p>
<p>All in all, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/hyundai-completes-deal-for-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics/">Boston Dynamics could have landed</a> in a much worse place from the standpoint of robotic experimentation.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2248465" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2248465" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-full wp-image-2248465" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49093-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1536" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49093-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg 3250w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49093-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49093-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49093-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49093-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49093-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49093-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=1365,2048 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49093-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2248465" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>Hyundai</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248462" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>And now, there’s the Mobile Eccentric Droid (MobED). The four-wheel, Segway-style device is a platform in the strictest sense. That is to say, it’s open to a wide range of different applications &#8212; and you can also, quite literally, put stuff on top of it. It’s effectively a mobile wheelbase designed for a wide range of environments on which roboticists can build autonomous and controlled robotic applications on top of.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_BI8usSuo7I?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Judging from the <a href="https://youtu.be/_BI8usSuo7I" target="_blank" rel="noopener">brightly-colored YouTube video</a> the company released ahead of CES (where the system will be on display), potential applications include package delivery, the transportation of small infant humans and teleconferencing. Other potential applications for MobED include mobility for people with walking difficulties.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have developed the MobED platform to overcome the limitations of existing indoor guide and service robots while maximizing its usability in cities by dramatically improving the platform&#8217;s overall mobility,&#8221; Hyundai Motor Group Robotics Lab head <span class="xn-person">Dong Jin Hyun said in a release</span>. &#8220;We are also looking ahead to assess how potential users of MobED will further expand their needs and use for this type of technology.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2248464" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2248464" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2248464" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49095-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49095-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg 4672w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49095-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49095-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49095-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49095-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49095-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49095-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Large-49095-HyundaiMotorGroupRevealMobileEccentricDroidMobEDanAll-NewMobilityPlatformforVersatileApplications.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2248464" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Hyundai</p></div></p>
<p>The system weighs 110 pounds and is capable of speeds up to 19 miles an hour. The built-in battery should last around four hours, per Hyundai’s estimation. The “eccentric” bit reference to the system’s control mechanism.</p>
<p>Per Hyudai:</p>
<blockquote><p>The eccentric mechanism-based posture control system also stabilizes the body attitude by adjusting the height of each wheel according to the ground environment. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The MobED&#8217;s 12-inch pneumatic tires further help to absorb bumps and vibrations. </span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">More on this &#8212; and other Hyundai robots &#8212; to follow at CES next month.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/hyundais-mobile-eccentric-droid-tries-hard-to-live-up-to-its-name/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248462</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>KakaoEntertainment subsidiary acquires fantasy fiction platform Wuxiaworld</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/kakaoentertainment-subsidiary-acquires-fantasy-fiction-platform-wuxiaworld/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/kakaoentertainment-subsidiary-acquires-fantasy-fiction-platform-wuxiaworld/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kakao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kakao Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radish Originals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tapas media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webtoon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Korean startup Kakao Entertainment announced today it has acquired Wuxiaworld, an Asia fantasy fiction platform, via its serialized fiction app subsidiary Radish to bolster the mobile storytelling business. The transaction size is $37.5 million.   Wuxiaworld, which has grown through word-of-mouth, claims it is now the largest English-language Asia fantasy platform in the U.S. in terms of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span style="color: #0e101a;">South Korean startup</span><a href="https://kakaoent.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="color: #4a6ee0;"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Kakao Entertainment</span></span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> announced today it has acquired </span><a href="https://www.wuxiaworld.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="color: #4a6ee0;"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Wuxiaworld</span></span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">, an Asia fantasy fiction platform, via its serialized fiction app subsidiary </span><a href="https://www.radishfiction.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="color: #4a6ee0;"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Radish</span></span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> to bolster the mobile storytelling business. The transaction size is $37.5 million.</span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span style="color: #0e101a;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><span style="color: #0e101a;">Wuxiaworld, which has grown through word-of-mouth, claims it is now the largest English-language Asia fantasy platform in the U.S. in terms of the number of users. The fans have translated more than a hundred thousand Chinese and Korean fiction chapters into English. Approximately 30% of its users are from the U.S and Canada, while 30% and 20% are from Southeast Asia and Europe. The rest are scattered across the globe. </span></span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247737" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><span style="color: #0e101a;"> </span></span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><span style="color: #0e101a;">The announcement comes nearly seven months after Kakao Entertainment&#8217;s <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/kakao-entertainment-acquires-tapas-and-radish-media-two-leading-us-based-storytelling-platforms-301288196.html">two U.S-based storytelling platform acquisitions</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/serial-fiction-app-radish-acquired-by-kakao-entertainment-for-440m/">Radish</a> and </span><a href="https://tapas.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="color: #4a6ee0;">Tapas Media.</span></a></span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="peeu4ZMK33"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/serial-fiction-app-radish-acquired-by-kakao-entertainment-for-440m/">Serial fiction app Radish acquired by Kakao Entertainment for $440M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Serial fiction app Radish acquired by Kakao Entertainment for $440M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/serial-fiction-app-radish-acquired-by-kakao-entertainment-for-440m/embed/#?secret=peeu4ZMK33" data-secret="peeu4ZMK33" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QnUkamdkAd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/22/tapas-media/">Tapas Media aims to turn digital comics into the next big entertainment franchise</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tapas Media aims to turn digital comics into the next big entertainment franchise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/22/tapas-media/embed/#?secret=QnUkamdkAd" data-secret="QnUkamdkAd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><span style="color: #0e101a;">Wuxiaworld was founded in 2014 by Jingping (JP) Lai, a former American diplomat and passionate fan of Chinese fantasy martial arts novels, or Wuxia, who started translating Chinese martial arts fiction into English out of his love for these works. Wuxiaworld does not have physical offices, although it is headquartered in Hong Kong, Lai said. It will continue operating 100% work-from-home as it has been since its founding, with founder Lai remaining CEO of the Asia fantasy storytelling platform, Lai told TechCrunch. </span></span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span style="color: #0e101a;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><span style="color: #0e101a;">Wuxiaworld expects to launch more content in its platform with Kakao Entertainment&#8217;s broad access to the best original stories and intellectual properties in Korea&#8217;s fast-growing online serial fiction market and Radish&#8217;s strong marketing team (in the U.S.), Lai said. Wuxiaworld also has partnerships with Chinese digital publishers that can create additional synergies. </span></span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span style="color: #0e101a;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><span style="color: #0e101a;">Wuxiaworld has millions of page views daily in over 100 countries via its website and app with a majority male audience. In contrast, Radish’s audience is primarily female-driven, which perfectly complements to diversifying Kakao Entertainment’s web fiction portfolio in the U.S. market, according to its statement. </span></span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span style="color: #0e101a;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm;"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><span style="color: #0e101a;">“Wuxiaworld is a truly gem of a company. Supported by strong word-of-mouth and an active community, 85% of Wuxiaworld’s total revenue comes through content purchased by a monthly subscription model. The company continues to grow impressively, with annual year-over-year profit growth of up to 40%,” said global strategy officer of Kakao Entertainment and CEO of Radish and Seungyoon Lee, who led the acquisition of Wuxiworld. </span></span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2247900" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2247900" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2247900" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KE-and-Radish-Media-acquires-Wuxiaworld.png?w=300" alt="Kakao Entertainment / Radish" width="800" height="176" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KE-and-Radish-Media-acquires-Wuxiaworld.png?resize=150,33 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KE-and-Radish-Media-acquires-Wuxiaworld.png?resize=300,67 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KE-and-Radish-Media-acquires-Wuxiaworld.png?resize=680,151 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KE-and-Radish-Media-acquires-Wuxiaworld.png?resize=50,11 50w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2247900" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Kakao Entertainment/ Radish/ Wuxiaworld</p></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NuEfC1hcc6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/radish-softbank-kakao/">Serialized fiction startup Radish raises $63.2M from SoftBank and Kakao</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Serialized fiction startup Radish raises $63.2M from SoftBank and Kakao&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/radish-softbank-kakao/embed/#?secret=NuEfC1hcc6" data-secret="NuEfC1hcc6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Wuxiaworld&#8217;s subscription system allows users to read ongoing episodes free, but all completed episodes are paywalled. It also offers a monthly ad-free subscription model that enables users to read various completed series for free each month and a novel-specific sponsorship program that lets readers access the next chapters of ongoing episodes. </span></p>
<p>Kakao Entertainment’s popular martial arts and fantasy fiction contents such as “The Second Coming of Gluttony” and “Overgeared” already account for approximately 5% of the Wuxiaworld library among the top-grossing intellectual properties, driving almost a quarter of its revenue.</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“Both companies [Kakao Entertainment and Radish] are committed to creating high-quality mobile fiction, which forms the basis for their strong market leadership in the U.S. and Korea,” Lai said. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Kakao Entertainment, which owns a slew of collections of Korean web fiction, will accelerate its business growth in English-speaking markets with Radish’s expertise in delivering mobile novels to U.S. consumers and Wuxiaworld’s commitment to translation excellence, as per its statement. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">&#8220;Radish and Kakao Entertainment hopes to further realize Wuxiaworld&#8217;s infinite growth potential to reach a new and wider demographic in the U.S. market,&#8221; Lee said. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Following the acquisition, Kakao Entertainment now has three storytelling platforms: Radish, Tapas and Wuxiaworld. Having launched across Asia and Europe this year, the company plans to expand further in international markets next year, aiming to triple its transaction from overseas in the next three years. Kakao Entertainment announced last week <a href="https://kr.ambafrance-culture.org/kakao-job/">its webtoon service launch in France</a> as early as this month. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Kakao Entertainment opened offices in Thailand and Taiwan earlier this year. It also entered Indonesia in 2017 and Indian in 2020. Its sister company Piccoma, formerly known as Kakao Japan, provides web cartoons and novels in Japan.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">South Korea’s two largest internet giants Kakao and Naver compete in the storytelling platform market. In May, Naver has also completed an acquisition of Wattpad, a Canada-based web novel platform.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lmsl0MlLlG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/with-new-owner-naver-wattpad-looks-to-level-up-its-user-generated-ip-factory/">With new owner Naver, Wattpad looks to supercharge its user-generated IP factory</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With new owner Naver, Wattpad looks to supercharge its user-generated IP factory&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/with-new-owner-naver-wattpad-looks-to-level-up-its-user-generated-ip-factory/embed/#?secret=lmsl0MlLlG" data-secret="lmsl0MlLlG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/kakaoentertainment-subsidiary-acquires-fantasy-fiction-platform-wuxiaworld/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247737</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canoo ends partnership with VDL Nedcar to manufacture EVs in Europe, partners with VDL Groep</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/canoo-ends-partnership-with-vdl-nedcar-to-manufacture-evs-in-europe-partners-with-vdl-groep/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/canoo-ends-partnership-with-vdl-nedcar-to-manufacture-evs-in-europe-partners-with-vdl-groep/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 23:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vdl nedcar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Electric vehicle startup Canoo is ending its deal with Dutch automotive manufacturing company VDL Nedcar to serve as its contract manufacturer in Europe, according to a Securities and Exchange Commission filing on Wednesday. A separate filing reveals that Canoo will also be exploring a new deal with VDL Groep, another Dutch auto manufacturing company, to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="Text__text___3eVx1j Text__dark-grey___AS2I_p Text__regular___Bh17t- Text__large___1i0u1F Body__base___25kqPt Body__large_body___3g04wK ArticleBody__element___3UrnEs" data-testid="paragraph-0">Electric vehicle startup Canoo is ending its deal with Dutch automotive manufacturing company VDL Nedcar to serve as its contract manufacturer in Europe, according to a <a href="https://sec.report/Document/0001213900-21-065494/ea152435ex99-2_canoo.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Securities and Exchange Commission filing on Wednesday</a>. <a href="https://sec.report/Document/0001213900-21-065494/ea152435ex99-1_canoo.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A separate filing</a> reveals that Canoo will also be exploring a new deal with VDL Groep, another Dutch auto manufacturing company, to produce vehicles in the U.S.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">“We appreciate the months of effort VDL Nedcar invested to provide us with a contract manufacturing option, but we have concluded that building in America is better aligned with our mission and current focus to invest in the communities and states that are investing in hi-tech manufacturing alongside us, creating American jobs and innovation,&#8221; said Tony Aquila, Canoo&#8217;s CEO, in the filing. &#8220;The support from Oklahoma and Arkansas will allow us to achieve SOP earlier and with less risk on many fronts.”</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">As part of the breakup, VDL Nedcar will return Canoo’s prepayment of $30.4 million, and as part of the new partnership, VDL Groep will purchase $8.4 million of Canoo stock.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248350" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">The news comes about a month after<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/canoo-is-setting-up-headquarters-in-walmarts-hometown-picks-panasonic-as-battery-supplier/"> Canoo shared plans to move its headquarters and an advanced manufacturing industrialized facility to Bentonville, Arkansas</a>, where Walmart is also headquartered. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/ev-startup-canoo-is-gearing-up-for-production-in-oklahoma-factory/">During Canoo&#8217;s second-quarter earnings call</a>, Aquila had estimated VDL Nedcar would produce up to 25,000 units of the automaker&#8217;s lifestyle vehicle in 2023, but it appears those vehicles will now be manufactured in Arkansas.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">Canoo is also working on its &#8220;mega microfactory&#8221; in Oklahoma, which is expected to come online in late 2023 and will build Canoo pickup trucks and multipurpose delivery vehicles. Oklahoma committed $300 million in non-dilutive financial incentives to support Canoo&#8217;s facility and the next phase of its manufacturing. Canoo has not replied to requests for information about similar financial incentives offered by Arkansas, but it&#8217;s likely those incentives exist. The SEC filing states that Canoo will be able to better utilize the incentives from Oklahoma and Arkansas now that the startup and VDL Nedcar have ceased contract manufacturing discussions, and that it can better facilitate its ability to deliver vehicles ahed of Q4 without the 25% tariff that would have attached if the vehicles were manufactured in Europe.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">With the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/15/us/politics/biden-signs-infrastructure-bill.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$1 trillion infrastructure bill officially signed into law</a>, which includes the Buy American Act, it&#8217;s possible Canoo will be chasing federal government contracts and other government incentives. The act restricts the purpose of non-domestic supplies, stipulates that the end product must be manufactured in the United States and applies to federal government contracts for products used in the U.S.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">“In addition, we will be 100% built in the heartland of America, and we have proudly achieved another major milestone of having sourced 96% of our parts from U.S. and Allied Nations,” said Aquila.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">By choosing a different manufacturing partner, Canoo hopes to reduce supply chain vulnerabilities, increase speed to market, more securely control the creation of additional innovation and IP, increase advanced manufacturing jobs in local communities and save thousands of dollars per unit by &#8220;eliminating warranty risks, tariffs and overseas shipping costs,&#8221; according to the filing.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">On Wednesday, Canoo also shared upgraded guidance on its refined manufacturing strategy and production roadmap for 2022 to 2025. Next year, Canoo aims to produce 3,000 to 6,000 units, up from 500 to 1,000 units. In 2023, it hopes to produce 14,000 to 17,000, up from 15,000 units. And its 2024 and 2025 targets are 40,000 to 50,000 units and 70,000 to 80,000 units, respectively.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/canoo-ends-partnership-with-vdl-nedcar-to-manufacture-evs-in-europe-partners-with-vdl-groep/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248350</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Crypto custody provider Anchorage Digital valued at $3B after $350M Series D</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/daily-crunch-104/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/daily-crunch-104/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 23:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for December 15, 2021! Big news from TechCrunch this week, namely that our events are returning to your neighborhood next year! For a rundown of what we have currently planned, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/techcrunch-2022-events/">head here</a>. But Disrupt, many Sessions and more are going IRL in 2022. I will see you there! —<a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2247467" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/techcrunch-2022-events/"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2247467" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2247467 size-full" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tc-disrupt-moscone-2-48835355513_4394e0513c_o.jpg" alt="TechCrunch in a crowd at Moscone West in San Francisco" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tc-disrupt-moscone-2-48835355513_4394e0513c_o.jpg 3270w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tc-disrupt-moscone-2-48835355513_4394e0513c_o.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tc-disrupt-moscone-2-48835355513_4394e0513c_o.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tc-disrupt-moscone-2-48835355513_4394e0513c_o.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tc-disrupt-moscone-2-48835355513_4394e0513c_o.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tc-disrupt-moscone-2-48835355513_4394e0513c_o.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tc-disrupt-moscone-2-48835355513_4394e0513c_o.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tc-disrupt-moscone-2-48835355513_4394e0513c_o.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2247467" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nicole Henderson for TechCrunch</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248262" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/katie-haun-is-splitting-off-from-a16z-to-launch-her-own-crypto-fund/">Katie Haun is leaving a16z:</a> </strong>News is out today that Katie Haun is leaving a16z. She’s best known, TechCrunch notes, for co-leading the investing group’s $2.2 billion crypto fund. What’s she off to do? Starting a new crypto fund, of course, and she’s taking along some of her colleagues in the process. As far as crypto investing goes, this is seismic.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/the-era-of-ultra-rich-software-valuations-could-be-behind-us/">Are rich tech valuations set to fall?</a> </strong>As interest rates rise and are set to further scale next year, valuation pressure evident in the back half of 2021 could grow next year. That could mean lower top-tier revenue multiples for tech’s highest fliers and perhaps compressed valuations for slower-growing public tech companies. For startups, the impact could be constrained comps and lower private-market pricing.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/samsara-prices-at-top-of-range-crashes-through-10b-valuation-mark-in-public-debut/">The final tech IPO of the year:</a></strong> Capping off a busy IPO year, Samsara’s IoT-themed public debut went well. The company priced at the top end of its range and traded up around 5% toward the end of its first day as a public company. Samsara is now worth comfortably more than $10 billion after raising hundreds of millions in its public offering.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>TechCrunch covered far more startup news in the last 24 hours than I can include for you in our normal format. So, I’ve written blurbs for some of the most interesting items of the day, and then included links to others, in case you are diving deep this afternoon.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/crypto-company-anchorage-raises-350-million-at-3-billion-valuation/"><strong>This may be the largest party round we’ve seen:</strong></a> Crypto custody concern Anchorage has raised a $350 million round that values it at more than $3 billion. Everyone and their dog took part in the round, including KKR, Andreessen Horowitz, Goldman Sachs, Apollo (hey, it’s the parents!), Blockchain Capital, BlackRock, PayPal Ventures, Lux Capital and others. Why? “Because Anchorage received a federal banking charter, turning it into a digital asset bank,” TechCrunch reports.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/norwest-unveils-a-3-billion-fund-which-is-a-whopping-one-fourth-the-capital-it-has-ever-raised/"><strong>Norwest raises its biggest fund yet:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Speaking of the $3 billion number, that’s also the amount of money that investing group Norwest has raised for its 16th fund. It’s also the largest capital pool that the tenured firm has raised to date. Perhaps we should just call the current venture capital cycle the Super Size Me era.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/hong-kong-hardware-accelerator-brinc-raises-30m-series-b/"><strong>Hong Kong accelerator raises $30M:</strong></a><strong> </strong>While China figures out how to quash democratic voices and sentiment in Hong Kong, the city’s startup scene is not entirely moribund. Evidence of that fact can be found in Brinc’s recent Series B, worth some $30 million. The group is an accelerator that we’re most familiar with for its consumer hardware work, though it has expanded in scope in recent years.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/sqream-acquires-no-code-data-platform-panoply/"><strong>SQream buys Panoply:</strong></a><strong> </strong>SQream is what TechCrunch described as a “well-funded Israel-based data analytics platform.” And it has purchased “no-code data platform Panoply in an effort to expand its cloud services.” Panoply raised $24 million before selling to its new parent company. I would also like 10 points for not using the headline “You SQream, I SQream, we all SQream for startup-to-startup no-code acquisitions.”</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/us-puts-drone-maker-dji-and-seven-other-chinese-companies-on-investment-blocklist/"><strong>Drone maker DJI makes the U.S. block list:</strong></a> Rising economic tensions between the United States and China are hitting more companies this week, with DJI and a half dozen other companies finding themselves on the U.S. naughty list. Why is DJI in trouble? Per TechCrunch, “alleged involvement in surveillance of Uyghur Muslims.” Seems like a pretty solid reason, frankly.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/swimply-raises-40m/"><strong>Pool sharing makes a splash:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Yep, you read that correctly. A startup focused on pool rentals from the consumer supply, well, pool, just raised a bunch of money. The startup is called Swimply. Presumably the name is a hybrid of “swim” and “simply,” even if it sounds like a neat acne nickname.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Money, money, money:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/ai-powered-vfx-startup-wonder-dynamics-raises-10m-a-round/">AI-powered VFX startup Wonder Dynamics raises $10M A round</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/brazils-olist-gets-its-horn-with-new-186m-funding-round/">Brazil’s Olist gets its horn with new $186M funding round</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/proov-raises-9-7m-series-a-for-at-home-ovulation-testing-platform/">Proov raises $9.7M Series A for at-home ovulation testing platform</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/for-course-hero-venture-capital-was-once-an-unobvious-solution/">For Course Hero, venture capital was once an unobvious solution</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/noname-security-unicorn-series-c/">Noname Security hits $1B valuation after $135M Series C raise</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/brazilian-consumer-credit-startup-open-co-raises-115m-in-softbank-led-round/">Brazilian consumer credit startup Open Co raises $115M in SoftBank-led round</a></li>
<li>And there’s even more on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch.com</a>!</li>
</ul>
<h2>Ample’s John de Souza on the merits of B2B, company culture and investors who get it</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2247393" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/amples-john-de-souza-on-the-merits-of-b2b-company-culture-and-investors-who-get-it/"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2247393" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2247393 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/de-souza-ample.jpg" alt="John de Souza, co-founder of Ample, EV battery swapping company" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/de-souza-ample.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/de-souza-ample.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/de-souza-ample.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/de-souza-ample.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/de-souza-ample.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/de-souza-ample.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/de-souza-ample.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/de-souza-ample.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2247393" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin</p></div></p>
<p>Launching a startup is inherently risky, but scaling up a company to succeed where others have failed spectacularly is a very bold move.</p>
<p>San Francisco-based Ample is partnering with companies that manage EV fleets to swap its modular battery packs in and out of their vehicles. &#8220;Fourteen years ago, Better Place raised nearly a billion dollars to do what Ample’s doing, and it ended up declaring bankruptcy,&#8221; reports Rebecca Bellan.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/amples-john-de-souza-on-the-merits-of-b2b-company-culture-and-investors-who-get-it/">In an extended interview with co-founder John de Souza</a>, she asked about the company&#8217;s go-to-market strategy, its culture and why he&#8217;s certain Ample will succeed where others did not.</p>
<p>&#8220;The economics and operations work very well because you don’t need a large number at a single station to break even. With a small fleet, you’d have it at max 20 cars and it will break even. That’s what makes it so attractive. You don’t need to deploy the stations until you have a customer.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/amazon-to-lower-its-cut-of-alexa-skill-developer-revenue-starting-in-2022/"><strong>Amazon lowers Alexa cut:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Developers building “skills” for the Alexa AI and smart-speaker line will see Amazon take a smaller cut of their revenues in the future, with the figure dropping from 30% to 20% “for Alexa skill developers who earn less than $1 million in revenue” for their work. A small change, but a welcome one.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/aurora-self-driving-trucks-are-using-uber-freight-to-haul-goods-for-customers/">Aurora, Uber team up for autonomous freight:</a> </strong>Recall that self-driving startup Aurora once bought Uber’s self-driving assets. The pair is still teaming up, this time with &#8220;Aurora’s self-driving trucks [hauling] goods for Uber Freight customers in Texas.”</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/apple-removes-csam-detection-website/"><strong>Apple backtracks on its CSAM scanning plan:</strong></a><strong> </strong>After running into a wall of concern and complaint, Apple’s controversial plan to scan phones for child-abuse imagery has been removed from its website.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend software consultants who have expertise in UI/UX, website development, mobile development and more! If you’re a software consultant, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl?typeform-source=techcrunch.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/daily-crunch-104/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248262</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTC may consider rule curbing algorithmic discrimination and &#8216;commercial surveillance&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/ftc-may-consider-rule-curbing-algorithmic-discrimination-and-commercial-surveillance/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/ftc-may-consider-rule-curbing-algorithmic-discrimination-and-commercial-surveillance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 22:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lina Khan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248263</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Federal Trade Commission appears to be preparing to consider a rule aimed at digital platforms that either invasively track their users or allow others to do so. The &#8220;Trade Regulation Rule on Commercial Surveillance&#8221; is at a very early stage but could be the first major anti-Big-Tech action by new FTC Chair Lina Khan. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Federal Trade Commission appears to be preparing to consider a rule aimed at digital platforms that either invasively track their users or allow others to do so. The &#8220;Trade Regulation Rule on Commercial Surveillance&#8221; is at a very early stage but could be the first major anti-Big-Tech action by new FTC Chair Lina Khan.</p>
<p>It is currently only described in <a href="https://www.reginfo.gov/public/do/eAgendaViewRule?pubId=202110&amp;RIN=3084-AB69" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this Office of Management and Budget summary</a>, after the FTC submitted information to that agency on potential upcoming regulatory actions. According to the listing, the rule would &#8220;curb lax security practices, limit privacy abuses, and ensure that algorithmic decision-making does not result in unlawful discrimination.&#8221; There is no public draft of the rule and no indication of whether the rule-making is more than notional at this point.</p>
<p>An FTC spokesperson offered the following statement, but declined to comment further: &#8220;The FTC is prepared to use all of our tools to combat harmful commercial surveillance practices and protect Americans&#8217; privacy.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248263" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Senator Brian Schatz called attention to the filing, lauding the agency (perhaps a bit prematurely) for taking this on: &#8220;I’m glad to see Chair Khan and the agency take this step to crack down on companies using discriminatory algorithms. It’s crucial that we address this,&#8221; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>The rule-making would use the FTC&#8217;s Section 18 authority to regulate &#8220;Unfair or deceptive acts or practices,&#8221; which is an established source of authority for establishing a variety of requirements and prohibitions.</p>
<p>This rule could potentially be along the lines of the proposed (and discarded) Broadband Privacy Act, among other attempts to shield consumers from the hidden depredations of everything from social media companies to internet providers.</p>
<p>Of course the FTC cannot simply invent rules out of thin air — they do establish rules, but it&#8217;s often when a new or changing industry has managed to circumvent rules that already exist for good reason.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For instance, if a yogurt label says it&#8217;s fat-free and testing shows it has fat, that&#8217;s obviously false advertising. But if a social media company says (as they often do) that you &#8220;own your data&#8221; or some such, but you can&#8217;t download it, prevent them from selling it or completely delete it from their platform, is <em>that</em> false advertising? It might not be until the FTC updates its rules and guidance to include the practice.</p>
<p>&#8220;Unlawful discrimination&#8221; might also occur when an algorithm fed with badly configured data ends up favoring or disfavoring a group of people based on a protected status like religion, race or medical status. At present there is little in the way of formal requirements for vetting algorithms, as they and their sources are often trade secrets or otherwise shielded from public view and inquiry. An FTC rule could help make this a requirement rather than a voluntary action.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pUYjnqGfH2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/lina-khan-ftc-confirmed/">Biden elevates tech antitrust crusader Lina Khan to FTC chair</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Biden elevates tech antitrust crusader Lina Khan to FTC chair&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/lina-khan-ftc-confirmed/embed/#?secret=pUYjnqGfH2" data-secret="pUYjnqGfH2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Sometimes these efforts are backed up by legislation or executive action, and Khan certainly has something of a mandate from the White House to rein in Big Tech (her rapid ascendance from legal adviser to top of the heap is a strong endorsement of actions like this potential rule).</p>
<p>To be clear, at this point this is more or less a twinkle in the FTC&#8217;s eye, but the filing with the OMB does establish it as a likely priority in 2022 — an election year when the current administration would like to appear effective. Taking on Big Tech is one of very few bipartisan efforts extant so work on these lines could be a plank in a few political platforms.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/ftc-may-consider-rule-curbing-algorithmic-discrimination-and-commercial-surveillance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248263</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok is testing a desktop streaming software called TikTok Live Studio</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/tiktok-is-testing-a-desktop-streaming-software-called-tiktok-live-studio/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/tiktok-is-testing-a-desktop-streaming-software-called-tiktok-live-studio/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 21:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Livestreaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streamlabs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What if instead of watching your favorite TikTok star stream on Twitch, you could watch them play video games live on TikTok? For the last few days, according to the platform, TikTok has been testing a Windows program called TikTok Live Studio. Once downloaded to your desktop, the program allows users to log in with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">What if instead of watching your favorite TikTok star stream on Twitch, you could watch them play video games live on TikTok? For the last few days, according to the platform, TikTok has been testing a Windows program called <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/studio/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TikTok Live Studio</a>.</p>
<p>Once downloaded to your desktop, the program allows users to log in with their TikTok account and stream directly to TikTok Live. Within the program, you can communicate with viewers through the chat feature, and you can stream content from your computer, your phone or a gaming console. TikTok told TechCrunch that this program is currently available only in a handful of Western markets for a few thousand users.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">It&#39;s super basic in its current state. </p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248245" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Has both Landscape and Portrait Scenes.</p>
<p>Sources include Game Capture, Mobile Capture, Video Capture, Program Capture, and some text/images. No browser sources, or alerts.</p>
<p>Emojis are limited to the stock ones. <a href="https://t.co/oOHwUbSdUF">pic.twitter.com/oOHwUbSdUF</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Zach Bussey (@zachbussey) <a href="https://twitter.com/zachbussey/status/1471172519226916865?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 15, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>An obvious benefit for TikTok in testing this feature is that creators might be motivated to stay within their app, instead of asking their audience to watch them stream on Twitch or YouTube Gaming. From the look of TikTok&#8217;s promotional images, it seems that the company is catering toward people looking to stream video games. But in its nascent form, TikTok Live Studio lacks the features that seasoned streamers can find on broadcast software like OBS or Streamlabs &#8212; which makes sense, as the product is still in testing. For example, even though you can hook up a video game console to TikTok Live Studio, you can&#8217;t use browser windows as a source, and you can&#8217;t set up in-stream alerts for tips or new follows.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2248267" style="width: 2890px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2248267" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2248267 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/310ca031b66cac4cc9cf.png" alt="" width="2880" height="942" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/310ca031b66cac4cc9cf.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/310ca031b66cac4cc9cf.png?resize=150,49 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/310ca031b66cac4cc9cf.png?resize=300,98 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/310ca031b66cac4cc9cf.png?resize=768,251 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/310ca031b66cac4cc9cf.png?resize=680,222 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/310ca031b66cac4cc9cf.png?resize=1536,502 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/310ca031b66cac4cc9cf.png?resize=2048,670 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/310ca031b66cac4cc9cf.png?resize=50,16 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2880px) 100vw, 2880px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2248267" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/studio/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TikTok Live Studio </a><span class="screen-reader-text"><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/studio/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener">(opens in a new window)</a></span></p></div></p>
<p>But a goal of this feature test is to see how creators use the software. TikTok Live Studio isn&#8217;t guaranteed to roll out, the company told TechCrunch &#8212; whenever TikTok tests a feature, that doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s here to stay forever. But if we do see a true launch of TikTok Live Studio, the platform will study what creators are using the software for, then tailor it to better suit those use cases.</p>
<p>Already, creators are using TikTok&#8217;s livestreaming tools to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tiktok-expands-live-platform-with-new-features-for-creators-and-fans/">monetize</a> and expand their followings. Creators can accept <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/creators/creator-portal/en-us/getting-paid-to-create/live-gifting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tips</a>, schedule events, use live Q&amp;A tools, go live with other users, filter certain keywords and assign moderators. Right now, TikTok Live Studio allows users to choose whether they want to enable gifting and comments, and they can set up keyword filters. But other existing livestreaming features like assigning moderators and scheduling streams could potentially be incorporated into a future, more robust product.</p>
<p>This streaming software could also mark an opportunity for TikTok to reach more desktop users. For creators, a desktop streaming software is essential, since a smartphone simply isn&#8217;t built to connect to your gaming console and stream at the same time. Though people do watch video game streams on their phones, the user experience is generally better on desktop, which could help users create the habit of using TikTok on their computer.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NH22BY0AHj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tiktok-expands-live-platform-with-new-features-for-creators-and-fans/">TikTok expands LIVE platform with new features, including events, co-hosts, Q&#038;As and more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok expands LIVE platform with new features, including events, co-hosts, Q&#038;As and more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tiktok-expands-live-platform-with-new-features-for-creators-and-fans/embed/#?secret=NH22BY0AHj" data-secret="NH22BY0AHj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/tiktok-is-testing-a-desktop-streaming-software-called-tiktok-live-studio/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248245</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voly raises $13M led by Sequoia to deliver instant groceries in Australia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/voly-raises-13m-led-by-sequoia-to-deliver-instant-groceries-in-australia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/voly-raises-13m-led-by-sequoia-to-deliver-instant-groceries-in-australia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 21:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CloudKitchens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global founders capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goPuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sydney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The trend that is instant grocery delivery &#8212; online ordering of essentials with your purchases being delivered to you in under an hour &#8212; continues to proliferate across multiple markets, and in the latest development, Sequoia is leading an investment in one out of Australia. Voly, a five-month-old Sydney-based startup that offers thousands of SKUs [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The trend that is instant grocery delivery &#8212; online ordering of essentials with your purchases being delivered to you in under an hour &#8212; continues to proliferate across multiple markets, and in the latest development, Sequoia is leading an investment in one out of Australia.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.getvoly." target="_blank" rel="noopener">Voly</a>, a five-month-old Sydney-based startup that offers thousands of SKUs and promises deliveries in 15 minutes at a flat fee of A$2.99 ($2.14), has raised A$18 million (just under $13 million at today&#8217;s rates) in a seed round of funding that it will be using to expand its business to cities and towns across the country.</p>
<p>In addition to Sequoia, by way of Sequoia Capital India, other investors in the round include Global Founders Capital (GFC) and Artesian Capital, an Australian firm; the latter two also previously backed Voly in a $1 million pre-seed round.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248211" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>At a time when the instant grocery market is very crowded in certain regions like Europe &#8212; where a number of local startups are coexisting and competing with some very heavily capitalised players with international ambitions like Gopuff, Gorillas, Flink and Getir &#8212; Voly has picked a ripe moment to ramp up in Australia.</p>
<p>The market for groceries in the country is estimated to be worth some A$90 billion ($64.6 billion) annually, but while there are some services for delivering so-called &#8220;big basket&#8221; purchases that are typically made weekly, the field appears to be pretty open for those offering deliveries in under an hour.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;Instant delivery is still very revolutionary here,&#8221; Mark Heath, the co-CEO and co-founder, said in an interview earlier.</p>
<p>&#8220;We were the country that got left behind by the other delivery startups,&#8221; joked Thibault Henry, the other founder and CEO. &#8220;We are a breath of fresh air.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It currently offers some 2,000 SKUs and the plan is to grow that to 3,000, with groceries and essentials also complemented by modular shopping that mimics the concept of meal kits: A customer can select recipes based on preparation time, and then buy the ingredients needed to make them.</p>
<p>Heath said this has helped the company market itself not just to the younger, urban-dwelling millennials that typical are the early adopters of instant grocery services; but also working parents &#8220;who still want to cook tasty food for their families.&#8221; Henry believes the typical Voly user will use its service several times a week.</p>
<p>That lack of competition could be one reason investors have been bullish on Voly; the other might be the track record of the founders.</p>
<p>Heath helped launch Uber in Australia heading up operations and logistics, and then he worked as the country manager for CloudKitchens. Henry, meanwhile founded and ran a last-mile refrigerated delivery startup, Balto Logistics, which racked up a long list of on-demand food delivery brands as customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Australia&#8217;s grocery market, which sees $90 billion in annual spends, is a large and profitable space that continues to be dominated by offline retail,&#8221; said Abheek Anand, MD, Sequoia India, in a statement. &#8220;The Sequoia Capital India team was impressed by the strong consumer love for VOLY, their compelling value proposition, and an impressive team of repeat founders that has blitzscaled businesses in Australia before. With on-demand models traditionally scaling very successfully in the country, the decision to lead their seed round and help them scale their business across Australia was an easy one to make.&#8221;</p>
<p>While Voly may be a very new and likely very small outfit &#8212; it&#8217;s not disclosing customer numbers but says that right now its growing at a rate of 100% each month &#8212; it&#8217;s indeed the collective experience and network that the two have that&#8217;s helping them build their platform and establish supply chains that don&#8217;t completely kill Voly on margins while still aiming to sell goods at retail, rather than marked-up, prices.</p>
<p class="p1">Another point of distinction in how Voly is growing is that it&#8217;s choosing to make its drivers full-time employees rather than contractors. &#8220;That&#8217;s our choice,&#8221; Heath said. &#8220;Uber and DoorDash are gig economy companies. We&#8217;ve chosen a different model.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/voly-raises-13m-led-by-sequoia-to-deliver-instant-groceries-in-australia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248211</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UBQ Materials&#8217; plastic replacement product attracts $170M from impact investor TPG Rise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/ubq-materials-plastic-replacement-product-attracts-170m-from-impact-investor-tpg-rise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/ubq-materials-plastic-replacement-product-attracts-170m-from-impact-investor-tpg-rise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 21:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plastic recycling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recycling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UBQ Materials, which claims it has developed a plastic-like material made from 100% unsorted household waste, has raised a $170 million funding round led by TPG Rise, TPG’s global impact investing platform, made through TPG Rise Climate, the firm’s dedicated climate investing fund, and The Rise Funds, its multisector impact investing fund. The financing round [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.ubqmaterials.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UBQ Materials</a>, which claims it has developed a plastic-like material made from 100% unsorted household waste, has raised a $170 million funding round led by TPG Rise, TPG’s global impact investing platform, made through TPG Rise Climate, the firm’s dedicated climate investing fund, and The Rise Funds, its multisector impact investing fund.</p>
<p>The financing round also included participation from existing investor, Battery Ventures, and others including M&amp;G’s Catalyst strategy, a U.K.-based investor.</p>
<p>UBQ Materials says it can turn landfill-destined municipal solid waste, including all organics, into recyclable plastic substitute. Its “UBQ” product can then be used both on its own and in conjunction with conventional oil-based resins in construction, automotive, logistics, retail and even 3D printing, it says.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248295" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Steve Ellis, co-managing partner of The Rise Funds said:</p>
<blockquote><p>In addition to converting municipal waste into functional thermal plastics, UBQ’s material solution is energy efficient, uses no water and produces no effluents UBQ can be utilized in a broad array of industrial and consumer applications.</p></blockquote>
<p>The company is vague on how it achieves all this but we will be following its claims with interest.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/ubq-materials-plastic-replacement-product-attracts-170m-from-impact-investor-tpg-rise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248295</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sound.xyz raises $5M from a16z to explore how web3 can upend the economics of the music business</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/sound-xyz-raises-5m-from-a16z-to-explore-how-web3-can-upend-the-economics-of-the-music-business/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/sound-xyz-raises-5m-from-a16z-to-explore-how-web3-can-upend-the-economics-of-the-music-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 21:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music industry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This year, we&#8217;ve seen plenty of evidence that NFTs can shake up the economics of selling visual art, but there&#8217;s been less activity when it comes to web3 upending the economics of different verticals in the art world, including music. Sound.xyz is a new startup looking to help recording artists monetize their community through NFTs, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This year, we&#8217;ve seen plenty of evidence that NFTs can shake up the economics of selling visual art, but there&#8217;s been less activity when it comes to web3 upending the economics of different verticals in the art world, including music.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sound.xyz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sound.xyz</a> is a new startup looking to help recording artists monetize their community through NFTs, as the startup looks to build out a suite of tools designed to bring musicians into the so-called &#8220;web3&#8221; fold. The startup released is first product earlier this month, Listening Parties, which enable artists to sell NFTs tagged to the release of new songs.</p>
<p>The startup tells TechCrunch it has raised $5 million in a seed raise led by Andreessen Horowitz. Other investors in the round include Variant Fund, Weekend Fund, Scalar Capital, Flamingo, Packy McCormick and 21 Savage, among others.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248140" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The startup is looking to push emerging artists to monetize their work more effectively by leveraging NFTs and help them rise above earning minute fractions of pennies per stream on platforms like Spotify.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re building a suite of economic tools to help artists monetize their songs in new ways,&#8221; Sound CEO David Greenstein tells TechCrunch. &#8220;The problems that we want to solve are: Can we get music heard and can we get artists paid?&#8221;</p>
<p>The startup has partnered with a number of &#8220;crypto-friendly&#8221; recording artists that have been engaging with the community. The early drops have been limited to a couple dozen limited-edition NFTs that have sold out instantly.  While selling $10,000 worth of NFTs may not sound too noteworthy in an industry friendly to million-dollar sales, Greenstein says the proceeds make a big difference to artists who might need hundreds of thousands of streams to earn that same amount on Spotify. As the startup gauges demand for NFT drops tied to song drops for certain artists, they have ambition to release more NFTs to the community. The startup notably does not take a commission on the sales and the NFTs.</p>
<p>The team has been experimenting with other features for the drops like enabling NFT holders to leave comments on the streams for artists to read. Down the road, the startup wants to create broader tools that allow musicians to crowdfund from fans to create new works and tackle new projects while also creating new incentive models for curators to discover and showcase new music.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sound is not the only player in the NFT music space. Last month, a16z Crypto backed <a href="https://royal.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Royal</a>, an NFT music platform looking to tokenize royalties and sell them to fans. <a href="https://audius.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Audius</a>, a music-streaming platform on the blockchain, has raised over $13.5 million in funding from firms including General Catalyst and Coinbase Ventures.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="T4xzj9Dul5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/nft-music-rights-startup-royal-banks-55m-investment-from-a16z-crypto/">NFT music rights startup Royal banks $55M investment led by a16z Crypto</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NFT music rights startup Royal banks $55M investment led by a16z Crypto&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/nft-music-rights-startup-royal-banks-55m-investment-from-a16z-crypto/embed/#?secret=T4xzj9Dul5" data-secret="T4xzj9Dul5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/sound-xyz-raises-5m-from-a16z-to-explore-how-web3-can-upend-the-economics-of-the-music-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248140</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global climate tech investment triples, but cash for tech directly cutting emissions lags</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/global-climatetech-investment-triples-but-cash-for-tech-directly-cutting-emissions-lags/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/global-climatetech-investment-triples-but-cash-for-tech-directly-cutting-emissions-lags/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 21:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon dioxide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pricewaterhousecoopers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investment from VC and PE into climate tech is booming, reaching $87.5 bilion over H2 2020 and H1 2021, with in excess of $60 billion in the first half of 2021 alone, according to a new report from PWC. This is a 210% increase from the $28.4 billion invested in the 12 months prior; some [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Investment from VC and PE into climate tech is booming, reaching $87.5 bilion over H2 2020 and H1 2021, with in excess of $60 billion in the first half of 2021 alone, according to <a href="https://www.pwc.com/climatetech" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a new report from PWC</a>.</p>
<p>This is a 210% increase from the $28.4 billion invested in the 12 months prior; some 14 cents of every dollar of VC now going to climate tech.</p>
<p>However, not all is rosy. The investment is mostly focused on technology solutions accounting for 20% of emissions reduction potential. So PWC says there is an opportunity to shift the focus to areas and technologies with a more direct impact on emissions.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248277" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Despite this overall growth, the number of early VC, seed and Series A investments in climate tech has remained largely stagnant since 2018.</p>
<p>Of 15 solutions analyzed, the top five, representing more than 80% of emissions reduction potential by 2050, received just 25% of the climate tech investment between 2013 and H1 2021.</p>
<p>In other words, VC needs to put more into directly affecting emissions not just SaaS platforms, etc., which track them.</p>
<p>Emma Cox, global climate leader, PwC U.K., said:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>The world has 10 years to halve global greenhouse emissions if we are to have hope of achieving net-zero by 2050 …  However, our research has found there is potential to better channel and incentivize investment in technology areas that have the greatest future emissions reduction potential. This raises the question of why these sectors are missing out — are investors missing a valuable opportunity or is there an incentive problem that needs the attention of policymakers?</p></blockquote>
<p>Climate tech encompasses technologies focused on reducing greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Climate tech investment plateaued in 2018-2020 but has rebounded in the first half of 2021 — driven by a refreshed focus on ESG in private markets, emerging regulations and standards, and more companies committing to net-zero strategies.</p>
<p>Here are some extracts from PWC’s report:</p>
<blockquote><p>• The average climate tech deal size nearly quadrupled in H1 2021 to US$96M, from US$27M one year prior.<br />
• About 1,600 investors were active in H1 2021, compared to fewer than 900 active investors in H1 2020 as the wider investment community becomes familiar with the opportunities in climate tech as an asset class.<br />
• SPACs (special purpose acquisition companies) were tested to further stimulate climate tech’s growth and raised US$25bn in H1 2021, accounting for more than a third of all funding.<br />
• Mobility and Transport continues to receive the lion’s share of climate tech funding as electric vehicles (EVs), micro-mobility and other innovative transit models attract investor attention.  This challenge area raised nearlyUS$58bn between H2 2020 and H1 2021, representing two-thirds of total climate tech funding raised in the period.<br />
• Mobility and Transport, Industry, Manufacturing and Resource management (IM&amp;R) and Financial Services saw the fastest growth year over year between H2 2019 &#8211; H1 2021, each more than 260%, reaching US$58bn, US$6.9bn and US$1.2bn respectively.<br />
• The top five technologies representing over 80% of future emissions reduction potential include: Solar Power, Wind Power, Food Waste Technology, Green Hydrogen Production, and Alternative Foods/Low GHG Proteins.</p></blockquote>
<p>PWC said the United States leads in climate tech investing, attracting nearly 65% of VC investment, $56.6 billion from H2 2020 to H1 2021. China is estimated to have seen $9 billion in climate tech investment in the same period, while Europe totaled $18.3 billionn, driven by a nearly 500% (494%) increase in Mobility and Transport in H2 2020 and H1 2021, compared to the prior 12 month period.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/global-climatetech-investment-triples-but-cash-for-tech-directly-cutting-emissions-lags/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248277</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
