<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:53:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Microsoft announces new tools to modernize supply chain and manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-announces-new-tools-to-modernize-supply-chain-and-manufacturing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-announces-new-tools-to-modernize-supply-chain-and-manufacturing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital transformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dynamics 365]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic has wreaked havoc on the world&#8217;s supply chains for a number of reasons from a lack of raw material to labor shortages, but whatever the reason the problems are persisting and Microsoft has decided to put its considerable resources to bear on modernizing supply chain and manufacturing To help address these issues, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The pandemic has wreaked havoc on the world&#8217;s supply chains for a number of reasons from a lack of raw material to labor shortages, but whatever the reason the problems are persisting and Microsoft has decided to put its considerable resources to bear on modernizing supply chain and manufacturing</p>
<p>To help address these issues, the company is announcing a new manufacturing solution called the Microsoft Cloud for Manufacturing along with Dynamics 365 Supply Chain Insights, a tool designed to give customers more visibility into what&#8217;s happening along their supply chain routes and intelligence to deal with issues as they arise. Both products are being announced at Microsoft Ignite and are available in preview starting today.</p>
<p>Caglayan Arkan, VP of manufacturing and supply chain at Microsoft, says the company has been thinking about ways to help companies solve these issues, and at the same time evolve into more digitally-focused companies, something that has been a challenge for manufacturers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227657" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Arkan says that Microsoft examined the state of things and saw brittle systems that when faced with the pressure of the pandemic didn&#8217;t hold up well. &#8220;Manufacturing and the supply chain has been very stable; very, very lean, perhaps too lean. They grew very comfortable in their very long cycles and manual siloed data state,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He added that manufacturers have been working this way for years and they had no real reason to change until the pandemic came along. &#8220;Everything stopped. The music stopped, and you couldn&#8217;t send employees to the shop floor anymore, supplies were not there. You couldn&#8217;t even see your supplier to know where your goods were, and that was a huge disruption,&#8221; Arkan explained.</p>
<p>The manufacturing cloud is designed to help digitize the factory floor, and provide a path to become fully digital by moving from  traditional systems of record to what Arkan calls &#8220;systems of reality.&#8221;</p>
<p>That means that manufacturers need to be able to link what&#8217;s happening in the marketplace in terms of demand, what&#8217;s happening on their shop floor in terms of production and what&#8217;s happening in the world in terms of supplies to get a big picture view, so they won&#8217;t get caught flat-footed as they did when demand for toilet paper and PPE ballooned early in the pandemic.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The manufacturing cloud is designed to help collect these signals and warn manufacturers when they might need additional supplies. The Supply Chain Insights tool is specifically designed to map out supply chain routes and root out issues that could affect delivery of key raw materials before bottlenecks happen. Together they are designed to bring more agility and flexibility to manufacturing companies.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227667" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227667" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2227667" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-02-at-9.34.27-AM-1.jpg?w=680" alt="Microsoft Dynamics 365 Supply Chain Insights tool" width="680" height="680" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227667" class="wp-caption-text">Microsoft Dynamics 365 Supply Chain Insights tool. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Microsoft</p></div></p>
<p>Unlike in the past, Microsoft recognizes that these kinds of companies, which have been traditionally modernized very slowly, don&#8217;t want to rip and replace existing systems and take on a huge project. As Arkan says, you need to start with one successful project and then move to the next one, and he says this solution is designed to be delivered in this way.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, he says that each project can build on one another and fund the next one through savings and innovation. &#8220;Every step of your digital transformation, every engagement with us creates economic headroom to add funds to the next one because we either give you more top-line revenue, capacity or provide savings or quality improvements in a matter of 8-12 weeks,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a bold promise, but if Microsoft can deliver on that &#8212; and that&#8217;s a big if &#8212; it creates a comfortable path to modernization for companies that have traditionally rejected big kinds of changes like this.</p>
<p>If Microsoft and other large enterprise companies like SAP and Salesforce can begin to solve some of these fundamental problems, it could begin to loosen the supply chain issues we are seeing today. While software alone can&#8217;t magically produce scarce raw materials or hire enough people to build and deliver supplies and goods, it can be part of a solution to help mitigate these kinds of crises in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-announces-new-tools-to-modernize-supply-chain-and-manufacturing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227657</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft launches Google Wave</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-launches-google-wave/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-launches-google-wave/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content management systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Wave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft-Office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft is bringing back Google Wave, the doomed real-time messaging and collaboration platform Google launched in 2009 and prematurely shuttered in 2010. Maybe we should&#8217;ve seen this coming. Back in 2019, Microsoft announced the Fluid Framework (not to be confused with the Fluent design system). The idea here was nothing short of trying to re-invent [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Microsoft is bringing back <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2010/08/04/wave-goodbye-to-google-wave/">Google Wave</a>, the doomed real-time messaging and collaboration platform Google launched in 2009 and prematurely <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2010/08/04/wave-goodbye-to-google-wave/">shuttered</a> in 2010.</p>
<p>Maybe we should&#8217;ve seen this coming. Back in 2019, Microsoft <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/04/microsoft-launches-the-first-public-preview-of-its-fluid-framework-for-collaborative-editing/">announced</a> the Fluid Framework (not to be confused with the Fluent design system). The idea here was nothing short of trying to re-invent the nature of business documents and how developers build real-time applications. Last year, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/microsofts-fluid-framework-is-now-open-source-comes-to-office-365/">open-sourced Fluid</a> and started building it into a few of its own Office applications. Today, at its Ignite conference, it&#8217;s launching a whole new product built on top of Fluid: Microsoft <del>Wave</del> Loop.</p>
<p>Loop is a new app &#8212; and concept &#8212; that takes the Fluid framework, which provides developers with flexible components to mix and match in order to create real-time editing-based applications, to create a new experience for users to collaborate on documents. In many ways, that was also the promise of Google Wave &#8212; real-time collaboration plus a developer framework and protocol to bring Wave everywhere.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226604" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2226605" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Loop_People-moving-in-and-out-of-pages.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226605" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2226605" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Loop_People-moving-in-and-out-of-pages.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="576" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2226605" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Microsoft</p></div></p>
<p>Now, you may say: isn&#8217;t that what Teams is for? Why isn&#8217;t this built into Teams. And yes, all of that is in the works, but there will also be a Loop app, which Microsoft says &#8220;combines a powerful and flexible canvas with portable components that move freely and stay in sync across apps – enabling teams to think, plan and create together.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226802" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Loop_Thoughts-and-high-five.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226802" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2226802" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Loop_Thoughts-and-high-five.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="576" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2226802" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Microsoft</p></div></p>
<p>There are three elements to Loop: Loop components, &#8220;atomic units of productivity&#8221; (tip of my hat to whoever came up with that phrase) like lists, tables, notes and tasks; Loop pages, &#8220;flexible canvases where you can organize your components and pull in other useful elements like files, links, or data to help teams think, connect, and collaborate;&#8221; and Loop workspaces, shared spaces where you somehow can catch up on what everybody is working on and track progress toward shared goals.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>One thing Wave never had that is apparently a core feature of Loop is that Loop tracks your cursor position in real time. That&#8217;s the current state of the metaverse for you right there. Nothing says I&#8217;m present and active in a meeting like moving your cursor around, after all.</p>
<p>Some new Loop/Fluent components coming soon are a voting table (a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2009/05/28/google-wave-drips-with-ambition-can-it-fulfill-googles-grand-web-vision/">day-one feature of Google Wave</a>, I might add) and a status tracker.</p>
<p>Google Wave was clearly ahead of its time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-launches-google-wave/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226604</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft launches Azure Container Apps, a new serverless container service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-launches-azure-container-apps-a-new-serverless-container-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-launches-azure-container-apps-a-new-serverless-container-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[http]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microservices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft-azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serverless computing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its Ignite conference, Microsoft today announced the preview launch of Azure Container Apps, a new fully managed serverless container service that complements the company&#8217;s existing container infrastructure services like the Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS). Microsoft notes that Azure Container Apps was specifically built for microservices, with the ability to quickly scale based on HTTP [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its Ignite conference, Microsoft today announced the preview launch of Azure Container Apps, a new fully managed serverless container service that complements the company&#8217;s existing <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/product-categories/containers/">container infrastructure services</a> like the Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS). Microsoft notes that Azure Container Apps was specifically built for microservices, with the ability to quickly scale based on HTTP traffic, events or long-running background jobs.</p>
<p>In many ways, it&#8217;s probably most like <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/apprunner/?c=cn&amp;sec=srv">AWS App Runner</a>, one of Amazon&#8217;s small fleet of serverless container services, with App Runner also specifically focused on microservices. Google meanwhile also offers a set of container-centric services, including <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/serverless/cloud-run-bringing-serverless-to-containers">Cloud Run</a>, its serverless platform for running container-based applications.</p>
<p>Microsoft says that with Azure Container Apps, developers will be able to build their apps in the language and with the framework of their choosing and then deploy it with the help of this new service. The infrastructure itself sits on top of open-source projects like Microsoft&#8217;s own <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/microsofts-dapr-open-source-project-hits-1-0/">Dapr application runtime</a> and its scaling technology is powered by <a href="https://keda.sh/">Kubernetes Event-Driven Autoscaling</a> (KEDA), a project that is supported by Microsoft, Red Hat and Codit, as well as Vexxhost and Snyk.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226807" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;I think about the Azure Container Apps experience as more like a PasS-like experience to AKS, which is your IaaS,&#8221; <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Roanne Sones, Microsoft&#8217;s corporate VP for Azure Edge and Platform, explained. &#8220;I</span>n a world where customers start with IaaS and, eventually, if they could just have gone straight to PaaS, they probably would have. Because why not? All I have to do is think about my app and or consume the app &#8212; and it&#8217;s done for me. That&#8217;s how I think about that laddering. If AKS is the underlying infrastructure service that you give to customers for running a CNCF-compliant Kubernetes service, then Azure Container Apps sits above that and it abstracts away more of the infrastructure so you don&#8217;t have to get into the guts of that level of design and lifecycle management.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s maybe no surprise that all of the major cloud providers now offer serverless container services of various kinds, both for sophisticated ops teams that need to have full control of their deployments and for companies that want others to handle all of this for them. And despite a plethora of tools to make this easier, managing Kubernetes clusters remains a full-time job for infrastructure teams, after all. The promise of containers has always been the ability to easily scale services up and down as needed and to free developers from having to think about the infrastructure that their code will run on. For a lot of teams that simply want to get their services into production, serverless is the way to go.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-launches-azure-container-apps-a-new-serverless-container-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226807</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visual workspace Whimsical closes first funding as it enters next phase of growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/visual-workspace-whimsical-closes-first-funding-as-it-enters-next-phase-of-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/visual-workspace-whimsical-closes-first-funding-as-it-enters-next-phase-of-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Basis Set Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collaboration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daniel Levine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaspars dancis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whimsical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workplace collaboration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workplace productivity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227244</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whimsical aims to make work collaborative, distributed and quick, enabling teams to create and share without having to open another tab or website.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://whimsical.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Whimsical</a>, a startup creating tools for workplace collaboration, announced Tuesday its first funding round, a $30 million Series A investment led by Accel.</p>
<p>The company was founded by Kaspars Dancis in 2017 when he saw that the tools most people use for work &#8212; the documents, spreadsheets and slide decks &#8212; were not conducive to the way people were working, for example, increasingly remote.</p>
<p>The idea for the company originated over 20 years ago when Dancis, who is from Latvia, started his professional career and was working in California, but corresponding with peers around the world.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227244" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“I always worked in some form of distributed organization with a larger engineering theme of people everywhere trying to make it work,” he told TechCrunch. “I felt some of the technology was evolving and getting better, but there were still parts of work that if you tried to be distributed, it felt like not being in the same room was a disadvantage.”</p>
<p>The company’s goal is to make distributed work better than being in the same room by focusing on content and collaboration, something Dancis said existing tools have, but are still siloed in a way that you would have to drop something in another tool in order to share it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WEewsvynF5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/13/more-companies-should-shift-to-a-work-from-home-model/">More companies should shift to a work-from-home model</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;More companies should shift to a work-from-home model&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/13/more-companies-should-shift-to-a-work-from-home-model/embed/#?secret=WEewsvynF5" data-secret="WEewsvynF5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As its name suggests, Whimsical aims to make work collaborative, distributed and quick, enabling teams to create and share flowcharts, wireframes, mind maps, sticky notes and documents without having to open another tab or website.</p>
<p>The funding follows four years of bootstrapped growth and profitability, Dancis said. This includes three times revenue growth in the past 12 months and acquiring a couple million total users at companies like Intercom, Netflix and Twilio.</p>
<p>Whimsical built itself in an organic way during that time and got early traction, which enabled it to continue building products. The company remained a small team for years, only growing from 12 to 30 in the past few months, Dancis said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227250" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227250" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2227250" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/whimsical-screenshot@2x.png" alt="Whimsical" width="1024" height="813" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/whimsical-screenshot@2x.png 3236w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/whimsical-screenshot@2x.png?resize=150,119 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/whimsical-screenshot@2x.png?resize=300,238 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/whimsical-screenshot@2x.png?resize=768,610 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/whimsical-screenshot@2x.png?resize=680,540 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/whimsical-screenshot@2x.png?resize=1536,1220 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/whimsical-screenshot@2x.png?resize=2048,1627 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/whimsical-screenshot@2x.png?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227250" class="wp-caption-text">Whimsical dashboard. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Whimsical</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Then in 2021, he felt the company “reach a milestone inflection point where being bootstrapped was working, but was slowing it down.” In order to get to the next level, he needed partners to be able to invest more in the product and its go-to-market strategy. This is as the <a href="https://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/productivity-management-software-market" target="_blank" rel="noopener">global productivity management software market</a> was valued at $42.6 billion in 2020 and is <a href="https://www.grandviewresearch.com/press-release/global-productivity-management-software-market" target="_blank" rel="noopener">poised to nearly triple by 2028</a>, according to Grandview Research.</p>
<p>“We are achieving the vision of an integrated experience and still have some building blocks to create,” Dancis added. “We have this content that can be broadly described as a whiteboard and early this year introduced Docs, but there are some we want to add and also focused on creating a spreadsheet experience, but we want to do it in a way that it will be integrated with everything else we’ve created.”</p>
<p>He felt Accel was that partner, along with Basis Set Ventures and angel investments from dozens of company executives, including those from Dropbox, Stripe, GitHub and Google, that joined in on the funding round.</p>
<p>Accel partner Daniel Levine said he first began hearing about Whimsical a few years ago and officially met the team in 2020. He took it as a sign that sophisticated companies were already customers and the people who used the tools were passionate about doing so.</p>
<p>While many tools like Figma and Slack were built with communication and collaboration in mind, Levine said when teams went fully remote, they had to be adapted as people tried to do remote better.</p>
<p>One of the challenges that emerged was that people wanted more particular tools that were tailored toward collaborative work, which he said Whimiscal solved.</p>
<p>“When I met Kaspars, I thought he was really thoughtful and sharp,” he said. “Whimsical feels like it has a simple vibe, but when you go deeper around these tools, you see they are built for the 80% of people that want to do things super quick. Whimsical was tailor-made for a particular case and we will see more dedicated tools like that in the future, but the company is ahead on this.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YBxIBgjHZO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/how-2-companies-leveraged-organic-and-inorganic-growth/">How 2 companies leveraged organic and inorganic growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How 2 companies leveraged organic and inorganic growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/how-2-companies-leveraged-organic-and-inorganic-growth/embed/#?secret=YBxIBgjHZO" data-secret="YBxIBgjHZO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/visual-workspace-whimsical-closes-first-funding-as-it-enters-next-phase-of-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227244</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Teams gets 3D animated avatars, because metaverse</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-teams-gets-3d-animated-avatars-because-metaverse/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-teams-gets-3d-animated-avatars-because-metaverse/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accenture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avatar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft HoloLens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixed reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online meetings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft wants a piece of the metaverse, too, so at its Ignite conference today, the company announced 3D avatars for those Teams meetings where you don&#8217;t want to be on camera. Those animated personalized avatars are part of what Microsoft calls &#8216;Mesh for Teams,&#8217; which combines the company&#8217;s Mesh platform (not to be confused with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Microsoft wants a piece of the metaverse, too, so at its Ignite conference today, the company announced 3D avatars for those Teams meetings where you don&#8217;t want to be on camera. Those animated personalized avatars are part of what Microsoft calls &#8216;Mesh for Teams,&#8217; which combines the company&#8217;s <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/mesh?activetab=pivot%3aprimaryr7">Mesh platform</a> (not to be confused with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Live_Mesh">Windows Live Mesh</a>) for powering shared experiences in virtual reality, augmented reality and elsewhere, with Teams and its built-in productivity tools. It&#8217;s still the same meetings that should&#8217;ve been an email, but different.</p>
<p>To access Mesh for Teams, you will be able use anything from a smartphone to a VR headset or a HoloLens. Microsoft is quite open about the fact that this is its metaverse play for productivity, &#8220;designed to make online meetings more personal, engaging and fun,&#8221; Microsoft&#8217;s John Roach writes in today&#8217;s announcement. &#8220;It’s also a gateway to the metaverse &#8212; a persistent digital world that is inhabited by digital twins of people, places and things. Think of the metaverse as a new version &#8212; or a new vision  &#8212; of the internet, one where people gather to communicate, collaborate and share with personal virtual presence on any device.&#8221;</p>
<p>In that vision, you&#8217;re still having meetings, but they will be more fun now, because of the metaverse. Or something like that.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226559" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2226567" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/content.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226567" class="size-full wp-image-2226567" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/content.png" alt="" width="1024" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2226567" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Microsoft</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;As a company whose focus is on productivity, on knowledge workers, it’s something that customers are really asking us for, and it’s coupled with the vision of mixed reality that we’ve been working on for 12 years. It’s all coming together,&#8221; said always enthusiastic Microsoft Technical Fellow Alex Kipman.</p>
<p>For now, for most users, Mesh won&#8217;t be much more than these 3D personalized avatars that mimic your own speech, but not movements. Microsoft says businesses can also create their own spaces &#8212; or metaverses, because that&#8217;s the term we use now &#8212; within Teams, where people can virtually mingle and collaborate.</p>
<p>&#8220;There will be a feeling of presence even though it’s as simple as being able to take your audio and manifest that as facial expressions. That’s the first release,&#8221; wrote Katie Kelly, a principal project manager at Microsoft working on Mesh for Teams. &#8220;The ambition is to closely follow that with Microsoft’s plethora of AI technologies so that we can use the camera to insinuate where your mouth is and mimic your head and facial movements.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Accenture has been testing some of this together with Microsoft. The company built a virtual campus for its employees to &#8220;gather for coffees, presentations, parties and other events.&#8221; It&#8217;s also using it to onboard new employees. Accenture apparently hires 100,000 people each year. At 600,000 employees, I&#8217;m not sure the metaverse is going to help with that turnover rate, but they are high-paid consultants, so they probably know best.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-teams-gets-3d-animated-avatars-because-metaverse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226559</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft&#8217;s new Azure OpenAI Service brings GPT-3 to (a few) more developers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsofts-new-azure-openai-service-brings-gpt-3-to-a-few-more-developers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsofts-new-azure-openai-service-brings-gpt-3-to-a-few-more-developers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[access management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Copilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gpt-2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gpt-3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai codex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sam altman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unsupervised learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today announced the launch of the Azure OpenAI Service, which, as the name implies, makes OpenAI&#8217;s machine learning models available on the Azure platform. Specifically, that means GPT-3, OpenAI&#8217;s groundbreaking language model that can, under the right circumstances, produce human-like text with just a few prompts. There is a catch, though. At least for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Microsoft today announced the launch of the Azure OpenAI Service, which, as the name implies, makes <a href="https://openai.com/">OpenAI&#8217;s machine learning models</a> available on the Azure platform. Specifically, that means <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GPT-3">GPT-3</a>, OpenAI&#8217;s groundbreaking language model that can, under the right circumstances, produce human-like text with just a few prompts.</p>
<p>There is a catch, though. At least for now, not all Azure users will get access to it (even if they are willing to pay). Access will be invitation-only and for &#8220;customers who are planning to implement well-defined use cases that incorporate responsible principles and strategies for using the AI technology.&#8221; Microsoft will offer safety monitoring and analysis to find cases of abuse or misuse of GPT-3 and it will offer filters to make sure your GPT-3-based chatbot doesn&#8217;t start swearing at your executives (even if GPT-3 thinks they deserve it).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226601" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/OpenAI-Five-sec.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226601" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2226601" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/OpenAI-Five-sec.gif" alt="open ai demo" width="1024" height="576" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2226601" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Microsoft</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226573" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that OpenAI itself already made a GPT-3 API available last year, though <a href="https://beta.openai.com/">there is still a waitlist</a>. Microsoft, too, is already using GPT-3 to power GitHub&#8217;s <a href="https://copilot.github.com/">Copilot</a> tool that helps developers write code for them. But while there are already ways to access GPT-3 outside of Azure, Microsoft argues that it can offer &#8220;additional layers of security, access management, private networking, data handling protections or scaling capacity.&#8221;</p>
<p>Microsoft <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/22/microsoft-invests-1-billion-in-openai-in-new-multiyear-partnership/">invested $1 billion in OpenAI</a> back in 2019 and licenses GPT-3, so it&#8217;s no surprise that the company is trying to bring it to a wider range of products now.</p>
<p>&#8220;GPT-3 has really proven itself as the first powerful, general-purpose model for natural language — it’s one model you can use for all these things, which developers love because you can try things very easily,&#8221; OpenAI CEO Sam Altman said. &#8220;For a while now, we’ve wanted to figure out a way to scale it as broadly as possible, which is part of the thing that really excites us about the partnership with Microsoft.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SZxEbFPoJ7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/22/microsoft-invests-1-billion-in-openai-in-new-multiyear-partnership/">Microsoft invests $1 billion in OpenAI in new multiyear partnership</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft invests $1 billion in OpenAI in new multiyear partnership&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/22/microsoft-invests-1-billion-in-openai-in-new-multiyear-partnership/embed/#?secret=SZxEbFPoJ7" data-secret="SZxEbFPoJ7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsofts-new-azure-openai-service-brings-gpt-3-to-a-few-more-developers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226573</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Azure wants to make working with data on its platform easier</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-azure-wants-to-make-working-with-data-on-its-platform-easier/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-azure-wants-to-make-working-with-data-on-its-platform-easier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cassandra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data lake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft-azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rohan Kumar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its Ignite conference today, Microsoft announced a number of new features for its Azure data platform. These range from a first preview of the 2022 edition of its venerable SQL Server line to updates to the Azure Synapse Analytics platform and new tools that make it easier to move Cassandra workloads to the cloud. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its Ignite conference today, Microsoft announced a number of new features for its <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/solutions/databases/">Azure data platform</a>. These range from a first preview of the 2022 edition of its venerable SQL Server line to updates to the Azure Synapse Analytics platform and new tools that make it easier to move Cassandra workloads to the cloud. But at the core of many of these updates is a deeper integration between the platform&#8217;s various services &#8212; and that&#8217;s no coincidence.</p>
<p>As Rohan Kumar, Microsoft&#8217;s corporate VP for Azure Data, told me, the plethora of available data services available in the cloud has become a pain point for customers. &#8220;There&#8217;s a purpose-built service for everything. Pick your favorite tasks that you want to do for data and there&#8217;s a service for that,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The thing that we heard loud and clear from our customers is that gets super challenging. First of all, there&#8217;s this plethora of options, things are changing almost on a daily basis. And then, a lot of customer pain truly comes from stitching a bunch of these things together.&#8221;</p>
<p>From a user&#8217;s perspective, they have to manage their operational databases that power their various applications, but there&#8217;s also analytics, business intelligence and predictive services based on machine learning, usually backed by data warehouses and data lakes. And then, all of this data, which often includes sensitive information, also has to be governed to ensure compliance with various regulations &#8212; all that data may also be spread across multiple clouds and on-premises data centers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227182" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>With Synapse Analytics, CosmosDB, Azure Data Lake, Purview and its other tools, Microsoft has a solution for all of these use cases, but it is now explicitly focusing on tying them all together into more easily manageable systems.</p>
<p>As Kumar noted, the team believes that it is able to provide best-of-class services across its data portfolio. &#8220;But if you look at truly how we differentiate &#8212; what is unique about Microsoft&#8217;s data [products] and about Microsoft itself, it&#8217;s the fact that we have all these pillars [&#8230;]. For us, this integration is as important as being the best in class in each pillar,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s easier said than put in practice, of course, but some of today&#8217;s updates at Ignite show the direction Microsoft is going in. SQL Server 2022, for example, which is now in preview, features integrations with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/microsoft-launches-azure-synapse-link-to-help-enterprises-get-faster-insights-from-their-data/">Synapse Link</a>, Microsoft&#8217;s tools for using their databases for both analytical and transactional workloads, and Azure Purview for easier data governance. It&#8217;ll also feature support for Azure SQL Managed Instance for deeper cloud integrations and disaster recovery.</p>
<p>Synapse Link is going to be a key piece of the Azure Data integration story, Kumar noted. &#8220;You can imagine the sheer amount of technical innovation that needs to go in. We had to optimize both the source and the target. So Synapse [Analytics] is optimized for this, Cosmos DB is optimized for this &#8212; and in time, Azure SQL and other [data] stores are going to be optimized for this as well,&#8221; he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition to these new features &#8212; and a continued focus on Azure Purview to help enterprises with their data governance &#8212; the Azure Data team is also introducing a number of other new features. There is support for migrating Apache Cassandra data to Cosmos DB. Azure Advisor is getting new cost-control features. There are other updates to Azure SQL Managed Instance. It&#8217;s Microsoft Ignite, so as usual, there are more new features than you can sum up. But what matters more than these individual features is the renewed focus on integrations between the various products.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BxPMU8VKRR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/microsoft-launches-azure-synapse-link-to-help-enterprises-get-faster-insights-from-their-data/">Microsoft launches Azure Synapse Link to help enterprises get faster insights from their data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft launches Azure Synapse Link to help enterprises get faster insights from their data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/microsoft-launches-azure-synapse-link-to-help-enterprises-get-faster-insights-from-their-data/embed/#?secret=BxPMU8VKRR" data-secret="BxPMU8VKRR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-azure-wants-to-make-working-with-data-on-its-platform-easier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Azure expands its hybrid and multi-cloud reach</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-azure-expands-its-hybrid-and-multi-cloud-reach/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-azure-expands-its-hybrid-and-multi-cloud-reach/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft-azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetApp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nokia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vmware]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft Azure, just like its competitors, launched a number of tools in recent years that allow enterprises to use a single platform to manage their virtual machines and containers across clouds and in their own data centers. For Microsoft, the main tool for managing these is Azure Arc. Given the event&#8217;s focus on IT professionals, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/">Microsoft Azure</a>, just like its competitors, launched a number of tools in recent years that allow enterprises to use a single platform to manage their virtual machines and containers across clouds and in their own data centers. For Microsoft, the main tool for managing these is <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/azure-arc/">Azure Arc</a>. Given the event&#8217;s focus on IT professionals, it&#8217;s no surprise that the company is using its Ignite conference today to highlight a number of new features in Arc and its overall hybrid/multi-cloud lineup.</p>
<p>&#8220;Customers just have thousands and thousands of apps, databases, servers they run in different locations,&#8221; <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Roanne Sones, Microsoft&#8217;s corporate VP for Azure Edge and Platform, told me.</span> &#8220;Regulation is constantly evolving and growing. Security attacks are becoming more and more sophisticated &#8212; and their ability to actually manage that in any sort of a consistent way, given just how sprawled across their environment it is, it&#8217;s just really hard. So they&#8217;re pretty overwhelmed. At the same time, they look at the cloud and they want to hitch themselves to that innovation wagon and it&#8217;s hard for them because there are just going to be workloads that never move to the cloud. So how do they take some of the things that they&#8217;ve sampled in the cloud, but be able to actually run it wherever they need to run it, however they need to run it?&#8221;</p>
<p>The first step, Sones argues, is to find a consistent way to manage all of that. Given the complexity of modern infrastructures, that&#8217;s a bit of a journey, but at Ignite, Microsoft is showing off a few new integrations that will make this easier. These include integrations with Azure Stack HCI, VMware vSphere and Azure Policy Guest Configuration. Azure Stack HCI (where HCI stands for &#8216;hyperconverged infrastructure&#8217;), for example, is now Arc-enabled by default, while vSphere users now get self-service VM control from Azure to manage VMs based on vSphere templates. In addition, Azure Arc now also supports machine learning inferencing after an earlier update already allowed users to build and train models in Arc-enabled environments.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227424" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;Now you have full consistency between cloud and edge,&#8221; Sones said. &#8220;You don&#8217;t have to move your data if you don&#8217;t want to move your data. Previously, you had to move your data on-prem. In the cloud, you can do all your Arc-enabled capabilities there &#8212; and then bring it back. Now we&#8217;ve got that new that full lifecycle.&#8221;</p>
<p>Currently, most of Microsoft&#8217;s customers are using these AI capabilities in the context of proof of concepts but not necessarily in production. The enterprise moves slowly, after all, but Sones says she&#8217;s already seeing some customers who are starting to put their models into production in multi-cloud environments (largely because these Azure customers, with Nokia being a marquee user, service highly regulated industries).</p>
<p>Another semi-related new feature, though with a focus of on-premises use cases, is the launch of Azure Virtual Desktops &#8212; the ability to run multi-session Windows 10 and 11 desktop instances in the cloud &#8212; on Azure Stack HCI in a customer&#8217;s on-premises data center. As Sones noted, that&#8217;s a feature users in regulated industries have been asking for, but these local deployments also matter for use cases where latency could be an issue.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-azure-expands-its-hybrid-and-multi-cloud-reach/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227424</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Azure gets a Chaos Studio</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/azure-gets-a-chaos-studio/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/azure-gets-a-chaos-studio/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chaos engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chaos monkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microosft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft-azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software development]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Resorting to chaos may not sound like a sound engineering method, but chaos engineering is quickly becoming a standard way to test complex systems before real-world outages put those systems to a test. Netflix&#8217;s engineering team launched Chaos Monkey back in 2012 and that remains one of the most-used tools for this, but Microsoft Azure [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Resorting to chaos may not sound like a sound engineering method, but chaos engineering is quickly becoming a standard way to test complex systems before real-world outages put those systems to a test. Netflix&#8217;s engineering team launched <a href="https://netflix.github.io/chaosmonkey/">Chaos Monkey</a> back in 2012 and that remains one of the most-used tools for this, but Microsoft Azure today also launched a similar tool for users on its cloud platform: Azure Chaos Studio.</p>
<p>Using Chaos Studio, Azure users can see how their apps respond against real-world disruptions by throwing random outages, extreme network latencies, expired secrets and even complete data center outages at them. It&#8217;s one thing to theorize what would happen if one of those things happened and plan accordingly. It&#8217;s another to see it in action. Given the complexity of modern data center infrastructures, chances are that even a minor outage somewhere could cascade into a much larger issue and before you know it, your platform is down <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roblox-outage-ends-210646994.html">for a few days</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that AWS, with its Fault Injection Simulator, offers <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/fis/">similar capabilities</a> for its users and like with any popular engineering concept, there are startups like <a href="https://www.gremlin.com/">Gremlin</a> that fully specialize in chaos engineering as a service.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227327" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bpp4V6QJ3z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/04/the-rise-of-chaos-engineering/">The rise of chaos engineering</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The rise of chaos engineering&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/04/the-rise-of-chaos-engineering/embed/#?secret=bpp4V6QJ3z" data-secret="bpp4V6QJ3z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/azure-gets-a-chaos-studio/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227327</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Googler who came to monetize space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/the-googler-who-came-to-monetize-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/the-googler-who-came-to-monetize-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Riggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Axiom Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international space station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tejpaul Bhatia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Axiom Space, builder of the next International Space Station, recruited Tejpaul Bhatia to become its first chief revenue officer, responsible for the growth and monetization of the space ecosystem.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Martine Paris</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/contentnow">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Martine Paris is a freelance writer covering space, electric vehicles, climate tech, robotics, AI, consumer tech, e-commerce, streaming, gaming, venture capital and startup culture. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Following its billion-dollar valuation earlier this year, Axiom Space, builder of the next International Space Station, recruited Google&#8217;s Tejpaul Bhatia to become its first chief revenue officer, responsible for the growth and monetization of the space ecosystem.</p>
<p>Introduced to Axiom in 2017 while serving as executive in residence at Citi Ventures, Bhatia invested in the company as an angel investor in 2020 after it landed its <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-selects-first-commercial-destination-module-for-international-space-station" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$140 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> contract with NASA. He then joined as part of the leadership team in July.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227414" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227414" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2227414" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tejpaul-Bhatia.jpg?w=300" alt="Tejpaul Bhatia, chief revenue officer, Axiom Space" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tejpaul-Bhatia.jpg 750w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tejpaul-Bhatia.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tejpaul-Bhatia.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tejpaul-Bhatia.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tejpaul-Bhatia.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tejpaul-Bhatia.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tejpaul-Bhatia.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tejpaul-Bhatia.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tejpaul-Bhatia.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227414" class="wp-caption-text">Tejpaul Bhatia, chief revenue officer, Axiom Space</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227363" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>But Axiom is not the only space pioneer in the universe. With <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/voyager-nanoracks-and-lockheeds-starlab-is-the-latest-sign-that-the-low-earth-orbit-economy-is-coming/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$400 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in NASA contracts up for grabs, a gold rush is on for space ventures to set up shop in Sky City.</span></p>
<p>More than <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2019/blue-origin-boeing-space-stations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a dozen contractors</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have thrown their hats into the ring, with two announced last month. On October 22, Lockheed Martin, in a partnership with Voyager Space and Nanoracks, submitted a bid to launch its </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/nanoracks-lockheed-martin-and-voyager-space-plan-to-launch-crewed-commercial-space-station-by-2027/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starlab space station</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by 2027, and on October 25, Jeff Bezos announced Blue Origin’s plan to partner with Sierra Space and Boeing to launch its </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/blue-origin-boeing-and-others-join-sierra-space-to-build-commercial-space-station/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orbital Reef space station</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> between 2025 and 2030.</span></p>
<p>For Axiom’s part, NASA approved the Axiom Station to be built in stages while attached to the ISS to ensure a seamless transition from the ISS being decommissioned in 2028.</p>
<p>The first module, Hub 1, is slated to dock in 2024 and will include research facilities and living quarters for four crew members, with a touchscreen communications panel and a large window. A second module, Hub 2, with similar amenities, is planned for 2025. A microgravity lab will follow in 2026. Then in 2027, a Power Tower with solar arrays will attach to the three modules and form Axiom Station, which will double the capacity of ISS. In 2028, Axiom Station will detach and begin to self-orbit.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>TechCrunch talked with Bhatia about his ambitions over the next seven to 10 years to build a massive industrial complex in low Earth orbit that will not only serve as a WeWork for off-planet retreats and a research hub for brands and institutions, but also a way for smaller nations to set up their own space program.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taking a page out of Google’s playbook, this is how he plans to monetize the final frontier.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227409" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227409" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2227409" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Axiom-Station-Timeline.jpg" alt="Axiom Station construction timeline" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Axiom-Station-Timeline.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Axiom-Station-Timeline.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Axiom-Station-Timeline.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Axiom-Station-Timeline.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Axiom-Station-Timeline.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Axiom-Station-Timeline.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Axiom-Station-Timeline.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227409" class="wp-caption-text">Axiom Station timeline (photo credit: Axiom Space)</p></div></p>
<h2>Booking the ultimate getaway<b></b></h2>
<p>Axiom Space was founded in 2016 by former International Space Station manager Michael Suffredini and Intuitive Machines co-founder Kam Ghaffarian. It has raised a total of $150 million, having closed a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/axiom-space-raises-130-million-for-its-commercial-space-station-ambitions/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">$130 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Series B round led by C5 Capital in February, with its lead investor, former Blue Origin president Rob Meyerson, taking a seat on the board. The company has more than 300 employees headquartered in Houston. </span></p>
<p>Axiom’s main source of revenue comes from being an end-to-end mission provider of short-duration stays on the ISS. That means it packages astronaut training and round-trip transport on SpaceX (which includes food, water, oxygen, communications, data, power and other essentials) and sells to private citizens an all-inclusive stay of seven to 10 days. It also sells research missions for experiments to be conducted in the ISS microgravity lab, and has begun to sell content and media sponsorships.</p>
<p>Two missions are planned for next year. Retired NASA astronaut and Axiom VP Michael López-Alegria will lead its first, <a href="https://www.axiomspace.com/ax1" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ax1</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which is scheduled for </span><a href="https://twitter.com/Axiom_Space/status/1442504464758284289?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">February 21</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Investors Larry Connor, Mark Pathy and Eytan Stibbe will serve as crew. The Washington Post reported the ticket price to be </span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/01/26/private-space-flight-axiom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$55 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> per passenger.</span></p>
<p>Its second mission, <a href="https://www.axiomspace.com/press-release/ax2" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ax2</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is planned for later in 2022, and will include retired NASA astronaut Peggy Whitson, who holds the American record for most time spent in space, and John Shoffner, American investor, racing car driver and pilot. Two seats are still available on this trip, but Axiom would not confirm whether Tom Cruise, who is working on a </span><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elon-musk-helping-tom-cruise-go-space-movie-nasa-1533780" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$200 million Universal film</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with Elon Musk and is rumored by </span><a href="https://twitter.com/JimBridenstine/status/1257752395750289409?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NASA</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to be going up, is on that flight.</span></p>
<p>Its third and fourth missions are being planned for 2023, and one will include the winner of its Discovery Channel competition reality TV show, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/contestants-will-compete-for-a-spacex-trip-to-the-international-space-station-in-new-reality-tv-show/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Who Wants To Be An Astronaut?”</span></a></p>
<p>Axiom’s competitors in this sector include <a href="https://spaceadventures.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Space Adventures</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, co-founded in 1998 by BOLD Capital’s Peter Diamandis. The company has transported seven private citizens, including Cirque du Soleil co-founder Guy Laliberté, to the ISS through the Russian space agency Roscosmos. Its second scheduled mission to the ISS in 2023 will be a space walk. It had an orbital trip planned on SpaceX later this year but </span><a href="https://spacenews.com/space-adventures-no-longer-planning-crew-dragon-flight/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">cancelled it</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> due to low demand, according to SpaceNews.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the hype, the past few months around billionaires Richard Branson, Jeff Bezos and Elon Musk taking private citizens, including Star Trek’s William Shatner, on joyrides to the edge of space, the market is limited for those who can afford the ticket price. </span></p>
<p>Fortunately for Axiom, billionaires are not their target market.</p>
<p>[gallery ids="2227413,2227407,2227408,2227404"]</p>
<h2>Welcome to Sky City</h2>
<p>Although it may not look like &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">The Jetsons,&#8221;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with space cars zipping around celestial buildings aglow with neon lights, things are going to get a lot more interesting come 2024 when Axiom docks its first habitat on the ISS.</span></p>
<p>Bhatia said the extra crew quarters and lab facilities will enable Axiom to offer more missions since it will no longer be subject to ISS capacity constraints. As demand dictates, Axiom is also open to working with other rocket providers like SpaceX, including Boeing’s <a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialcrew/2021/10/08/nasa-boeing-update-starliner-orbital-flight-test-2-status/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starliner</span></a>,<span style="font-weight: 400;"> once approved.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bhatia sees 2024 as a key inflection point for revenue growth.</span></p>
<p>“Once Axiom station comes on, we will have a hybrid model where companies, institutions and governments can custom build, buy or lease physical and digital space,” he said.</p>
<p>“The cool thing about our physical space is that the modules, which can be a lab, data center or habitat, can undock, fly around and reassemble like Legos.”</p>
<p>But Bhatia shuddered at the thought of it being called a space hotel, where rooms can be booked off an app. He sees Axiom station as a massive industrial space complex with prospective customers ranging from governments seeking to build their own space programs to companies and institutions in need of microgravity laboratories and colocation manufacturing facilities.</p>
<p>“We offer physical space that includes the food, water, oxygen, life support systems, bandwidth, data, insights, edge computing, communications, power &#8212; things that have to happen in orbit that every business, institution or government would need to operate,” he said.</p>
<p>“But even more exciting is we can also offer our digital platform which we are selling as infrastructure-as-a-service where developers can use the sensors and other instrumentation onboard to create businesses, similar to how developers use the sensors of the iPhone to create apps.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227411" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227411" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2227411" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-station-quarters2.jpg" alt="Render of the Axiom crew station quarters" width="1024" height="640" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-station-quarters2.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-station-quarters2.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-station-quarters2.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-station-quarters2.jpg?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-station-quarters2.jpg?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-station-quarters2.jpg?resize=1536,960 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/crew-station-quarters2.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227411" class="wp-caption-text">Render of the Axiom crew station quarters | photo credit Axiom Space</p></div></p>
<p>Whether Bhatia will actually create a software development kit to allow third-party development of the Axiom Station operating system remains to be seen, but he did say good uses of the station’s sensors could include monitoring of space debris and Earth’s climate.</p>
<p>As for the total addressable market, Bhatia measures it as countries that have budgets for space programs and those that haven’t yet been able to afford one.</p>
<p>“Our goal is to ensure that there isn’t a gap &#8212; that once ISS reaches its end of life, there is a full service, fully functioning private station for everyone,” he said. “Whether a country has a budget of billions of dollars or a fraction of it, we can create a solution to meet their needs.”</p>
<p>Bhatia is hoping that NASA, ESA, JAXA, Canadian Space Agency and Roscosmos move their <a href="https://oig.nasa.gov/docs/IG-18-021.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$2 billion to $3 billion annual revenue</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> spend to Axiom Station, as the successor to ISS. Longer term, he expects Axiom to be servicing a multibillion-dollar market, referencing a Morgan Stanley report that pegs the commercial space sector at </span><a href="https://www.morganstanley.com/ideas/investing-in-space" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$350 billion in 2020 and $1 trillion by 2040</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.<br />
</span></p>
<h2>It takes a Googler</h2>
<p>As a serial entrepreneur, investor and tech executive who helped build the startup ecosystem for Google Cloud, Bhatia said the space economy needs the venture capital mindset.</p>
<p>“As chief revenue officer my mandate is to create a hyper growth business platform that will serve as a launchpad for businesses, industries and markets to scale exponentially over the next seven to 10 years,” he said. “That’s a very different model than how the space industry has operated to date as a government taxpayer endeavor. The private sector is far better suited for the task.”</p>
<p>As for competition from Starlab and Orbital Reef, Bhatia says he welcomes it and is confident that Axiom is years ahead.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227412" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227412" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2227412" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Fabrication-of-Axiom-plant.jpg" alt="Fabrication of Axiom Hub 1 at the Thales Alenia (TASI) plant in Turin Italy (photo credit: Axiom Space)" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Fabrication-of-Axiom-plant.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Fabrication-of-Axiom-plant.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Fabrication-of-Axiom-plant.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Fabrication-of-Axiom-plant.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Fabrication-of-Axiom-plant.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Fabrication-of-Axiom-plant.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Fabrication-of-Axiom-plant.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227412" class="wp-caption-text">Fabrication of Axiom Hub 1 at the Thales Alenia (TASI) plant in Turin Italy (photo credit: Axiom Space)</p></div></p>
<p>“I’m a little over 100 days on the job and see it’s not theoretical &#8212; metal is being bent, people are going up, contracts are being signed,” he said. “Our first module is already under construction at our Thales Alenia plant in Italy. This is not science fiction. It’s really happening.”</p>
<p>And for the time being, he’s not worried about profitability.</p>
<p>“Fundraising is very important and we’re following the model of the five most valuable companies in the world &#8212; Facebook, Apple, Amazon, Microsoft and Google &#8212; which operated at a loss when they first started out. We are trying to create as much shareholder value as possible and taking capital to build essential infrastructure and innovate at speed while staying focused on safety.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/the-googler-who-came-to-monetize-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227363</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zoom is piloting ads for free users</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/zoom-is-piloting-ads-for-free-users/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/zoom-is-piloting-ads-for-free-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video calling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videoconferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Zoom is introducing a pilot advertising program that will show ads to users on its &#8216;Basic&#8217; free tier. The company says the ads will support investments and enable it to continue providing its platform to free users. Basic tier users will only see ads if they join a meeting hosted by another Basic tier user. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Zoom is introducing a <a href="https://blog.zoom.us/zoom-continued-access-for-basic-users-with-advertising-program/">pilot advertising program</a> that will show ads to users on its &#8216;Basic&#8217; free tier. The company says the ads will support investments and enable it to continue providing its platform to free users.</p>
<p>Basic tier users will only see ads if they join a meeting hosted by another Basic tier user. For the initial test, ads will be displayed on the browser page users see when they end their meeting. It’s possible that Zoom may show ads in other areas of the user interface once initial testing is concluded.</p>
<p>As part of the pilot, Zoom users will see a banner on its website that provides a link to its cookies management tool so they can manage what ads they are shown. Zoom also notes that it has updated its Privacy Statement to make it clear that it will not use meeting, webinar, or messaging content for any marketing, promotions, or third-party advertising purposes.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227692" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2227699" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227699" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2227699" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/zoom-ads.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/zoom-ads.jpeg 1366w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/zoom-ads.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/zoom-ads.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/zoom-ads.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/zoom-ads.jpeg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/zoom-ads.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227699" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: Zoom</strong></p></div></p>
<p>Although the company has made it clear that users won’t see ads during meetings, this latest move is a significant change for Zoom. The platform’s free basic service lets users host group meetings for up to 40 minutes, which allowed Zoom’s popularity to skyrocket amid the pandemic. With this latest change, Zoom is imposing a new restriction upon its free basic users, which it says is a necessary step.</p>
<p>“This change ensures that our free Basic users are able to continue connecting with friends, family, and colleagues with the same robust platform we have always offered,” Janine Pelosi, Zoom’s chief marketing officer, outlined in a blog post.</p>
<p>The change comes as Zoom has spent the last year focused on being more than just a popular video conferencing tool. Earlier this year, the company launched a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/zoom-launches-100m-zoom-apps-investment-fund/">$100 million fund</a> to invest in companies building applications based on the company’s platform. Zoom recently made its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/30/zoom-announces-first-startups-receiving-funding-from-100m-zoom-apps-investment-fund/">first round</a> of investments as part of the fund.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In terms of acquisitions, the company recently announced plans to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/zoom-to-acquire-german-startup-to-bring-real-time-translation-to-meetings/">acquire German startup</a> Karlsruhe Information Technology Solutions or &#8216;Kites&#8217; for short, to bring real-time machine-learning-based translation to its platform. Zoom had also planned to<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/and-thats-that-as-the-zoom-deal-to-buy-five9-is-called-off/"> acquire Five9</a>, a maker of cloud-based customer service software, but the deal was subsequently called off.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/zoom-is-piloting-ads-for-free-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227692</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hone, a human-powered platform for leadership training, nabs $16 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/hone-a-human-powered-platform-for-leadership-training-nabs-16-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/hone-a-human-powered-platform-for-leadership-training-nabs-16-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cowboy ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the Great Resignation builds, corporations and organizations are looking for bigger and better ways to retain talent. One of the most popular ways to do that, right now, is to offer better tools around personal development and career growth to employees. Hone, a startup backed by Cowboy Ventures, is looking to do just that. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/01/great-resignation-may-be-altering-workforce-dynamic-for-good.html">the Great Resignation builds</a>, corporations and organizations are looking for bigger and better ways to retain talent. One of the most popular ways to do that, right now, is to offer better tools around personal development and career growth to employees.</p>
<p><a href="https://honehq.com/">Hone</a>, a startup backed by Cowboy Ventures, is looking to do just that.</p>
<p>The company is today announcing the close of a $16 million Series A funding round led by F-Prime Capital, with participation from Cowboy Ventures, NextGen Venture partners, Slack Fund, Gaingels, and SemperVirens.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227640" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Specifically, Hone focuses on leadership training within organizations with live, intimate online classes led by a coach. New students will enter into a four-week bootcamp, with topics selected by the company. From there, they have unlimited access to Hone classes throughout the year.</p>
<p>There are plenty of corporate training topics that don&#8217;t necessarily require live sessions, such as security and data protection. But when it comes to having tough conversations with employees, coaching them through a challenge, or leading discussions on diversity and inclusion, strong communication and interpersonal skills are absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>Hone provides a platform that gives managers the tools they need, and lets them practice those skills, without bringing them to an in-person two-day conference that has no real lasting effect.</p>
<p>Moreover, Hone&#8217;s software makes it really easy to schedule across different geographies and timezones with our now-commonplace distributed workforces, letting senior leaders at the company focus on the important stuff.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Personal development and leadership training has become an incredibly hot space in the past couple of years. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/21/chief-the-leadership-network-for-women-raises-15-million-in-funding/">Chief</a> has raised $40 million, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/medley-the-coaching-platform-for-personal-and-professional-development-gets-3-7m-led-by-a16z/">Medley</a> has come on to the scene with a fresh take around group learning, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/30/how-one-founder-turned-painful-personal-experience-into-the-solution-for-a-huge-gap-in-healthcare/">Inclusivv</a> is another player getting in on this sector.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the biggest challenges is meeting the demand we&#8217;re seeing right now,&#8221; said cofounder Savina Perez. &#8220;Global organizations are coming to us, so being able to deliver for them, thinking about localization and translation, is something that keeps me up.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cofounder Tom Griffiths added that it&#8217;s tougher to scale a business like Hone, which has so much human input, rather than a standard SaaS product.</p>
<p>Thus far, the company has attracted over 100 customers (organizations), which represents 400 percent YoY growth. Hone does 300 classes per month and has a team of 30 people, with 50 percent of the team being female and 43 percent being people of color.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/hone-a-human-powered-platform-for-leadership-training-nabs-16-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227640</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Today! Join NASA, US Space Force fireside chat on the new space age</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/today-join-nasa-us-space-force-fireside-chat-on-the-new-space-age/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/today-join-nasa-us-space-force-fireside-chat-on-the-new-space-age/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emily Calandrelli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emmy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steve isakowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thompson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning at 8:30 am PT we are hosting a live, 30-minute FREE webinar called, Full Speed Ahead: Accelerating Government and Commercial Collaboration in the New Space Age. Join experienced space leaders for this candid discussion and learn how government demands for mission success intersect with new capabilities from commercial companies. This event is free, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning at 8:30 am PT we are hosting a live, 30-minute FREE webinar called, <a href="https://hopin.com/events/full-speed-ahead-accelerating-government-and-commercial-collaboration-in-the-new-space-age" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Full Speed Ahead: Accelerating Government and Commercial Collaboration in the New Space Age.</strong></a></p>
<p>Join experienced space leaders for this candid discussion and learn how government demands for mission success intersect with new capabilities from commercial companies. This event is free, but you must <a href="https://hopin.com/events/full-speed-ahead-accelerating-government-and-commercial-collaboration-in-the-new-space-age" target="_blank" rel="noopener">register to attend.</a></p>
<p>The conversation, moderated by Emily Calandrelli, an MIT-trained engineer and Emmy-nominated science TV host, features Steve Isakowitz, president and CEO of The Aerospace Corporation; Gen. David D. “DT” Thompson, the vice chief of space operations, United States Space Force; Mandy Vaughn, the CEO and founder of GXO, Inc.; and Alex MacDonald, chief economist at NASA.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227568" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The booming space industry is evolving and expanding at an unprecedented rate. It’s the most complex, costly sector, and the traditional boundaries between national security, civil and commercial space are changing rapidly to create new opportunities.</p>
<p>Topics on the table include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Challenges to “evolving space at speed,” including key trends and drivers of change that are impacting missions and shaping this moment in space.</li>
<li>Current capability gaps surrounding specific applications, mission integration challenges and a robust workforce.</li>
<li>How to best leverage commercial capabilities at the national level to support enterprise mission success.</li>
<li>Opportunities for new space companies to partner and do business with government space programs.</li>
</ul>
<p>Don’t miss this rare chance to gain a deeper understanding of partnering opportunities to unlock new era of human achievement in space.</p>
<p>Full Speed Ahead: Accelerating Government and Commercial Collaboration in the New Space Age takes place today from 8:30 am – 9:00 am (PT) / 11:30 am – 12:00 pm (ET). <a href="https://hopin.com/events/full-speed-ahead-accelerating-government-and-commercial-collaboration-in-the-new-space-age" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Register to attend today for 100% free</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/today-join-nasa-us-space-force-fireside-chat-on-the-new-space-age/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227568</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Independent worker network Contra goes commission-free as it secures new NEA-led capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/independent-worker-network-contra-goes-commission-free-as-it-secures-new-nea-led-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/independent-worker-network-contra-goes-commission-free-as-it-secures-new-nea-led-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ann Bordetsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cowboy ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unusual Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wikis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Contra provides tools for independent workers to build a professional identity and manage their work from inquiry to project scope discussion to signing a contract to getting paid.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.contra.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Contra</a>, a professional network for independent workers, unveiled a new payment model Tuesday that lets users accept payments for their services on Contra without paying any commission fees.</p>
<p>The new feature comes as the company brings in $30 million in Series B funding, led by NEA, with participation from Unusual Ventures and Cowboy Ventures, both of which invested in Contra’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/contra-series-a/">$14.5 million Series A</a> earlier this year. The latest funding round gives the company just under $45 million in total funding, Ben Huffman, Contra founder and CEO told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Contra provides tools for independent workers to build a professional identity and manage their work from inquiry to project scope discussion to signing a contract to getting paid, all without having to pay upwards of 20% of fees that other independent work websites may charge, Huffman said.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227147" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2227149" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227149" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2227149" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg" alt="Contra" width="1024" height="408" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg 3860w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=150,60 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=300,119 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=768,306 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=680,271 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=1536,612 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=2048,815 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Contra-2@2x.jpg?resize=50,20 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227149" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Contra</p></div></p>
<p>Securing the new funding is giving Contra an opportunity to not only work with Ann Bordetsky, partner at NEA, but capitalize on “the crazy amount of user growth post-pandemic,” as more people turned to independent work, Huffman said. He cited figures that said over 50% of people stated working independently at the start of the pandemic and more than 1 million people joined Contra to find work or hire talent.</p>
<p>“We have always wanted to roll this out, but wanted to be able to ensure the client pays and there is trust on the network,” he added. “We have users in 139 countries, and while many workers complete successful projects, they don’t get stocks or other benefits, so we want to help them collect on that stored value and make it easier to get paid.”</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the company surveyed over 10,000 independent workers for its first <a href="https://contra.com/freelance-industry-report-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">State of Independence</a> report and found that independent workers value the freedom, autonomy and financial benefits of freelance work: In fact, 86% surveyed said they work less than 40 hours per week. In addition, by having a fluid revenue stream through Contra, they are charging for per-project versus hourly, which enables them to earn the same amount of money with fewer projects, Huffman said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Meanwhile, the new funding will be funneled into hiring and continued product innovation with new products on tap to be released early next year.</p>
<p>With many people opting for the flexibility of independent work, NEA’s Bordetsky said she was intrigued by the trend and spoke with people who all had shared pain points of wanting to work in this way, yet not being satisfied by the existing marketplaces for building careers.</p>
<p>She saw that Contra was becoming a resource that “the Gen Z digital worker is excited to use” and how the company leveraged TikTok and other tools to build an audience.</p>
<p>“Ben knows those pain points,” Bordetsky added. “What was impressive was his creative vision for what the platform could do and also his practical understanding. Ben is the visionary to build this in the space, and NEA supports that Contra is following that trend.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N69kKfPuqq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/31/freelancers-rights-come-of-age-as-gig-economy-booms/">Freelancers rights come of age as gig economy booms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Freelancers rights come of age as gig economy booms&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/31/freelancers-rights-come-of-age-as-gig-economy-booms/embed/#?secret=N69kKfPuqq" data-secret="N69kKfPuqq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/independent-worker-network-contra-goes-commission-free-as-it-secures-new-nea-led-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227147</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Activeloop snags $5M seed to build streaming database for AI applications</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/activeloop-snags-5m-seed-to-build-database-for-ai-applications/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/activeloop-snags-5m-seed-to-build-database-for-ai-applications/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activeloop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer Vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[databases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Activeloop, a member of the Y Combinator summer 2018 cohort, is building a database specifically designed for media-focused  artificial intelligence applications. Today the company announced a $5 million seed investment led by 468 Capital and CM Ventures with participation from Tribe Capital, Shasta Ventures and various tech industry angels. Davit Buniatyan, founder and CEO at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.activeloop.ai/">Activeloop</a>, a member of the Y Combinator <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/activeloop">summer 2018 cohort</a>, is building a database specifically designed for media-focused  artificial intelligence applications. Today the company announced a $5 million seed investment led by 468 Capital and CM Ventures with participation from Tribe Capital, Shasta Ventures and various tech industry angels.</p>
<p>Davit Buniatyan, founder and CEO at the company says the company developed out of research he was doing at Princeton where saw the need for a streaming database of unstructured data like images and video specifically designed for AI use cases. The company is also launching an alpha version of a commercial product today.</p>
<p>&#8220;[We are] introducing a database for AI, specifically a storage layer that helps to very efficiently store the data and then stream this to machine learning applications or training models to do computer vision, audio processing, NLP (natural language processing) and so on,&#8221; Buniatyan explained.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227331" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In practical terms, this takes the form of an open source API that enables users to convert the data (video, audio, etc) into a mathematical representation that machines can understand. In addition, the API lets you track different versions of the data and finally lets you store that in a repository like Amazon S3.</p>
<p>By streaming the data, the data scientist or developer no longer has to download all of this data to a local laptop, but sends it through for use by the model in the same way that Netflix streams a movie to you, so you aren&#8217;t downloading the whole thing to your local machine.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227343" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227343" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2227343" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/visualization-activeloop-gif.gif?w=680" alt="Gif of Activeloop streaming database in action showing hundreds of images." width="680" height="383" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227343" class="wp-caption-text">Activeloop image database.<strong> Image Credits:</strong> Activeloop</p></div></p>
<p>He says that there are 55 contributors to the open source project and 700 community members overall. The program has been downloaded 300,000 times so far.</p>
<p>He came up with the idea for streaming the data while working on large amounts of data at the neuroscience lab at Princeton. He found the files were so huge, it wasn&#8217;t practical to download them, so he came up with this way of streaming them that would become the basis for Activeloop.</p>
<p>The company has 15 employees so far and is looking to hire around half a dozen high-end engineers. He says as he builds the company he is looking at diverse talent wherever it may be. He points out that his VP of Engineering is a woman. Recently the company offered a job to an Ethiopian engineer who ended up turning it down, but he says it&#8217;s an example of looking for talent wherever it happens to be.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not about where a person is originally from, or what kind of biases in terms of where in the world he or she was born. What matters is that we are on this mission. We are building this [company] to have an impact, and we do care about people on our team who are building this,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The API is open source, but the company&#8217;s commercial product, which is being released in alpha today, will be adding features on top of this such as being able to run SQL queries on the streaming data, which aren&#8217;t available in the open source product. The company is pre-revenue at the moment, but is hoping to release the commercial version in Q1 next year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/activeloop-snags-5m-seed-to-build-database-for-ai-applications/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227331</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla recalls 11,704 vehicles after identifying Full Self-Driving Beta software error</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tesla-recalls-11704-vehicles-after-identifying-full-self-driving-beta-software-error/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tesla-recalls-11704-vehicles-after-identifying-full-self-driving-beta-software-error/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autopilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[full self driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national highway transportation and safety administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nhtsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tesla voluntarily recalled nearly 11,704 vehicles after identifying a software error that could cause a false forward-collision warning or unexpected activation of the automatic emergency brake system, the National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration said. All of the affected vehicles had early access to the automaker’s “Full Self-Driving Beta,” it’s advanced driver assistance system. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tesla voluntarily recalled nearly 11,704 vehicles after identifying a software error that could cause a false forward-collision warning or unexpected activation of the automatic emergency brake system, the National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration said.</p>
<p>All of the affected vehicles had early access to the automaker’s “Full Self-Driving Beta,” it’s advanced driver assistance system. The system, which is still in beta mode and requires the driver to be attentive at all times, has been released to thousands of customers in recent weeks. Tesla said it was not aware of any crashes or injuries as a result of the software error.</p>
<p>The over-the-air firmware update, which was released on October 23, introduced what the regulator called “a software communication disconnect” between two on-board chips. The following day, Tesla said it started receiving reports from customers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227651" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“This communication disconnect can result in the video neural networks that operate on that chip to run less consistently than expected,” <a href="https://static.nhtsa.gov/odi/rcl/2021/RCLRPT-21V846-7836.PDF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the safety recall report</a> said. “The inconsistency can produce negative object velocity detections when other vehicles are present, which in turn can lead to false [forward-collision warnings] and [automatic emergency braking] events.”</p>
<p>Affected vehicles include certain Model S, Model X, Model 3 cars that were manufactured between 2017-2021, and certain Model Y models that were manufactured between 2020-2021. Tesla has released a separate over-the-air software update to address the issue and owners will be sent letters notifying them of the issue and resolution.</p>
<p>&#8220;In a matter of hours, we investigated the reports and took actions to mitigate any potential safety risk,&#8221; Tesla said.</p>
<p>The formal recall is a marked departure from the California automaker’s recent interactions with the country&#8217;s top automotive safety agency, which includes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/us-regulator-targets-tesla-on-ndas-over-the-air-software-updates/">releasing a software update for a separate bug identified in its Autopilot system</a> last month, for which Tesla did not issue a recall. NHTSA sent a letter to the automaker on October 12 asking why it did not issue a recall.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“As Tesla is aware, the Safety Act imposes an obligation on manufacturers of motor vehicles and motor vehicle equipment to initiate a recall by notifying NHTSA when they determine vehicles or equipment they produced contain defects related to motor vehicle safety or do not comply with an applicable motor vehicle safety standard,” the agency wrote.</p>
<p>The regulator has opened a separate investigation into Autopilot in August after identifying 12 separate incidents in which a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/u-s-safety-regulator-opens-investigation-into-tesla-autopilot-following-crashes-with-parked-emergency-vehicles/">Tesla crashed into parked emergency vehicles</a>.</p>
<p>Regarding this recall, NHTSA said it would “continue its conversations with Tesla to ensure that any safety defect is promptly acknowledged and addressed.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tesla-recalls-11704-vehicles-after-identifying-full-self-driving-beta-software-error/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227651</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tempo launches a $395 home fitness system the size of a minifridge</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tempo-launches-a-400-home-fitness-system-the-size-of-a-minifridge/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tempo-launches-a-400-home-fitness-system-the-size-of-a-minifridge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connected fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tempo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic drove explosive growth for the connected fitness industry, as gyms shut down and people struggled to find ways to work out without leaving their homes. Along with the likes of Peloton and Mirror, Tempo is one of the companies that has benefitted from the trend. The San Francisco-based company specializes in cardio and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The pandemic drove <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/the-peloton-effect/">explosive growth</a> for the connected fitness industry, as gyms shut down and people struggled to find ways to work out without leaving their homes. Along with the likes of Peloton and Mirror, <a href="https://tempo.fit/">Tempo</a> is one of the companies that has benefitted from the trend. The San Francisco-based company specializes in cardio and strength training through guided workouts using a system of barbells and dumbbells.</p>
<p>For many, however, there have been two primary barriers to entry: price and size. The company&#8217;s Tempo Studio product is a perfect example of those blockers, standing six feet tall and running $2,500 for the starter pack. That’s a lot of space and money to get your foot in the door.</p>
<p>Today, however, the company is introducing a much lower barrier of entry in the form of the Tempo Move.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225401" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2225412" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225412" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2225412" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="751" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg 2680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=150,110 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=300,220 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=768,563 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=680,499 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1127 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1502 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-27-at-6.30.21-PM.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2225412" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tempo</p></div></p>
<p>The $395 system is roughly the size of a side table or minifridge, if you will. It serves as storage for 50 pounds of weight plates and dumbbells &#8212; no barbells here, for what should be obvious reasons. Up top is a “core” docking system for an iPhone. The core is effectively the brain of the system, with a processor and 1GB of RAM.</p>
<p>Once plugged in, the handset’s True Depth camera system (with lidar use at some point in the future) serves as a rough approximation for the Studio’s on-board tracking, while an HDMI cable runs the data into a connected TV. The system taps into Tempo’s existing selection of live and on-demand classes, letting users filter by those that only require dumbbells. That system runs another $39 a month.</p>
<p>The Tempo Move is available for preorder now and is set to start shipping in early December.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Tempo&#8217;s expansion of its product line comes as Peloton sees its growth decelerate as its pandemic-fueled bump to sales ebbs. It will be interesting to see if the Move&#8217;s lower price point will open Tempo&#8217;s market to include more casual exercisers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tempo-launches-a-400-home-fitness-system-the-size-of-a-minifridge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225401</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cities have a new planning tool to fold ride-sharing into public transit systems</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/vias-remix-launches-tool-for-cities-to-plan-on-demand-and-fixed-route-transit-together/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/vias-remix-launches-tool-for-cities-to-plan-on-demand-and-fixed-route-transit-together/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on demand transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Remix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ride-sharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rideco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[via]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Remix, the mapping software startup acquired by Via in March, is launching a new product designed to help cities plan how on-demand rides and fixed route transit, like buses and subways, can work together. Usually, Remix uses data to help cities plan out things like public transportation services or where to build a new bike [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__right" role="presentation" data-qa="message_content">
<div class="c-message_kit__blocks c-message_kit__blocks--rich_text">
<div class="c-message__message_blocks c-message__message_blocks--rich_text">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer" data-qa="block-kit-renderer">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper--first">
<div class="p-rich_text_block" dir="auto">
<p class="p-rich_text_section">Remix, the mapping software startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/via-buys-mapping-startup-remix-for-100-million/">acquired by Via in March</a>, is launching a new product designed to help cities plan how on-demand rides and fixed route transit, like buses and subways, can work together.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">Usually, Remix uses data to help cities plan out things like public transportation services or where to build a new bike lane. Adding this tool to the mix allows cities to model<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> which routes can be replaced with flexible ride-sharing services and which ones would benefit from increased bus or light rail service. The new software is already being beta tested in nearly a dozen cities, where planners are able to evaluate a city&#8217;s metro or bus network based on ridership, demographics and service quality while simultaneously determining potential zones for ridesharing services.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">This is the first time t</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">hat Remix and Via are offering a joint product, and it&#8217;s one that truly helps cities visualize how on-demand services, such as those offered by companies like Via, RideCo, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/plentywaka-founder-onyeka-akumah-on-african-startups-and-global-expansion/">Treepz</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/15/meet-the-startups-changing-mobility-for-emerging-middle-classes/">Swvl</a>, can become part of the public transit system. </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">While Remix&#8217;s new tool is currently focused on ways to implement shared rides, it&#8217;s easy to imagine expanding the services to include things like micromobility zone planning.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226783" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>&#8220;Previously, on-demand was kind of in its own world, siloed into special projects, and then fixed route was the purview of typical strategic planning teams,&#8221; founder and CEO of Remix Tiffany Chu told TechCrunch. &#8220;Now, we&#8217;re going to be combining those two worlds together to more holistically help cities understand the allocation of resources before implementation.&#8221;</p>
<p>Over the years, Remix has received hundreds product requests for this type of tool, particularly from rural agencies or second tier cities that don&#8217;t have a public transit system that&#8217;s robust enough to handle the city&#8217;s mobility needs, according to Chu. As cities try to reach their carbon emissions goals, they are on the lookout for ways to get communities with high car ownership to mode shift.</p>
<p>The on-demand planning tool&#8217;s smart algorithm relies on data like demographics, population density, job makeup, car ownership status, geography and land use to help cities evaluate where it makes the most sense to deploy a flexible system in the context of what public transit they already have. The goal is by no means to cannibalize public transit, but rather to enhance it, according to Chu.</p>
<p>An agency&#8217;s interaction with the tool is fairly simple. A city planner draws a zone on a map, which immediately populates relevant statistics based on data from existing flexible and on-demand services around the world, including Via&#8217;s over 500 global partnerships and nearly 100 million rides with Remix&#8217;s intelligent transport planning software.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;And you can say, &#8216;If we have the budget for 10 vehicles, what would the waiting time be?&#8217; Or if you want to say, &#8216;I want to ensure a five minute wait time for an on-demand service, maybe that tells me I&#8217;m going to need 15 vehicles instead of 10,'&#8221; said Chu. &#8220;It helps you be very logical about your resources as opposed to this hand-wavy planning which was previously how a lot of these on-demand zones were planned.&#8221;</p>
<p>In Seattle, Remix and Via have been working with the King County Metro to plan transit that links commuters with the fairly new light rail service that runs north to south, and soon, east to west. The county wants to help people get to the train service without necessarily constructing huge parking structures next to the stations, so it&#8217;s been partnering with Via to determine the best way to deploy on-demand zones around all of the new light rail station openings.</p>
<p>“Overall, on-demand planning was super helpful as a starting point for understanding where to draw our service areas and how much service we can provide with our current budget,&#8221; said innovative mobility senior planner <span style="font-weight: 400;"> Casey Gifford in a statement.</span> &#8220;As a non-service planner, I was able to draft proposals and have data-driven, educated conversations with my service planning colleagues.”</p>
<p>Miami-Dade County has been working with Remix for the past two years to redesign its whole transit network, which means there will be cuts to lower performing fixed routes that were only servicing a handful of people.</p>
<p>“I sat down next to the director and drew an on-demand zone to substitute a low-performing fixed route,&#8221; said Carlos Cruz-Casas, assistant director of <span style="font-weight: 400;">Miami-Dade County’s Department of Transportation, in a statement</span>. &#8220;I was able to show that with the same number of vehicles, we can offer better service and save resources that could be reallocated into increasing fixed-route frequency on higher demand routes.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/vias-remix-launches-tool-for-cities-to-plan-on-demand-and-fixed-route-transit-together/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226783</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Martie launches with $3M to divert shelf-stable food items from landfills</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/martie-launches-with-3m-to-divert-shelf-stable-food-items-from-landfills/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/martie-launches-with-3m-to-divert-shelf-stable-food-items-from-landfills/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food sharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kari Morris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kobie Fuller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Louise Fritjofsson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Martie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supermarkets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upfront ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Martie aims to stop food from going into landfills that are thrown away due to package changes, being a seasonal product or reaching their expiration date before purchase.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Companies are attacking food waste in different ways, from developing a better food supply chain to “skins” for produce to food sharing.</p>
<p>And today, <a href="https://martie.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Martie</a> officially enters the market with its approach to stop from going into landfills food that is thrown away due to package changes, being a seasonal product or nearing their best buy date.</p>
<p>Louise Fritjofsson and Kari Morris started the company in January to “rescue” pantry staples and offer them, initially in California, for between 40% and 70% off retail prices. The pair met two years ago. Both previous entrepreneurs, Fritjofsson from the tech side and Morris on the food side, they bonded over wanting to make better-for-you food more accessible and affordable.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227285" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Fritjofsson says there are 13 million Americans who are food insecure and have to make the decision everyday on what to eat, and are often swayed by food that is not as healthy because it is cheaper.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2227288" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2227288" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2227288" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Martie-Website.gif" alt="Martie" width="1024" height="511" /><p id="caption-attachment-2227288" class="wp-caption-text">Martie website. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Martie</p></div></p>
<p>They tested a few different things, including launching five food brands, but kept having a surplus of items they didn’t know what to do with.</p>
<p>“If you don’t have a sustainable approach you shouldn’t do it,” Fritjofsson told TechCrunch. “We thought we were doing the right things, but we still had a surplus. We started talking to food brands about their surplus, and they usually sell it for pennies on the dollar.”</p>
<p>Ironically, they learned that donating surplus food to places like food banks was difficult, cumbersome and the tax credit only went so far. Though brands are usually careful with positioning their inventory in normal retail channels, some 40% of shelf-stable food — around 146 tons — goes to the landfill each year, she added.</p>
<p>Taking a nod from brands that paved the way by providing imperfect or “ugly” fruits and vegetables, Fritjofsson and Morris decided to do the same, but with pantry staples like cookies, coffee, baking ingredients and snacks. Products come in 10 categories, like breakfast, bakeshop, condiments and pastas.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Since the global pandemic started over 18 months ago, consumer behavior toward <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/content/2021-online-grocery-sales-will-surpass-100-billion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">purchasing groceries online</a> became more regular and is expected to grow to $190 billion by 2024. Not only that, but with food prices increasing since September, experts say <a href="https://theweek.com/culture/1006438/this-years-thanksgiving-dinner-could-be-the-most-expensive-meal-in-the-history-of" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this year’s Thanksgiving dinner could be the most expensive meal</a> in the holiday’s history.</p>
<p>Martie comes online with over 400 SKUs and $3 million in funding from Upfront Ventures. The new funding enables the company to make new hires to build efficiencies on the website, form additional buyer relationships and develop marketing.</p>
<p>There is no subscription or membership for Martie. Consumers can go to the website, pick the items they want and check out.</p>
<p>“Our goal is to keep barriers low, so there are no constraints,” Fritjofsson said. “We even have a call-in number in Spanish and English for people who are not comfortable placing an online order.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="StFwiU2ZNj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apeel-bites-into-another-250m-funding-round-at-a-2b-valuation-to-accelerate-fresh-food-supply-chains/">Apeel bites into another $250M funding round, at a $2B valuation, to accelerate fresh food supply chains</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apeel bites into another $250M funding round, at a $2B valuation, to accelerate fresh food supply chains&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apeel-bites-into-another-250m-funding-round-at-a-2b-valuation-to-accelerate-fresh-food-supply-chains/embed/#?secret=StFwiU2ZNj" data-secret="StFwiU2ZNj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Kobie Fuller, partner at Upfront Ventures, says his firm has a history of investing in retail and consumer, with a big emphasis on startups that have an impact on the planet, including Apeel Sciences, which recently brought in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apeel-bites-into-another-250m-funding-round-at-a-2b-valuation-to-accelerate-fresh-food-supply-chains/">$250 million in new funding</a> to continue developing its plant-based layer for the surface of fruits and vegetables that is tasteless and odorless and that keeps moisture in while letting oxygen out.</p>
<p>Fuller heard about what Fritjofsson and Morris were doing and their sustainability approach checked off a lot of boxes for him. The future of food waste will require “a village of companies” and the new wave of investments into this space are necessary to elevate those successes into household names that will be the model for sustainability, he added.</p>
<p>Fuller knew Fritjofsson from a previous company and while he didn’t invest in that one at the time, he thought the concept of Martie was a hit.</p>
<p>“Here is a budding product that rescues foods while offering discounts and does it in a way that the brand is elevated,” he said. “For me, this is brilliant. I am super impressed with Louise and her team and think this is going to be gigantic.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6gb9d9HN9h"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/4-sustainable-industries-where-founders-and-vcs-can-see-green-by-going-green/">4 sustainable industries where founders and VCs can see green by going green</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 sustainable industries where founders and VCs can see green by going green&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/4-sustainable-industries-where-founders-and-vcs-can-see-green-by-going-green/embed/#?secret=6gb9d9HN9h" data-secret="6gb9d9HN9h" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/martie-launches-with-3m-to-divert-shelf-stable-food-items-from-landfills/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227285</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Autonomous delivery startup Nuro lands investment from Google, Tiger Global in new $600 million round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/nuro-lands-investment-from-google-tiger-global-in-new-600-million-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/nuro-lands-investment-from-google-tiger-global-in-new-600-million-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fidelity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2227341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nuro has raised $600 million in a fundraising round led by new investor Tiger Global Management, capital that the autonomous delivery startup will use to ramp up commercial operations. The funding has pushed Nuro&#8217;s valuation to about $8.6 billion — or some 72% higher than a year ago — according to people familiar with the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nuro has raised $600 million in a fundraising round led by new investor Tiger Global Management, capital that the autonomous delivery startup will use to ramp up commercial operations.</p>
<p>The funding has pushed Nuro&#8217;s valuation to about $8.6 billion — or some 72% higher <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/autonomous-delivery-startup-nuro-hits-5-billion-valuation-on-fresh-funding-of-500-million/">than a year ago</a> — according to people familiar with the round who requested to anonymity because they are not authorized to speak for the company. A group of mostly existing investors joined the Series D round, including Baillie Gifford, Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company, China-based venture firm Gaorong Capital, grocery retailer Kroger, SoftBank Vision Fund 1, funds and accounts advised by T. Rowe Price Associates, Inc. and Woven Capital, a venture arm of Toyota subsidiary Woven Planet. Google, a new investor, also joined the round.</p>
<p>&#8220;With the boost of this new funding, we&#8217;re turning our focus to commercializing and scaling the production of our third-generation vehicle at our new facility in Southern Nevada,&#8221; Dave Ferguson, Nuro co-founder and president said in an email to TechCrunch. He added that construction on its manufacturing facility will begin in December and is expected to be completed in 2022.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2227341" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6xjH6EOttQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec-1/">The Nuro EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Nuro EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec-1/embed/#?secret=6xjH6EOttQ" data-secret="6xjH6EOttQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As part of Tuesday&#8217;s funding news, Nuro also announced a five-year partnership with Google Cloud. Securing a cloud computing platform partnership is on the to-do list of any autonomous vehicle company hoping to commercialize. Self-driving vehicles — on the road or in a computer simulation to test the technology— generates vast amounts of data, making cloud services one of the bigger costs for an AV company.</p>
<p>Under this particular deal, Nuro and Google said they will also &#8220;explore opportunities together to strengthen and transform local commerce.&#8221; What&#8217;s unclear is how this partnership and investment in Nuro fits in with Waymo, the former Google self-driving project that spun out to become a standalone business under parent company Alphabet.</p>
<p>Nuro is developing autonomous vehicle technology. Unlike others in the burgeoning segment, Nuro has focused its capital on designing and deploying a low-speed electric self-driving vehicle that transports packages, not people.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Nuro has found a steady and ready stream of investors since former Google engineers Ferguson and Jiajun Zhu founded the company in June 2016. Nuro’s Series A funding round of $92 million, which officially closed in June 2017, included Greylock, Banyan and gave NetEase founder Ding Lei (aka William Ding) a seat on Nuro’s board. Less than two years later, a $940 million investment made by the SoftBank Vision Fund helped push Nuro ahead of numerous other startups attempting to commercialize autonomous vehicle technology.</p>
<p>Nuro has also landed several<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-partnerships/"> high-profile partners</a>. The company has completed or is currently piloting its technology with a number of companies, including fast casual restaurant chain Chipotle, CVS pharmacies, FedEx, Kroger grocery stores and Walmart.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/nuro-lands-investment-from-google-tiger-global-in-new-600-million-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2227341</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
