<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 13:02:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>AcuityMD raises $7M to better track the evolving world of medical hardware</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/acuitymd-raises-7m-to-better-track-the-evolving-world-of-medical-hardware/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/acuitymd-raises-7m-to-better-track-the-evolving-world-of-medical-hardware/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 13:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benchmark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HealthTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medtech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a world defined by tons of noise and little signal, startups that make it easier for consumers to make a choice just make sense. Career Karma helps students pick a tech bootcamp, Stackin’ helps millennials navigate the world of neobank and savings apps, and a new Boston-based company is helping doctors keep track of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a world defined by tons of noise and little signal, startups that make it easier for consumers to make a choice just make sense. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/career-karma-series-a/">Career Karma helps students</a> pick a tech bootcamp, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/stackin-raises-12-6-series-b-to-help-millennials-navigate-the-crowded-fintech-space/">Stackin’ helps millennials</a> navigate the world of neobank and savings apps, and a new Boston-based company is helping doctors keep track of the most up-to-date medical devices on the market.</p>
<p><a href="https://acuitymd.com/about/">AcuityMD</a>, founded in 2019 by Mike Monovoukas, Lee Smith, and Robert Coe, is an enterprise software company that wants to unlock the often siloed world of medical device data. And to do so, it landed a $7 million seed round this week, led by Benchmark.</p>
<p>As part of the deal, Benchmark GP Eric Vishria will join AcuityMD’s board of directors. Ajax Health, which <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/ajax-health-raises-100-million-to-advance-innovations-in-medtech-300927456.html">closed $100 million in 2019</a> to back medtech companies, also participated in the round. With seed capital, Monovoukas said that AcuityMD plans to double its eight-person team by the end of the year, and invest heavily in one specific area: “product, product, product.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>AcuityMD is a data platform that tracks the entire medical device lifecycle &#8211; from the sale of an item to a patient’s outcome after a surgery. It aggregates industry and market data on individual medical devices to give a metadata of sorts on a singular product.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2157014 aligncenter" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png" alt="" width="828" height="537" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png 1468w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png?resize=300,195 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png?resize=768,498 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png?resize=680,441 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 828px) 100vw, 828px" /></p>
<p>“There are 1000s of products being launched each year and so it&#8217;s almost impossible for a surgeon, after they&#8217;ve graduated fellowship or residency to keep track of the latest and greatest medical technology out there,” Monovoukas said. “We view this as a software and coordination problem, where you have all this data out there and it’s inefficient in getting to the decision-maker.”</p>
<p>Monovoukas experienced noticed inefficiencies in medical device management first-hand when a family member needed to go through a series of surgeries.</p>
<p>“What was fascinating to me is that the manufacturer holds a lot of information about what to use, [and] sometimes that didn&#8217;t get disseminated to the right surgeon at the right point of time,” he said. “The fundamental realization I had was that the information flow in this industry was a little bit broken&#8230;It wasn&#8217;t an issue of being competent doctors or surgeons, but a lack of information transfer, which is kind of crazy in a data driven world.”</p>
<p>So, the entrepreneur, who worked at Bain &amp; Company as well as a medical device company prior, began thinking of how to use data to make medical devices more responsive to long-term patient outcomes. While doctor’s were a key stakeholder set to benefit from more information, AcuityMD’s team landed on selling to device manufacturers as their key customer.</p>
<p>Now, part of that reason might be because hospitals and doctors are notoriously a pain to sell to. The other reason, Monovouukas tells me, is that performance data on medical devices is a key signal that Sales teams within manufacturers can use to beef up, and better target, their pitches. The co-founder explained how manufacturers want visibility into the market for their products, ranging from data on where high volume surgeons might need one of their devices to long-term outcomes on certain devices over time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2157013" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png" alt="" width="521" height="468" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png 1245w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png?resize=150,135 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png?resize=300,269 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png?resize=768,690 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png?resize=680,611 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 521px) 100vw, 521px" /></p>
<p>The data could help a sales rep pre-emptively figure out how targeting 10 surgeons for a specific product impacts the manufacturer financially and in context with the rest of the market.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>AcuityMD is teeing itself up to become a real-time database of medical devices. Long-term, it could position itself as a Same Day Shipping service connecting manufacturers to surgeons in high-demand and vital transactions. Monovaukus says that while logistics and inventory is a “visceral” problem for the medical device industry, it doesn’t have a solution in place yet. He could see the startup getting to a point in the future where they can predict inventory levels required at each facility &#8211; similar to how some companies already like <a href="https://www.medinas.com/">Medinas</a>, co-founded by Chloe Alpert, operate and manage within hospital systems.</p>
<p>But for now, AcuityMD thinks it can best use its platform and millions of venture-backed capital outside the provider system. It sources a lot of its data on hospitals and surgeons from Medicare CMS and insurance companies, so leaving no action required on the end of providers.</p>
<p>A challenge will be making sure those data sources are good enough to extract true signals. The startup is still defining good.</p>
<p>“I heard someone once say that any digital health company eventually becomes a healthcare data company,” he said. “We’re approaching things a little bit differently.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/acuitymd-raises-7m-to-better-track-the-evolving-world-of-medical-hardware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157000</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forter raises $300M on a $3B valuation to combat e-commerce fraud</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/forter-raises-300m-on-a-3b-valuation-for-a-platform-to-combat-e-commerce-fraud/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/forter-raises-300m-on-a-3b-valuation-for-a-platform-to-combat-e-commerce-fraud/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[E-commerce is on the rise, but that also means the risk, and occurrence, of e-commerce fraud is, too. Now, Forter, one of the startups building a business to tackle that malicious activity, has closed $300 million in funding &#8212; a sign both of the size of the issue, and its success in tackling it to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">E-commerce is on the rise, but that also means the risk, and occurrence, of e-commerce fraud is, too. Now, <a href="https://www.forter.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forter</a>, one of the startups building a business to tackle that malicious activity, has closed $300 million in funding &#8212; a sign both of the size of the issue, and its success in tackling it to date.</p>
<p>The new funding, a Series F, values Forter at $3 billion &#8212; notable not least because the funding is coming only about <a href="https://www.forter.com/blog/expansion-fraud-fighting-network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">six months since Forter&#8217;s previous round</a>, a $125 million Series E that valued it at over $1.3 billion.</p>
<p>Tiger Global Management is leading this latest equity infusion, with new backers Third Point Ventures and Adage Capital Management, and existing investors Bessemer Venture Partners, Sequoia Capital, March Capital, NewView Capital, Salesforce Ventures and Scale Venture Partners, also involved.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The plan will be to use to the money to expand Forter &#8212; founded in Tel Aviv and now based in New York &#8212; geographically, to bring more functionality into its product, and to look at adjacent areas where Forter might expand its capabilities, either organically or by way of acquisition.</p>
<p>Forter today focuses mainly on identifying fraud at the point of transaction and building an AI-based platform that &#8220;learns&#8221; more behaviors to improve its accuracy; it also builds models that keep more people transacting and helps bring down the number of &#8220;false positives&#8221; where activity that appears suspicious actually is not.</p>
<p>One area on its roadmap for expansion is remediation after the fraud occurs, said Liron Damri, Forter&#8217;s co-founder and president.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our vision is to serve the merchant as the go-to trusted partner for everything, so remediation is definitely on our roadmap,&#8221; he said of potential acquisition targets.</p>
<p>Damri, who co-founded the company with Michael Reitblat, CEO, and Alon Shemesh, chief analyst, said in an interview that the startup &#8212; which works with some 350 large customers like Priceline and Instacart and a growing number of service providers like FreedomPay and Flutterwave, altogether seeing some $250 billion dollars worth of transactions globally last year &#8212; wasn&#8217;t proactively looking for more money.</p>
<p>&#8220;All we wanted to do was go back to run the company,&#8221; he said. &#8220;But in the past six months we’ve seen such a great momentum, doubling revenue and ARR, and seeing our customer volumes grow.&#8221;</p>
<p>That led to a lot of investors proactively reaching out and ask questions, he continued. He described Tiger as a &#8220;kingmaker&#8221; in the category of e-commerce, so it was an easy decision to make, and gave it the &#8220;gas&#8221; it needed to take its next growth steps.</p>
<p>E-commerce has been one of the major technology growth stories of the last year, fueled by a rush of consumers and businesses playing out their lives online at a time when it has been harder, and in some cases impossible, to transact in person.</p>
<p>While we have definitely seen a lot of growth, and growing sophistication, in the number of tools on the market to combat cybercrime, it&#8217;s in some ways an ouroboros of a problem: the more transactions that are made, the more there are that need to be monitored for suspicious activity. And in any case fraud in e-commerce is not exactly going away. It&#8217;s estimated that it will cost retailers <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210425005002/en/Juniper-Research-eCommerce-Losses-to-Online-Payment-Fraud-to-Exceed-20-Billion-Annually-in-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some $20 billion in 2021</a> and is always on the rise.</p>
<p>Forter got its start in 2013 focusing first on monitoring activity on sites wherever customers happened to be to identify suspicious behavior &#8212; a sign that it might be a bot or someone on an illicit spending spree racking up a lot of items in quick succession &#8212; with the bigger concept being to build a network of activity from which to learn and help make more informed decisions over time.</p>
<p>In more recent years, the essence of the issue has expanded somewhat, and also grown more sophisticated. As companies have grown their businesses to reach beyond early adopters and core audiences, and into a more &#8220;omnichannel&#8221; environment beyond basic check-outs on their own sites, so too have the kinds of consumers coming to shop.</p>
<p>This has meant that traditional &#8220;signals&#8221; of legitimate buyers no longer were the same as before &#8212; a predicament that really rose in profile in the last year, as many newcomers came to e-commerce for the first time during the pandemic. In fact, Damri told me that in 2020 there were seven times more &#8220;newcomers&#8221; to sites than in 2019, huge growth of that segment.</p>
<p>So with most of the flagging of suspicious activity coming up at the point of transaction, Forter expanded to analyzing activity there.</p>
<p>As with a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/14/stripe-acquires-bouncer-will-integrate-its-card-authentication-into-the-radar-fraud-detection-tool/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent acquisition of Stripe&#8217;s, Bouncer</a>, to build out its own anti-fraud product, a large part of Forter&#8217;s attention these days is on providing tools to companies to identify suspicious purchasing, but even more than that, to make sure that the many occasions that might look suspicious are not, to help reduce the amount of &#8220;cart abandonment&#8221; and increase conversions.</p>
<p>The old way of doing things, Damri said, involved &#8220;thousands of rules and applying suspicion on everyone. You were guilty unless proved otherwise.&#8221;</p>
<p>Using its AI engine and a some risk analysis (not unlike the kind that, say, an insurance or loan provider might apply in their businesses), Forter turned the proposition on its head.</p>
<p>&#8220;We wanted to approve as much as possible. We wanted to gradually increase the trust you have of your own customers. We changed the sentiment and approach&#8230; especially in areas that were neglected, such as those who saw significant changes in life,&#8221; Damri said. &#8220;This was extremely important as Covid-19 hit.&#8221;</p>
<p>Forter&#8217;s risk tolerance model, it seems, has so far proven out. Damri said that its algorithms applied reduce the total number of declines by 80%, but also reduce the number of chargebacks &#8212; one indicator of a mistake &#8212; by 60%.</p>
<p>This implies that it&#8217;s blocking more of the &#8220;wrong&#8221; kind of purchases, and letting through more of the legitimate ones.  (That is, he pointed out, in addition to a few bad actors Forter intentionally lets buy things, just to learn how they operate. Damri referred to this as &#8220;paid-tuition.&#8221;)</p>
<p>Risk-based approvals, coupled with algorithms to learn what is truly bad, has resonated with customers, and investors.</p>
<p>“With the unprecedented rate of digital transformation and the fierce competition in creating the slickest user experience, superior fraud prevention plays an ever more critical role in e-commerce revenue growth&#8221; said John Curtius, a partner at Tiger Global Management, in a statement. &#8220;After we talked with dozens of customers of every relevant solution in this space, it was very clear to us that Forter is the clear leader in performance and scale.”</p>
<p>“As a longtime investor, it’s been incredible to see Forter’s ascent,” added Ravi Viswanathan, NewView Capital. “It’s a testament to the leadership team’s vision and execution in allowing merchants to provide the seamless experiences customers expect and to be able to accept as many transactions as possible, while still accurately identifying and blocking fraud.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/forter-raises-300m-on-a-3b-valuation-for-a-platform-to-combat-e-commerce-fraud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156814</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atlan raises $16M led by Insight Partners to build a collaboration hub for data-driven teams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/atlan-raises-16m-led-by-insight-partners-to-build-a-collaboration-hub-for-data-driven-teams/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/atlan-raises-16m-led-by-insight-partners-to-build-a-collaboration-hub-for-data-driven-teams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[auren-hoffman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bob Moore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bob muglia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liveramp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safegraph]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snowflake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waterbridge Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Young startup Atlan, which has built a SaaS data collaboration platform and is courting customers in international markets, has now won the trust of some high-profile investors. Atlan said on Tuesday it has raised $16 million in its Series A financing round that was led by Insight Partners. Bob Muglia (former CEO of Snowflake), Bob [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Young startup Atlan, which has built a SaaS data collaboration platform and is courting customers in international markets, has now won the trust of some high-profile investors.</p>
<p>Atlan said on Tuesday it has raised $16 million in its Series A financing round that was led by Insight Partners. Bob Muglia (former CEO of Snowflake), Bob Moore and Jake Stei (founders of Stitch) and Auren Hoffman (founder of Safegraph and Liveramp), and Akshay Kothari (co-founder and COO of Notion) also invested in the round, as did existing investors Sequoia Surge and Waterbridge Ventures.</p>
<p>The startup &#8212; which was founded in India and now has teams across the U.S., Singapore, Philippines, and Nigeria &#8212; operates an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/01/atlan-socialcops/">eponymous data stack that brings together diverse data from internal and external sources</a> such as Snowflake and Databricks to one interface and allows teams to collaborate easily.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The thesis behind Atlan is that the way most people in enterprises deal with data is inefficient. This is because of the fundamental diversity of people involved &#8212; scientists, analysts, engineers, business users &#8212; who all have their own skill sets and tool preferences.</p>
<p>This makes collaboration between the teams a challenge as they struggle to find the right data at the right time, for instance.</p>
<p>It’s a challenge that the founders of Atlan &#8212; Prukalpa Sankar and Varun Banka (pictured above) &#8212; faced first hand at their first venture, SocialCops. The venture was behind several data science for social good projects including India&#8217;s National Data Platform and SDGs global monitoring in collaboration with the United Nations.</p>
<p><a href="https://atlan.com">Atlan</a> started out as an internal tool to help the data team at SocialCops carry out projects more efficiently, before being opened up to teams around the world.</p>
<p>“We are reimagining the human experience with data &#8212; why can’t data assets be shared as easily as sharing a link on Google Docs, or if Google Analytics can tell you usage on a website, why can’t we do the same for our data?” said Sankar.</p>
<p>Teddie Wardi, Managing Director at Insight Partners, likened Atlan’s relevance to companies just as Figma is crucial to design teams and Github is important to engineering teams.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1851098" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1851098" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1851098 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?w=680" alt="Atlan Discovery 2" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg 5184w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1851098" class="wp-caption-text">Dashboard of Atlan (Atlan)</p></div></p>
<p>In an interview with TechCrunch, Sankar said more than 60% of Atlan&#8217;s clients today are in the U.S., and the market will be a big focus as the startup scales. She declined to reveal the number of clients the startup has amassed, but said the startup has grown 16X times in the last two quarters.</p>
<p>Some of its clients include giants such as Unilever, Scripps Health, Postman, and Techstyle, one of the world’s largest membership-based fashion firms with a diverse portfolio of brands including Fabletics, Savage X Fenty, JustFab, FabKids, and ShoeDazzle.</p>
<p>“As we rolled-out our modern data platform, we were looking for a product that made it easier to democratize our data and was less dependent on someone central answering each individual analyst’s questions on a one-off basis. Legacy solutions in the market were tailored to legacy systems and approaches where IT or a single data stewardship team owns the data,&#8221; said Danielle Boeglin Ragan, Vice President of Data &amp; Analytics at Techstyle, in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;Atlan was the only solution that was built for a collaborative, bottom-up approach. With native integrations with our modern analytics stack like Snowflake and Tableau, Atlan was very easy to set-up &#8211; we had all of our data sources flowing within the first day.”</p>
<p>The startup plans to deploy the fresh capital to expand its team of 40 people across marketing, sales, and customer success, said Banka.</p>
<p>“Atlan has become a valuable resource for the data team to get context about data. In the long run, for our data democratization vision, we see the entire organization working towards analyzing the data and taking actions in a coherent, seamless fashion. Having Atlan in the mix of our toolchains opens the possibility of providing data context at scale, thereby enabling the entire org to be data aware and data driven.” said Prudhvi Vasa, Analytics Leader at Postman, in a statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/atlan-raises-16m-led-by-insight-partners-to-build-a-collaboration-hub-for-data-driven-teams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indoor farming company Bowery raises $300M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indoor-farming-company-bowery-raises-300m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indoor-farming-company-bowery-raises-300m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bowery Farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fidelity Management & Research Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indoor farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vertical farming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New York City-based vertical farming startup Bowery Farming this week has announced a $300 million Series C. The round, which brings its total funding north of $472 million, values the company at $2.3 billion. Fidelity Management &#38; Research Company led the beefy round, with participation from existing investors GV (formerly Google Ventures), General Catalyst, GGV [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">New York City-based vertical farming startup Bowery Farming this week has announced a $300 million Series C. The round, which brings its total funding north of $472 million, values the company at $2.3 billion.</p>
<p>Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company led the beefy round, with participation from existing investors GV (formerly Google Ventures), General Catalyst, GGV Capital, Temasek and Groupe Artémis. Amplo and Gaingels participated, as well, along with some celebrity individual investors, including Lewis Hamilton, Chris Paul, Natalie Portman, José Andrés and Justin Timberlake.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pAEJna7Mb9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/12/bowery-an-indoor-farming-startup-raises-90-million-more-including-to-counter-a-softbank-funded-rival/">Bowery, an indoor farming startup, raises $90 million more, including to counter a SoftBank-funded rival</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bowery, an indoor farming startup, raises $90 million more, including to counter a SoftBank-funded rival&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/12/bowery-an-indoor-farming-startup-raises-90-million-more-including-to-counter-a-softbank-funded-rival/embed/#?secret=pAEJna7Mb9" data-secret="pAEJna7Mb9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The funding comes as Bowery has experienced some impressive real-world growth, touting a 750% increase in availability since January of last year. If anything, the company appears to have thrived during the pandemic. Its vertically farmed produce is now available in 850 grocery stores, including big-name chains like Albertsons (incl. Safeway and Acme), Giant Food, Walmart and Whole Foods.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156871" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156871" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2156871" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1280" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=120,150 120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=240,300 240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=768,960 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=544,680 544w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=1229,1536 1229w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=1638,2048 1638w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=40,50 40w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156871" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bowery Farming</p></div></p>
<p>Amazon Fresh has also provided a sizable e-commerce footprint &#8212; a big must during the pandemic-fueled shutdowns of the past year.</p>
<p>“This infusion of new capital from Fidelity, other new investors, and the additional support of our long-term investor partners is acknowledgement of the critical need for new solutions to our current agricultural system, and the enormous economic opportunity that comes with supporting our mission,” CEO Irving Fain said in a release. “This funding not only fuels our continued expansion but the ongoing development of our proprietary technology, which sits at the core of our business and our ability to rapidly and efficiently scale towards an increasingly important opportunity in front of us.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156873" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156873" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2156873" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="819" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg 3540w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=680,544 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=1536,1229 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=2048,1638 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156873" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bowery Farming</p></div></p>
<p>The company says the massive windfall will go toward expanding its indoor farms to additional locations in the United States, as well as investing in headcount and R&amp;D. Included in the former is a new site located in an industrial area in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, which Bowery says will be its largest to date.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yl8gcjBRJM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/bowery-farming-adds-executives-as-it-expands-to-sell-produce-in-650-stores/">Bowery Farming adds executives as it expands to sell produce in 650 stores</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bowery Farming adds executives as it expands to sell produce in 650 stores&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/bowery-farming-adds-executives-as-it-expands-to-sell-produce-in-650-stores/embed/#?secret=yl8gcjBRJM" data-secret="yl8gcjBRJM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wMjvNQNZzB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/farmland-could-be-the-next-big-asset-class-modernized-by-marketplace-startups/">Farmland could be the next big asset class modernized by marketplace startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Farmland could be the next big asset class modernized by marketplace startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/farmland-could-be-the-next-big-asset-class-modernized-by-marketplace-startups/embed/#?secret=wMjvNQNZzB" data-secret="wMjvNQNZzB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indoor-farming-company-bowery-raises-300m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156818</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canvas lands $20M so tech&#8217;s biggest companies can find diverse talent</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/canvas-lands-20m-so-techs-biggest-companies-can-find-diverse-talent/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/canvas-lands-20m-so-techs-biggest-companies-can-find-diverse-talent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board member]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canvas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jumpstart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lachy Groom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Vernal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ben Herman and Adam Gefkovicz launched Jumpstart in 2017 with a clear mission: to make the world more equitable via a more fair and balanced hiring process. The company released its “Diversity Recruitment Platform” in July of 2018 with the aim of helping people earlier in their careers get a “jumpstart&#8221; via technology. Over the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ben Herman and Adam Gefkovicz </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">launched Jumpstart in 2017 with a clear mission: to make the world more equitable via a more fair and balanced hiring process.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company released its “Diversity Recruitment Platform” in July of 2018 with the aim of helping people earlier in their careers get a “jumpstart&#8221; via technology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the years, the startup’s mission has evolved beyond helping college grads to helping all employees &#8212; regardless of career stage &#8212; get a fair shot at jobs. And it’s doing that by teaming up with hundreds of companies &#8212; such as Airbnb, Bloomberg, Coinbase, Samsung, Lyft, Pinterest, Plaid, Roblox, Audible, Headspace and Stripe &#8212; to help them hire a more diverse pool of candidates.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FcNivBPIxm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/18/jumpstart-nabs-8-5m-led-by-sequoia-for-a-recruitment-platform-that-aims-to-increase-diversity/">Jumpstart nabs $8.5M led by Sequoia for a recruitment platform that aims to increase diversity</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jumpstart nabs $8.5M led by Sequoia for a recruitment platform that aims to increase diversity&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/18/jumpstart-nabs-8-5m-led-by-sequoia-for-a-recruitment-platform-that-aims-to-increase-diversity/embed/#?secret=FcNivBPIxm" data-secret="FcNivBPIxm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Demand has accelerated exponentially, and the San Francisco-based startup saw its revenue grow “3x” in 2020 compared to 2019, although execs declined to provide hard figures. Considering its broadened focus, Jumpstart has rebranded to </span><a href="http://canvas.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Canvas</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and announced today that it has closed on $20 million in funding. Early Stripe employee and angel investor Lachy Groom and</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Sequoia Capital co-led the round, which included participation from Four Rivers Capital. The raise brings Canvas&#8217; total raised to $32.5 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We knew we were only scratching the surface of our vision, and knew we had a solution that could reimagine diversity hiring for everyone,” said co-founder and CEO Ben Herman. “You know how everyone has a CRM? We believe every company should have a DRP, which is a diversity recruitment platform. That&#8217;s the category we want to create and we want to be the largest in that space.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No doubt that the Black Lives Matter movement in the aftermath of George Floyd’s murder helped, well jumpstart, the company’s efforts. Canvas is able to sell its offering as more companies “are being held accountable for their promises of equity and hiring diverse talent,” Herman said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Hiring diverse teams is not only a matter of corporate social responsibility,” he added. “Diversity and inclusion are a competitive advantage and strategic priority for every company in today’s landscape. We believe representation is a huge part of what we stand for. So we want everyone to be able to create their own canvas, and to be able to paint their own picture.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Canvas describes its SaaS offering as a “fully virtual” recruiting platform that is based on self-reported data. About 87% of candidates on its platform disclose their demographic information (which it says is 7x the industry standard), according to the startup. Canvas also says it gives companies the ability to narrow down the priority groups and talent it wants to focus on by filtering over 75+ self-reported candidate data points. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup claims that it’s different from others in the space for that reason, among other features.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Unlike other solutions that might utilize inferred data that could be inaccurate or illegal, Canvas helps create a more accurate data set to identify diverse candidates, helping to solve the core problem of talent discovery,” Herman said. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GCHOcmhcUX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/on-the-diversity-front-2020-may-prove-a-tipping-point/">On the diversity front, 2020 may prove a tipping point</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;On the diversity front, 2020 may prove a tipping point&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/on-the-diversity-front-2020-may-prove-a-tipping-point/embed/#?secret=GCHOcmhcUX" data-secret="GCHOcmhcUX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also &#8212; unlike some diversity hiring platforms &#8212; does not rely on artificial intelligence, a fact that Herman is actually proud of.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We don&#8217;t believe that AI is the future. It&#8217;s not about getting someone&#8217;s gender or ethnicity based off of their name, or to inform the hiring decision without candidates knowing,” Herman told TechCrunch. “It&#8217;s all about how to empower talent to self-identify&#8230;We want to enable the talent to own their data, and truly be able to represent themselves in unique ways. That’s not leveraging AI.”</span></p>
<p>Canvas also gives companies a way to design, promote and run events, such as webinars, aimed at hiring diverse talent.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup also wants to get to a place where companies are working together “to complete the diversity data gap.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The problem is about accessibility, and so we want to give equal access to anyone and everyone &#8212; from all companies to all candidates,” Herman said. “And so that is really the most important part of what we are creating &#8212; the ability for companies to share data.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, how does it measure its own success? Canvas claims that 56% of all hires on the Canvas platform are made from underrepresented groups (URGs), and that it helps employers achieve a 30% reduction in time to hire.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Herman is not your typical startup founder, having dropped out of high school and starting his own recruitment agency at the age of 21. His tenacity is one of the things that attracted Sequoia partner and Canvas board member Mike Vernal to back the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When we first met Ben, it was clear that he was&#8230;a natural-born talent scout,” Vernal told TechCrunch. “He thought there was a better way for the industry to work &#8212; one where companies and recruiters were more collaborative and used technology to build stronger, more diverse teams.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since its initial investment in the company, Vernal believes building diverse teams has never been more important.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Those teams create better products, make stronger business decisions, and it’s just the right thing to do,” he said. “We believe companies can do a better job sourcing underrepresented talent using Canvas than on their own.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Canvas plans to use its new capital to expand the product into other industries and verticals beyond technology and continue to address the recruiting process for later stages of people&#8217;s careers. The company currently has 70 employees and expects to have 100 by the end of 2021.</span></p>
<p>As mentioned above, hiring diverse talent is becoming a bigger priority for big tech companies (such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/hp-outlines-ambitious-diversity-goals/">HP</a>) and startups alike. Earlier this year, diverse hiring startup SeekOut <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/seekout-raises-65m/">raised $65 million</a>. The company has built out a database with hundreds of millions of profiles using its AI-powered talent search engine and “deep interactive analytics.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WOvNmRQXB5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/as-companies-prioritize-diversity-startups-are-trying-to-productize-diverse-hiring/">As companies prioritize diversity, startups are trying to productize diverse hiring</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As companies prioritize diversity, startups are trying to productize diverse hiring&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/as-companies-prioritize-diversity-startups-are-trying-to-productize-diverse-hiring/embed/#?secret=WOvNmRQXB5" data-secret="WOvNmRQXB5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/canvas-lands-20m-so-techs-biggest-companies-can-find-diverse-talent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156678</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sinch, a Swedish customer engagement giant, raises $1.1B, SoftBank and Temasek participating</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/sinch-a-swedish-customer-engagement-giant-raises-1-1b-softbank-and-temasek-participating/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/sinch-a-swedish-customer-engagement-giant-raises-1-1b-softbank-and-temasek-participating/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[APIs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sinch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sinch &#8212; a Twilio competitor based out of Sweden that provides a suite of services to companies to build communications and specifically &#8220;customer engagement&#8221; into their services by way of APIs &#8212; has been on a steady funding and acquisitions march in the last several months to scale its business, and today comes the latest [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.sinch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sinch</a> &#8212; a Twilio competitor based out of Sweden that provides a suite of services to companies to build communications and specifically &#8220;customer engagement&#8221; into their services by way of APIs &#8212; has been on a steady funding and acquisitions march in the last several months to scale its business, and today comes the latest development on that front.</p>
<p>The company has <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/sinch-ab-publ-sinch-completes-220300243.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that it has raised another $1.1 billion in a direct share issue, with significant chunks of that funding coming from Temasek and SoftBank, in order to continue building its business.</p>
<p>Specifically, the company &#8212; which is traded on the Swedish stock exchange Nasdaq Stockhom and currently has a market cap of around $11 billion &#8212; said that it was making a new share issue of 7,232,077 shares at SEK 1,300 per share, raising approximately SEK 9.4 billion (equivalent to around $1.1 billion at current rates).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sinch said that investors buying the shares included &#8220;selected Swedish and international investors of institutional character,&#8221; highlighting that Temasek and SB Management (a direct subsidiary of SoftBank Group Corp.) would  respectively take SEK 2,085 million and 0.7 million shares. This works out to a $252 million investment for Temasek, and $110 million for SoftBank.</p>
<p>SoftBank last December took a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/softbank-takes-a-690m-stake-in-cloud-based-swedish-crm-company-sinch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$690 million stake in Sinch</a> (when it was valued <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/sinch-inteliquent/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">at $8.2 billion). That was just ahead of the company scooping</a> up Inteliquent in the U.S. in January for $1.14 billion to move a little closer to Twilio&#8217;s home turf.</p>
<p>Sinch is not saying much more beyond the announcement of the share issue for now, except that the raise was made to shore up its financial position ahead of more M&amp;A activity.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sinch has an active M&amp;A-agenda and a track record of successful acquisitions, making [it] well placed to drive continued consolidation of the messaging and [communications platform as a service, CPaaS] market,&#8221; it said in a short statement. &#8220;Furthermore, the increased financial flexibility that the directed new share issue entails further strengthens the Company’s position as a relevant and competitive buyer.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company is profitable and active in more than 40 markets, and <a href="https://investors.sinch.com/static-files/6d18a742-dd9f-40af-a973-ff69163aa56b" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CEO Oscar Werner said in Sinch&#8217;s most recent earnings report</a> that in the last quarter alone that its communications APIs &#8212; which works across  channels like SMS, WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, chatbots, voice and video &#8212; handled 40 billion mobile messages.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Notably, its strategy has a strong foothold in the U.S. because of the Inteliquent acquisition. It will be interesting to see how and if it continues to consolidate to build up market share in that part of the world, or whether it focuses elsewhere, given the heft of two very strong Asian investors now in its stable. </span></p>
<p>“Becoming a leader in the U.S. voice market is key to establish Sinch as the leading global cloud communications platform,” said Werner in January.</p>
<p>While Sinch has focused much of its business, like Twilio, around an API-based model focused on communications services, its acquisition of Inteliquent also gave it access to a large, legacy Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS) product set, aimed at telcos to provide off-net call termination (when a call is handed off from one carrier to another) and toll-free numbers.</p>
<p>Tellingly, when Sinch acquired Inteliquent, the two divisions each accounted for roughly half of its total business, but the CPaaS business is growing at twice the rate of IaaS, which points to how Sinch views the future for itself, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/sinch-a-swedish-customer-engagement-giant-raises-1-1b-softbank-and-temasek-participating/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156966</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google&#8217;s data terms are now in Germany&#8217;s competition crosshairs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/googles-data-terms-are-now-in-germanys-competition-crosshairs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/googles-data-terms-are-now-in-germanys-competition-crosshairs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreas Mundt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bundeskartellamt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Court of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Germany&#8217;s national competition regulator, the Bundeskartellamt, has continued its investigative charge against big tech &#8212; announcing that it&#8217;s opened two proceedings into Google. The move follows earlier proceedings targeting Amazon and Facebook &#8212; both of which are also looking to determine whether their businesses are of “paramount significance for competition across markets”, as German competition law [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Germany&#8217;s national competition regulator, the <em>Bundeskartellamt</em>, has continued its investigative charge against big tech &#8212; <a href="https://www.bundeskartellamt.de/SharedDocs/Meldung/EN/Pressemitteilungen/2021/25_05_2021_Google_19a.html?nn=3591568">announcing</a> that it&#8217;s opened two proceedings into Google.</p>
<p>The move follows earlier proceedings targeting <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/amazons-market-power-to-be-tested-in-germany-in-push-for-early-action-over-antitrust-risks/">Amazon</a> and Facebook &#8212; both of which are also looking to determine whether their businesses are of “paramount significance for competition across markets”, as German competition law puts it. (The regulator is also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/facebook-hit-with-antitrust-probe-for-tying-oculus-use-to-facebook-accounts/">probing Facebook&#8217;s tying of Oculus to Facebook accounts</a>.)</p>
<p>In Google&#8217;s case, one of the <em>Bundeskartellamt&#8217;s </em>new proceedings will confirm whether amended competition rules, which came into force in January, apply in its case &#8212; which would enable the FCO to target it with proactive interventions in the interests of fostering digital competition.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The second, parallel procedure will see the Federal Cartel Office (FCO) undertake an in-depth analysis of Google&#8217;s data processing terms in a move that looks intended to avoid wasting time &#8212; i.e. that its working assumption is that Google/Alphabet&#8217;s business meets the legal bar in the GWB Digitalisation Act.</p>
<p>By running the two Google procedures in parallel the German competition regulator will be in a position to act faster &#8212; assuming the first proceeding confirms it can indeed intervene.</p>
<p>The second probe running alongside would then identify potential problems to shape any intervention &#8212; with the FCO saying for example that it will look at whether Google/Alphabet &#8220;makes the use of services conditional on the users agreeing to the processing of their data without giving them sufficient choice as to whether, how and for what purpose such data are processed&#8221;.</p>
<p>It also says it will &#8220;examine the extent to which the terms provide Google with an opportunity to process data on an extensive cross-service basis&#8221; and will seek to clarify &#8220;how the company’s data processing policy applies to the processing of user data obtained from third-party websites and apps&#8221; (such as through Google’s advertising services).</p>
<p>Another key element of the proceeding will aim to establish what choice users actually have with regard to Google’s processing of their data, with the FCO noting that protecting consumer choice is a primary aim of competition law.</p>
<p>Given those point of focus it&#8217;s possible to imagine a future order from the FCO to Google could require it to simplify how it asks users for consent, to ensure genuine choice &#8212; and also shrink its ability to link first party user data with information obtained on people elsewhere online.</p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Andreas Mundt, president of the <em>Bundeskartellamt</em> said: &#8220;An ecosystem which extends across various markets may be an indication that a company holds such a market position [i.e. whether it is of paramount significance across markets]. It is often very difficult for other companies to challenge this position of power. Due to the large number of digital services offered by Google, such as the Google search engine, YouTube, Google Maps, the Android operating system or the Chrome browser, the company could be considered to be of paramount significance for competition across markets.”</p>
<p>“Google’s business model relies to a very large extent on processing data relating to its users. Due to its established access to data relevant for competition, Google enjoys a strategic advantage. We will therefore take a close look at the company’s data processing terms. A key question in this context is whether consumers wishing to use Google’s services have sufficient choice as to how Google will use their data,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Reached for comment on the FCO proceedings, Google said it will fully cooperate with the FCO&#8217;s process but rejected the charge that people are forced to use its services &#8212; further claiming in a statement attributed to spokesperson, Ralf Bremer, that it offers &#8220;simple controls&#8221; so people can &#8220;limit&#8221; its use of their information:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;People choose Google because it’s helpful, not because they&#8217;re forced to, or because they can&#8217;t find alternatives. German consumers have enormous choice online and we give people simple <a href="https://safety.google/privacy/ads-and-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://safety.google/privacy/ads-and-data/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1622026087917000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGWH9M-MbTvhZXYsWSJZ4Y_l-LVaw">controls</a> to manage their information and limit the use of personal data. We will cooperate fully with the German Competition Authority and look forward to answering their questions.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The <em>Bundeskartellamt</em>&#8216;s in-depth prove of Google&#8217;s data processing terms picks up on long running criticism that the tech giant relies on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/25/facebook-google-face-first-gdpr-complaints-over-forced-consent/">forced and/or manipulative consent from users</a> to obtain their data. Whereas the pan-EU legal standard if consent is used as a legal basis to process people&#8217;s information is that it should be clear, informed and freely given.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wBKkiuOA6Y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/25/facebook-google-face-first-gdpr-complaints-over-forced-consent/">Facebook, Google face first GDPR complaints over &#8216;forced consent&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook, Google face first GDPR complaints over &#8216;forced consent&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/25/facebook-google-face-first-gdpr-complaints-over-forced-consent/embed/#?secret=wBKkiuOA6Y" data-secret="wBKkiuOA6Y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Back in 2019 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/french-data-protection-watchdog-fines-google-57-million-under-the-gdpr/">Google was fined $57M</a> by France&#8217;s data protection watchdog under the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) over a failure to provide “sufficiently clear” information to Android users when it sought their consent to use their data for targeted ads.</p>
<p>However, subsequent to the CNIL&#8217;s action, the tech giant limited its exposure to the privacy regulation by <a href="https://www.blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/some-changes-our-service-model-europe/">changing the legal jurisdiction</a> of where it processes European users’ data to Ireland.</p>
<p>The Irish Data Protection Commission (DPC) then became Google&#8217;s lead data supervisor under the GDPR&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism. And the DPC has not decided a single GDPR complaint against Google &#8212; though it has a number of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/22/googles-lead-eu-regulator-opens-formal-privacy-probe-of-its-adtech/">open investigations</a>. It continues to face high level criticism over its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/lack-of-big-tech-gdpr-decisions-looms-large-in-eu-watchdogs-annual-report/">enforcement record</a> on key cross-border cases against big tech.</p>
<p>The awakening of European competition regulators to the issue of how abuse of user privacy is an anti-competitive tactic that can lock in the dominance of digital giants by unfairly enabling them to grab and link people&#8217;s data is thus a very important development in the regulation of big tech &#8212; and one where the <em>Bundeskartellamt </em>has already been a pioneer.</p>
<p>In an earlier FCO <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/antitrust-case-against-facebooks-super-profiling-back-on-track-after-german-federal-court-ruling/">&#8216;super profiling&#8217; case against Facebook</a> &#8212; which predates the amendments to national digital competition law &#8212; it ordered the social media behemoth not to combine user data from across its different products.</p>
<p>Facebook has sought to block the order in the German courts. And, back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/competition-challenge-to-facebooks-superprofiling-of-users-sparks-referral-to-europes-top-court/">March</a>, the case was referred to Europe&#8217;s top court &#8212; meaning the FCO&#8217;s order to it remains on hold pending the CJEU&#8217;s ruling (which could take years to be handed down).</p>
<p>The FCO confirmed today that the Facebook case is still pending before the court, reiterating <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">the decision of the </span><span lang="de" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" xml:lang="de">Düsseldorf</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> Higher Regional Court to refer certain issues relating to the application of the GDPR to the European Court of Justice &#8212; which means that a decision on the merits of the case &#8220;can only be rendered after these issues have been clarified&#8221;.</span></p>
<p>The <em>Bundeskartellamt&#8217;s</em> investigation of Facebook&#8217;s data practices started all the way back in in March 2016. So it&#8217;s a safe bet that the regulator&#8217;s experience of digging into the detail of how tech giants process people&#8217;s data &#8212; and how hard it is to make cases stick against them &#8212; has helped inform the amendments to Germany&#8217;s competition law that introduce ex ante powers to tackle digital giants deemed to be of “paramount significance for competition across markets”.</p>
<p>Although there is still another waiting period baked in to this approach &#8212; as the regulator must first assess whether tech giants meet that legal bar.</p>
<p>The EU has proposed a similar ex ante approach for what it dubs as digital &#8220;gatekeepers&#8221;, under the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/">Digital Markets Act</a>, which it introduced at the end of last year.</p>
<p>Although with the bloc&#8217;s co-legislative process ongoing that regulation is likely some years away from adoption and pan-EU application &#8212; meaning Germany&#8217;s national law and the energetic FCO could be a significant actor in the meanwhile.</p>
<p>The EU&#8217;s competition commission are also <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-google-antitrust-eu-idUSKBN29P23U">digging into Google&#8217;s adtech practices</a> &#8212; though they&#8217;re having to do so under existing powers, for now, which have been shown to be a painstakingly slow and not very effective route to tackle digital market power.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in Europe, the UK, which now sits outside the bloc, is also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/uk-to-set-up-pro-competition-regulator-to-put-limits-on-big-tech/">shaping its own an ex ante regime</a> to curb the market power of digital giants. So regardless of political cross-currents in the region &#8212; and the problem of patchy privacy enforcement &#8212; there is growing consensus that European competition authorities must be empowered to step in proactively to tackle digital market abuses.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gA1j2bLoGk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/">Europe lays out its plan to reboot digital rules and tame tech giants</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe lays out its plan to reboot digital rules and tame tech giants&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/embed/#?secret=gA1j2bLoGk" data-secret="gA1j2bLoGk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a1ii3QU7iS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/embed/#?secret=a1ii3QU7iS" data-secret="a1ii3QU7iS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e4NmsbIKEv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/the-uks-plan-to-tackle-big-tech-wont-be-one-sized-fits-all/">The UK&#8217;s plan to tackle big tech won&#8217;t be one-size fits all</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The UK&#8217;s plan to tackle big tech won&#8217;t be one-size fits all&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/the-uks-plan-to-tackle-big-tech-wont-be-one-sized-fits-all/embed/#?secret=e4NmsbIKEv" data-secret="e4NmsbIKEv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/googles-data-terms-are-now-in-germanys-competition-crosshairs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156947</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weight-loss platform Noom bulks up on $540 million in new funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/weight-loss-platform-noom-bulks-up-on-540-million-in-new-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/weight-loss-platform-noom-bulks-up-on-540-million-in-new-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silver lake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight loss]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since the pandemic began last year, nearly 61% of adults in the United States gained weight, with the average adult surveyed gaining 15 pounds, according to a report from the American Psychological Association. Likely as a result of that rise in girths, Noom witnessed a surge of demand for its weight-loss app, generating $400 million in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Since the pandemic began last year, nearly 61% of adults in the United States gained weight, with the average adult surveyed gaining 15 pounds, according to <a href="https://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/stress/2021/one-year-pandemic-stress">a report</a> from the American Psychological Association. Likely as a result of that rise in girths, <a href="https://www.noom.com">Noom</a> witnessed a surge of demand for its weight-loss app, generating $400 million in revenues in 2020 — almost twice <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/monicamelton/2020/01/14/weight-loss-app-noom-quadruples-revenue-again-this-time-to-237-million/?sh=25fec78660f2">the $237 million it made the year before</a>.</p>
<p>Following on the heels of a banner year, and to fuel expansion into new categories and new countries around the globe, Noom announced this morning it had raised a $540 million Series F round led by Silver Lake. Other investors who participated in the round included Oak HC/FT, Temasek, Novo Holdings, Sequoia Capital, RRE, and Samsung Ventures.</p>
<p>“Most people want to eat healthier, exercise more, be less stressed, and get better sleep, but it’s not easy to change these behaviors,” said Saeju Jeong, co-founder and CEO of Noom in a statement. “This strategic round of funding reflects our investors’ confidence in the immense opportunity we have in building a business around helping as many people as possible live healthier lives through behavior change.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Noom also announced the addition of two new board members, Silver Lake managing director Adam Karol, and former TaskRabbit CEO Stacy Brown-Philpot.</p>
<p>The Noom app may be a success now with 45 million downloads to date in 100 countries including the U.S., UK, Canada, Australia, Ireland, and New Zealand, but cofounders Jeong and Artem Petakov officially founded their startup in 2007 as a different venture entirely, experimenting with a connected bike and calorie-counting app. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/07/05/noom-weight-loss-coach-gets-a-revamp-after-hitting-13-5m-organic-downloads-on-android/">It had some early success</a>, but it wasn’t until 2017, when Jeong and Petakov released a customer-focused and weight-loss-oriented app that the startup finally hit its stride, resonating with legions of people who longed to shed the weight they’d gained. The company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/06/heath-coaching-app-noom-will-expand-its-product-team-after-raising-58m-led-by-sequoia/">raised $58 million of funding</a> in mid-2019 led by Sequoia.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cEOHJVXy4t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/06/heath-coaching-app-noom-will-expand-its-product-team-after-raising-58m-led-by-sequoia/">Health coaching app Noom will expand its product team after raising $58M led by Sequoia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Health coaching app Noom will expand its product team after raising $58M led by Sequoia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/06/heath-coaching-app-noom-will-expand-its-product-team-after-raising-58m-led-by-sequoia/embed/#?secret=cEOHJVXy4t" data-secret="cEOHJVXy4t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“If you go and you say, ‘Hey, I can solve hypertension for you, nobody cares,” explains Noom president and co-founder Artem Petakov. “So we put our heads together, and thought, ‘how do you make it work with consumers?’ Well, weight loss is a human value proposition that’s working. Can we double-down on that?”</p>
<p>Though the Noom app enables users to count the number of calories they consume each day — a feature that other apps like MyFitnessPal, LoseIt!, and MyPlate Calorie Counter share — Noom says the key to its users keeping the weight off in the medium-to-long term lies in its use of Cognitive Behavioral Therapy, a goal-oriented psychotherapy treatment that helps people understand and combat the things that trigger negative thoughts, compulsive actions, and unwelcome consequences.</p>
<p>Whether Noom can maintain its momentum remains to be seen. According to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-18/noom-is-said-to-get-silver-lake-backing-ahead-of-potential-ipo?sref=T1S3vg3f">a Bloomberg report</a> last week, the startup has reportedly met with potential advisers to gear up for an IPO later this year or early next year with a targeted valuation of nearly $10 billion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/weight-loss-platform-noom-bulks-up-on-540-million-in-new-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156918</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Affirm spinout Resolve raises $60M for its B2B &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/affirm-spinout-resolve-raises-60m-for-its-b2b-buy-now-pay-later-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/affirm-spinout-resolve-raises-60m-for-its-b2b-buy-now-pay-later-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alda Leu Dennis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clocktower Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commerce ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[haystack vc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initialized capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Levchin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online selling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resolve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156852</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buy now, pay later is everywhere these days, mostly focused on the consumer. Resolve &#8212; a San Francisco-based startup in the space specializing in &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; capabilities for B2B transactions &#8212; announced today that it has raised $60 million in funding. Initialized Capital led the round &#8212; the company’s first funding since its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buy now, pay later is everywhere these days, mostly focused on the consumer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Resolve &#8212; a San Francisco-based startup in the space specializing in &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; capabilities for B2B transactions &#8212; announced today that it has raised $60 million in funding. Initialized Capital led the round &#8212; the company’s first funding since its 2019 inception. KSD Capital, Haystack VC, Commerce Ventures, Clocktower Ventures and others also participated.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The funding is a combination of equity and asset funding according to co-founder and CEO Chris Tsai, although he declined to reveal the breakdown.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since launching as a spinout from Affirm in 2019, Resolve says it has seen “overwhelming” demand for its B2B buy now, pay later (BNPL) billing offering for business purchases. Notably, the two companies refer business to each other. Tsai describes Affirm founder Max Levchin as a “friend” with whom he has been working in a variety of capacities since 2012. (He’s also reportedly an investor in the company.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike Affirm &#8212; which is more focused on the consumer &#8212; Resolve is exclusively focused on business-to-business billing by automating the process of billing and purchasing on credit. What it’s doing is basically allowing businesses to defer payments digitally and on better terms than what they’ve seen historically via an automated underwriting process, the company claims. This, it says, can lead to faster invoice payment and thus, improved cash flow. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company also claims it can offer</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> extended payment terms with buyers not having to pay any interest or fees if accounts are repaid within the agreed-upon terms. Meanwhile, merchants receive full payment (minus any fees) as soon as an order is placed. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2TQh1NMC2E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/in-the-buy-now-pay-later-wars-paypal-is-primed-for-dominance/">In the &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; wars, PayPal is primed for dominance</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;In the &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; wars, PayPal is primed for dominance&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/in-the-buy-now-pay-later-wars-paypal-is-primed-for-dominance/embed/#?secret=2TQh1NMC2E" data-secret="2TQh1NMC2E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Resolve offers businesses loan terms ranging from 30 to 90 days and gives them more control of their billing and cash flow, according to Tsai. While he declined to give specifics around any growth metrics, he said the company has seen a &#8220;significant and meaningful&#8221; uptick in growth in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic because of so many businesses&#8217; shift to digital e-commerce. For example, one of its customers is a bike merchant that had to expand into online selling in the wake of the pandemic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is not a new transaction type, but being able to do it in this new digital or e-commerce way of buy now, pay later, like Affirm &#8212; that&#8217;s very new and in fact it&#8217;s still very much not the norm yet,” he told TechCrunch. “But we&#8217;re finding, especially post-pandemic, incredible demand for switching to more digital e-commerce payment formats.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156856" style="width: 1013px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156856" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2156856 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg" alt="" width="1003" height="781" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg 1003w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg?resize=150,117 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg?resize=300,234 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg?resize=768,598 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg?resize=680,529 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1003px) 100vw, 1003px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156856" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Resolve</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Among Resolve’s features is a “Smart Credit Engine,” which the company says creates a direct sync with a merchant’s real-time data feed of past payment histories to allow for “immediate” credit line decisioning with no input required from buyers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its embedded bill payment portal gives its B2B customers a way to pay vendor bills “while building their business credit history” bureaus, the company says.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Digital and e-commerce transformation is coming for B2B payments,” Tsai said. “Growing companies must balance heightened demand for deferring payments from their business customers with their own limited capacities to satisfy that demand.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The embedded nature of Resolve’s platform gives it an edge, Tsai believes, in that it integrates into a company’s existing financial tech stack. The benefit to the business, he said, is increased growth and sales revenue as well as optimized cash flow “while removing risk for the company.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Initialized Capital General Partner Alda Leu Dennis said she was familiar with Tsai and co-founder Brian </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nguyen</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> since their days at Celery, their prior startup. She views them as experienced and determined.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We also have conviction around the clear market need for digitizing net terms for small businesses that are increasingly moving their ordering online,” she said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In her view, Resolve&#8217;s unique differentiation is that it provides software that solves net terms billing complexity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Businesses desperately need to manage their B2B billing operations, from helping them gauge the strength of their customers to chasing down payments,” she told TechCrunch. “Their [Resolve’s] approach of accelerating payments and collections via software and offering payment terms as an ancillary service is a powerful pairing; it provides an easy yet comprehensive way for merchants to improve their entire system of managing receivables and billing on credit.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The San Francisco startup is using the money primarily to grow its embedded billing platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We&#8217;re doing a lot of work to scale the platform. So we&#8217;re investing heavily in products and the customer sides of the business, given all the demand that we&#8217;ve seen,” Tsai said. “The operations software that we’ve built is very seamless for our customers, but there&#8217;s a lot going on in the background that we have to do to reduce the complexity for our customers.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="37M9ciFiug"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/tillit/">Tillit, a fintech offering buy now, pay later for B2B purchases, is closing in on investment from Sequoia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tillit, a fintech offering buy now, pay later for B2B purchases, is closing in on investment from Sequoia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/tillit/embed/#?secret=37M9ciFiug" data-secret="37M9ciFiug" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/affirm-spinout-resolve-raises-60m-for-its-b2b-buy-now-pay-later-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156852</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Venture capital investment in Africa predicted to reach a record high this year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/venture-capital-investment-in-africa-predicted-to-reach-a-record-high-this-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/venture-capital-investment-in-africa-predicted-to-reach-a-record-high-this-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 10:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flutterwave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TymeBank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital investments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investments in African startups keep growing at a healthy pace ever since reports started keeping count in 2015. That year, publications Disrupt Africa and Partech released independently researched and contrasting figures showing that venture capital investments hit $186 million and $277 million, respectively. Those are ridiculously low figures for a continent when you consider that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investments in African startups keep growing at a healthy pace ever since reports started keeping count in 2015</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">That year, publications Disrupt Africa and Partech released independently researched and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/23/the-rise-of-silicon-savannah-and-africas-tech-movement/">contrasting figures</a> showing that venture capital investments hit $186 million and $277 million, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those are </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ridiculously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> low figures for a continent when you consider that four-year-old Snapchat raised more than $500 million in one round that same year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. However, w</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">hile the disparity in funding between Africa and a single high-growth U.S. startup continues, the good news is that more money is coming into the continent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2019, Africa&#8217;s venture capital investments rose to an all-time high, per Partech&#8217;s report</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. According to Partech, 234 African tech companies <a href="https://partechpartners.com/documents/12/2020.01_Partech_Africa_-_2019_Africa_Tech_VC_Report_FINAL.pdf">raised $2.02 billion</a> in 250 equity rounds. This indicated a 74% increase from 2018’s figure of $1.163 billion raised by 146 startups in 164 rounds.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was shared</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> optimism that 2020 would record a new high, but that was before the pandemic struck. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For that reason, African tech ecosystem accelerator <a href="https://www.africarena.com/">AfricArena</a> predicted that venture capital funding in the continent&#8217;s startups would <a href="https://techpoint.africa/2020/05/06/african-venture-capital-to-drop-by-40-at-the-end-of-the-year/">fall between</a> $1.2 billion and $1.8 billion</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In what may </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be described</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as an educated guess or a calculated prediction by the publication, year-end reports by Partech and Briter Bridges pegged total investment raised at $1.4 billion and $1.3 billion, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XZWXCn6sf1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/">How African startups raised investments in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How African startups raised investments in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/embed/#?secret=XZWXCn6sf1" data-secret="XZWXCn6sf1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This year, AfricArena, in <a href="https://f1d0651a-c40a-4877-b5d5-7f6204467ba9.filesusr.com/ugd/cdd60c_5d9debf5822c4e84940b69925d8d2ba2.pdf">a new report</a>, is predicting that VC funding in the continent&#8217;s startups would increase between $2.25 billion and $2.8 billion, which, if met, will surpass 2019 figures for a record high on the continent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here&#8217;s the rationale behind the prediction from an excerpt in the report:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We foresee that the first two quarters of 2021 will be similar Q4 2020 with the mix of factors. Vaccine campaigns will likely take longer than hoped to have a meaningful impact. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, this rollout – regardless of how long they will actually take &#8211; will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">eliminate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the major uncertainty about the end of the pandemic, which is only a question of time</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a result, we expect an </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">extremely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> strong acceleration of deals from seed to Series B as well as major growth deals, together with some IPOs (Nigeria’s Interswitch, for example), that will propel deal activity to never seen before levels of activity</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As of April 2020, our forecast for 2021 ranged from under $1.6 billion to over $3 billion. The worst-case scenario was based on a prolonged and fragmented impact on the African economies and the best-case scenario factoring in a full recovery Q1 2021</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Based on the above observations, our views are now that 2021 will range between $2.25 and $2.8 billion.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As of April 30, the total disclosed venture capital funding stood a <a href="https://twitter.com/MaxBayen/status/1388051116831744000">little over $800 million</a>, according to Maxime Bayen, deal tracker and senior venture builder at BFA Global</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If that pace </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is kept</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> throughout the year, African startups might raise more than $2 billion.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156949" style="width: 585px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156949" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2156949" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-147.png?w=575" alt="AfricArena" width="575" height="341" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-147.png 575w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-147.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-147.png?resize=300,178 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-147.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 575px) 100vw, 575px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156949" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> AfricArena</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2020, the number of early-stage deals increased, but there was a drop in growth deals and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">overall</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ticket sizes, constituting the drop in funding activities</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Per <a href="https://cdn-website.partechpartners.com/media/documents/2021-02_Partech_Africa_2020_Africa_Tech_VC_Report.pdf">Partech</a>, seed rounds grew 80% year-on-year and accounted for 64% of all deals made. In total, African startups raised $220 million in seed funding, which was a 47% increase year on year. Series A and B rounds grew likewise. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Series A deals went up 9% (86 rounds), and Series B deals, 16% (29 rounds), yet their investment sizes dropped 5% ($447 million) and 8% ($449 million), </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Growth deals also dropped by 16%, and only two deals closed above $50 million compared to the 10 that took place in 2019, some of which include Interswitch, OPay, Branch and Andela</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The driving force to exceed the $2 billion mark in 2021 lies on VCs to make more deals and startups to replicate the large growth rounds of 2019</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The former appears to be in place as African startups continue to raise money week in and week out. However, there&#8217;s still work to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be done</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the latter, as only two African startups have raised more than $100 million in a single round so far &#8212; fintech startups <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/african-payments-company-flutterwave-raises-170m-now-valued-at-over-1b/">Flutterwave</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/south-african-digital-bank-tymebank-lands-109m-from-uk-and-phillippines-investors/">TymeBank</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ln90GNnSLl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/african-countries-need-startup-acts-more-than-ever-to-support-innovation/">African countries need &#8216;startup acts&#8217; more than ever to support innovation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;African countries need &#8216;startup acts&#8217; more than ever to support innovation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/african-countries-need-startup-acts-more-than-ever-to-support-innovation/embed/#?secret=Ln90GNnSLl" data-secret="Ln90GNnSLl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/venture-capital-investment-in-africa-predicted-to-reach-a-record-high-this-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156797</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian logistics SaaS startup FarEye raises $100 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-raises-100-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-raises-100-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 10:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dragoneer investment group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eight Roads Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fareye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Honeywell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCV]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156944</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[FarEye, an Indian SaaS startup that helps firms globally optimize their supply chain and logistics operations, said on Tuesday it has raised a new financing round, its third since the pandemic broke last year, as it looks to further expand in international markets. The Noida-headquartered startup has raised $100 million in its Series E round, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">FarEye, an Indian SaaS startup that helps firms <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/14/fareye-series-d-india-logistics/">globally optimize their supply chain and logistics operations</a>, said on Tuesday it has raised a new financing round, its third since the pandemic broke last year, as it looks to further expand in international markets.</p>
<p>The Noida-headquartered startup has raised $100 million in its Series E round, which was co-led by high-profile backers TCV and Dragoneer Investment Group. Existing investors Eight Roads Ventures, Fundamentum, Honeywell also participated in the round, which takes seven-and-a-half-year-old startup’s to-date raise to about $153 million.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.getfareye.com/">FarEye</a> helps companies orchestrate, track, and optimize their logistics operations. The startup’s flagship logistics management software supports the entire supply chain &#8212; from first-mile seller pick-ups to last-mile delivery &#8212; to provide end-to-end logistics visibility, reduce operational costs and improve customer experience.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>One use case of FarEye&#8217;s technology, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-bags-13-million/">we wrote last year</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Say you order a pizza from Domino’s, the eatery uses FarEye’s service, which integrates into the system it is using, to quickly inform the customer how long they need to wait for the food to reach them.</p>
<p>Behind the scenes, FarEye is helping Domino’s evaluate a number of moving pieces. How many delivery people are in the vicinity? Can it bundle a few orders? What’s the maximum number of items one can carry? How experienced is the delivery person? What’s the best route to reach the customer? And, would the restaurant need the same number of delivery people the following day?</p></blockquote>
<p>The startup works with over 150 e-commerce and delivery companies globally &#8212; including popular names such as Walmart, UPS, DHL e-commerce, Domino’s, Posti, and Gordon Foods, and Amway &#8212; and processes over 100 million transactions each month.</p>
<p>More than two million vehicles and over 25,000 drivers are on FarEye&#8217;s platform today.</p>
<p>The coronavirus pandemic has helped the business as more companies, including large FMCG brands and retailers, begin to engage directly with customers, sort out their logistics and look for optimizing the cost, said Nahata in an interview.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not like these companies didn&#8217;t knew,&#8221; Nahata said, referring to companies building and digitizing their own logistics. &#8220;Earlier this was on their three-to-five year plans, but now they want to deploy this in within a quarter.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1974650" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1974650" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1974650 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="631" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg 2687w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=300,185 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=768,474 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=680,419 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=1536,947 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=2048,1263 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1974650" class="wp-caption-text">Gautam Kumar (left), Gaurav Srivastava (centre), and Kushal Nahata co-founded FarEye in 2013</p></div></p>
<p>“The logistics and supply chain industry is going through a long awaited software-led creative disruption, led by emerging leaders like FarEye that provide multi- tenant SaaS platforms with low code configuration to enhance visibility to the enterprise and deliver superlative last mile experiences for the end consumer. Gopi Vaddi, General Partner at TCV,</p>
<p>Customers are also beginning to place more orders online. &#8220;For existing customers, we have seen an increase in volume of orders especially in grocery and food categories,&#8221; Nahata said.</p>
<p>The firm today also has clients in several international markets including the U.S., Europe, and Singapore, that is already bringing more than half of revenues for the startup and has grown nearly three times in the past 12 months.</p>
<p>Nahata said the startup didn&#8217;t initially think that Western markets would be prone to similar logistics challenges as those in India and other Asian markets, but despite the growth of e-commerce in some markets, some common underlying issues remain.</p>
<p>Nahata also pointed out that the payments infrastructure that has emerged in India in recent years still doesn&#8217;t exist in other markets, which creates an additional challenge to tackle for the firm.</p>
<p>“FarEye’s leading delivery management platform provides impressive visibility and control across the supply chain, which has never been more critical for retailers, manufacturers and 3PLs,” said Eric Jones, Partner at Dragoneer Investment Group, in a statement. “We look forward to partnering with FarEye as they continue to redefine how products are delivered across diverse logistics networks and expand their footprint in Europe and North America.”</p>
<p>The startup recently hired a number of senior executives including a new CRO (Amit Bagga &#8212; formerly President of APAC at BlueYonder and  and strategic sales leader at Oracle), and a new CPO (Suvrat Joshi &#8212; former executive at Dropbox, Amazon, Facebook, Microsoft.) It&#8217;s looking to further expand the team and is also open to exploring acquisition of smaller firms in international markets, said Nahata.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-raises-100-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156944</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interactio, a remote interpretation platform, grabs $30M after seeing 12x growth during COVID-19</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/interactio-a-remote-interpretation-platform-grabs-30m-after-seeing-12x-growth-during-covid-19/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/interactio-a-remote-interpretation-platform-grabs-30m-after-seeing-12x-growth-during-covid-19/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 07:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eight Roads Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european parliament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interactio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jaan Tallinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jp morgan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lithuania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine translation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Notion Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online meetings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Practica Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silicon Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Skype]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storm ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Translation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Translator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video conferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web conferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WebEX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[young sohn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Interactio, a remote interpretation platform whose customers include massive institutions like the United Nations, European Commission and Parliament along with corporates like BMW, JP Morgan and Microsoft, has closed a whopping $30 million Series A after usage of its tools grew 12x between 2019 and 2020 as demand for online meeting platforms surged during the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.interactio.io">Interactio</a>, a remote interpretation platform whose customers include massive institutions like the United Nations, European Commission and Parliament along with corporates like BMW, JP Morgan and Microsoft, has closed a whopping $30 million Series A after usage of its tools grew 12x between 2019 and 2020 as demand for online meeting platforms surged during the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>The Series A funding is led by Eight Roads Ventures and Silicon Valley-based Storm Ventures, along with participation from Practica Capital, Notion Capital, as well as notable angels such as Jaan Tallinn, the co-founder of Skype, and Young Sohn, ex-chief strategy officer of Samsung.</p>
<p>The Vilnius, Lithuania-based startup offers digital tools to connect meetings with certified interpreters who carry out real-time interpretation to bridge language divides between participants. It does also offer a video conferencing platform which its customers can use to run remote meetings but will happily integrate with thirty party software like Zoom, Webex etc. (Last year it says its digital tools were used alongside 43 different video streaming platforms.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Interactio&#8217;s interpreters can be in the room where the meeting is taking place or doing the real-time interpretation entirely remotely by watching and listening to a stream of the meeting. (Or, indeed, it can support a mix of remote and on-site interpretation, if a client wishes.)</p>
<p>It can also supply all the interpreters for a meeting &#8212; and it touts a strict vetting procedure for onboarding certified interpreters to its platform &#8212; or else it will provide training to a customer&#8217;s interpreters on the use of its tools to ensure things run smoothly on the day.</p>
<p>At present, Interactio says it works with 1,000+ freelance interpreters, as well as touting &#8220;strong relations with interpretation agencies&#8221; &#8212; claiming it can easily quadruple the pool of available interpreters to step up to meet rising demand.</p>
<p>It offers its customers interpretation in any language &#8212; and in an unlimited number of languages per event. And last year it says it hosted 18,000+ meetings with 390,000 listeners spread across more than 70 countries.</p>
<p>Now, flush with a huge Series A, Interactio is gearing up for a future filled with increasing numbers of multi-lingual online meetings &#8212; as the coronavirus continues to inject friction into business travel.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we started, our biggest competition was simultaneous interpretation hardware for on-site interpretation. At that time, we were on the mission to fully replace it with our software that required zero additional hardware for attendees besides their phone and headphones. However, for institutions, which became our primary focus, hybrid meetings are the key, so we started partnering with simultaneous interpretation hardware manufacturers and integrators by working together on hybrid events, where participants use hardware on-site, and online participants use us,&#8221; a spokeswoman told us.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is how we differentiate ourselves from other platforms &#8212; by offering a fully hybrid solution, that can be integrated with hardware on-site basically via one cable.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Moreover, when we look at the market trends, we still see Zoom as the most used solution, so we compliment it by offering professional interpretation solutions,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>A focus on customer support is another tactic that Interactio says it relies upon to stand out &#8212; and its iOS and Android apps do have high ratings on aggregate. (Albeit, there are bunch of historical complaints mixed in suggesting it&#8217;s had issues scaling its service to large audiences in the past, as well as sporadic problems with things like audio quality over the years.)</p>
<p>While already profitable, the 2014-founded startup says the  Series A will be used to step on the gas to continue to meet the accelerated demand and exponential growth it&#8217;s seen during the remote work boom.</p>
<p>Specifically, the funds will go on enhancing its tech and UX/UI &#8212; with a focus on ensuring ease of access/simplicity for those needing to access interpretation, and also on upgrading the tools it provides to interpreters (so they have &#8220;the best working conditions from their chosen place of work&#8221;).</p>
<p>It will also be spending to expand its client base &#8212; and is especially seeking to onboard more corporates and other types of customers. (&#8220;Last year’s focus was and still is institutions (e.g. European Commission, European Parliament, United Nations), where there is no place for an error and they need the most professional solution. The next step will be to expand our client base to corporate clients and a larger public that needs interpretation,&#8221; it told us.)</p>
<p>The new funding will also be used to expand the size of its team to support those goals, including growing the number of qualified interpreters it works with so it can keep pace with rising demand.</p>
<p>While major institutions like the UN are never going to be tempted to skimp on the quality of translation provided to diplomats and politicians by <em>not</em> using human interpreters (either on premise or working remotely), there may be a limit on how far professional real-time translation can scale given the availability of real-time machine translation technology &#8212; which offers a cheap alternative to support more basic meeting scenarios, such as between two professionals having an informal meeting.</p>
<p>Google, for example, offers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/12/interpreter-googles-real-time-translator-comes-to-mobile/">a real-time translator mode</a> that&#8217;s accessible to users of its smartphone platform via the Google voice assistant AI. Hardware startups are also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/05/waverly-labs-new-wearable-translater-arrives-in-april-at-200/">trying to target real-time translation</a>. The dream of a real-life AI-powered &#8216;Babel Fish&#8217; remains strong.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, such efforts aren&#8217;t well suited to supporting meetings and conferences at scale &#8212; where having a centralized delivery service that&#8217;s also responsible for troubleshooting any audio quality or other issues which may arise looks essential.</p>
<p>And while machine translation has undoubtedly got a lot better over the years (albeit performance can vary, depending on the languages involved) there is still a risk that key details could be lost in translation if/when the machine gets it wrong. So offering highly scalable human translation via a digital platform looks like a safe bet as the world gets accustomed to more remote work (and less globetrotting) being the new normal.</p>
<p>&#8220;AI-driven translation is a great tool when you need a quick solution and are willing to sacrifice the quality,&#8221; says Interactio when we ask about this. &#8220;Our clients are large corporations and institutions, therefore, any kind of misunderstanding can be crucial. Here, the translation is not about saying a word in a different language, it’s about giving the meaning and communicating a context via interpretation.</p>
<p>&#8220;We strongly believe that only humans can understand the true context and meaning of conversations, where sometimes a tone of voice, an emotion and a figure speech can make a huge difference, that is unnoticed by a machine.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="20YWHRK3Oe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/14/zoom-launches-its-events-platform-and-marketplace-brings-apps-to-your-calls/">Zoom launches its events platform and marketplace, brings apps to your calls</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zoom launches its events platform and marketplace, brings apps to your calls&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/14/zoom-launches-its-events-platform-and-marketplace-brings-apps-to-your-calls/embed/#?secret=20YWHRK3Oe" data-secret="20YWHRK3Oe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="A8pXo9q3Us"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/salesforce-updates-includes-sales-info-overlay-for-zoom-meetings/">Salesforce updates includes sales info overlay for Zoom meetings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce updates includes sales info overlay for Zoom meetings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/salesforce-updates-includes-sales-info-overlay-for-zoom-meetings/embed/#?secret=A8pXo9q3Us" data-secret="A8pXo9q3Us" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AQtCnzKROP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/otter-ais-new-assistant-can-automatically-transcribe-your-zoom-meetings/">Otter.ai&#8217;s new assistant can automatically transcribe your Zoom meetings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Otter.ai&#8217;s new assistant can automatically transcribe your Zoom meetings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/otter-ais-new-assistant-can-automatically-transcribe-your-zoom-meetings/embed/#?secret=AQtCnzKROP" data-secret="AQtCnzKROP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/interactio-a-remote-interpretation-platform-grabs-30m-after-seeing-12x-growth-during-covid-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156367</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AnyClip snaps up $47M for its video search and analytics technology</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/anyclip-snaps-up-47m-for-its-video-search-and-analytics-technology/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/anyclip-snaps-up-47m-for-its-video-search-and-analytics-technology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 07:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156937</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Video is, quite literally, what gets the world moving online these days, expected to account for 82% of all IP traffic this year. Today a startup that has built a set of tools to help better parse, index and ultimately discover that trove of content is announcing a big round of funding to expand its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Video is, quite literally, what gets the world moving online these days, expected to account for <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/m/en_us/solutions/service-provider/vni-forecast-highlights/pdf/Global_2021_Forecast_Highlights.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">82% of all IP traffic this year</a>. Today a startup that has built a set of tools to help better parse, index and ultimately discover that trove of content is announcing a big round of funding to expand its business after seeing 600% growth in the last year.</p>
<p><a href="https://anyclip.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AnyClip</a> &#8212; which combines artificial intelligence with more standard search tools to provide better video analytics for content providers to improve how those videos can be used and viewed &#8212; has raised $47 million, money that it will be using to build out its platform and where it can be applied.</p>
<p>The funding is being led by JVP, with La Maison, Bank Mizrahi and internal investors also participating. The company is not officially disclosing its valuation but has raised $70 million to date and I understand from reliable sources that it is around $300 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded in Tel Aviv and now co-headquartered in New York, the challenge that AnyClip is tackling is the fact that there is a huge amount of video out in the world today, and it remains one of the most-used content mediums, whether you are a consumer binging a Netflix series, someone trying to dig up an obscure classical music recording on YouTube, a business user on Zoom, or something in the very large in-between those scenarios. The problem is that in most cases, people are just scratching the surface when they search.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s not just because hosts tweak algorithms to lead to watching some things instead of others; it&#8217;s because in most cases it&#8217;s too difficult, and some might say impossible, to search everything in an efficient way.</p>
<p>AnyClip is among the tech companies that believe it&#8217;s not impossible. Using technologies that include deep learning models based on computer vision, NLP, speech-to-text, OCR, patented key frame detection and closed captioning to &#8220;read&#8221; the content in videos. It can recognize people, brands, products, actions, millions of keywords and build taxonomies based around what the videos contain. These can be based on, for example, content category, brand safety, or whatever a customer requests.</p>
<p>The videos that AnyClip currently works with are hosted by AnyClip itself &#8212; on AWS, president and CEO Gil Becker tells me &#8212; and the process of reading and indexing is super quick, &#8220;10x faster than real time.&#8221;</p>
<p>The resulting data and what can be done with it, as you might guess, has a lot of potential uses. Currently, Becker said that AnyClip is finding a strong audience among customers that are looking for ways of better organising their video content for a variety of use cases, whether that&#8217;s for internal purposes, for B2B purposes, or for consumers to better discover something.</p>
<p>And as the illustration above shows, that tech can be used, naturally, to better monetize video. By identifying more objects, themes, moods and language in videos more efficiently, AnyClip essentially can build a framework not just for people to better discover videos, but for advertisers to place ads next to whatever they want to be near (or conversely, better avoid content that they do not want any association with at all).</p>
<p>The list of those it works with is pretty impressive &#8212; it includes although Becker would not get very specific on what it does for all of its clients. It includes Samsung, Microsoft, AT&amp;T, Amazon (Prime Video specifically), Heineken, Discovery, Warner Media (the latter two soon to be one), Tencent, Internet Brands and Google.</p>
<p>Among the work it does with Google, AnyClip does not count Google as an investor per se, but it has <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/anyclip-wins-funding-from-google-301017419.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">received funding from it</a>, specifically as part of its Google News Initiative&#8217;s Innovation Challenge to create a streaming video page experience for media companies that mimics the functionality and design of today&#8217;s most popular video-on-demand services while accessing advanced video management tools supported by AnyClip&#8217;s AI backbone.  <span class="il">AnyClip</span> was chosen from among hundreds of companies for its solution that allows companies to transform any library into a &#8216;Netflix or YouTube-like&#8221; library, creating channels and subchannels, in less than 30 seconds.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">AnyClip has an interesting history that led to it building the search and discovery tools that it sells today. It started life <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2009/09/15/tc50-find-the-perfect-scene-every-time-anyclip-is-a-search-engine-for-movie-clips/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">back in 2009</a> with a concept that spoke directly to its name: it let media companies create clips of films that could be shared around the internet, which it hosted on a site of its own. These could be found using a number of taxonomies built by AnyClip&#8217;s algorithms, by humans at the company, and by contributors. Kind of like a Giphy before its time, if you will. </span></p>
<p>It turned out to be possibly <em>too</em> far ahead of its time. At a time when piracy was still a big deal, and there were no Netflixes or other places for streaming efficiently and legally, the idea proved to be too complicated and too hard of a sell for rights owners. The company subsequently pivoted to building a video-based ad network, which itself was probably too early, too.</p>
<p>But there was something to the technology, given the right place and right time, and that seems to be where the startup has landed today, with patents behind what it has built and a team of engineers continuing to expand the tech. It hopes that this will be enough to keep it ahead of competitors, which include the likes of Kaltura, Brightcove and many others. And naturally, given the size of the opportunity, that competition will not be disappearing soon.</p>
<p>Notably, AnyClip&#8217;s own growth, on the back of what has up to now been a modest amount of funding ($30 million in 12 years) definitely speaks of its own ability not just to win business against them, but be capital efficient in what is typically considered a very bandwidth and resource-intensive medium.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is a revolution coming in the way enterprises use video to convey their message and their identity&#8221;, says Erel Margalit, JVP founder and Chairman, and Anyclip&#8217;s Board Chairman, in a statement. &#8220;For the first time, AI meets video. Companies and organizations are now working to utilize this to create a new mode of communications, internally and externally, in all areas where video dominates in a much stronger way than text. Whether it&#8217;s how to create videos for consumers or training videos for the organization, or learning how to manage conferences run by video on zoom which need intelligent management in the retrieving of content. This is a new era, and AnyClip is a vital tool for anyone embarking upon it.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/anyclip-snaps-up-47m-for-its-video-search-and-analytics-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156937</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook co-founder Saverin&#8217;s B Capital doubles down on SaaS in China</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/b-capital-expansion-china/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/b-capital-expansion-china/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 03:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b capital group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bain Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross-border e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce enabler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[globalization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raj Ganguly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shanghai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155796</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[B Capital Group, the six-year-old venture capital fund formed by Facebook co-founder Eduardo Saverin and Bain Capital veteran Raj Ganguly, is doubling down on China as it looks to allocate $500 million to $1 billion of its fund into Chinese tech companies over the next few years. With $1.9 billion assets under management, B Capital [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">B Capital Group, the six-year-old venture capital fund formed by Facebook co-founder Eduardo Saverin and Bain Capital veteran Raj Ganguly, is doubling down on China as it looks to allocate $500 million to $1 billion of its fund into Chinese tech companies over the next few years.</p>
<p>With $1.9 billion assets under management, B Capital is going after enterprise software providers in China, an area that has seen &#8220;explosive growth&#8221; but is still only a &#8220;fraction the size of the U.S. SaaS market,&#8221; Ganguly said in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The idea that Chinese companies are reluctant to shell out for software is &#8220;very backward-looking thinking&#8221;, he added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>One force fueling the boom of B2B companies in China is surging labor costs. As such, B Capital is hunting down software that could make labor and business operations more productive, and subsequently, give companies a competitive edge. Covid-19 accelerated the shift, as well-digitized companies had proven much more resilient to disruptions caused by the pandemic.</p>
<p>B Capital is able to discern what enterprises need thanks to its close partnership with Boston Consulting Group, which has a raft of customers ranging from healthcare, finance to transportation looking to digitize.</p>
<p>These large corporations &#8220;understand that their internal technology can&#8217;t be the only solution and they have to look to the outside and be willing to partner with early-stage, high-growth, or late-stage tech companies,&#8221; Ganguly suggested. They are also more willing to pay for software compared to scrappy, cash-strapped startups.</p>
<p>B Capital began deploying capital in China early this year and has already closed three deals. It&#8217;s stage-agnostic &#8212; though growth-stage startups are the focus &#8212; and plans to back 15-20 projects in China over the next few years. About 15 of its investment and operating employees are based out of Hong Kong and Beijing. It has around 110 staff worldwide.</p>
<p>Ganguly declined to disclose the names of its Chinese investees at this stage but said they include a biotech company, an automotive parts business, and an e-commerce enabler. Leveraging BCG&#8217;s expertise, the biotech company is learning how it can bring actual drugs to market faster. And the automotive business is similarly working with BCG to figure out its pricing and go-to-market strategy.</p>
<h2>Going global</h2>
<p>Overall, B Capital looks for opportunities in healthcare, fintech, industrial digitalization, and other horizontal enterprise services. Chinese startups that interest B Capital most are also those with the intention and ability to cross borders.</p>
<p>&#8220;Biotech is the area that we&#8217;ve been the most impressed by what&#8217;s happening in China and how that technology can be exported to other countries,&#8221; Ganguly said. B Capital has backed one biotech startup with offices in both Shanghai and Cambridge, Massachusettes, and is on track to close a deal with another that also straddles China and the U.S.</p>
<p>The other target is e-commerce, which Ganguly described as &#8220;cross-border by its nature&#8221; because a product is often sourced in one country, made in another, and then sold in a third market.</p>
<p>The investor is certainly right about the potential of cross-border e-commerce in China, where consumers have a big appetite for imported goods and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/shein-overtakes-amazon/?tpcc=ECTW2020">manufacturers look for new ways to sell globally</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SkVdhao58X"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/shein-overtakes-amazon/">Shein overtakes Amazon as the most installed shopping app in US</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Shein overtakes Amazon as the most installed shopping app in US&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/shein-overtakes-amazon/embed/#?secret=SkVdhao58X" data-secret="SkVdhao58X" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>China is also in a good position to export its enterprise software, similar to how Indian counterparts have succeeded overseas, said Ganguly. The difference is that few Indian corporations are willing to pay big bucks for software, which forces B2B entrepreneurs to seek market abroad, whereas China&#8217;s domestic companies have an increasing demand for SaaS.</p>
<p>Despite ongoing geopolitical complications, Ganguly is optimistic that the world &#8220;is still moving towards globalization&#8221; over the long term.</p>
<p>&#8220;Certain innovation cycles have started in Silicon Valley and spread to places like China and Southeast Asia. But frankly, other innovation cycles have started in China and gone to South and Southeast Asia and the U.S. We think that China&#8217;s enterprise [software], artificial intelligence and biotech are some of the best technology that we&#8217;ve seen.&#8221;</p>
<p>But these globalizing companies must be able to adapt, hire talent outside their core market, get regulatory approvals, and build the right distribution networks, the investor suggested.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think that there are aspects of globalization that have become very politicized, and I think that&#8217;s unfortunate but understandable. Our belief is that businesses that we invest in have the ability to cross borders. Sometimes that means going from China to South and Southeast Asia, and sometimes that means extending to the U.S. Sometimes it just means the ability to import or export their products or software, and even staying in China where they can sell their technologies overseas.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Xu6Hzt9HuV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/07/catching-up-with-b-capital-the-fast-growing-firm-founded-by-eduardo-saverin-and-raj-ganguly/">Catching up with B Capital, the fast-growing firm founded by Eduardo Saverin and Raj Ganguly</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Catching up with B Capital, the fast-growing firm founded by Eduardo Saverin and Raj Ganguly&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/07/catching-up-with-b-capital-the-fast-growing-firm-founded-by-eduardo-saverin-and-raj-ganguly/embed/#?secret=Xu6Hzt9HuV" data-secret="Xu6Hzt9HuV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/b-capital-expansion-china/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155796</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Germany gives greenlight to driverless vehicles on public roads</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/germany-gives-greenlight-to-driverless-vehicles-on-public-roads/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/germany-gives-greenlight-to-driverless-vehicles-on-public-roads/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 01:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driverless vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self driving vehicles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156909</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Germany has adopted legislation that will allow driverless vehicles on public roads by 2022, laying out a path for companies to deploy robotaxis and delivery services in the country at scale. While autonomous testing is currently permitted in Germany, this would allow operations of driverless vehicles without a human safety operator behind the wheel.  The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Germany has adopted legislation that will allow driverless vehicles on public roads by 2022, laying out a path for companies to deploy robotaxis and delivery services in the country at scale. While autonomous testing is currently permitted in Germany, this would allow operations of driverless vehicles without a human safety operator behind the wheel. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The bill, which last week passed the Bundestag, Germany’s lower house of parliament, specifically looks at vehicles with Level 4 autonomy. Level 4 autonomy is a designation by the Society of Automobile Engineers (SAE) which means the computer handles all the driving in certain conditions or environments. In Germany, these vehicles will be limited to  geographic areas. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In the future, autonomous vehicles should be able to drive nationwide without a physically present driver in specified operating areas of public road traffic in regular operation,” </span><a href="https://www.bundestag.de/dokumente/textarchiv/2021/kw20-de-autonomes-fahren-840196"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reads the legislation</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. “According to the Federal Government, further steps must be taken to introduce corresponding systems into regular operation so that the potential of these technologies can be exploited and society can participate in them.” </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The bill still needs to pass through the upper chamber of parliament, or the Bundesrat. Included in the bill are possible initial applications for self-driving cars on German roads, such as public passenger transport, business and supply trips, logistics, company shuttles that handle employee traffic and trips between medical centers and retirement homes.</span></p>
<p>Companies looking to operate commercial driverless vehicles in Germany will need to adhere to a number of other rules, such as carrying liability insurance and having access to stop autonomous operations remotely.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Companies already testing in Germany might have an upper hand in Europe’s largest economy. Argo AI, for example, has been </span><a href="https://www.munich-airport.com/press-argo-ai-to-test-autonomous-driving-10754964"><span style="font-weight: 400;">testing its autonomous vehicles at the LabCampus innovation center at Munich Airport</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Last June, the company opened its European headquarters in the Bavarian city, and this summer it will open its </span><a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/pittsburgh/news/2021/05/12/argo-ai-to-start-testing-avs-in-munich.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">test site in partnership with Volkswagen</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to test the VW ID.Buzz electric vans. </span><a href="https://www.fleeteurope.com/en/autonomous/germany/features/mobileye-tests-avs-germany-130-kmh?a=FJA05&amp;t%5B0%5D=Mobileye&amp;t%5B1%5D=TUV%20SUD&amp;t%5B2%5D=Moovit&amp;curl=1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Intel-subsidiary Mobileye also has a footprint testing AVs in Germany</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p>Several U.S. states and countries have regulations around testing and potentially commercial deployment. <span style="font-weight: 400;">Last week, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/chinese-startup-pony-ai-can-now-test-driverless-vehicles-in-three-california-cities/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chinese robotaxi startup Pony.ai</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> became the eighth company to be granted a permit to test driverless vehicles in California, and Nuro is the only company with a deployment permit to operate commercially on public roads in the state. In China, companies like Alibaba-backed AutoX are also testing driverless fleets on public roads. Germany’s legislation is a step beyond testing in the direction of integration into regular traffic. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Vf7JhqNzQa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/">The battle for voice recognition inside vehicles is heating up</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The battle for voice recognition inside vehicles is heating up&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/embed/#?secret=Vf7JhqNzQa" data-secret="Vf7JhqNzQa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/germany-gives-greenlight-to-driverless-vehicles-on-public-roads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156909</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Light is the key to long-range, fully autonomous EVs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/light-is-the-key-to-long-range-fully-autonomous-evs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/light-is-the-key-to-long-range-fully-autonomous-evs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battery Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Photonic computing technology is on the brink of being commercially available and has the potential to supercharge the current roadmap of autonomous driving while also reducing its carbon footprint.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Nick Harris</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/theanalognick">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Nick Harris is a scientist, engineer, and the founder and CEO of <a href="https://lightmatter.co/">Lightmatter</a>, which manufactures photonic processors.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Advanced driver assistance systems (ADAS) hold immense promise. At times, the headlines about the autonomous vehicle (AV) industry seem ominous, with a focus on accidents, regulation or company valuations that some find undeserving. None of this is unreasonable, but it makes the amazing possibilities of a world of AVs seem opaque.</p>
<p>One of the universally accepted upsides of AVs is the potential positive impact on the environment, as most AVs will also be electric vehicles (EVs).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.linleygroup.com/report_detail.php?num=69">Industry analyst reports</a> project that by 2023, 7.3 million vehicles (7% of the total market) will have autonomous driving capabilities requiring $1.5 billion of autonomous-driving-dedicated processors. This is expected to grow to $14 billion in 2030, when upward of 50% of all vehicles sold will be classified as SAE Level 3 or higher, as <a href="https://www.nhtsa.gov/technology-innovation/automated-vehicles-safety">defined</a> by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Fundamental innovation in computing and battery technology may be required to fully deliver on the promise of AEVs with the range, safety and performance demanded by consumers.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>While photonic chips are faster and more energy efficient, fewer chips will be needed to reach SAE Level 3; however, we can expect this increased compute performance to accelerate the development and availability of fully SAE Level 5 autonomous vehicles. In that case, the market for autonomous driving photonic processors will likely far surpass the projection of $14 billion by 2030.</p>
<p>When you consider all of the broad-based potential uses of autonomous electric vehicles (AEVs) &#8212; including taxis and service vehicles in major cities, or the clean transport of goods on our highways &#8212; we begin to see how this technology can rapidly begin to significantly impact our environment: by helping to bring clean air to some of the most populated and polluted cities.</p>
<p>The problem is that AEVs currently have a sustainability problem.</p>
<p>To operate efficiently and safely, AEVs must leverage a dizzying array of sensors: cameras, lidar, radar and ultrasonic sensors, to name just a few. These work together, gathering data to detect, react and predict in real time, essentially becoming the &#8220;eyes&#8221; for the vehicle.</p>
<p>While there’s some debate surrounding the specific numbers of sensors required to ensure effective and safe AV, one thing is unanimously agreed upon: These cars will create massive amounts of data.</p>
<p>Reacting to the data generated by these sensors, even in a simplistic way, requires tremendous computational power — not to mention the battery power required to operate the sensors themselves. Processing and analyzing the data involves deep learning algorithms, a branch of AI notorious for its outsized carbon footprint.</p>
<p>To be a viable alternative, both in energy efficiency and economics, AEVs need to get close to matching gas-powered vehicles in range. However, the more sensors and algorithms an AEV has running over the course of a journey, the lower the battery range &#8212; and the driving range &#8212; of the vehicle.</p>
<p>Today, EVs are barely capable of reaching 300 miles before they need to be recharged, while a traditional combustion engine averages 412 miles on a single tank of gas, according to the <a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/vehicles/fact-939-august-22-2016-all-electric-vehicle-ranges-can-exceed-those-some-gasoline">U.S. Department of Energy</a>. Adding autonomous driving into the mix widens this gap even further and potentially accelerates battery degradation.</p>
<p>Recent work published in the journal <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41560-020-0644-3.epdf?sharing_token=-2h1AonBifDqx83jK3qlHdRgN0jAjWel9jnR3ZoTv0PkV4h-0BfuDxTt20euiNiwgJB6g8CLgd2HJNRMDTCSC8_8JcBgF0-pv7-mboFgY-h88dzdoIggR95UkVmkCdlw2hfjGxCUzDwlWphvJ5ecSDurTdn-t4gEFdDq8Le_8BcntFFo1h9arXsOtQfTjkgSBdelM2H_hHPNj0YprRaW1w%3D%3D&amp;tracking_referrer=www.wired.com">Nature Energy</a> claims that the range of an automated electric vehicle is reduced by 10%-15% during city driving.</p>
<p>At the 2019 Tesla Autonomy Day event, it was revealed that driving range could be reduced by up to 25% when Tesla’s driver-assist system is enabled during city driving. This reduces the typical range for EVs from 300 miles to 225 — crossing a perceived threshold of attractiveness for consumers.</p>
<p>A first-principle analysis takes this a step further. NVIDIA’s AI compute solution for robotaxis, DRIVE, has a power consumption of <a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/15800/nvidia-announces-new-drive-platforms-with-orin-and-ampere-">800 watts</a>, while a Tesla Model 3 has an energy consumption rate of about <a href="https://www.tesmanian.com/blogs/tesmanian-blog/tesla-model-3-sr-is-the-lowest-energy-consumption-of-all-bevs-says-report">11.9 kWh/100 km</a>. At the typical city speed limit of 50 km/hour (about 30 mph), the Model 3 is consuming approximately 6 kW — meaning power solely dedicated to AI compute is consuming approximately 13% of total battery power intended for driving.</p>
<p>This illustrates how the power-hungry compute engines used for automated EVs pose a significant problem for battery life, vehicle range and consumer adoption.</p>
<p>This problem is further compounded by the power overhead associated with cooling the current generation of the power-hungry computer chips that are currently used for advanced AI algorithms. When processing heavy AI workloads, these semiconductor chip architectures generate massive amounts of heat.</p>
<p>As these chips process AI workloads, they generate heat, which increases their temperature and, as a consequence, performance declines. More effort is then needed and energy wasted on heat sinks, fans and other cooling methods to dissipate this heat, further reducing battery power and ultimately EV range. As the AV industry continues to evolve, new solutions to eliminate this AI compute chip heat problem are urgently needed.</p>
<h2>The chip architecture problem</h2>
<p>For decades, we have relied on Moore’s law, and its lesser-known cousin Dennard scaling, to deliver more compute power per footprint repeatedly year after year. Today, it’s well known that electronic computers are no longer significantly improving in performance per watt, resulting in overheating data centers all over the world.</p>
<p>The largest gains to be had in computing are at the chip architecture level, specifically in custom chips, each for specific applications. However, architectural breakthroughs are a one-off trick &#8212; they can only be made at singular points in time in computing history.</p>
<p>Currently, the compute power required to train artificial intelligence algorithms and perform inference with the resulting models is growing exponentially — five times faster than the rate of progress under Moore’s law. One consequence of that is a huge gap between the amount of computing needed to deliver on the massive economic promise of autonomous vehicles and the current state of computing.</p>
<p>Autonomous EVs find themselves in a tug of war between maintaining battery range and the real-time compute power required to deliver autonomy.</p>
<h2>Photonic computers give AEVs a more sustainable future</h2>
<p>Fundamental innovation in computing and battery technology may be required to fully deliver on the promise of AEVs with the range, safety and performance demanded by consumers. While quantum computers are an unlikely short- or even medium-term solution to this AEV conundrum, there’s another, more available solution making a breakthrough right now: photonic computing.</p>
<p>Photonic computers use laser light, instead of electrical signals, to compute and transport data. This results in a dramatic reduction in power consumption and an improvement in critical, performance-related processor parameters, including clock speed and latency.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0zhYjLEXG3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/arrivals-denis-sverdlov-on-the-new-era-of-car-manufacturing/">Arrival&#8217;s Denis Sverdlov on the new era of car manufacturing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Arrival&#8217;s Denis Sverdlov on the new era of car manufacturing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/arrivals-denis-sverdlov-on-the-new-era-of-car-manufacturing/embed/#?secret=0zhYjLEXG3" data-secret="0zhYjLEXG3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Photonic computers also enable inputs from a multitude of sensors to run inference tasks concurrently on a single processor core (each input encoded in a unique color), while a traditional processor can only accommodate one job at a time.</p>
<p>The advantage that hybrid photonic semiconductors have over conventional architectures lies within the special properties of light itself. Each data input is encoded in a different wavelength, i.e., color, while each runs on the same neural network model. This means that photonic processors not only produce more throughput compared to their electronic counterparts, but are significantly more energy efficient.</p>
<p>Photonic computers excel in applications that require extreme throughput with low latency and relatively low power consumption — applications like cloud computing and, potentially, autonomous driving, where the real-time processing of vast amounts of data is required.</p>
<p>Photonic computing technology is on the brink of becoming commercially available and has the potential to supercharge the current roadmap of autonomous driving while also reducing its carbon footprint. It’s clear that interest in the benefits of self-driving vehicles is increasing and consumer demand is imminent.</p>
<p>So it is crucial for us to not only consider the industries it will transform and the safety it can bring to our roads, but also ensure the sustainability of its impact on our planet. In other words, it’s time to shine a little light on autonomous EVs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/light-is-the-key-to-long-range-fully-autonomous-evs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156416</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hyundai is launching in-car payments in the all-electric Ioniq 5</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/hyundai-is-launching-in-car-payments-in-the-all-electric-ioniq-5/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/hyundai-is-launching-in-car-payments-in-the-all-electric-ioniq-5/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hyundai developed an in-car payment system that will debut in its upcoming all-electric Ioniq 5 crossover that will offer drivers the ability to find and pay for EV charging, food and parking — the latest example of automakers finding new ways to generate revenue and offer customers features that are typically associated with smartphones. When [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hyundai developed an in-car payment system that will debut in its upcoming all-electric Ioniq 5 crossover that will offer drivers the ability to find and pay for EV charging, food and parking — the latest example of automakers finding new ways to generate revenue and offer customers features that are typically associated with smartphones.</p>
<p>When the vehicle comes to North America in fall 2021, the payments system will launch with Dominoes, ParkWhiz and Chargehub, the company said Monday. The in-car payments system was just one of several new details released during the Ioniq 5&#8217;s North American debut.</p>
<p>The payments feature works through Bluelink, Hyundai&#8217;s branded connected car system that gives users control over various vehicle functions and services. Bluelink, which requires a subscription, is offered in three different packages that cover areas such as vehicle maintenance and alerts, remote climate control and unlocking and locking as well as destination search. Bluelink also can be linked to a user&#8217;s Google Assistant feature on their smartphone to send information to their Hyundai vehicle.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The in-car payments system will eventually expand to include other companies that fall into the charging, food and coffee on-the-go and parking categories. A company spokesperson said Hyundai will continue to add new merchants regularly via the Xevo Marketplace platform.</p>
<p>The Ioniq 5 is the company&#8217;s first dedicated battery-electric vehicle built on the new Electric-Global Modular Platform, or E-GMP platform. This platform is shared with Kia and is the underlying foundation of the new EV6.</p>
<p>If the Ioniq name sounds familiar, it’s because it already exists. In 2016, Hyundai introduced the Ioniq, a hatchback that came in hybrid, plug-in hybrid and electric versions. The Korean automaker is using that vehicle as the jumping off point for its new EV brand.</p>
<p>All of the vehicles under the Ioniq brand will have the E-GMP platform. The Ioniq 5 is based on Hyundai’s Concept 45, a monocoque-style body crossover that the company unveiled in 2019 at the International Motor Show in Frankfurt. Designers of the Concept 45 leaned on some of the lines and characteristics from Hyundai’s first concept, the 1974 Pony Coupe. The “45” name comes, in part, from the 45-degree angles at the front and rear of the vehicle.</p>
<p>Hyundai has yet to release pricing for the Ioniq 5.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dQaJvSU4ZQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/automakers-suppliers-and-startups-see-growing-market-for-in-vehicle-ar-vr-applications/">Automakers, suppliers and startups see growing market for in-vehicle AR/VR applications</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Automakers, suppliers and startups see growing market for in-vehicle AR/VR applications&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/automakers-suppliers-and-startups-see-growing-market-for-in-vehicle-ar-vr-applications/embed/#?secret=dQaJvSU4ZQ" data-secret="dQaJvSU4ZQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/hyundai-is-launching-in-car-payments-in-the-all-electric-ioniq-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156727</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Florida&#8217;s ban on bans will test First Amendment rights of social media companies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/floridas-ban-on-bans-will-test-first-amendment-rights-of-social-media-companies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/floridas-ban-on-bans-will-test-first-amendment-rights-of-social-media-companies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 22:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Amendment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free Speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moderation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Section 230]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156748</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Florida governor Ron DeSantis has signed into law a restriction on social media companies&#8217; ability to ban candidates for state offices and news outlets, and in doing so offered a direct challenge to those companies&#8217; perceived free speech rights. The law is almost certain to be challenged in court as both unconstitutional and in direct [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Florida governor Ron DeSantis has <a href="https://www.flgov.com/2021/05/24/governor-ron-desantis-signs-bill-to-stop-the-censorship-of-floridians-by-big-tech/">signed into law</a> a restriction on social media companies&#8217; ability to ban candidates for state offices and news outlets, and in doing so offered a direct challenge to those companies&#8217; perceived free speech rights. The law is almost certain to be challenged in court as both unconstitutional and in direct conflict with federal rules.</p>
<p>The law, Florida Senate Bill 7072, provides several new checks on tech and social media companies. Among other things:</p>
<ul>
<li>Platforms cannot ban or deprioritize candidates for state office.</li>
<li>Platforms cannot ban or deprioritize any news outlet meeting certain size requirements.</li>
<li>Platforms must be transparent about moderation processes and give users notice of moderation actions.</li>
<li>Users and the state will have the right to sue companies that violate the law. Statutory fines could be as high as $250,000 per day for some offenses.</li>
</ul>
<p>The law establishes rules affecting these companies&#8217; moderation practices; that much is clear. But whether doing so amounts to censorship — actual government censorship, not the general concept of limitation frequently associated with the word — is an open question, if a somewhat obvious one, that will likely be forced by legal action against SB 7072.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While there is a great deal of circumstantial precedent and analysis, the problem of &#8220;are moderation practices of social media companies protected by the First Amendment&#8221; is as yet unsettled. Legal scholars and existing cases fall strongly on the side of &#8220;yes,&#8221; but there is no single definitive precedent that Facebook or Twitter can point to.</p>
<p>The First Amendment argument starts with the idea that although social media are very unlike newspapers or book publishers, they are protected in much the same way by the Constitution from government interference. &#8220;Free speech&#8221; is a term that is interpreted extremely liberally, but if a company spending money is considered a protected expression of ideas, it&#8217;s not a stretch to suggest that same company applying a policy of hosting or not hosting content should be as well. If it is, then the government is prohibited from interfering with it beyond very narrow definitions of unprotected speech (think shouting &#8220;fire&#8221; in a crowded theater). That would sink Florida&#8217;s law on constitutional grounds.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tcsQYn4wHp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clarence-thomas-plays-a-poor-devils-advocate-in-floating-first-amendment-limits-for-tech-companies/">Clarence Thomas plays a poor devil&#8217;s advocate in floating First Amendment limits for tech companies</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clarence Thomas plays a poor devil&#8217;s advocate in floating First Amendment limits for tech companies&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clarence-thomas-plays-a-poor-devils-advocate-in-floating-first-amendment-limits-for-tech-companies/embed/#?secret=tcsQYn4wHp" data-secret="tcsQYn4wHp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The other conflict is with federal law, specifically the much-discussed Section 230, which protects companies from being liable for content they publish (i.e. the creator is responsible instead), and also for the choice to take down content via rules of their own choice. As the law&#8217;s co-author Senator Ron Wyden (D-OR) has put it, this gives those companies both a shield and a sword with which to do battle against risky speech on their platforms.</p>
<p>But SB 7072 removes both sword and shield: It would limit who can be moderated, and also creates a novel cause for legal action against the companies for their remaining moderation practices.</p>
<p>Federal and state law are often in disagreement, and there is no handbook for how to reconcile them. On one hand, witness raids of state-legalized marijuana shops and farms by federal authorities. On the other, observe how strong consumer protection laws at the state level aren&#8217;t preempted by weaker federal ones because to do so would put people at risk.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zxeU8s0djM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/section-230-bills-algorithms-congress-hearing/">At social media hearing, lawmakers circle algorithm-focused Section 230 reform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;At social media hearing, lawmakers circle algorithm-focused Section 230 reform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/section-230-bills-algorithms-congress-hearing/embed/#?secret=zxeU8s0djM" data-secret="zxeU8s0djM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>On the matter of Section 230 it&#8217;s not straightforward who is protecting whom. Florida&#8217;s current state government claims that it is protecting &#8220;real Floridians&#8221; against the &#8220;Silicon Valley elites.&#8221; But no doubt those elites (and let us be candid — that is exactly what they are) will point out that in fact this is a clear-cut case of government overreach, censorship in the literal sense.</p>
<p>These strong legal objections will inform the inevitable lawsuits by the companies affected, which will probably be filed ahead of the law taking effect and aim to have it overturned.</p>
<p>Interestingly, two companies that will not be affected by the law are two of the biggest, most uncompromising corporations in the world: Disney and Comcast. Why, you ask? Because the law has a special exemption for any company &#8220;that owns and operates a theme park or entertainment complex&#8221; of a certain size.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s right, there&#8217;s a Mouse-shaped hole in this law — and Comcast, which owns Universal Studios, just happens to fit through as well. Notably this was added in an amendment, suggesting two of the largest employers in the state were unhappy at the idea of new liabilities for any of their digital properties.</p>
<p>This naked pandering to local corporate donors puts proponents of this law at something of an ethical disadvantage in their righteous battle against the elites, but favor may be moot in a few months&#8217; time when the legal challenges, probably being drafted at this moment, call for an injunction against SB 7072.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LyPBdPFuvc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/the-far-rights-favorite-registrar-is-building-censorship-resistant-servers/">The far right&#8217;s favorite registrar is building &#8216;censorship-resistant&#8217; servers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The far right&#8217;s favorite registrar is building &#8216;censorship-resistant&#8217; servers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/the-far-rights-favorite-registrar-is-building-censorship-resistant-servers/embed/#?secret=LyPBdPFuvc" data-secret="LyPBdPFuvc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/floridas-ban-on-bans-will-test-first-amendment-rights-of-social-media-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156748</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zocdoc says &#8216;programming errors&#8217; exposed access to patients&#8217; data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/zocdoc-bug-patient-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/zocdoc-bug-patient-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 22:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Password]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ZocDoc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Zocdoc says it has fixed a bug that allowed current and former staff at doctor&#8217;s offices and dental practices to access patient data because their user accounts weren&#8217;t properly decommissioned. The New York-based company revealed the issue in a letter to the California attorney general&#8217;s office, which requires companies with more than 500 residents of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Zocdoc says it has fixed a bug that allowed current and former staff at doctor&#8217;s offices and dental practices to access patient data because their user accounts weren&#8217;t properly decommissioned.</p>
<p>The New York-based company revealed the issue <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/20787225-zocdoc-security-incident?20787225">in a letter</a> to the California attorney general&#8217;s office, which requires companies with more than 500 residents of the state affected by a security lapse or breach to disclose the incident. Zocdoc confirmed that around 7,600 users across the U.S. are impacted by the security incident.</p>
<p>Zocdoc, which lets prospective patients book appointments with doctors and dentists, said that it gives each medical or dental practice usernames and passwords for its staff to access appointments made through Zocdoc, but that &#8220;programming errors&#8221; — essentially a software bug in Zocdoc&#8217;s own systems — &#8220;allowed some past or current practice staff members to access the provider portal after their usernames and passwords were intended to be removed, deleted or otherwise limited.&#8221;</p>
<p>The letter confirmed that patient data stored in Zocdoc&#8217;s portal could have been accessed, including a patient&#8217;s name, email address, phone number, and the times and dates of their appointments, but also other data that may have been shared with the practice — such as insurance details, Social Security numbers and details of the patient&#8217;s medical history.</p>
<p>But Zocdoc said payment card numbers, radiological or diagnostic reports, and medical records were not taken, since it does not store this data.</p>
<p>In an email, Zocdoc spokesperson Sandra Glading said that the company discovered the bug in August 2020, but &#8220;due to the complexity of the code, it took a significant amount of investigation to determine which, if any, practices and users were affected and how.&#8221; The company said it provided notice to the California&#8217;s attorney general&#8217;s office &#8220;as soon as was practicable.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zocdoc said it has &#8220;detailed logs that can detect exploitation of any data, including any potential exploitation of this vulnerability,&#8221; and that after a review of those logs and other investigative work, &#8220;we have no indication, at this time, that any personal information was misused in any way.&#8221;</p>
<p>Around 6 million users access Zocdoc a month, the company said.</p>
<p>If this incident sounds vaguely familiar, it&#8217;s because this was a near-identical security issue to one Zocdoc reported in 2016. A <a href="https://www.databreaches.net/patient-appointment-booking-service-notifying-patients-of-potential-breach/">letter filed at the time</a> cited similar &#8220;programming errors&#8221; that allowed staff at medical providers to improperly access patient data.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IVHOirDcs7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/how-to-respond-to-a-data-breach/">How to respond to a data breach</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to respond to a data breach&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/how-to-respond-to-a-data-breach/embed/#?secret=IVHOirDcs7" data-secret="IVHOirDcs7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/zocdoc-bug-patient-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156644</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Police search 2 Twitter offices in India after politician receives warning label</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/daily-crunch-9/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/daily-crunch-9/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 22:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Welcome back to Daily Crunch. It’s Monday, May 24, and all I can think about is how much I want a Surface Duo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/microsofts-surface-duo-gets-dual-screen-gaming-support/">now that it can do two-screen gaming</a>. And one of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/apple-24-inch-m1-imac-review/">those new iMacs</a>. I don’t need either, of course, but that doesn’t stop my coveting both of the gadgets. Alas.</p>
<p>Regardless, it was a super busy start to the week, with lots of startup funding rounds, more in the long-running saga of governments trying to control social media platforms, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/zeta-globals-ipo-filing-uncovers-modest-growth-strong-adjusted-profitability/">even more IPO news</a> and the latest troubles with Tesla. Let’s cut the chatter and dive in. &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Governments vs. Tech: </strong>Indian police tied to the central government showed up at two different Twitter offices today, in what <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/delhi-police-run-by-indias-central-government-raids-twitter-offices-over-manipulated-label/">appeared to be an intimidation effort</a> following Twitter’s decision to not unlabel a tweet from a member of the current ruling party as manipulated media.</li>
</ul>
<p>A few things here. First, India is <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/24/technology/florida-twitter-facebook-ban-politicians.html"><em>not</em> alone</a> in trying to force social media companies to behave as local governments want them to. That said, what the current Indian government is doing is particularly egregious and doesn’t bode well for the country’s tech ecosystem as a whole.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Tesla owes Norway: </strong>American electric car darling Tesla appears to be in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/tesla-faces-163m-payout-to-drivers-in-norway-following-court-decision/">hot water with Norway</a> after a “Norwegian conciliation council” ordered the company to pay $16,000 each to thousands of Model S owners after “it found that a software update led to longer charging times.” Ouch. Tesla will have to sell lots of American regulatory credits to cover that loss. Norway is a key market for EVs.</li>
<li><strong>U.S. cities buy abuse-linked tech:</strong> From the “you should read this” files, the latest report from our own Zack Whittaker and IPVM states that “at least a hundred U.S. counties, towns and cities <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/united-states-towns-hikvision-dahua-surveillance/">have bought Chinese-made surveillance systems that the U.S. government has linked to human rights abuses</a>.” Not good.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups and VC</h2>
<p>As always we’re picking and choosing the best rounds from the day, so feel free to scrounge around the blog if you need even more!</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/this-crypto-surveillance-startup-were-bomb-sniffing-dogs-just-raised-series-a-funding/"><strong>Solidus Labs raises $20M for crypto-snooping</strong></a><strong>:</strong> As the value of cryptocurrencies rose in the past year, so too did business at Solidus Labs, which detects “volume and price manipulation” among bitcoin and its brethren. Per its CEO, Asaf Meir, his company saw a “400% increase in inbound demand over 2020.” That sounds about right. Also, Solidus should drop a monthly report on the level of manipulation on every exchange and crypto. That would rule.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/fireflies-ai-raises-14m-for-its-meeting-transcription-and-automation-service/"><strong>Fireflies.ai raises $14M to record, transcribe and connect your meetings</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Former Acceleprise company Fireflies is building software that will record and transcribe your meetings, and then connect the text &#8212; and perhaps the embedded tasks &#8212; to other bits of software. It’s interesting, and growing like a weed. So Khosla helped put $14 million into it.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/nigerias-mono-raises-millions-to-power-the-internet-economy-in-africa/"><strong>Mono raises $2M to power African fintech</strong></a><strong>:</strong> From building the Plaid for Africa to “power the internet economy in Africa,” Mono is not short on vision. And now it has had its accounts refreshed to pursue its plans to “[streamline] various financial data in a single API for companies and third-party developers.” APIs are cool. Fintech is cool. Fintech APIs are extra cool. That’s our take.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/seed-stage-accelerator-flat6labs-closes-13-2m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/"><strong>Flat6Labs raises $13.2M to fund Egyptian startups</strong></a><strong>:</strong> This is fund news, but it’s small enough that it fits inside the startup section today. In short, since 2011 Flat6Labs has been an accelerator in Egypt and Tunisia. And now it has a new checkbook to play with.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/zeta-globals-ipo-filing-uncovers-modest-growth-strong-adjusted-profitability/"><strong>Inside Zeta Global’s IPO</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Finally from the startup world today, Zeta Global is going public. It’s an offering that could set the tone for the martech world for some time to come. So, we dug into its numbers a bit tardily to figure out just what Zeta has that public investors might want.</p>
<h2>When to walk away from a VC who wants to invest in your startup</h2>
<p>Ofri Ben-Porat flew from London to NYC to meet potential investors, but at the last minute, one canceled, claiming illness. Moments later, he received a DocSend push notification informing him that said VC had just opened the pitch deck he&#8217;d sent days before.</p>
<p>Undeterred, he showed up anyway and pretended he hadn&#8217;t received their email. The discussion went well; after he flew home, the VCs offered pre-terms and due diligence, &#8220;but ultimately, I didn’t feel right taking money from them,&#8221; says Ben-Porat.</p>
<p>Securing the right amount of funding at the right moment can make or break a startup, but founders who can&#8217;t identify red flags — or worse, ignore them — will live to regret it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZifzZctmaY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/when-to-walk-away-from-a-vc-who-wants-to-invest-in-your-startup/">When to walk away from a VC who wants to invest in your startup</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;When to walk away from a VC who wants to invest in your startup&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/when-to-walk-away-from-a-vc-who-wants-to-invest-in-your-startup/embed/#?secret=ZifzZctmaY" data-secret="ZifzZctmaY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>What has a zillion hands and likes to copy its friends? Facebook! This time, however, Facebook could be doing something interesting. TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/new-instagram-insights-make-its-tiktok-competitor-reels-more-appealing/">dug through some creator-friendly feature work</a> that Big Blue is putting into its TikTok clone. So it’s still running the copy machine at full tilt, just with a few upgrades.</p>
<p>Turning back to Apple, not everything is M1 chips and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/purple-iphone-purple-iphone-purple-iphone-purple-iphone-purple-iphone/">purple iPhones</a>. Some things are less good at the Cupertino-based technology leviathan. Today <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/malware-xcsset-macos/">TechCrunch reported on a few different macOS vulnerabilities</a> that, frankly, don’t sound good. What’s the old adage? Buy a PC; they just work?</p>
<p>In happier Apple news, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/apple-just-dropped-a-whole-bunch-of-os-updates-and-wwdc-info/">has a <em>pile</em> of new software updates</a> for your enjoyment, especially if you are an iPhone or iPad user.</p>
<p>Don’t fret, Microsoft fans, we have something for you as well. Namely a review of the new Surface Laptop 4. It’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/23/taking-microsofts-surface-laptop-4-for-a-spin/">pretty darn good</a>, keeping all its predecessor’s weaknesses and strengths, with new guts.</p>
<p>Wrapping, ByteDance has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/capcut-bytedance-tiktok/">another chart-topping app</a>; Airbnb is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/airbnb-doubles-down-on-flexible-search-improves-the-host-flow-in-preparation-for-summer-2021/">doubling down on guest flexibility</a>, though we have questions; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/siriusxm-partners-with-tiktok-on-a-new-music-channel-pandora-playlists-and-more/">SiriusXM is partnering with TikTok</a> on a new channel; and SensorTower is making sure that there is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/sensor-tower-makes-its-first-acquisition-with-deal-for-market-intelligence-company-pathmatics/">at least <em>some</em> M&amp;A to report on</a>.</p>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Email Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2154311" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154311" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2154311" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?w=680" alt="Intellect illustration" width="680" height="427" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg 7311w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=1536,964 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=2048,1286 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2154311" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch Experts is still collecting survey responses to help us identify the top email marketers in tech!</p>
<p>At this time, we’re not looking for self-nominations &#8212; we’re only seeking nominations from clients. We want to hear all about your experience and how you found the right expert for your needs. <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/oYNNmGpd">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>We’re excited to move this project forward. Visit <a href="https://techcrunch.com/experts/">techcrunch.com/experts</a> to find out more!</p>
<h2>TC Eventful</h2>
<p>Last year, we held our first dedicated space startup event, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020">TC Sessions: Space</a>, featuring some of the industry&#8217;s top founders and leaders, including <strong>Rocket Lab&#8217;s Peter Beck, Lockheed Martin&#8217;s Lisa Callahan, Amazon&#8217;s Dave Limp, NASA&#8217;s Kathy Lueders</strong> and many more. This year, we&#8217;re excited to announce we&#8217;re doing it again with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021?promo=launchpost">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a>, happening virtually December 14-15.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0NdBY9ConV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/tc-sessions-space-is-returning-in-december/">TC: Sessions Space is returning in December</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TC: Sessions Space is returning in December&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/tc-sessions-space-is-returning-in-december/embed/#?secret=0NdBY9ConV" data-secret="0NdBY9ConV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2022&amp;utm_content=sua&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sua&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a> is right around the corner of your calendar (June 9). If you want to place your ground-breaking, edge-cutting, envelope-pushing (no extra charge for clichés) early-stage startup in front of the world’s leading mobility movers, shakers and makers you gotta hustle. You have just one week left to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2022&amp;utm_content=sua&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sua&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">buy one of our remaining three Startup Exhibitor Packages.</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zvgyQ7tYDB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/only-3-startup-demo-booths-left-at-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/">Only 3 startup demo booths left at TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Only 3 startup demo booths left at TC Sessions: Mobility 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/only-3-startup-demo-booths-left-at-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/embed/#?secret=zvgyQ7tYDB" data-secret="zvgyQ7tYDB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/daily-crunch-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156729</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
