<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 14:28:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>With liberty and privacy for some: Widening inequality on the digital frontier</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/with-liberty-and-privacy-for-some-widening-inequality-on-the-digital-frontier/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/with-liberty-and-privacy-for-some-widening-inequality-on-the-digital-frontier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 14:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187017</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We deserve meaningful privacy protections that no company can afford to omit from their products. We deserve a both/and approach: Privacy that is both meaningful and widely available.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Cillian Kieran</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/cillian">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Cillian Kieran is CEO and co-founder of <a href="https://ethyca.com/">Ethyca</a>, a New York-based privacy company.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Privacy is emotional — we often value privacy the most when we feel vulnerable or powerless when confronted with creepy data practices. But in the eyes of the court, emotions don&#8217;t always constitute harm or a reason for structural change in how privacy is legally codified.</p>
<p>It might take a material perspective on widening privacy disparities — and their implication in broader social inequality — to catalyze the privacy improvements the U.S. desperately needs.</p>
<p>Apple&#8217;s leaders announced their plans for the App Tracking Transparency (ATT) update in 2020. In short, iOS users can refuse an app&#8217;s ability to track their activity on other apps and websites. The ATT update has led to a sweeping <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/after-apple-tightens-tracking-rules-advertisers-shift-spending-toward-android-devices-11625477401">three-quarters</a> of iOS users opting out of cross-app tracking.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Whenever one user base gears up with privacy protections, companies simply redirect their data practices along the path of least resistance.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>With less data available to advertisers looking to develop individual profiles for targeted advertising, targeted ads for iOS users look less effective and appealing to ad agencies. As a result, new findings show that advertisers are spending <a href="https://bgr.com/tech/apples-iphone-is-so-good-at-protecting-privacy-advertisers-are-giving-up-and-switching-to-android/">one-third less</a> in advertising spending on iOS devices.</p>
<p>They are redirecting that capital into advertising on Android systems, which<a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/os-market-share/mobile/united-states-of-america"> account</a> for just over 42.06% of the mobile OS market share, compared to iOS at 57.62%.</p>
<p>Beyond a vague sense of creepiness, privacy disparities increasingly pose risks of material harm: emotional, reputational, economic and otherwise. If privacy belongs to all of us, as many tech companies say, then why does it cost so much? Whenever one user base gears up with privacy protections, companies simply redirect their data practices along the path of least resistance, toward the populations with fewer resources, legal or technical, to control their data.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>More than just ads</h2>
<p>As more money goes into Android ads, we could expect advertising techniques to become more sophisticated, or at least more aggressive. It is not illegal for companies to engage in targeted advertising, so long as it is done in compliance with users&#8217; legal rights to opt out under relevant laws like CCPA in California.</p>
<p>This raises two immediate issues. First, residents of every state except California currently lack such opt-out rights. Second, granting some users the right to opt out of targeted advertising strongly implies that there are harms, or at least risks, to targeted advertising. And indeed, there can be.</p>
<p>Targeted advertising involves third parties building and maintaining behind-the-scenes profiles of users based on their behavior. Gathering data on app activity, such as fitness habits or shopping patterns, could lead to further inferences about sensitive aspects of a user&#8217;s life.</p>
<p>At this point, a representation of a user exists in an under-regulated data system containing — whether correctly or incorrectly inferenced — data that the user did not consent to sharing. (Unless the user lives in California, but let&#8217;s suppose they live anywhere else in the U.S.)</p>
<p>Further, research finds that targeted advertising, in building detailed profiles of users, can enact discrimination in<a href="https://hbr.org/2019/11/how-targeted-ads-and-dynamic-pricing-can-perpetuate-bias"> housing and employment opportunities</a>, sometimes in violation of federal law. And targeted advertising can impede individuals&#8217; autonomy, preemptively narrowing their window of purchasing options, even when they don&#8217;t want to. On the other hand, targeted advertising can support niche or grassroots organizations in connecting them directly with interested audiences. Regardless of a stance on targeted advertising, the underlying problem is when users have no say in whether they are subject to it.</p>
<p>Targeted advertising is a massive and booming practice, but it is only one practice within a broader web of business activities that do not prioritize respect for users&#8217; data. And these practices are not illegal in much of the U.S. Instead of the law, your pocketbook can keep you clear of data disrespect.</p>
<h2>Privacy as a luxury</h2>
<p>Prominent tech companies, particularly Apple, declare privacy a human right, which makes complete sense from a business standpoint. In the absence of the U.S. federal government codifying privacy rights for all consumers, a bold privacy commitment from a private company sounds pretty appealing.</p>
<p><em>If the government isn&#8217;t going to set a privacy standard, at least my phone manufacturer will</em>. Even though only<a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2020/05/04/how-americans-see-digital-privacy-issues-amid-the-covid-19-outbreak/"> 6%</a> of Americans claim to understand how companies use their data, it is companies that are making the broad privacy moves.</p>
<p>But if those declaring privacy as a human right only make products affordable to some, what does that say about our human rights? Apple products skew toward<a href="https://www.comscore.com/Insights/Infographics/iPhone-Users-Earn-Higher-Income-Engage-More-on-Apps-than-Android-Users"> wealthier, more educated consumers</a> compared to competitors&#8217; products. This projects a troubling future of increasingly exacerbated privacy disparities between the haves and the have-nots, where a feedback loop is established: Those with fewer resources to acquire privacy protections may have fewer resources to navigate the technical and legal challenges that come with a practice as convoluted as targeted advertising.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t take this as me siding with Facebook in its feud with Apple about privacy versus affordability (see:<a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-fired-dozens-abusing-access-user-data-an-ugly-truth-2021-7"> systemic access control issues</a> recently coming to light). In my view, neither side of that battle is winning.</p>
<p>We deserve meaningful privacy protections that everyone can afford. In fact, to turn the phrase on its head, <em>we deserve meaningful privacy protections that no company can afford to omit from their products. </em>We deserve a both/and approach: privacy that is both meaningful and widely available.</p>
<h2>Our next steps forward</h2>
<p>Looking ahead, there are two key areas for privacy progress: privacy legislation and privacy tooling for developers. I again invoke the both/and approach. We need lawmakers, rather than tech companies, setting reliable privacy standards for consumers. And we need widely available developer tools that give developers no reason — financially, logistically or otherwise — to implement privacy at the product level.</p>
<p>On privacy legislation, I believe that policy professionals are already raising some excellent points, so I&#8217;ll direct you to some of my favorite recent writing from them.</p>
<p>Stacey Gray and her team at the Future of Privacy Forum have begun an excellent<a href="https://fpf.org/blog/preemption-in-us-federal-privacy-laws/"> blog series</a> on how a federal privacy law could interact with the emerging patchwork of state laws.</p>
<p>Joe Jerome published an outstanding<a href="https://techpolicy.press/a-post-mortem-on-state-privacy-legislation/"> recap</a> of the 2021 state-level privacy landscape and the routes toward widespread privacy protections for all Americans. A key takeaway: The effectiveness of privacy regulation hinges on how well it harmonizes among individuals and businesses. That&#8217;s not to say that regulation should be business-friendly, but rather that businesses should be able to reference clear privacy standards so they can confidently and respectfully handle everyday folks&#8217; data.</p>
<p>On privacy tooling, if we make privacy tools readily accessible and affordable for all developers, we really leave tech with zero excuses to meet privacy standards. Take the issue of access control, for instance. Engineers attempt to build manual controls over which personnel and end users can access various data in a complex data ecosystem already populated with sensitive personal information.</p>
<p>The challenge is twofold. First, the horse has already bolted. Technical debt accumulates rapidly, while privacy has remained outside of software development. Engineers need tools that enable them to build privacy features like nuanced access control prior to production.</p>
<p>This leads into the second aspect of the challenge: Even if the engineers overcame all of the technical debt and could make structural privacy improvements at the code level, what standards and widely available tools are available to use?</p>
<p>As a June 2021<a href="https://fpf.org/blog/new-fpf-report-highlights-privacy-tech-sector-evolving-from-compliance-tools-to-platforms-for-risk-management-and-data-utilization/"> report</a> from the Future of Privacy Forum makes clear, privacy technology is in dire need of consistent definitions, which are required for widespread adoption of trustworthy privacy tools. With more consistent definitions and widely available developer tools for privacy, these technical transformations translate into material improvements in how tech at large — not just tech of Brand XYZ — gives users control over their data.</p>
<p>We need privacy rules set by an institution that is not itself playing the game. Regulation alone cannot save us from modern privacy perils, but it is a vital ingredient in any viable solution.</p>
<p>Alongside regulation, every software engineering team should have privacy tools immediately available. When civil engineers are building a bridge, they cannot make it safe for a subset of the population; it must work for all who cross it. The same must hold for our data infrastructure, lest we exacerbate disparities within and beyond the digital realm.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qukgtht9od"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/building-customer-first-relationships-in-a-privacy-first-world-is-critical/">Building customer-first relationships in a privacy-first world is critical</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Building customer-first relationships in a privacy-first world is critical&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/building-customer-first-relationships-in-a-privacy-first-world-is-critical/embed/#?secret=qukgtht9od" data-secret="qukgtht9od" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/with-liberty-and-privacy-for-some-widening-inequality-on-the-digital-frontier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187017</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robinhood buys Say Technologies for $140M to improve shareholder-company relations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/robinhood-buys-say-technologies-for-140m-to-improve-shareholder-company-relations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/robinhood-buys-say-technologies-for-140m-to-improve-shareholder-company-relations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 14:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CrunchBase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PitchBook Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The deal is notable because it is Robinhood's first major purchase since going public in July, and because it illustrates where Robinhood may look to invest some of its newly liquid equity wealth.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">U.S. consumer investing and trading service Robinhood announced this morning that it will acquire Say Technologies in a $140 million cash deal.</p>
<p>Say Technologies is a venture-backed startup, having <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/asayinc/company_financials">raised $8 million in 2018, per Crunchbase data</a>. <a href="https://pitchbook.com/">PitchBook data</a> indicates that the company was worth $28 million on a post-money basis following the investment, implying that the company&#8217;s backers managed a roughly 5x return on their investment.</p>
<p>Say was backed by Point72 Ventures, among other investors.</p>
<p>The deal is notable because it is Robinhood&#8217;s first major purchase since going public in late July, and because it illustrates where Robinhood may look to invest some of its newly liquid equity wealth; when a company goes public, it can more easily purchase other companies thanks to recharged cash balances and a floating stock.</p>
<p>In a blog post, Robinhood <a href="https://blog.robinhood.com/news/2021/8/10/say-technologies-is-joining-robinhood">wrote</a> that &#8220;Say was built on the belief that everyone should have the same access to the financial markets as Wall Street insiders.&#8221; What does that mean? In practice, Say has built a communications platform that allows even smaller shareholders to pose questions to the companies in which they invest. Sure, some companies are including retail questions in their earnings calls, but what Say has in mind is broader.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OYzir089JD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/everyone-wants-to-fund-the-next-coinbase/">Everyone wants to fund the next Coinbase</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Everyone wants to fund the next Coinbase&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/everyone-wants-to-fund-the-next-coinbase/embed/#?secret=OYzir089JD" data-secret="OYzir089JD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>You can see how Say and Robinhood might fit together. Robinhood has a huge user pool of retail investors who like to trade and invest. Say has the technology to connect retail investors to the companies that they own. With Robinhood&#8217;s database of which retail investor owns what, and Say&#8217;s communications tech, the trading platform may be able to offer a better shareholder experience than what rival platforms can offer.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>By offering a service like what Say has built to its user base, Robinhood can offer a unique twist on retail investing. This feels somewhat analogous to Spotify spending heavily to procure exclusive rights to certain podcasts; such efforts differentiate Spotify from rivals despite having a commoditized core offering. Trading is now free in many places, so Robinhood layering specialized services on top of its investing service makes good sense, perhaps helping drive user loyalty and net new-user adds.</p>
<p>Shares of Robinhood are off around 1.2% today, despite generally higher markets. We might say that investors were selling lightly in wake of the news, but that would be a somewhat bold read of the day&#8217;s trading.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/robinhood-buys-say-technologies-for-140m-to-improve-shareholder-company-relations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187969</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>1910 Genetics&#8217; Jen Nwankwo and Playground Global&#8217;s Jory Bell are joining us for Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/1910-genetics-jen-nwankwo-and-playground-globals-jory-bell-are-joining-us-for-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/1910-genetics-jen-nwankwo-and-playground-globals-jory-bell-are-joining-us-for-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 14:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playground global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2181838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live gives you the chance to hear live from entrepreneurs who have successfully raised significant rounds of venture capital -- and from the investors who believed in them.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Our Extra Crunch Live series continues with some heavy hitters in August, including Jen Nwankwo, founder and CEO at 1910 Genetics, and Playground Global general partner Jory Bell. They&#8217;ll be with us live on <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-playground-global-and-1910-genetics">August 11 at 12 p.m. PT (3 p.m. ET)</a> to tell us all about how Nwankwo and her startup won over Bell and Playground as an investor, and as we do every week on Extra Crunch Live, we&#8217;ll conduct a live pitch feedback session featuring you, the members of our audience.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live gives you the chance to hear live from entrepreneurs who have successfully raised significant rounds of venture capital &#8212; and from the investors who believed in them. We go into detail about how the deal got done, and you&#8217;ll hear from both about what it takes to pitch VCs and what industry-leading VCs look for in prospective portfolio companies.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re thrilled to have Nwankwo and Bell joining us for this episode. Nwankwo founded and leads 1910 Genetics, which takes advantage of AI to accelerate the discovery and development of new drug therapies across a wide range of disease and condition categories. She has a Ph.D. in pharmacology and experimental therapeutics from Tufts University School of Medicine and participated in drug discovery development that led to the creation of Type 2 diabetes drug Trulicity prior to her graduate school work.</p>
<p>Bell&#8217;s career includes designing and building autonomous robots for deep-sea exploration, as well as a six-year stint at Apple designing notebooks for the consumer technology leader. Bell&#8217;s venture investment work began at Playground Global in 2015; he focuses on deep tech investments, including in aerospace, genomics, synthetic biology, and AI-assisted drug discovery, as in the case of 1910 Genetics.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live also features the ECL Pitch-off, where startups in the audience can virtually “raise their hand” to pitch their startup live on our stream. Our expert guests will give their feedback on each pitch. If you want to throw your hat in the ring, you have to show up.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live is accessible to everyone, but only Extra Crunch members can access the content on demand. We do these every week, so there are scores of episodes across a wide variety of startup sectors in the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">ECL Library</a>. It’s but one of many reasons to become an Extra Crunch member. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Join here.</a></p>
<p>Interested in hanging with us for this upcoming episode? <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-playground-global-and-1910-genetics">Register here for free! </a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/1910-genetics-jen-nwankwo-and-playground-globals-jory-bell-are-joining-us-for-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2181838</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Venmo to allow credit cardholders to automatically buy cryptocurrency with their cash back</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/venmo-to-allow-credit-cardholders-to-automatically-buy-cryptocurrency-with-their-cash-back/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/venmo-to-allow-credit-cardholders-to-automatically-buy-cryptocurrency-with-their-cash-back/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venmo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187950</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PayPal-owned Venmo is expanding its support for cryptocurrency with today&#8217;s launch of a new feature that will allow users to automatically buy cryptocurrency using the cash back they earned from their Venmo credit card purchases. Unlike when buying cryptocurrency directly, these automated purchases will have no transaction fees associated with them &#8212; a feature Venmo [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">PayPal-owned Venmo is expanding its support for cryptocurrency with today&#8217;s launch of a new feature that will allow users to automatically buy cryptocurrency using the cash back they earned from their Venmo credit card purchases. Unlike when buying cryptocurrency directly, these automated purchases will have no transaction fees associated with them &#8212; a feature Venmo says is not a promotion, but how the system will work long term. Instead, a cryptocurrency conversion spread is built into each monthly transaction.</p>
<p>Cardholders will be able to purchase Bitcoin, Ethereum, Litecoin and Bitcoin Cash through the new &#8220;Cash Back to Crypto&#8221; option, rolling out now to the Venmo app.</p>
<p>Venmo had first introduced the ability for customers to buy, hold and sell cryptocurrency in April of this year, as part of a larger investment in cryptocurrency led by parent company, PayPal. In partnership with <a href="https://www.paxos.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.paxos.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618924466703000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFORHplBX48OKy9S0KRYp6IimIx9A"><span class="m_-111796029276706869normaltextrun">Paxos Trust Company</span></a><span class="m_-111796029276706869normaltextrun">, a regulated provider of cryptocurrency products and services, Venmo&#8217;s over 70 million users are now able to access cryptocurrency from within the Venmo app. </span></p>
<p>The cash back feature, meanwhile, could help drive sign-ups for the Venmo Credit Card, by interlinking it with the cryptocurrency functionality. Currently, Venmo cardholders can earn monthly cash back across eight different spending categories, with up to 3% back on their top eligible spending category, then 2% and 1% back on the second highest and all other purchases, respectively. The top two categories are adjusted monthly, based on where consumers are spending the most.</p>
<p>To enable Cash Back to Crypto, Venmo customers will navigate to the Venmo Credit Card home screen in the app, select the Rewards tab, then &#8220;Get Started.&#8221; From here, they&#8217;ll agree to the terms, select the crypto of their choice, and confirm their selection. Once enabled, when the cash back funds hit the customer&#8217;s Venmo balance, the money is immediately used to make a crypto purchase &#8212; no interaction on the user&#8217;s part is required.</p>
<p>The feature will not include any transaction fees, as a cryptocurrency conversion spread is built into each monthly transaction. This is similar to how <a href="https://newsroom.paypal-corp.com/2021-03-30-PayPal-Launches-Checkout-with-Crypto">PayPal is handling Checkout with Crypto,</a> which allows online shoppers to make purchases using their cryptocurrency. The cryptocurrency is converted to fiat, but there are not transaction fees.</p>
<p>The feature can also be turned on or off at any time, Venmo notes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company views Cash Back to Crypto as a way for newcomers to cryptocurrency to enter the market, without having to worry about the process of making crypto purchases. It&#8217;s more of a set-it-and-forget-it type of feature. However, unless users make regular and frequent transactions with their Venmo Credit Card, these cash back-enabled crypto purchases will likely be fairly small.</p>
<p>The company has yet to offer details on how many Venmo credit cardholders are active in the market. So far, PayPal CEO Dan Schulman has only said, during Q1 earnings, that the card &#8220;is outpacing our expectations for both new accounts and transactions.&#8221; This past quarter, the exec noted that the company was also seeing &#8220;strong adoption and trading of crypto on Venmo.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The introduction of the Cash Back to Crypto feature for the Venmo Credit Card offers customers a new way to start exploring the world of crypto, using their cash back earned each month to automatically and seamlessly purchase one of four cryptocurrencies on Venmo,&#8221; noted Darrell Esch, SVP and GM at Venmo, in a statement. &#8220;We’re excited to bring this new level of feature interconnectivity on the Venmo platform, linking our Venmo Credit Card and crypto experiences to provide another way for our customers to spend and manage their money with Venmo,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>The new option will begin rolling out starting today to Venmo Credit Cardholders.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/venmo-to-allow-credit-cardholders-to-automatically-buy-cryptocurrency-with-their-cash-back/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187950</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surfside, a marketing technology for the cannabis space, inhales $4 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/surfside-a-marketing-technology-for-the-cannabis-space-inhales-4-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/surfside-a-marketing-technology-for-the-cannabis-space-inhales-4-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cannabis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casa verde]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187944</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surfside, a data and marketing platform aimed directly at the Cannabis industry, has today announced the close of a $4 million seed round led by Casa Verde. The firm&#8217;s managing partner, Karan Wadhera, will join the Surfside board. The startup is relatively new, but helmed by two founders experienced in the marketing and data space. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://surfside.io/">Surfside</a>, a data and marketing platform aimed directly at the Cannabis industry, has today announced the close of a $4 million seed round led by Casa Verde. The firm&#8217;s managing partner, Karan Wadhera, will join the Surfside board.</p>
<p>The startup is relatively new, but helmed by two founders experienced in the marketing and data space. Jon Lowen and Michael Blanche both hail from SITO Mobile, where they worked on location-based advertising and marketing via mobile devices.</p>
<p>The duo has built a platform that uses many of the same principles to bring better marketing acumen and strategies to bbusinesses in the cannabis space.</p>
<p>One of the major marketing challenges for dispensaries and cannabis brands is that the usual channels through which small brands advertise &mdash; Facebook and Google &mdash; are not available to them. Not only are those powerful marketing channels, but they also provide valuable analytics about potential and existing customers.</p>
<p>Surfside looks to fill that gap in the cannabis space, offering businesses data around their customers using a combination of existing data, publicly available data, loyalty program data, etc. to help these brands better understand their customers.</p>
<p>The startup creates profiles of customers, looking to understand their location, their other interests, and other important details that can help brands and businesses market and advertise to both existing and new customers.</p>
<p>But Surfside actually goes a step further and develops campaigns for these businesses, allowing them to work one-on-one with a marketing expert to develop and activate these campaigns.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Originally, Surfside generated revenue via the campaign itself, taking a cut of the spend.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re almost an extension of the marketing departments at a dispensary,&#8221; said Lowen. &#8220;Small dispensaries don&#8217;t necessarily have the bandwidth to run these campaigns or log into extra software. Our team can help plan, execute and get the most value out of the data for them. Now, we want to start empowering brands, retailers, dispensaries as they progress to be able to have ownership of the data, with these consumer insights and research at their fingertips, and give them the ability to decide if they want to activate on their own or continue using the experts we have here.&#8221;</p>
<p>With this new financing, the company is adding another revenue stream through its data platform, allowing cannabis businesses to purchase a SaaS license. This way, businesses who&#8217;d like to use the data but develop their own campaigns and marketing strategies have the option to do so.</p>
<p>Surfside believes that their technology can expand well beyond cannabis and into other verticals, but see an opportunity in the cannabis space to grow and build alongside the burgeoning industry.</p>
<p>Moreover, the complicated regulatory landscape in the cannabis space allows Surfside to become a compliance monitor, as well, which may end up being yet another revenue stream for the company.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/surfside-a-marketing-technology-for-the-cannabis-space-inhales-4-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187944</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Salesforce&#8217;s Kathy Baxter is coming to TC Sessions: SaaS to talk AI</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/salesforces-kathy-baxter-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas-to-talk-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/salesforces-kathy-baxter-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas-to-talk-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abby Kearns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ali ghodsi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Casey Aylward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daniel Dines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Databricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kathy Baxter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarah Guo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: SaaS 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uipath]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185776</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the use of AI has grown and developed over the last several years, companies like Salesforce have tried to tap into it to improve their software and help customers operate faster and more efficiently. Kathy Baxter, principal architect for the ethical AI practice at Salesforce will be joining us at TechCrunch Sessions: SaaS on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As the use of AI has grown and developed over the last several years, companies like <a href="http://salesforce.com">Salesforce</a> have tried to tap into it to improve their software and help customers operate faster and more efficiently. Kathy Baxter, principal architect for the ethical AI practice at Salesforce will be joining us at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=kathybaxterpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=kathybaxterpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TechCrunch Sessions: SaaS</a> on October 27th to talk about the impact of AI on SaaS.</p>
<p>Baxter, who has more than 20 years of experience as a software architect, joined Salesforce in 2017 after more than a decade at Google in a similar role. We&#8217;re going to tap into her expertise on a panel discussing AI&#8217;s growing role in software.</p>
<p>Salesforce was one of the earlier SaaS adherents to AI, announcing its artificial intelligence tooling, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/18/salesforce-turns-its-attention-to-artificial-intelligence-with-salesforce-einstein/">the company dubbed Einstein</a>, in 2016. While the positioning makes it sound like a product, it&#8217;s actually much more than a single entity. It&#8217;s a platform component, which the various pieces of the Salesforce platform can tap into to take advantage of various types of AI to help improve the user experience.</p>
<p>That could involve feeding information to customer service reps on Service Cloud to make the call move along more efficiently, helping salespeople find the customers most likely to close a deal soon in the Sales Cloud or helping marketing understand the optimal time to send an email in the Marketing Cloud.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IFp4AkiCfW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/18/salesforce-turns-its-attention-to-artificial-intelligence-with-salesforce-einstein/">Salesforce Einstein delivers artificial intelligence across the Salesforce platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce Einstein delivers artificial intelligence across the Salesforce platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/18/salesforce-turns-its-attention-to-artificial-intelligence-with-salesforce-einstein/embed/#?secret=IFp4AkiCfW" data-secret="IFp4AkiCfW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company began building out its AI tooling early on with the help of 175 data scientists and has been expanding on that initial idea since. Other companies, both startups and established companies like SAP, Oracle and Microsoft have continued to build AI into their platforms as Salesforce has. Today, many SaaS companies have some underlying AI built into their service.</p>
<p>Baxter will join us to discuss the role of AI in software today and how that helps improve the operations of the service itself, and what the implications are of using AI in your software service as it becomes a mainstream part of the SaaS development process.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition to our discussion with Baxter, the conference will also include Databricks’ Ali Ghodsi, UiPath’s Daniel Dines, Puppet’s Abby Kearns, and investors Casey Aylward and Sarah Guo, among others. We hope you&#8217;ll join us. It&#8217;s going to be a stimulating day.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=kathybaxterpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=kathybaxterpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your pass now</a> to save up to $100, and use CrunchMatch to make expanding your empire quick, easy and efficient. We can’t wait to see you in October!</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TC Sessions: SaaS 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-2f083db94b8f5e8250b262cd4659d929"
			width="99%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/2f083db94b8f5e8250b262cd4659d929"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-2f083db94b8f5e8250b262cd4659d929')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-2f083db94b8f5e8250b262cd4659d929'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/salesforces-kathy-baxter-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas-to-talk-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185776</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jumia&#8217;s Q2 results show moderate growth, rising spend, and continued losses</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/jumias-q2-results-show-moderate-growth-rising-spend-and-continued-losses/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/jumias-q2-results-show-moderate-growth-rising-spend-and-continued-losses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 13:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jumia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Internet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187930</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[African e-commerce giant Jumia today reported its second-quarter financial performance. In the wake of its earnings reports, Jumia&#8217;s shares climbed 3.38% to $21.99 per share with a market cap of $2.168 billion. Before we get into the company&#8217;s results, Jumia historically reported in its financial data in Euros. This was the case until April 1, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">African e-commerce giant Jumia today reported its <a href="https://s23.q4cdn.com/836376591/files/doc_financials/2021/q2/JMIA-Q2.21-ER-10.08.21.pdf">second-quarter financial performance</a>. In the wake of its earnings reports, Jumia&#8217;s shares climbed 3.38% to $21.99 per share with a market cap of $2.168 billion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before we get into the company&#8217;s results, Jumia historically reported in its financial data in Euros</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This was the case until April 1, when the company swapped for the American dollar.  </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jumia cites increases in cash balances from equity fundraising as the main reason backing this outcome</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The company adds that although the Dollar will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be used</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> going forward, starting from Q2 2021, comparative numbers from previous quarters &#8220;have </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been modified</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to reflect the change in presentation currency.&#8221; That will help us keep all the math straight.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, back to business. In the second quarter of 2021, Jumia reported revenues of $40.2 million, up 4.6% on a year-over-year basis.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wall Street <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/investing/stock/jmia?mod=mw_quote_tab">was optimistic</a> that Jumia would report revenue of $43.34 million, up from the $38.5 million recorded in Q2 2020</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although the company did not meet revenue expectations, it did surpass investor expectations of a loss worth $0.43 a share by reporting a more modest $0.41 per-share loss in the second quarter. For reference, Jumia lost $0.61 per share in the year-ago period.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the African e-commerce company has shifted from first-party sales to a marketplace for third parties, its first-party revenue increased 7% year-over-year in the second quarter. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jumia&#8217;s marketplace revenue, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">on the other hand</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, grew a smaller 0.6% to $26.2 million. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The revenue mix-shift helped Jumia&#8217;s gross profit grow 4% to $26.8 million in the most recent quarter compared to its year-ago comparable. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gross profit after fulfillment expense also expanded 16.3% to $7.7 million</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2>Continued losses</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Jumia&#8217;s operating losses and adjusted EBITDA declined in Q1 2021, they increased this past quarter</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Operating losses were $51.6 million in Q2 2021, up 24.7%, while adjusted EBITDA came in at -$41.6 million, worsening 15.1% compared to Q2 2020.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sharp losses were driven in part by how the African e-commerce juggernaut spent in the quarter. Jumia&#8217;s sales and advertising expenses rose</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 115% to $17.1 million. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the year-ago quarter, the number was a far-smaller $7.9 million. The huge gain in sales and advertising spending may indicate that the company is back to its old method of executing aggressive advertising, which initially slowed during the pandemic. </span></p>
<p>The company&#8217;s rising costs and declining profitability are not encouraging regarding its chances for near-term profitability. However, the company stressed long-term investments in its business in its earnings report that Jumia expects to leverage in the coming quarters and years. Given that Jumia&#8217;s shares rose following its earnings report, it appears that investors are at least amenable to the argument. Still, the company&#8217;s metrics paint a mixed picture of its efforts.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For instance, Jumia&#8217;s active customers only grew by 3.3% to 7 million in the second quarter, while orders grew by a stronger 12.8% to 7.6 million. In contrast, gross merchandise volume (GMV) fell 11% to $223.5 million in the second quarter.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jumia&#8217;s falling GMV impacted the total payment volume (TPV) of its payment arm, JumiaPay, in the quarter. That figure fell 4% to $56.6 million, compared to the year-ago quarter.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That said, on other fronts, JumiaPay&#8217;s recent results are impressive. The payment service&#8217;s &#8220;on-platform penetration&#8221; as a portion of GMV grew to 23.5% in the second quarter. And transactions made on the platform grew 12.1% to 2.7 million &#8212; the fastest transaction growth rate Jumia has </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">witnessed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the past four quarters, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">mostly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> supported by the company&#8217;s food delivery category.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the space of five months, from October 2020 to February 2021, Jumia&#8217;s share price spiked over 700% to $65, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">mostly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> due to the pandemic increasing appetite for e-commerce stocks globally. But the company&#8217;s share price has dropped </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">by more than 60% from those highs to a close at $21.27 last Friday.</span></p>
<p>Jumia closed its most recent quarter with $637.7 million in cash, which means that it has a good amount of runway ahead of itself to sort out growth and profitability.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/jumias-q2-results-show-moderate-growth-rising-spend-and-continued-losses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187930</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Everyone wants to fund the next Coinbase</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/everyone-wants-to-fund-the-next-coinbase/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/everyone-wants-to-fund-the-next-coinbase/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 13:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[falconx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In celebration of Coinbase's earnings report today, investors poured a mountain of cash into one of the company's global competitors.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In celebration of Coinbase&#8217;s earnings report today, investors poured a mountain of cash into one of the company&#8217;s global competitors.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m kidding, of course, but today really is <a href="https://investor.coinbase.com/news/news-details/2021/Coinbase-Announces-Date-of-Second-Quarter-2021-Financial-Results/default.aspx">Coinbase&#8217;s earnings day</a>, and private investors really did just push $210 million into another exchange.</p>
<p>The company, FalconX, is now worth $3.75 billion. As <a href="https://www.bloombergquint.com/business/crypto-platform-falconx-quintuples-valuation-to-3-75-billion">Bloomberg notes</a>, that&#8217;s a 5x valuation jump in less than half a year. FalconX raised a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-crypto-currency-falconx/cryptocurrency-platform-falconx-secures-50-million-investment-idUSKBN2B32VD">smaller $50 million round in March</a>, notably in part from Coinbase Ventures.</p>
<p>The FalconX news should not surprise. Indian crypto exchange <a href="https://thetechportal.com/2021/08/10/crypto-exchange-platform-coindcx-raises-90mn-led-by-b-capital-turns-unicorn/">CoinDCX just raised $90 million</a>, reaching a $1 billion valuation in the process. This past weekend, Indonesian cryptocurrency exchange <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/indonesias-pintu-exchange-raises-%2435m-in-extended-series-a-led-by-lightspeed-venture-2021">Pintu raised $35 million</a>. And earlier this year, Hong Kong-based crypto exchange <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/ftx-valued-at-18b-in-massive-900m-series-b">FTX raised $900 million</a> at an $18 billion valuation. There <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/argentinian-crypto-exchange-lemon-raises-030000578.html#:~:text=Lemon%2C%20an%20Argentina-based%20crypto%20exchange%2C%20raised%20%2416.3%20million,Peru%20and%20Uruguay%2C%20CEO%20Marcelo%20Cavazzoli%20told%20CoinDesk.">are other examples</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>It&#8217;s a lot of capital in a global race to fund the next Coinbase, I reckon.</p>
<p>And you can&#8217;t fault investors in their hunt. After all, Coinbase has proven to be an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/coinbases-monster-q1-in-context/">incredibly powerful business</a> when crypto interest is high; trading revenues at the U.S. crypto exchange rose to $1.80 billion in the first quarter of 2021, per its <a href="https://www.sec.gov/ix?doc=/Archives/edgar/data/1679788/000167978821000010/coin-20210331.htm">most recent 10-Q filing</a>. Coinbase managed to juice its revenue haul for $771.5 million in net income. In per-share terms, Coinbase earned $3.05 per diluted piece of equity.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995210 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>It was an impressive result. Today, investors are expecting Coinbase to report $1.77 billion to $1.83 billion in revenue, depending on which analyst summary you prefer, and earnings per share of around $2.57. You can somewhat easily puzzle out what sort of net income that EPS figure represents, given the company&#8217;s Q1 results.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d normally argue that Coinbase&#8217;s results today would help set the tone for venture investment in the private sector and valuations for other crypto exchanges. But given the sheer amount of money that has recently flowed into a coterie of startups around the globe hoping to build the Coinbase of their market, the concept seems somewhat moot.</p>
<p>Instead, Coinbase&#8217;s earnings and comments about the market will simply help us understand the playground in which <em>other</em> crypto exchanges are currently playing, admittedly from a decidedly U.S.-centric perspective. Coinbase&#8217;s last quarter saw it generate some 81% of its revenues from its domestic market, as a data point.</p>
<p>But that doesn&#8217;t mean that there&#8217;s no fun to be had. We can do some math regarding trading volumes and valuations. Since we have Coinbase&#8217;s trading volume data, we can parse other exchanges for their own shared data and see which seem expensive &#8212; or cheap. So, let&#8217;s do just that. Into the numbers!</p>
<h2>Trading volume as revenue proxy</h2>
<p>Per its 10-Q filing concerning the quarter ended March 31, 2021, Coinbase reported that it saw trading volume of $334.74 billion, up 1,022% from its Q1 2020 number of $29.83 billion. The company also reported that its transaction &#8212; trading &#8212; revenues for the period were $1.54 billion. So, Coinbase generated around $0.0046 per dollar of traded crypto on its platform in the period.</p>
<p>It goes without saying, but we&#8217;re wandering into the realm of speculative math, which means that everything we&#8217;re doing today is directional rather than absolute. Our goal of seeing how other exchanges are valued based on their trading volumes will be useful, but not definitive. We&#8217;ll have to wait for more S-1s and similar filings to get to full confidence.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/everyone-wants-to-fund-the-next-coinbase/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187914</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OwnBackup reels in $240M Series E on $3.35B valuation, up from $1.4B in January</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/ownbackup-reels-in-240m-series-e-on-3-35b-valuation-up-from-1-4b-in-january/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/ownbackup-reels-in-240m-series-e-on-3-35b-valuation-up-from-1-4b-in-january/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 13:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud backup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OwnBackup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OwnBackup, the late stage startup that helps companies in the Salesforce ecosystem back up their data, announced a $240 million Series E today at a $3.35 billion valuation. The latter is up from $1.4 billion in January when the company announced a $167.5 million Series D. Alkeon Capital and B Capital Group co-led today&#8217;s investment, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://ownbackup.com">OwnBackup</a>, the late stage startup that helps companies in the Salesforce ecosystem back up their data, announced a $240 million Series E today at a $3.35 billion valuation. The latter is up from $1.4 billion in January when the company announced <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210128005466/en/OwnBackup-Raises-167.5-Million-Investment-from-Insight-Partners-Salesforce-Ventures-and-Sapphire-Ventures">a $167.5 million Series D.</a></p>
<p>Alkeon Capital and B Capital Group co-led today&#8217;s investment, which also included BlackRock Private Equity Partners and Tiger Global along with existing investors Insight Partners, Salesforce Ventures, Sapphire Ventures and Vertex Ventures. The company has now raised close to $500 million, over $455 million coming since last July.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a lot of capital, but OwnBackup CEO Sam Gutmann says that as the Salesforce ecosystem has grown, which includes not only Salesforce itself, but companies like Veeva and nCino, business has been booming, growing 100% year-over-year since 2018. That kind of growth gets investor attention and Gutmann reported a lot of inbound investor interest in this round.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, the company announced that it will now support the same type of backup for Microsoft Dynamics 365 customers, thereby greatly expanding its potential market. &#8220;We&#8217;re also announcing that we are expanding into the Microsoft ecosystem specifically around Microsoft Dynamics 365&#8217;s huge ecosystem. I think it&#8217;s the second largest B2B SaaS ecosystem beyond Salesforce. We&#8217;re just getting started there, but super excited about the opportunity,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The company also sees the opportunity to grow the business through acquisition. Over the last year, it bought two small companies, but he says that was more focussed on acquiring specific talent to develop the platform, while future acquisitions could be more focussed on expanding the business itself. He certainl</p>
<p>As the company takes on this kind of investment, Gutmann sees an IPO possibility at some point in the future, but for now he&#8217;s concentrating on growth. &#8220;We&#8217;re not focused on exiting. We&#8217;ve really focused on developing what is already a huge market and growing into an even bigger market, continuing to expand with a business that has great unit economics and continues to grow nicely,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The company has ballooned to 500 employees this year with plans to double that number in the next year. As he does that, Gutmann says that hiring in general is challenging, but he is always looking to find ways to diversify his workforce. &#8220;It&#8217;s really, really hard. Our hiring managers definitely focus on [diversity], but at the end of the day, we want the best employees for the job. I think we&#8217;ve made a lot of strides. We&#8217;re working with one of our largest investors Insight, who is co-sponsoring a program to train, more on the junior side, some underrepresented minorities in technical fields and bring them on as full time employees after that program,&#8221; Gutmann said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Gutmann says his offices have remained open throughout the pandemic, but nobody was required to come in. In fact, he says that his company is one of the few that has actually added office space to make it easier to distance. The company, which is located in New Jersey, has also expanded space outdoors for working outside when the weather permits.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/ownbackup-reels-in-240m-series-e-on-3-35b-valuation-up-from-1-4b-in-january/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ScottsMiracle-Gro announces cannabis investment entity, and a $150m investment in RIV Capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/scottsmiracle-gro-announces-cannabis-investment-entity-and-a-150m-investment-in-riv-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/scottsmiracle-gro-announces-cannabis-investment-entity-and-a-150m-investment-in-riv-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 13:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cannabis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Scotts Miracle-Gro knows how to make plants grow, and now the company is looking to cannabis companies to grow its balance sheet. The company today announced an investment entity specifically for cannabis. Called The Hawthorne Collective, the entity is said to be pursuing minority investments in companies not currently being pursued by ScottsMiracle-Gro’s cannabis subsidiary, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Scotts Miracle-Gro knows how to make plants grow, and now the company is looking to cannabis companies to grow its balance sheet. The company today announced an investment entity specifically for cannabis.</p>
<p>Called The Hawthorne Collective, the entity is said to be pursuing minority investments in companies not currently being pursued by ScottsMiracle-Gro’s cannabis subsidiary, The Hawthorne Gardening Company, which owns and operates dozens of cannabis-focused gardening brands.</p>
<p>The Hawthorne Collective’s first investment comes in a $150 million convertible loan to Toronto-based RIV Capital, a cannabis investment and acquisition firm. <a href="https://scottsmiraclegro.gcs-web.com/news-releases/news-release-details/scottsmiracle-gro-announces-creation-new-investment-entity">According to the company’s press release,</a> the note accrues interest at 2.03%, and upon close, RIV Capital will become The Collective’s preferred vehicle for future investments.</p>
<p>The addition of this investment vehicle gives Scotts Miracle-Gro a new entry into the expanding world of cannabis. Its operating subsidiary, The Hawthorne Gardening Company, already houses some of cannabis’ most potent gardening brands.</p>
<p>“Indeed, the growth of The Hawthorne Gardening Company over the past six years has generated significant shareholder value,” said Jim Hagedorn, Scotts Miracle-Gro Chairman and CEO, in a released statement. “It also has allowed us to develop a rare level of expertise and insight regarding the cannabis space without being involved in the plant-touching aspects of the industry. That is why we are beginning to invest in other areas of the industry through The Collective while continuing to pursue near-in strategic acquisitions to fold into the existing Hawthorne Gardening business.”</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/scottsmiracle-gro-announces-cannabis-investment-entity-and-a-150m-investment-in-riv-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187947</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upscribe, raising $4M, wants to drive subscription-first DTC brand growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/upscribe-raising-4m-wants-to-drive-subscription-first-dtc-brand-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/upscribe-raising-4m-wants-to-drive-subscription-first-dtc-brand-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 13:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dileepan Siva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[direct to consumer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff clavier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscription services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncork Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Upscribe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Merchants use Upscribe’s technology to drive subscriber growth, reduce churn and enable personalized subscription experiences, like skipping shipments and swapping out products.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.upscribe.io">Upscribe</a> founder and CEO Dileepan Siva watched the retail industry make a massive shift to subscription e-commerce for physical products over the past decade, and decided to get in it himself in 2019.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles-based company, developing subscription software for direct-to-consumer e-commerce merchants, is Siva’s fourth startup experience and first time as founder. He closed a $4 million seed round to go after two macro trends he is seeing: buying physical products, like consumer-packaged goods, on a recurring basis, and new industries offering subscriptions, like car and fashion companies.</p>
<p>Merchants use Upscribe’s technology to drive subscriber growth, reduce churn and enable their customers to personalize a subscription experience, like skipping shipments, swapping out products and changing the order frequency. Brands can also feature products for upsell purposes throughout the subscriber lifecycle, from checkout to post-purchase.</p>
<p>Upscribe also offers APIs for merchants to integrate tools like Klaviyo, Segment and Shopify — a new subscription offering for checkouts.</p>
<p>Uncork Capital led the seed round and was joined by Leaders Fund, The House Fund, Roach Capitals’ Fahd Ananta and Shippo CEO Laura Behrens Wu.</p>
<p>“As the market for D2C subscriptions booms, there is a need for subscription-first brands to grow and scale their businesses,” said Jeff Clavier, founder and managing partner of Uncork Capital, in a written statement. “We have spent a long time in the e-commerce space, working with D2C brands and companies who are solving common industry pain points, and Upscribe’s merchant-centric approach raised the bar for subscription services, addressing the friction in customer experiences and enabling merchants to engage subscribers and scale recurring revenue growth.”</p>
<p>Siva bootstrapped the company, but decided to go after venture capital dollars when Upscribe wanted to create a more merchant-centric approach, which required scaling with a bigger team. The “real gems are in the data layer and how to make the experience exceptional,” he added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company is growing 43% quarter over quarter and is close to profitable, with much of its business stemming from referrals, Siva said. It is already working with customers like Athletic Greens, Four Sigmatic and True Botanicals and across multiple verticals, including food and beverage, health and wellness, beauty and cosmetics and home care.</p>
<p>The new funding will be used to “capture the next wave of brands that are going to grow,” he added. Siva cites the growth will come as the DTC subscription market is forecasted to reach $478 billion by 2025, and 75% of those brands are expected to offer subscriptions in the next two years. As such, the majority of the funding will be used to bring on more employees, especially in the product, customer success and go-to-market functions.</p>
<p>Though there is competition in the space, many of those are focused on processing transactions, while Siva said Upscribe’s approach is customer relationships. The cost of acquiring new customers is going up, and subscription services will be the key to converting one-time buyers into loyal customers.</p>
<p>“It is really about customer relationships and the ongoing engagement between merchants and subscribers,” he added. “We are in a different world now. The first wave could play the Facebook game, advertising on social media with super low acquisition and scale. That is no longer the case anymore.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VGFWnAHTns"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/3-issues-to-resolve-before-switching-to-a-subscription-business-model/">3 issues to resolve before switching to a subscription business model</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 issues to resolve before switching to a subscription business model&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/3-issues-to-resolve-before-switching-to-a-subscription-business-model/embed/#?secret=VGFWnAHTns" data-secret="VGFWnAHTns" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/upscribe-raising-4m-wants-to-drive-subscription-first-dtc-brand-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187386</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google to introduce increased protections for minors on its platform, including Search, YouTube and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/google-to-introduce-increased-protections-for-minors-on-its-platform-including-search-youtube-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/google-to-introduce-increased-protections-for-minors-on-its-platform-including-search-youtube-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search results]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube kids]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187712</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Weeks after Instagram rolled out increased protections for minors using its app, Google is now doing the same for its suite of services, including Google search, YouTube, YouTube Kids, Google Assistant, and others. The company this morning announced a series of product and policy changes that will allow younger people to stay more private and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Weeks after Instagram <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-to-default-young-teens-to-private-accounts-restrict-ads-and-unwanted-adult-contact/">rolled out</a> increased protections for minors using its app, Google is now doing the same for its suite of services, <a href="https://blog.google/technology/families/giving-kids-and-teens-safer-experience-online/">including</a> Google search, <a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/new-safety-and-digital-wellbeing-options-younger-people-youtube-and-youtube-kids/">YouTube</a>, YouTube Kids, Google Assistant, and others. The company this morning announced a series of product and policy changes that will allow younger people to stay more private and protected online and others that will limit ad targeting.</p>
<p>The changes in Google&#8217;s case are even more expansive than those Instagram announced, as they span across an array of Google&#8217;s products, instead of being limited to a single app.</p>
<p>Though Congress <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/facebook-google-and-twitter-grilled-by-congress-what-you-need-to-know/">has been pressing</a> Google and other tech companies on the negative impacts their services may have on children, not all changes being made are being required by law, Google says.</p>
<p>&#8220;While some of these updates directly address upcoming regulations, we’ve gone beyond what’s required by law to protect teens on Google and YouTube,&#8221; a Google spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;Many of these changes also extend beyond any single current or upcoming regulation. We’re looking at ways to develop consistent product experiences and user controls for kids and teens globally,&#8221; they added.</p>
<p>In other words, Google is building in some changes based on where it believes the industry is going, rather than where it is right now.</p>
<p>On YouTube, Google says it will &#8220;gradually&#8221; start adjusting the default upload setting to the most private option for users ages 13 to 17, which will limit the visibility of videos only to the the users and those they directly share with, not the wider public. These younger teen users won&#8217;t be prevented from changing the setting back to &#8220;public,&#8221; necessarily, but they will now have to make an explicit and intentional choice when doing so. YouTube will then provide reminders indicating who can see their video, the company notes. YouTube told us the changes will only apply to new uploads &#8212; it will not retroactively set any existing videos to private.</p>
<p>YouTube will also turn on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/11/youtube-rolls-out-new-tools-to-help-you-stop-watching/">its &#8220;take a break&#8221; and bedtime reminders</a> by default for all users ages 13 to 17 and will turn off autoplay. Again, these changes are related to the default settings  &#8212; users can disable the digital well-being features if they choose.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4ec10qfiHX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/11/youtube-rolls-out-new-tools-to-help-you-stop-watching/">YouTube rolls out new tools to help you stop watching</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;YouTube rolls out new tools to help you stop watching&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/11/youtube-rolls-out-new-tools-to-help-you-stop-watching/embed/#?secret=4ec10qfiHX" data-secret="4ec10qfiHX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>On YouTube&#8217;s platform for younger children, YouTube Kids, the company will also add an autoplay option, which is turned off autoplay by default so parents will have to decide whether or not they want to use autoplay with their children. The change puts the choice directly in parents&#8217; hands, after <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/22412232/youtube-kids-autoplay">complaints from child safety advocates and some members of Congress</a> suggested such an algorithmic feature was problematic. Later, parents will also be able to &#8220;lock&#8221; their default selection.</p>
<p>YouTube will also remove &#8220;overly commercial content&#8221; from YouTube Kid, in a move that also follows <a href="https://www.democraticmedia.org/article/ftc-complaints-filed-campaign-commercial-free-childhood-and-center-digital-democracy-lead">increased pressure</a> from consumer advocacy groups and childhood experts, who have long since argued that YouTube encourages kids to spend money (or rather, beg their parents to do so.)</p>
<p>How YouTube will draw the line between acceptable and &#8220;overly commercial&#8221; content <a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/10938174">is less clear</a>, but the company says it will, for example, remove videos that focus on product packaging &#8212; like the popular &#8220;unboxing&#8221; videos. This could impact some of YouTube&#8217;s <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/3/22/18275767/toy-unboxing-videos-youtube-advertising-ethics">larger creators</a> of videos for kids, like <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/12/24/949926198/9-year-old-boy-is-named-highest-earning-youtube-star-of-2020">multi-millionaire</a> Ryan&#8217;s Toy Review. In addition to product packaging, it also says it will look to remove any content that &#8220;incites viewers to buy a product&#8221; and &#8220;content focused on the excessive accumulation or consumption of products.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1877280" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1877280" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-1877280" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/youtube-kids-laptop-red1.png?w=680" alt="youtube kids laptop red1" width="680" height="361" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/youtube-kids-laptop-red1.png 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/youtube-kids-laptop-red1.png?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/youtube-kids-laptop-red1.png?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/youtube-kids-laptop-red1.png?resize=768,408 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/youtube-kids-laptop-red1.png?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/youtube-kids-laptop-red1.png?resize=1536,816 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/youtube-kids-laptop-red1.png?resize=2048,1088 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/youtube-kids-laptop-red1.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1877280" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> YouTube</p></div></p>
<p>Elsewhere on Google, other changes impacting minors will also begin rolling out.</p>
<p>In the weeks ahead, Google will introduce a new policy that will allow anyone under the age of 18, or a parent or guardian, to request the removal of their images from Google Image search results. This expands upon the existing &#8220;right to be forgotten&#8221; <a href="https://support.google.com/transparencyreport/answer/7347822?hl=en">privacy policies already live in the E.U.</a>, but will introduce new products and controls for both kids and teenagers globally.</p>
<p>The company will make a number of adjustments to user accounts for people under the age of 18, as well.</p>
<p>In addition to the changes to YouTube, Google will restrict access to adult content by enabling its <a href="https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/510?co=GENIE.Platform%3DAndroid&amp;hl=en">SafeSearch</a> filtering technology by default to all users under 13 managed by its <a href="https://families.google.com/familylink/">Google Family Link</a> service. It will also enable SafeSearch for all users under 18 and make this the new default for teens who set up new accounts. Google Assistant will enable SafeSearch protections by default on shared devices, like smart screens and their web browsers. In school settings where Google Workspace for Education is used, SafeSearch will be the default and switching to Guest Mode and Incognito Mode web browsing will be turned off by default, too,<a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/education/safer-learning-with-google-for-education/"> as was recently announced</a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, location history is already off by default on all Google accounts, but children with supervised accounts now won&#8217;t be able to enable it. This change will be extended to all users under 18 globally, meaning location can&#8217;t be enabled at all under the children are legal adults.</p>
<p>On Google Play, the company will launch a new <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/07/new-google-play-safety-section.html">section</a> that will inform parents about which apps follow its <a href="https://play.google.com/console/about/families/">Families policies</a>, and app developers will have to disclose how their apps collect and use data. These features &#8212; which were partially inspired by Apple&#8217;s App Store Privacy Labels &#8212; <a href="https://support.google.com/transparencyreport/answer/7347822?hl=en">had already been detailed for Android developers </a>before today.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lMdKQfcZ5b"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/google-unveils-its-proposed-safety-section-for-apps-on-google-play/">Google unveils its proposed &#8216;safety section&#8217; for apps on Google Play</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google unveils its proposed &#8216;safety section&#8217; for apps on Google Play&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/google-unveils-its-proposed-safety-section-for-apps-on-google-play/embed/#?secret=lMdKQfcZ5b" data-secret="lMdKQfcZ5b" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Google&#8217;s parental control tools are also being expanded. Parents and guardians who are Family Link users will gain new abilities to filter and block news, podcasts, and access to webpages on Assistant-enabled smart devices.</p>
<p>For advertisers, there are significant changes in store, too.</p>
<p>Google says it will expand safeguards to prevent age-sensitive ad categories from being shown to teens and it will block ad targeting based on factors like age, gender, or interests for users under 18. While somewhat similar <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-to-default-young-teens-to-private-accounts-restrict-ads-and-unwanted-adult-contact/">to the advertising changes Instagram introduced</a>, as ads will no longer leverage &#8220;interests&#8221; data for targeting young teens and kids, Instagram was still allowing targeting by age and gender. Google will not. The advertising changes will roll out globally in the &#8220;coming months,&#8221; the company says.</p>
<p>All the changes across Google and YouTube will roll out globally in the coming weeks and months.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/google-to-introduce-increased-protections-for-minors-on-its-platform-including-search-youtube-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187712</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elektra Health funnels new $3.75M round into helping women navigate menopause</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/elektra-health-targets-new-3-75m-round-to-help-women-navigate-menopause/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/elektra-health-targets-new-3-75m-round-to-help-women-navigate-menopause/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alessandra Henderson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexis Ohanian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elektra Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[femtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flare Capital Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jannine Versi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katelin Holloway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seven seven six]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telemedicine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187356</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every woman will go through menopause some time during her life, but like many other femtech topics, this is still not talked about as much as it should.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Every woman will go through menopause some time during her life, but like many other femtech topics, this one is still not talked about as much as it should be.</p>
<p>Enter <a href="https://www.elektrahealth.com/">Elektra Health</a>, a women’s health technology company startup that raised $3.75 million in seed funding to continue developing its platform that provides evidence-based care, education and a community for women going through the various stages of menopause.</p>
<p>Co-founders Alessandra Henderson and Jannine Versi told TechCrunch that more than 50 million women in the United States are currently in some stage of menopause, while the industry itself represents a <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/menopause-startups-vc-funding/">$600 billion global market opportunity</a>.</p>
<p>CEO Henderson, whose background includes business creation platform Human Ventures, called menopause a “cultural zeitgeist” that is coming into its own in terms of the conversation and having investors believe in Elektra’s mission. The company is also personal for Henderson — she went on a hormonal health journey that began four years ago after experiencing symptoms that went unexplained by specialists.</p>
<p>Several years later, she wanted to start a company in femtech. There was so much already in the reproductive space, yet no one was talking about what comes next or the phases for moving through menopause, Henderson said. It was when she was introduced to her co-founder Versi, whose background is in digital health, that the idea for Elektra came together.</p>
<p>Menopause is a hormonal health transition that typically starts in women when they reach their 40s or 50s. There have been up to 34 identified symptoms of menopause, and research has found that 80% of women say <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3576769/">menopause symptoms have negatively impacted their quality of life</a> in some way. At the same time, <a href="https://www.aarp.org/health/conditions-treatments/info-2018/menopause-symptoms-doctors-relief-treatment.html#:~:text=Most%20medical%20schools%20and%20residency,Mostly%2C%20the%20courses%20are%20elective.">less than 20% of obstetrics/gynecology residency programs educate doctors about menopause</a>.</p>
<p>Elektra’s platform is picking up that slack by offering clinical care via telemedicine and its proprietary <a href="https://www.elektrahealth.com/services/">“Meno-morphosis” program</a> that features evidence-based guidance on symptoms, a community of support and access to a 1:1 dedicated menopause expert. The program will open completely to the public in 2022.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We are all about caring for women by providing content, education, care, coaching and counseling, especially working in the arc of their journey,” Versi said. “This is such an intimate topic, but we have referral rates of 40% where women are talking about it themselves and then bring a friend along. Sustaining that is important to us. We are seeing clusters of friends come along and really bond with the community.”</p>
<p>The New York-based company’s seed funding was co-led by Alexis Ohanian’s Seven Seven Six and Flare Capital Partners, with participation from City Light Capital, January Ventures, Human Ventures, The Fund, Community Fund and a group of angel investors, including Hannah and Guy Raz, Claire Diaz-Ortiz and Jenny Fielding.</p>
<p>This new round of funding will be used to grow its team and to expand its integrative, evidence-based solution to millions of women in the U.S., and beyond.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iJaImDlIbF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/hormonal-health-is-a-massive-opportunity-where-are-the-unicorns/">Hormonal health is a massive opportunity: Where are the unicorns?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hormonal health is a massive opportunity: Where are the unicorns?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/hormonal-health-is-a-massive-opportunity-where-are-the-unicorns/embed/#?secret=iJaImDlIbF" data-secret="iJaImDlIbF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Since founding the company in 2019, more than 1,800 women have participated in Elektra’s private beta educational programming.</p>
<p>“Last year was about learning and growing the things that women want,” Henderson said. “We are making an impact in the way women deserve.”</p>
<p>Much of women’s health technology is aimed at fertility, but Elektra Health is not alone in tackling this issue: new startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/2182193/">Peppy recently reported funding</a> to address menopause in employee health; meanwhile, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/personalized-menopause-platform-vira-health-raises-1-5m-from-localglobe-mmc-ventures/">Vira Health raised £1.5 million</a> in seed funding for a U.K. platform.</p>
<p>Katelin Holloway, founding partner at Seven Seven Six, said in her previous roles leading compensation and benefits for companies, she became increasingly aware that the need for menopause care was just as desired by employees as fertility benefits.</p>
<p>When her employees began requesting desk fans, she started investigating the source of the requests and found it was from the company’s non-Gen Z employees, and all women.</p>
<p>“I realized I had a decent cohort of women experiencing menopause,” Holloway said. “The fan on the desk was kind of a ‘bat signal’ to other employees, unlocking conversations between them where they had previously been experiencing these symptoms in silos.”</p>
<p>Once she became an investor, she put out the call again looking for a company providing that kind of care and was introduced to Elektra. Holloway said there is a whole new group of women entering their 40s who want to talk about menopause and have the technology available, while also wanting privacy for care and a community to share in the experience.</p>
<p>She called Elektra’s co-founders “incredible women who care deeply about this space and have amazing credentials and background to bring to this company.” She also said she was sold on their approach of care, community and content, which aligns with what was working in the pregnancy and fertility spaces.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PRuvpVYjma"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/2182193/">Peppy, a B2B health platform for menopause, fertility, raises $10M Series A led by Felix Capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Peppy, a B2B health platform for menopause, fertility, raises $10M Series A led by Felix Capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/2182193/embed/#?secret=PRuvpVYjma" data-secret="PRuvpVYjma" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/elektra-health-targets-new-3-75m-round-to-help-women-navigate-menopause/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187356</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WoodSpoon’s food delivery service cooks up support for home chefs with $14M round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/woodspoons-food-delivery-service-cooks-up-support-for-home-chefs-with-14m-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/woodspoons-food-delivery-service-cooks-up-support-for-home-chefs-with-14m-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home Chef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurant brands international]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WoodSpoon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187394</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The co-founders reached out to local home chefs and gathered them together in a marketplace where they could share their culture and passion of food with others.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Home-cooked food delivery service <a href="https://www.eatwoodspoon.com">WoodSpoon</a> is planning an expansion after raising $14 million in Series A funding.</p>
<p>Restaurant Brands International led the round along with World Trade Ventures and a group of individual investors, including Victor Lazarte.</p>
<p>New York-based WoodSpoon was started in 2019 by Oren Saar and Merav Kalish Rozengarten, two Israelis in America that longed for the food they grew up with. They began reaching out to local home chefs in the area and gathered them together in a marketplace where they could share their culture and passion of food with others.</p>
<p>Two years later, the company boasts over 16,000 active customers in Manhattan, Brooklyn and Queens and 50% month over month growth. Customers can order dishes that run the gambit of world cuisine through WoodSpoon’s website or app and receive on-demand delivery to their doorstep or schedule service. Saar told TechCrunch that 35% of WoodSpoon’s customers have ordered four times in 17 days after their first order.</p>
<p>The new funding gives the company a total of $16 million — it raised $2 million at the end of 2020. Saar said the Series A enables the company to accelerate growth through R&amp;D and marketing and to double its team so it can expand into new markets, like major cities across the United States, over the next 12 months.</p>
<p>At the same time as it brings customers culturally diverse food, WoodSpoon helps generate income for its home chefs — a mix of 150 active professional chefs, immigrants and cooks making dishes for the company at least three times a month. WoodSpoon interviews each chef, inspects their kitchens and provides training to keep consistent quality.</p>
<p>“When you scale, you can lose touch with your customers and lose the personal connection with the home chefs,” Saar said. “We feel every home chef is part of our family and want to help them build their brand, so it is important that this food is high quality.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>WoodSpoon has about 30 employees and plans to hire more engineers to continue developing its technology. Saar said a new product will be launching at the end of August, while WoodSpoon’s app will get an overhaul to have a new look and feel.</p>
<p>The Series A also enables WoodSpoon to onboard its waitlist of hundreds of home chefs that want to join the marketplace.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/global-online-food-delivery-services-market-report-2021-market-is-expected-to-reach-192-16-billion-in-2025--from-126-91-billion-in-2021---long-term-forecast-to-2030--301285677.html">global online food delivery services market</a> is forecasted to be $126.91 billion in 2021, and then reach $192.16 billion in 2025, according to consultancy firm Research and Markets.</p>
<p>Chris Brigleb, head of corporate development at Restaurant Brands International, said technology is a big focus for his company, which spent a lot of time looking around for potential investments beyond the traditional quick-serve restaurant space.</p>
<p>He began meeting with tech-enabled businesses and came across WoodSpoon four months ago. The more Brigleb learned about the company, the more he liked it, and even encouraged Saar to speed up WoodSpoon’s growth and fundraising plans, he said.</p>
<p>Though WoodSpoon’s concept is not new, he felt its approach was the complete package of user experience on the customer side, the ease of searching the marketplace by chef or cuisine and support for the chef in terms of providing packaging and logistics management.</p>
<p>“The delivery was a key for us and a differentiator,” Brigleb said. “They take all of the hard parts about delivering for home chefs off of their plate so they can focus on the actual cooking that is special to them.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aXWmzd8dEw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/07/vcs-have-growing-appetite-for-agrifood/">VCs have growing appetite for &#8216;AgriFood&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;VCs have growing appetite for &#8216;AgriFood&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/07/vcs-have-growing-appetite-for-agrifood/embed/#?secret=aXWmzd8dEw" data-secret="aXWmzd8dEw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/woodspoons-food-delivery-service-cooks-up-support-for-home-chefs-with-14m-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187394</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Niantic acquires 3D scanning app Scaniverse</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/niantic-acquires-3d-scanning-app-scaniverse/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/niantic-acquires-3d-scanning-app-scaniverse/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[niantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pokémon Go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scaniverse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Niantic continues to push forward in its quest to build a 3D map of the world. This morning the company announced that it has acquired Scaniverse, an iPhone/iPad app for scanning objects and environments in high-resolution 3D. A rep for Niantic tells me that Scaniverse will remain on the App Store, with plans to continue [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Niantic continues to push forward in its quest to build a 3D map of the world.</p>
<p>This morning the company announced that it has acquired <a href="https://scaniverse.com/">Scaniverse</a>, an iPhone/iPad app for scanning objects and environments in high-resolution 3D.</p>
<p>A rep for Niantic tells me that Scaniverse will remain on the App Store, with plans to continue supporting it as a standalone app. Features previously limited to a $17-per-year &#8220;Pro&#8221; subscription, including higher-resolution processing and support for exporting models to other 3D software, will now be free.</p>
<p>As I <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/the-niantic-ec-1/">first wrote about years ago</a>, one of Niantic&#8217;s goals is to build a detailed and endlessly-evolving 3D map of the world — a step they see as fundamental to enabling true, rich augmented reality experiences if/when the world ever embraces something like AR glasses. It&#8217;s a rather massive (and never ending) task, but one made a bit more feasible by way of its ever-roaming player base across games like Pokémon GO, Harry Potter Wizards Unite, and Ingress.</p>
<p>As part of the deal, Scaniverse creator Keith Ito will be joining Niantic&#8217;s AR team. The company declined to outline any other terms of the acquisition. This is Niantic&#8217;s latest acquisition in the 3D mapping space, having <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/31/niantic-acquires-ar-startup-6d-ai-as-the-game-creator-squares-up-against-apple-facebook/">acquired 6D.ai for an undisclosed sum in early 2020</a>.</p>
<p>For context, here&#8217;s a demo of the Scaniverse app doing its thing:</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qarYpjeQOcU?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/niantic-acquires-3d-scanning-app-scaniverse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187679</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cannabis giant Leafly is going public through a SPAC merger</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/cannabis-giant-leafly-is-going-public-through-a-spac-merger/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/cannabis-giant-leafly-is-going-public-through-a-spac-merger/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 12:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cannabis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leafly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187923</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leafly is turning to a SPAC with Merdia Merger Corp. I to go public. The deal, valued at about $532 million and expected to generate proceeds of up to $161.5 million, includes Leafly’s recent capital raise of $31.5 million from investors, including Merida Capital Holdings.te The company is expected to list on Nasdaq under the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Leafly is turning to a SPAC with Merdia Merger Corp. I to go public. The deal, valued at about $532 million and expected to generate proceeds of up to $161.5 million, includes Leafly’s recent capital raise of $31.5 million from investors, including Merida Capital Holdings.te</p>
<p>The company is expected to list on Nasdaq under the ticker symbol of LFLY as Merida will adopt the Leafly name. Existing Leafly shareholders will own about 72% of the merged company. The deal is expected to close in the fourth quarter of 2021.</p>
<p>Leafly was founded in 2010 and has grown into a leading marketplace and resource. The company offers a deep library of content for consumers, including detailed information about strains, retailers, and current events. For retailers, Leafly offers a subscription-based platform that 7,800 brands and 4,600 retail subscribers use. <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/leafly-to-go-public-via-combination-with-spac-merida-merger-corp-i-271628512551">According to a report</a>, the company is expected to see revenue hit $43 million in 2021 and $65 million in 2022.</p>
<p>Despite the successes, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/26/leafly-lays-off-91-employees-with-funding-on-pause/">Leafly experienced a turbulent 2020</a> with layoffs and leadership changes. Yoko Miyashita took over as the company’s CEO in August 2020 and has been focused on Leafly, leaning heavily into building a better online shopping experience. In February 2021, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/leafly-and-jane-partner-to-build-a-better-online-cannabis-shopping-experience/">the company partnered with Jane</a> to improve Leafly’s e-commerce tools.</p>
<p>By going public through a SPAC, Leafly is signaling it&#8217;s entering a growth phase just in time for the US Government to loosen cannabis restrictions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="u2VqKbDgNn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/leafly-and-jane-partner-to-build-a-better-online-cannabis-shopping-experience/">Leafly and Jane partner to build a better online cannabis shopping experience</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Leafly and Jane partner to build a better online cannabis shopping experience&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/leafly-and-jane-partner-to-build-a-better-online-cannabis-shopping-experience/embed/#?secret=u2VqKbDgNn" data-secret="u2VqKbDgNn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RV6Sf3Xtwi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/cannabis-and-digital-health-start-up-sanity-group-closes-44-2m-series-a-led-by-redalpine/">Cannabis and digital health startup Sanity Group closes $44.2M Series A led by Redalpine</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cannabis and digital health startup Sanity Group closes $44.2M Series A led by Redalpine&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/cannabis-and-digital-health-start-up-sanity-group-closes-44-2m-series-a-led-by-redalpine/embed/#?secret=RV6Sf3Xtwi" data-secret="RV6Sf3Xtwi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="P0eIXEO4PU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/these-5-vcs-have-high-hopes-for-cannabis-in-2021/">These 5 VCs have high hopes for cannabis in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;These 5 VCs have high hopes for cannabis in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/these-5-vcs-have-high-hopes-for-cannabis-in-2021/embed/#?secret=P0eIXEO4PU" data-secret="P0eIXEO4PU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/cannabis-giant-leafly-is-going-public-through-a-spac-merger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187923</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wix launches a no-code app builder for $200 per month</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/wix-launches-a-no-code-app-builder-for-200-per-month/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/wix-launches-a-no-code-app-builder-for-200-per-month/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 12:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app builder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[svp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wix.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning, Wix announced a new product for business owners called Branded App by Wix, which allows users to develop native apps without writing code. The publicly-traded company provides tools for people and businesses to manage their online presence, but it&#8217;s most well-known for its drag-and-drop website builder. Now, the platform is expanding its user-friendly [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning, <a href="https://www.wix.com/">Wix</a> announced a new product for business owners called <a href="https://www.wix.com/app-builder">Branded App by Wix</a>, which allows users to develop native apps without writing code. The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/11/05/twitter-friends-ahead-of-its-public-debut-wednesday-wix-prices-ipo-at-16-50-per-share-with-valuation-near-800m/">publicly-traded</a> company provides tools for people and businesses to manage their online presence, but it&#8217;s most well-known for its drag-and-drop website builder. Now, the platform is expanding its user-friendly approach by making it possible for anyone to build an app without learning how to code.</p>
<p class="p1">“Users came to us with the need to create a native app that is branded with their name and logo,&#8221; said Ronny Elkayam, SVP of Mobile, App Market &amp; Strategic Products at Wix. &#8220;Many of our users are businesses, and businesses have a desire to portray a situation that they are bigger than they are. They want to follow the big businesses that have native apps.&#8221;</p>
<p>At $200 per month, Branded App by Wix is no small investment; users will also have to pay a yearly $99 fee to be on the App Store, and a one-time $25 fee for Google Play. But according to Wix, native mobile apps can help businesses ultimately drive more sales. For users that already have a Wix website, the app builder can automatically integrate features from their website, making the process more simple.</p>
<p>“If you&#8217;re a restaurant, and you have your menu configured on your website for online ordering, the same menu is going to show up on the app. You don’t need to configure it. Any purchases or any orders from that menu are going to show up in your dashboard,”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> Elkayam said.</span></p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oYYPmaFmCB4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Out of Wix&#8217;s 200 million users, 5 million are paid subscribers. For businesses, Wix&#8217;s most popular plan is $27 per month for a website, which includes access to e-commerce features. Even users with a free website (which has limited capabilities and is emblazoned with the Wix logo) can create an app &#8212; Branded App by Wix is a new product, not an additional feature for existing subscribers. Business owners can customize their app&#8217;s icon, layout, and content, including product pages, booking services, forums and groups, chat functions, blogs, push notifications, and more. Wix will automatically update users&#8217; apps to remain compatible with the latest versions of iOS and Android.</p>
<p>A competitor in the no-code app building space, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/no-code-bubble-series-a/">Bubble</a> charges between $29 and $529 per month, with a free plan for users to learn how to use the product and develop their app. But Bubble&#8217;s offerings are web-based, while Wix&#8217;s apps are native, which means they can be downloaded from the App Store and Google Play.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In 2020, Wix had 31 million new users &#8212; Elkayam said that Wix&#8217;s growth increased under the conditions of the coronavirus pandemic. The company will announce its Q2 earnings tomorrow, but in Q1, the company had $304 million in revenue, up 41% year-over-year.</p>
<p>After beta testing with hundreds of users, Branded App by Wix is now available to all users. Those who sign up during the temporary &#8220;presale&#8221; will get the product for 50% off for life.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5r80nyErwS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/26/the-no-code-generation-is-arriving/">The No-Code Generation is arriving</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The No-Code Generation is arriving&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/26/the-no-code-generation-is-arriving/embed/#?secret=5r80nyErwS" data-secret="5r80nyErwS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/wix-launches-a-no-code-app-builder-for-200-per-month/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187456</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After raising $10M, Breeze breathes fresh air into a stagnant disability insurance market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/after-raising-10m-breeze-breathes-fresh-air-into-a-stagnant-disability-insurance-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/after-raising-10m-breeze-breathes-fresh-air-into-a-stagnant-disability-insurance-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breeze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colin Nability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disability insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Link Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lisa Dolan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northwestern Mutual Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software development]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Working in the world of disability insurance, Colin Nability felt not everyone could access this type of insurance due to its nature being difficult to understand and underwrite.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Working in the world of disability insurance for a decade, Colin Nabity felt not everyone could access this type of insurance due to its nature of it being difficult to understand and underwrite.</p>
<p>Disability and critical illness insurance is typically income protection should someone be too sick or hurt to work. An average of <a href="https://disabilitycanhappen.org/disability-statistic/#:~:text=5.6%20percent%20of%20working%20Americans,on%20average%20every%20year5.">5.6% of working Americans each year will experience a short-term disability</a> during a period of six months or less due to illness, injury or pregnancy. At the same time, <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2018/p0816-disability.html">1 in 4 Americans currently live with a disability</a> that impacts their major life activities.</p>
<p>Similar to other insurance products, disability insurance was sold the same way for more than 20 years: using outdated technology, data science and underwriting that didn’t provide consumers an appropriate policy based on their occupation and health. In addition, there was not a digital platform to sell this type of insurance directly to consumers, Nabity said.</p>
<p>Enter Omaha, Nebraska-based <a href="https://www.meetbreeze.com/">Breeze</a>, the company Nabity started in 2019 with Cody Leach to enable individuals to go online and complete in 10 minutes the application process to receive a personalized quote for either disability insurance or critical illness insurance.</p>
<p>There are large incumbents in the space — for example Aflac, but Nabity said Breeze’s platform offers a digital approach to disability and critical illness applications, quotes and policy-making that offers consumers protection during events like cancer, heart attacks, strokes and other medical conditions that can lead to a loss of income if someone is unable to work.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.ibisworld.com/industry-statistics/market-size/disability-insurance-united-states/">U.S. market for disability insurance</a> was valued at $19.1 billion as of this year and was declining slightly since 2016, IBIS World reported. Breeze is reimagining these products to make them more affordable &#8212; a policy for several thousand dollars costs, on average, around $20 a month &#8212; and to provide consumer education so that purchasing this type of insurance is less intimidating, he added.</p>
<p>“We want a way for people to understand this type of insurance, make it more affordable and be bought completely online,” Nabity told TechCrunch. “These illnesses and injuries wreck families because they can be so financially devastating.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Breeze raised $10 million in Series A funding in a round led by Link Ventures that Nabity boasts is the “largest first round of institutional capital ever invested in a Nebraska-based software startup.” Northwestern Mutual Future Ventures, Silicon Valley Bank, M25, Fiat Ventures and Invest Nebraska also participated in the financing.</p>
<p>Lisa Dolan, managing director at Link Ventures, said she found the company while examining web traffic data, where Breeze was listed among industry incumbents among consumers searching for disability.</p>
<p>Dolan admits that even she was not familiar, at the time, with disability insurance and has since learned that the market is larger than originally thought. She believes that by using technology to route the appropriate customer to the approach insurance, Breeze is able to reach customers that incumbent insurance carriers can’t get to.</p>
<p>Nabity did not disclose any growth metrics, but said he intends to use the new funding — the company’s first round of institutional capital — to grow its core products and add new products, carriers and agents to the platform. He will also increase Breeze’s headcount in the areas of software development, customer service and marketing.</p>
<p>“We are in the process of opening up our platform to agents that have not sold these products before, and we will need product and support teams to handle that increased volume,” he added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1Qx9F3GW6P"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/02/why-vcs-are-dumping-money-into-insurance-marketplaces/">Why VCs are dumping money into insurance marketplaces</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why VCs are dumping money into insurance marketplaces&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/02/why-vcs-are-dumping-money-into-insurance-marketplaces/embed/#?secret=1Qx9F3GW6P" data-secret="1Qx9F3GW6P" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/after-raising-10m-breeze-breathes-fresh-air-into-a-stagnant-disability-insurance-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187363</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FireHydrant announces $23M Series B to grow disaster management platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/firehydrant-announces-23m-series-b-to-grow-disaster-management-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/firehydrant-announces-23m-series-b-to-grow-disaster-management-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disaster recovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FireHydrant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[site reliability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SREs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No matter how carefully you set up your systems, sooner or later something fundamental breaks. How you react during those times and how quickly you respond to the crisis is what people remember after it&#8217;s over. FireHydrant, a startup that helps companies prepare for and manage such crises, announced a $23 million Series B investment [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">No matter how carefully you set up your systems, sooner or later something fundamental breaks. How you react during those times and how quickly you respond to the crisis is what people remember after it&#8217;s over. <a href="https://www.firehydrant.io/">FireHydrant</a>, a startup that helps companies prepare for and manage such crises, announced a $23 million Series B investment today.</p>
<p>Harmony Partners led the round with participation from Salesforce Ventures and existing investors Menlo Ventures and Work-Bench. Today&#8217;s money brings the total raised to $32.5 million, according to the company.</p>
<p>The company focuses on helping customers navigate a crisis and a big part of that is run books, which act as playbooks for handling various crisis situations as they arise. As part of that, the company has added a directory of service owners to make it easier to find the people in charge of a given service should it be the cause or impacted by an ongoing event.</p>
<p>Company co-founder and CEO Robert Ross says that the company has grown customers 5x since <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/firehyrdant-lands-8m-series-a-for-disaster-management-tool/">the startup&#8217;s A round last year</a>, and they are seeing customers get creative with how they use run books.</p>
<p>&#8220;The run books functionality is really the bread and butter of functionality of FireHydrant, and we&#8217;re seeing customers leverage them in ways we didn&#8217;t really imagine, and truly kind of outperforming a lot of the expectations of that functionality. So they&#8217;re getting really creative in using them to onboard people into incidents and using them for better incident communication. So that&#8217;s been a really nice thing to see,&#8221; Ross told TechCrunch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5sbX99Z7MP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/firehyrdant-lands-8m-series-a-for-disaster-management-tool/">FireHydrant  lands $8M Series A for disaster management tool</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FireHydrant  lands $8M Series A for disaster management tool&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/firehyrdant-lands-8m-series-a-for-disaster-management-tool/embed/#?secret=5sbX99Z7MP" data-secret="5sbX99Z7MP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Ross says that they are trying to position incident management as a business problem, rather than purely an engineering problem. That&#8217;s because if your site goes down for a sustained period of time, people on Twitter aren&#8217;t going to be talking about the company&#8217;s engineering failure, they are going to say the business is failing because it&#8217;s not up and running at full capacity or in some cases at all.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Obviously I believe that site reliability in general is going to be something that has an impact on the business no matter what. If it&#8217;s something as simple as your app not working or just being glitchy, people are going to get upset,&#8221; Ross said.</p>
<p>The company has grown substantially since we spoke in May 2020 going from 10 employees to 54. As he continues to add new employees to the mix, Ross says that he trying to stay on top of all three aspects of diversity, equity and inclusion, but it all starts with the sources you use to hire new people. &#8220;Our philosophy is that diversity, equity and inclusion in the business starts at the top of your funnel, and we made sure to put a lot of effort into that,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>As the pandemic ebbs and flows, Ross says that he has no intention of requiring folks to come into the office, and this is especially true since he has been hiring regardless of geography since the pandemic began. He has a small office in New York City, but nobody is required to go in. He is considering adding office hubs when the pandemic quiets down in Austin, Denver and San Diego.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="21zMCE434a"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/31/how-you-react-when-your-systems-fail-may-define-your-business/">How you react when your systems fail may define your business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How you react when your systems fail may define your business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/31/how-you-react-when-your-systems-fail-may-define-your-business/embed/#?secret=21zMCE434a" data-secret="21zMCE434a" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/firehydrant-announces-23m-series-b-to-grow-disaster-management-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187607</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech-driven Butternut Box eats its own dog food — raises $55.4M to scale-up</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/tech-driven-butternut-box-eats-its-own-dog-food-raises-55-4m-to-scale-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/tech-driven-butternut-box-eats-its-own-dog-food-raises-55-4m-to-scale-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 11:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Butternut Box, a London-based fresh dog food business with a tech-driven platform that delivers HelloFresh-style, catered dogfood, has raised $55.4 million (€47.2 million) in a funding round led by L Catterton, the consumer-focused private equity firm, and included participation from White Star Capital, Five Seasons Ventures and Passion Capital. We covered their early funding round [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://butternutbox.com/">Butternut Box</a>, a London-based fresh dog food business with a tech-driven platform that delivers HelloFresh-style, catered dogfood, has raised $55.4 million (€47.2 million) in a funding round led by L Catterton, the consumer-focused private equity firm, and included participation from White Star Capital, Five Seasons Ventures and Passion Capital. We covered their early funding round <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/17/butternut-box-raises-1m-for-its-algorithm-driven-natural-dog-food-startup/">back in 2017</a>.</p>
<p>Founded in 2016, Butternut Box bills itself as a “human-grade, fresh dog food company” with a “personalized dietary offering” driven by its own tech platform.</p>
<p>Jean-Philippe Barade, Partner, L Catterton Europe, and head of the firm’s London office, commented; “We have long been impressed by how Butternut Box has established itself as the trusted brand of choice in the UK among a loyal base of pet owners… Butternut Box continues to leverage its innovative digital platform to raise the bar in the growing pet food market.”</p>
<p>Led by Goldman Sachs alumni Kevin Glynn and David Nolan, the company says its proprietary algorithm identifies how many calories each individual dog needs based on age, weight, breed, activity levels, and body condition and then pre-portions this amount into daily servings.</p>
<p>It also makes its own “natural” dog food, because studies show that dogs fed a natural diet have a longer life capacity than those fed on industrial canned products &#8211; up to 3 years, a long time in dog years. Since British dog owners spend over £200 million in vet’s fees, overfeeding, and unhealthy food is a key issue for owners.</p>
<p>However, Butternut Box is not alone, since they competing with Lily’s Kitchen, Tails.com and Natural Instinct for this lucrative new market.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/tech-driven-butternut-box-eats-its-own-dog-food-raises-55-4m-to-scale-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187910</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
