<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 13:37:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Nubank files to go public</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/nubank-files-to-go-public/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/nubank-files-to-go-public/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 13:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LATAM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nubank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Brazilian neobank Nu, better known as Nubank, announced that it has filed to go public. Today its S-1 filing remains private, but the announcement of its existence implies that Nu is on track to go public soon, perhaps inside of 2021. The company filed with both the American Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This morning Brazilian neobank Nu, better known as Nubank, </span><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20211027005661/en/Nu-Announces-Confidential-Submission-of-Draft-Registration-Statement-for-Proposed-Initial-Public-Offering"><span style="font-weight: 400;">announced</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that it has filed to go public. Today its S-1 filing remains private, but the announcement of its existence implies that Nu is on track to go public soon, perhaps inside of 2021.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company filed with both the American Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Comissão de Valores Mobiliários (CVM) in Brazi, it saidl. Per the company’s bulletin, Nu intends to list in the United States with intent to “negotiate a program of Brazilian Depositary Receipts” in its home country.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In June, Nu </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/fintech-all-star-nubank-raises-a-750m-mega-round/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised a $750 million round</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> led by Berkshire Hathaway at a $30 billion valuation, making it one of the most valuable unicorns in the world. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224850" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At that time, Nu had 40 million users across Brazil, Mexico and Colombia. Its sheer number of users makes Nubank the largest digital bank in the world in terms of customers. Notably, it had 25 million users in June of 2020 and 6 million in 2018 &#8212; so its pace of growth and acquiring customers is quite remarkable.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Colombian businessman and former Sequoia VC David Velez founded Nu in 2013 with the mission of fixing the dated Brazilian banking system. The company set out to help serve the underbanked and unbanked in the country with a range of products and services. It is estimated that tens of millions remain unbanked in Brazil, so the opportunity for the neobank remains quite large, especially considering the increased use of smartphones and the move to digital overall.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TechCrunch dug deep into Nu in </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">this series</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> earlier this year.</span></p>
<p><b>The Neobanking boom’s leading candidates</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">News of Nu’s private IPO filing come on the heels of news that American neobank Chime is also targeting a public offering. Per </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jeffkauflin/2021/10/23/chime-in-talks-to-go-public-at-35-to-45-billion-valuation/?sh=5598213732ff"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forbes reporting</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Chime could seek a valuation of between $35 to $45 billion, and could go public next March.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Q4 2021 Nu IPO followed by a Q1 2022 IPO would shift a simply huge fraction of global neobank equity from the private markets into the public. But the two companies’ respective transitions will bring risk along with potentially lucrative returns for their backers. If Nu or Chime struggle when they do list, or price at a valuation that underperforms expectations, we could see the value of yet-private neobanks slip.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Recall that while we are certain that private-market investors are smitten with the neobanking startup and unicorn cohort, we have yet to see how the public markets may react to the most valuable companies in the group. Though the fact that </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/18/chime-adds-485m-at-a-14-5b-valuation-claims-ebitda-profitability/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chime was EBITDA positive in late 2020</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> implies that we’re not going to see every neobank file with yawning losses on its books.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What we’ll see when we get a public S-1 filing from Nu is less clear, though we are modestly bursting with curiosity. Just how strong of a business set has the neobanking industry managed to concoct with ample capital and plenty of time? We’ll know soon enough.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="B6PUdSYN63"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1/">The Nubank EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Nubank EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1/embed/#?secret=B6PUdSYN63" data-secret="B6PUdSYN63" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/nubank-files-to-go-public/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224850</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hinge launches a new &#8216;Voice Prompts&#8217; feature to give users a new way to interact</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/hinge-launches-a-new-voice-prompts-feature-to-give-users-a-new-way-to-interact/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/hinge-launches-a-new-voice-prompts-feature-to-give-users-a-new-way-to-interact/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 13:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hinge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tinder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hinge is rolling out a new ‘Voice Prompts’ feature to give its users a new way to connect with their matches. Voice Prompts will allow users to answer a prompt through a 30-second voice recording. The new feature is rolling out globally starting today. Hinge says the new feature allows people to give others a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hinge is rolling out a new ‘Voice Prompts’ feature to give its users a new way to connect with their matches. Voice Prompts will allow users to answer a prompt through a 30-second voice recording. The new feature is rolling out globally starting today.</p>
<p>Hinge says the new feature allows people to give others a glimpse into their personality and perhaps hint at what a first date would be like. The feature will prompt users to discuss a certain topic or share a specific fun story. For instance, the prompts may ask users to discuss their biggest date fail or share a random fact that they love.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The company says 65 percent of its users say they believe hearing someone’s voice would help them determine interest in a match, as 75 percent of users said it’s difficult to feel connected with a match when their conversation is limited to just text and photos.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224653" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Hinge also plans to launch a new ‘Voice Notes’ feature later this fall. Voice Notes will make it possible for users to have a conversation that captures their personality while messaging each other. Hinge says both Voice Notes and Voice Prompts will allow people to better showcase who they are at different points in their dating journey.</p>
<p>Additionally, Hinge is updating its algorithm to help non-binary users better represent themselves while connecting with others on the app. To do this, Hinge will offer a “non-binary” gender category to ensure that their gender is acknowledged.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that Hinge isn&#8217;t the only dating app to add voice features, as audio options are becoming more popular in the space. For instance, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/28/bumble-now-lets-you-call-your-matches-without-exchanging-numbers/">Bumble</a> and <a href="https://www.happn.com/en/">Happn</a> both have voice note features. Additionally, a new app called <a href="https://www.stringdating.com/">String</a> lets users only communicate through voice notes. It&#8217;s clear that dating apps are looking to leverage the convenience of voice notes to retain and garner more users, as the feature takes away the awkwardness of a phone call but takes the conversation a step further than texts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/hinge-launches-a-new-voice-prompts-feature-to-give-users-a-new-way-to-interact/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224653</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Groopit announces $2M pre-seed to help execs access crowd-sourced company data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/groopit-announces-2m-pre-seed-to-help-execs-access-crowd-sourced-company-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/groopit-announces-2m-pre-seed-to-help-execs-access-crowd-sourced-company-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 13:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data gathering tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female founders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Groopit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Groopit, an early stage startup from a 20-year Microsoft veteran, wants to help companies crowdsource data from information supplied by employees working in the field. Today, the company announced a $2 million pre-seed round led by Ascend.vc with participation from a group of investors that includes Voyager Capital and Vulcan Capital. The startup has raised [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.groopit.co/">Groopit</a>, an early stage startup from a 20-year Microsoft veteran, wants to help companies crowdsource data from information supplied by employees working in the field. Today, the company announced a $2 million pre-seed round led by Ascend.vc with participation from a group of investors that includes Voyager Capital and Vulcan Capital. The startup has raised $2.75 million since inception.</p>
<p>Groopit co-founder and CEO Tammy Savage says that when she was working at Microsoft she saw a problem around getting data to people where it was needed inside the organization. &#8220;What Groopit does is it combines data collection and real-time data sharing into one lightweight workflow. So it empowers everyone involved to understand a problem and tackle a problem,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>She likens it to Waze, the crowd-sourced traffic app, where individuals on the road can report to a group of users what&#8217;s happening in real time. Savage believes that by giving teams this kind of insight from the field can be a real advantage to companies.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224477" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>She uses retail customer Stuckey&#8217;s as an example. It&#8217;s a company that sells nut products in retail stores across the country. As sales people go into stores to check supplies, they can take a photo of the display, note the location inside the store and rate how the merchandise is being presented, all from an app on their phones. They can even capture competitor product data including SKUs that appear to be selling faster than the company&#8217;s product. All of this gives executives quick access to data, which they can then share in other tools like a CRM or a collaboration tool. It also has the added benefit of saving time in meetings because salespeople no longer have to give status reports.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2224494" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224494" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2224494" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Stuckeys-Screenshot.png?w=680" alt="Groopit data gathering example" width="680" height="487" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Stuckeys-Screenshot.png 1122w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Stuckeys-Screenshot.png?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Stuckeys-Screenshot.png?resize=300,215 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Stuckeys-Screenshot.png?resize=768,550 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Stuckeys-Screenshot.png?resize=680,487 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Stuckeys-Screenshot.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224494" class="wp-caption-text">Groopit web and mobile apps. <strong>Image Credits: </strong>Groopit</p></div></p>
<p>The product can be customized in a variety of ways to work for an individual business to gather the specific kinds of data it needs &#8212; and it works across mobile and Web.</p>
<p>The company launched in 2018 after Savage left Microsoft. She worked on it for a couple of years before releasing the first version of the product at the end of 2020. The company has 18 employees at this point, and has no plans to hire additional people for the time being, but she says that as a female founder she understands the need for diversity inside her organization.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We actually have more women working on this business than men right now. I think one of the things that happens is we just naturally see talent in different places. So we recruit and hire the people we do because we&#8217;re looking in different places for the talent and&#8230;we just end up with a diverse team,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Savage says that her experience working at Microsoft all those years really helped inform her experience creating Groopit. &#8220;A lot of my understanding of that challenge that leaders have is from my leadership years at Microsoft, plus a lot of research, but that experience was just crucial. It&#8217;s what Groopit is really born out of &#8212; a collision between my experience as a leader plus my experience doing software design,&#8221; she said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/groopit-announces-2m-pre-seed-to-help-execs-access-crowd-sourced-company-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224477</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Panda Express brings Beyond Meat orange chicken to additional locations across US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/panda-express-brings-beyond-meat-orange-chicken-to-additional-locations-across-us/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/panda-express-brings-beyond-meat-orange-chicken-to-additional-locations-across-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beyond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beyond Meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat substitutes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[panda express]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a limited-edition pilot announced over the summer, Panda Express announced this morning that it will be bringing Beyond Meat-based orange chicken to 70 locations across the U.S. Initially introduced at a handful of locations in New York City and Southern California, the plant-based entrée is coming to additional locations in California, New York, Georgia, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After a limited-edition pilot announced over the summer, Panda Express announced this morning that it will be bringing Beyond Meat-based orange chicken to 70 locations across the U.S. Initially introduced at a handful of locations in New York City and Southern California, the plant-based entrée is coming to additional locations in California, New York, Georgia, Illinois, Texas, Florida, Washington, Pennsylvania, Maryland and Virginia.</p>
<p>“We received an overwhelmingly positive guest response when we introduced Beyond The Original Orange Chicken at select locations earlier this year,” Panda Express’ Executive Director of Culinary Innovation Jimmy Wang said in a release. “In fact, we wok-fired more than 1,300 pounds of Beyond The Original Orange Chicken in just the first day. “It’s one of Panda’s most successful regional launches to date, which further reinforces the desire we’re seeing from our guests for more diverse and plant-based options.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tpGQ0Mwttf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/panda-express-is-piloting-beyond-meat-orange-chicken-in-select-locations/">Panda Express is piloting Beyond Meat orange chicken in select locations</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224352" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Panda Express is piloting Beyond Meat orange chicken in select locations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/panda-express-is-piloting-beyond-meat-orange-chicken-in-select-locations/embed/#?secret=tpGQ0Mwttf" data-secret="tpGQ0Mwttf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>For the America Chinese fast-food chain, a partnership with Beyond is an opportunity to expand its non-meat menu, which currently includes eggplant tofu, super greens, chow mein and vegetable spring rolls. The company also lists brown and white rice as examples of its vegetarian menu items, which is probably as good a sign as any that the company’s got a ways to go on that front.</p>
<p>Anything that offers an alternative to meat consumption is probably a net positive in the end. In addition to Panda Express, Beyond has provided various meat alternatives to Pizza Hut, KFC, Denny’s and Dunkin’. The new meatless orange chicken is available at those new locations starting today.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/panda-express-brings-beyond-meat-orange-chicken-to-additional-locations-across-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224352</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DJI&#8217;s latest GoPro competitor is a stunner, but can’t handle the heat</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/djis-latest-gopro-competitor-is-a-stunner-but-cant-handle-the-heat/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/djis-latest-gopro-competitor-is-a-stunner-but-cant-handle-the-heat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 13:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[action camera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brian heater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Camcorders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DJI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Essential Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GoPro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[helicopters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phantom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224665</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DJI&#8217;s second-generation GoPro killer couldn&#8217;t look better&#8230; on paper. The stunning little Action 2 is compact and boasts a full-featured list of specs with a fascinating modular design which allows users to augment the functionality of a core camera unit. It honestly looks like what Apple would create if they were tasked with redesigning the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">DJI&#8217;s second-generation GoPro killer couldn&#8217;t look better&#8230; on paper.</p>
<p>The stunning little Action 2 is compact and boasts a full-featured list of specs with a fascinating modular design which allows users to augment the functionality of a core camera unit. It honestly looks like what Apple would create if they were tasked with redesigning the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/20/gopro-kills-the-session-camera-cube/">GoPro Session</a> camera of yesteryear. It comes in dual variations, a $399 bundle that includes the core camera unit and a battery cube which snaps to it magnetically adding hours of recording time to the device, and a pricier $519 varietal that includes the camera unit and a front-facing display module. The 56 gram Action 2 core camera unit matches the 4K/120fps power of the latest GoPro Hero10 Black in a package that&#8217;s half the size, or at least that&#8217;s how it&#8217;s advertised.</p>
<p>I got a chance to spend a few days with the device and, as the headline suggests, I wasn&#8217;t all that pleased with my hands-on time. In short, this device is very pretty and innovates in a couple of clear ways but also was nowhere near ready for launch.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224665" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>First off, the good stuff.</p>
<p>The hardware is quite nice and the modular design is better executed than one might expect. The magnetic clips and locking mechanisms are solid and overall everything has a really dense heftiness to it that feels more premium than any action camera I&#8217;ve tried. Video quality generally met expectations for an action camera of this price point and I enjoyed some of the accessories that DJI sent along including a necklace-like mount and a magnetic macro lens. There are some quirks like not being able to charge the central camera unit without it being attached to either the external battery unit or front-facing display, but overall the modularity is done pretty well.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2224691" style="width: 2596px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224691" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2224691 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.04.03-PM.png" alt="" width="2586" height="1616" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.04.03-PM.png 2586w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.04.03-PM.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.04.03-PM.png?resize=300,187 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.04.03-PM.png?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.04.03-PM.png?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.04.03-PM.png?resize=1536,960 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.04.03-PM.png?resize=2048,1280 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.04.03-PM.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2586px) 100vw, 2586px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224691" class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: DJI</p></div></p>
<p>That design is mostly about balancing portability with battery life. If a user just wants to shoot a few quick videos for their Instagram, they can choose to leave the additional modules at home. DJI has aims to sell the Action 2 as a crossover action camera that&#8217;s built for pro athletes and influencers alike with a compact design that can be worn on a user&#8217;s chest with the included magnetic lanyard. Shooting (well, trying to shoot) 4K video on the Action 2, I found you can get about 30 minutes worth of footage from the core camera unit on a single charge, which is a lot for social media clips but not that much for a standard action cam (DJI claims up to 70 minutes of run time). Shooting when connected to either the battery module or front-facing camera module allowed for much lengthier usage.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Now, the bad stuff.</p>
<p>On paper, stabilized 4K video at 120 frames is incredibly impressive in a package this small, but unfortunately I found those claims to be too good to be true &#8212; way too good to be true. The device was able to shoot at its highest end setting for less than five minutes before the device automatically stopped recording because of overheating. Indeed, I wasn&#8217;t able to shoot 4K at any setting without the device eventually shutting down due to overheating even at the device&#8217;s lowest 24fps setting (I was able to capture just under 15 minutes of footage in that mode). Becoming so hot that it can no longer function is a rough issue for a product that DJI is partially pitching as a chest-mounted or head-mounted wearable.</p>
<p>A DJI spokesperson confirmed that other reviewers had similar issues with overheating and that the only fix for now is to shoot at a lower resolution.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2224689" style="width: 2058px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224689" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2224689 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/eQcBOdDw.jpg" alt="" width="2048" height="1536" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/eQcBOdDw.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/eQcBOdDw.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/eQcBOdDw.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/eQcBOdDw.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/eQcBOdDw.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/eQcBOdDw.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/eQcBOdDw.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224689" class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: DJI</p></div></p>
<p>I struggle to go much more in depth than this for the hands-on, because not being able to consistently shoot 4K quality video at any frame rate makes this is a pretty hard sell for anyone to buy at launch. While I can appreciate the boldness of such a major inter-generational design change for the Action 2, I&#8217;ve also gained a respect for GoPro&#8217;s more incremental successive upgrades which may lack some of the pizazz of the Action 2 but do consistently function as advertised.</p>
<p>We were generally big fans of the first DJI Action camera, which launched in 2019 and proved to be a convincing competitor to GoPro. The original Action showcased a very convincing set of features, many of which would be adopted by GoPro in successive generations. &#8220;For now, however, most of the nits that can be picked here are on the small side. That’s fairly remarkable for what’s essentially a first-generation product — albeit one from a well-established company,&#8221; my colleague Brian Heater wrote at the time.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a different story with the Action 2, and while DJI may resolve these issues with firmware updates, this device clearly wasn&#8217;t ready to send out to reviewers and I&#8217;d be wary to order one (the Action 2 is available for purchase today) until the company has showcased a number of key fixes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gEkqvCZw7K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/15/dji-is-out-goproing-gopro-with-its-own-action-camera/">DJI is out-GoProing GoPro with its own action camera</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DJI is out-GoProing GoPro with its own action camera&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/15/dji-is-out-goproing-gopro-with-its-own-action-camera/embed/#?secret=gEkqvCZw7K" data-secret="gEkqvCZw7K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/djis-latest-gopro-competitor-is-a-stunner-but-cant-handle-the-heat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224665</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adobe&#8217;s Project Strike a Pose uses AI to pose your models for you</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/adobes-project-strike-a-pose-uses-ai-to-pose-your-models-for-you/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/adobes-project-strike-a-pose-uses-ai-to-pose-your-models-for-you/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 13:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe Creative Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe max 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe photoshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer Vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neural network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the highlights of Adobe&#8217;s annual MAX conference is its so-called &#8216;Sneaks&#8217; session, where the company shows off some of its most cutting-edge research projects. Some of these make it into the mainline Creative Cloud apps and some simply remain cool demos. At this year&#8217;s MAX, one of the most interesting sneaks is Project [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">One of the highlights of Adobe&#8217;s annual MAX conference is its so-called &#8216;Sneaks&#8217; session, where the company shows off some of its most <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/adobes-project-sharp-shots-uses-ai-to-deblur-your-videos-with-one-click/">cutting-edge</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/05/adobes-project-sweet-talk-makes-portraits-come-alive/">research</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/03/adobes-project-voco-lets-you-edit-speech-as-easily-as-text/">projects</a>. Some of these make it into the mainline Creative Cloud apps and some simply remain cool demos. At this year&#8217;s MAX, one of the most interesting sneaks is Project Strike a Pose.</p>
<p>Here is the problem it tries to solve: sometimes, you may have a photo of a model you want to use, but you don&#8217;t have a photo of this specific model in the exact pose you need. Project Strike a Pose then lets you use another photo of another model in the right pose as an example and the software &#8212; powered by Adobe&#8217;s Sensei AI platform &#8212; will automatically generate a new image with the original model in that same pose. It&#8217;s basically a kind of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_Style_Transfer">style transfer</a> &#8212; but for model poses.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2224670" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_2.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224670" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2224670" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="615" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_2.png 2168w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_2.png?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_2.png?resize=300,180 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_2.png?resize=768,461 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_2.png?resize=680,408 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_2.png?resize=1536,922 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_2.png?resize=2048,1230 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_2.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2224670" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adobe</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224667" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>What&#8217;s impressive here is that the result isn&#8217;t just some rough approximation of the example pose or just the faces swapped between the source and example. At least in the demo Adobe&#8217;s Krishna Kumar Singh, the research scientist behind the project, showed me, Project Strike a Pose&#8217;s neural network was able to dream up the right look for the clothes the model is wearing, for example, and even rotate the model&#8217;s head as needed &#8212; and it even gets the shoes right, too.</p>
<p>Impressively, this even works when you ask the tool to dream up an image of the model&#8217;s back &#8212; though as you can see in the example below, the hair here is a bit off.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2224668" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_3.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224668" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2224668" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_3.png" alt="" width="1024" height="604" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_3.png 2172w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_3.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_3.png?resize=300,177 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_3.png?resize=768,453 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_3.png?resize=680,401 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_3.png?resize=1536,907 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_3.png?resize=2048,1209 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/snapshot_3.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2224668" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adobe</p></div></p>
<p>Adobe wouldn&#8217;t say too much about how it trained the algorithms behind this project. Clearly, though, to train a neural network like this, it had to use a lot of examples of models in a wide variety of poses. Singh previously worked on <a href="http://krsingh.cs.ucdavis.edu/">a lot of research</a> related to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_adversarial_network">generative adversarial networks</a>, so chances are this new project is already based on this technique.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As of now, this is only an experimental research project and like with so many of the company&#8217;s sneaks at MAX, it may or may not ever make it into a tool like Photoshop. If it works as well as it does in the demos, though (and Adobe says the software has no issues handling models of different ethnicities either), it would surely be a feature that many users would like to see in something like Photoshop or even in a tool like Adobe Spark that is already geared toward a broader audience with fewer image manipulation skills.</p>
<p>Sadly, it&#8217;s also easy to see how somebody could abuse a system like this. In the age of deep fakes and manipulated photos, this could become an easy avenue for somebody non-technical to create a compromising image of a public figure &#8212; or anybody else for that matter. You can already do that today, of course, but it takes quite a bit of skill to pull it off. Project Strike a Pose would make it a matter of a few clicks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/adobes-project-strike-a-pose-uses-ai-to-pose-your-models-for-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224667</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok brings its Video Kit to desktop, web and consoles</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/tiktok-brings-its-video-kit-to-desktop-web-and-consoles/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/tiktok-brings-its-video-kit-to-desktop-web-and-consoles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Likee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Picsart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[share]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok announced today it&#8217;s expanding its Video Kit offering for developers to include those building apps for the web, desktop, and consoles, in addition to its previous support for mobile platforms. Alongside the news, the company unveiled a host of new third-party apps that would now integrate with TikTok, including Clipchamp, Combo, Grabyo, Kapwing, Mobcrush, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok announced today it&#8217;s expanding its Video Kit offering for developers to include those building apps for the web, desktop, and consoles, in addition to its previous support for mobile platforms. Alongside the news, the company unveiled a host of new third-party apps that would now integrate with TikTok, including Clipchamp, Combo, Grabyo, Kapwing, Mobcrush, and LG U+.</p>
<p>Video Kit is TikTok&#8217;s solution which includes the &#8220;Share to TikTok&#8221; option that allows third-party tools and apps to integrate with TikTok so their users can upload video files directly to TikTok from their own app&#8217;s editing platform. First <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/launching-share-to-tiktok-with-adobe-premiere-rush-and-more-partners">launched in 2019,</a> Share to TikTok was the first feature introduced in the TikTok for Developers program, which has since expanded to offer <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/tiktok-expands-integrations-with-third-party-apps-for-logins-sharing-sounds-and-more/">new tools like Login Kit and Sound Kit</a>.</p>
<p>Today, Share to TikTok can be found in a number of tools, like Adobe Premiere Rush, Picsart, Enlight Videoleap, Momento GIF Maker, and others. These sorts of apps are often used by professional creators who want to be able to make more advanced edits than what&#8217;s offered by the TikTok app alone.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224802" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>By now expanding to include desktop and web tools, as well, TikTok is broadening its reach to even more pro creators and even brands or businesses. <a href="https://clipchamp.com/en/">Clipchamp</a>, for example, was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/microsoft-acquires-video-creation-and-editing-software-maker-clipchamp/">recently acquired by Microsoft</a> to bring its video creation and editing software to Microsoft&#8217;s lineup of productivity software, with the company calling video a new type of &#8220;document&#8221; that businesses now use to do things like pitch an idea, explain a process or communicate with team members.</p>
<p>​<a href="https://www.joincombo.com/">Combo&#8217;s</a> platform is designed to help creators save time repurposing their content, which could enable streaming services to turn their highlights and clips into TikTok videos. <a href="https://about.grabyo.com/us/">Grabyo&#8217;s</a> cloud video production platform gives broadcasters and media publishers the tools to produce, edit and deliver live and real-time video content across all major broadcast, digital and social platforms.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/03/11/super-league-gaming-will-acquire-mobcrush-game-livestreaming-platform/">Super League Gaming</a>-owned <a href="https://nam12.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https://studio.mobcrush.com/v1/index.html#/auth/login&amp;data=04%7C01%7Cgillian.sheldon@superleague.com%7C0f49a3f557f946ae17ae08d994c9a18e%7C7c7d867f4005487ea03261aa2dca8302%7C1%7C0%7C637704415996124727%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0=%7C1000&amp;sdata=ZiT+L2jreRgFx0jSXTi2+alnDzHJL0A8CNC505zQoL4=&amp;reserved=0">Mobcrush</a> offers tools aimed at gamers and live streamers, while <a href="https://www.kapwing.com/">Kapwing&#8217;s</a> video editor includes collaborative tools for creative teams. Collaborative platform U2 (provided by LG U+) will include the functionality later this year, allowing creators to work on video storyboards with a team.</p>
<p>TikTok says other developers interested in the new tools can visit <a href="http://developers.tiktok.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://developers.tiktok.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1635344399304000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF4OhvFjhWSZTho_fJMSDASDbhbgw">developers.tiktok.com</a> to get started.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/tiktok-brings-its-video-kit-to-desktop-web-and-consoles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224802</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OurCrowd raises $25M from SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund 2</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/ourcrowd-raises-25m-from-softbanks-vision-fund-2/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/ourcrowd-raises-25m-from-softbanks-vision-fund-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beyond Meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jon Medved]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OurCrowd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Investment Advisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank Vision Fund]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223074</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Israeli venture platform OurCrowd today announced that SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund 2 has made a $25 million convertible equity investment into the firm. As part of this deal, OurCrowd is also entering into a strategic partnership with SoftBank Investment Advisers (SBIA) to &#8220;consider investment opportunities via OurCrowd’s online venture capital investment platform&#8221; and jointly evaluate market [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Israeli venture platform <a href="https://www.ourcrowd.com/">OurCrowd</a> today announced that SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund 2 has made a $25 million convertible equity investment into the firm. As part of this deal, OurCrowd is also entering into a strategic partnership with SoftBank Investment Advisers (SBIA) to &#8220;consider investment opportunities via <span class="il">OurCrowd</span>’s online venture capital investment platform&#8221; and jointly evaluate market trends. The focus here will be on startups that work on projects related to artificial intelligence, quantum computing, mobility, AgTech, security, HealthTech and more.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2224684" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/b1ce6372-194a-4f74-953e-532fea43b3a8-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224684" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2224684" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/b1ce6372-194a-4f74-953e-532fea43b3a8-1.jpg?w=300" alt="Jon Medved, CEO of OurCrowd" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/b1ce6372-194a-4f74-953e-532fea43b3a8-1.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/b1ce6372-194a-4f74-953e-532fea43b3a8-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/b1ce6372-194a-4f74-953e-532fea43b3a8-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/b1ce6372-194a-4f74-953e-532fea43b3a8-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/b1ce6372-194a-4f74-953e-532fea43b3a8-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/b1ce6372-194a-4f74-953e-532fea43b3a8-1.jpg?resize=1536,1023 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/b1ce6372-194a-4f74-953e-532fea43b3a8-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2224684" class="wp-caption-text">Jon Medved, CEO of OurCrowd</p></div></p>
<p><span lang="EN-US">“</span>The Softbank investment in Ou<span lang="EN-US">r</span>Crowd will create real mutual value as we work together on behalf of further innovation in the venture capital asset class,&#8221; OurCrowd CEO Jon Medved said. &#8220;I could not ask for better or stronger partners who are known above all for the incredible support they provide to their portfolio companies and entrepreneurs.<span lang="EN-US">”</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223074" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Currently, OurCrowd&#8217;s platform plays host to about 140,000 accredited investors. New registrations on the platform were at 25,000 in 2020 and have already surpassed 75,000 in 2021. As for new investments, the firm expects a number that will exceed $500 million this year.</p>
<p>OurCrowd says it will use the new funding to expand its platform and investor base and to accelerate its processes to identify new startups for inclusion on its platform. So far, the firm has invested in about 280 companies across its <a href="https://www.ourcrowd.com/funds">30 funds</a>. Its most successful exits to date include Lemonade, Beyond Meat, Jump, Kenna, Argus and Wave.</p>
<p>&#8220;Softbank has been investing ahead of major technology trends for over 40 years and we believe there is huge, embedded potential in the private markets ecosystem,&#8221; said Yossi Cohen, head of SBIA’s operations in Israel. &#8220;In OurCrowd, we have an investment partner with the networks and pedigree to help promising Israeli startups to potentially emerge as international tech champions.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/ourcrowd-raises-25m-from-softbanks-vision-fund-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223074</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>InCloudCounsel raises $200M, rebrands as Ontra to expand its automation tools for contract management</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/incloudcounsel-raises-200m-rebrands-as-ontra-to-expand-its-automation-tools-for-contract-management/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/incloudcounsel-raises-200m-rebrands-as-ontra-to-expand-its-automation-tools-for-contract-management/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackstone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackstone Growth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board member]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig. worker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[incloudcounsel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law firms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musicians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prudential]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valuation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A typical enterprise grapples with hundreds or thousands of agreements, contracts and other legal documents every year, and it usually engages costly legal counsel either inside or outside the company to assess those documents on their behalf. Now, a startup called InCloudCounsel that is part RPA and part BPO &#8212; it has built tools to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A typical enterprise grapples with hundreds or thousands of agreements, contracts and other legal documents every year, and it usually engages costly legal counsel either inside or outside the company to assess those documents on their behalf. Now, a startup called <a href="https://www.incloudcounsel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">InCloudCounsel</a> that is part RPA and part BPO &#8212; it has built tools to both automate and, in some cases, outsource this work &#8212; is announcing a Series B round of $200 million, money that it will be using to meet demand for its services.</p>
<p>Alongside this, the startup is rebranding to <a href="https://www.ontra.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ontra</a> &#8212; signifying &#8220;getting to the heart of contracts&#8221;, according to the startup&#8217;s CEO and founder Troy Pospisil.</p>
<p>The round is being led by Blackstone Growth (the growth equity business of the investment giant), with previous backer Battery Ventures and board member Mike Paulus (who previously ran and sold Assurance IQ to Prudential, and before that was an investor with Andreessen Horowitz). Valuation is not being disclosed, but prior to this, in July 2019, the company had raised $40 million in a round led by Battery &#8212; a sum that had previously been undisclosed until today.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224783" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company is not talking about its valuation, but as a marker of what kinds of companies Ontra is targeting and working with, Blackstone is a strategic and financial investor in this round: Blackstone MD Paul Morrissey tells me that the firm is a strong user of Ontra&#8217;s tech to filter through thousands of NDAs and other contracts that it issues and receives every year, where the technology uses AI techniques like NLP to essentially guard Blackstone&#8217;s interests, scanning documents for items that are unusual or might need modifying ahead of being signed, and then passing on those documents to human lawyers for final checks. In all, Ontra is processing some 20,000 NDAs monthly at the moment.</p>
<p>Pospisil said first came up with the idea for Ontra when he was working as an investment specialist at HIG Capital, where he saw how the need to triage large volumes of contracts would slow down deals and other important transactions that the company was making. HIG would have a large legal counsel on board to handle work, but even so it needed to rely on outside organizations also to complement and supplement that.</p>
<p>&#8220;Even simple contracts needed to be recorded and catalogued,&#8221; he recalled. &#8220;We would send these to a law firm, or we might staff up a team, but no one was using any technology to track what they were doing. There was no visibility into what is where, whether data is lost in the process.&#8221; This covered long, complex agreements; important contracts and credit agreements, he said. &#8220;All these were incredibly complicated.&#8221;</p>
<p>It was 2014, and he was living in San Francisco and seeing a lot of interesting business models such as Uber&#8217;s emerging that gave him an idea to, in his words, &#8220;combine tech and a labor model to solve the problem.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Ontra&#8217;s approach thus encompasses two parts. First, tapping into innovations were happening in the wider world of document management processing, it uses natural language and other algorithmic techniques to speed up the processing of large amounts of documentation faster and more efficiently than a human might do it. You might think of this as akin to a kind of very specialized version of robotic process automation.</p>
<p>That document processing work, in turn, is then handed over to the second part of the Ontra platform, its crowdsourced network of lawyers. Essentially, following the Uber and others&#8217; model of bringing in gig workers to handle jobs on demand, Ontra has amassed a team of legal professionals &#8212; typically corporate lawyers &#8212; who either provide some hours to Ontra in a side-gig if they are not already working full time, or in some cases as a small way to earn money using their skill at a time when may be doing something else (or, not working at all). Pospisil said that in cases where a company might have their own in-house teams, they might also use Ontra just for the processing side to speed work up, but as a general rule, customers are taking the full package.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is like payroll,&#8221; he said. &#8220;You don’t want to be doing it internally if it&#8217;s not strategically important to what you want to be doing as a business.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ontra interestingly has not yet come up against legal firms that might see it as competition.</p>
<p>&#8220;We were a little worried that we would be considered competition to the law firms, but they really like us,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They don’t want to be doing this work, either. They are focusing on larger M&amp;A transactions and supporting the company. The world has this weird idea that legal work always needs to be sent to a law firm, but it&#8217;s not always efficient to do that, and lawyers are too expensive to do that. It&#8217;s not right-sized.&#8221;</p>
<p>Morrissey at Blackstone believes that the future lies in continuing to pursue the two sides of the business model, with the lawyer network an important complement to what is at heart a tech company, with more software being added all the time.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s hard to underestimate the tech they have built,&#8221; he said, which is partly there in aid of making its network of lawyers much more efficient. &#8220;It means Ontra is also improving the workflow for them, with analytics that essentially say ‘focus on this’ and not other things in a contract.&#8221; The company also offers a full invoicing platform for the legal market, he said, &#8220;similar to the piece Uber has built for consumers so that drivers get paid and don’t have to worry about anything else.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/incloudcounsel-raises-200m-rebrands-as-ontra-to-expand-its-automation-tools-for-contract-management/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224783</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biotech startup Shiru sprouting plant-based ingredients with new capital infusion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/biotech-startup-shiru-sprouting-plant-based-ingredients-with-new-capital-infusion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/biotech-startup-shiru-sprouting-plant-based-ingredients-with-new-capital-infusion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chuck Templeton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CPT Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emles Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fermentation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthy food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jasmin Hume]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lux capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plant-based food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[s2g ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shiru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The W Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veronorte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company plans to have ingredients ready by next year, which means we could see the first commercial products containing Shiru’s ingredients on grocery store shelves as early as 2023.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Protein biochemist Dr. Jasmin Hume was working in the alternative food space when she saw an opportunity to evolve technology so that our global food industry can reduce its reliance on animals.</p>
<p>She started <a href="https://www.shiru.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shiru</a> in 2019, and the company uses a “precision fermentation” process to create plant-based ingredients for food companies. The result has similar taste, texture, versatility and cost at scale as its animal analogs, Hume told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>“The opportunity that I saw and learned about is that the ingredients that we get from animals, the egg proteins or dairy proteins, pop up in food labels in weird places,” she added. “For example, white, spongy bread has milk proteins. We aim to cover a lot of food categories, but by replacing them with sustainable and nutritious ingredients.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224644" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Both the food ingredients and plant-based proteins markets are poised for steady growth. The <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/627706/market-size-of-food-ingredients-worldwide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">global food ingredients market</a> is forecasted to be valued at $400 billion by 2022, while <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/company/press/plant-based-foods-market-to-hit-162-billion-in-next-decade-projects-bloomberg-intelligence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">plant-based foods</a> are in line to be a $162 billion market by 2030.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9w3XY7f2yx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/beyond-meats-plant-based-chicken-tenders-are-coming-to-grocery-stores/">Beyond Meat&#8217;s plant-based &#8216;chicken&#8217; tenders are coming to grocery stores</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Beyond Meat&#8217;s plant-based &#8216;chicken&#8217; tenders are coming to grocery stores&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/beyond-meats-plant-based-chicken-tenders-are-coming-to-grocery-stores/embed/#?secret=9w3XY7f2yx" data-secret="9w3XY7f2yx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Shiru’s catalog currently has six different ingredients that are colorless and flavorless and can be added to a variety of food products, like packaged baked goods, sauces, burgers and yogurt.</p>
<p>One of the food targets Hume and her team are looking to replace is methyl cellulose, a starch that is used in foods like vegetable protein-based foods.</p>
<p>“It provides a binding function that isn’t already in plant-based burgers and sauces, however, it is a nasty ingredient to have on the label,” Hume added. “Food companies have issues with methyl cellulose, but no one is talking about it. That type of ingredient compels a replacement, and we have the ingredients to replace that.”</p>
<p>To get out ahead of the industry demand and be able to deliver these first ingredients to companies by early next year, the Emeryville-based company today announced a $17 million Series A round, led by S2G Ventures.</p>
<p>Joining S2G on the round are returning investors Lux Capital, CPT Capital, Y Combinator and Emles Venture Partners, and new investors, The W Fund, SALT and Veronorte. The new funding brings Shiru’s total funding to date to just over $20 million, Hume said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As part of the investment, Chuck Templeton, managing director of S2G, joined Shiru’s board. The firm is an investment fund focused on healthy food and sustainable agriculture, and often invests in companies that have impact and an analog to replace animal products.</p>
<p>There has been an evolution of plant-based foods, with each new version aimed at being better tasting, though still not as healthy as could be, he said. Shiru’s ingredients, on the other hand, are poised to be a new version that not only &#8220;tastes great,&#8221; but closely mirrors the analog it is trying to replace and is healthier, he added.</p>
<p>In addition, Templeton believes the company has figured out the cost structure, nutritional panels and the right labeling to “get customers excited.”</p>
<p>“They are just now discovering products and proteins faster and are able to look at how to bring ingredients to market that have multiple uses,” he added. “This gives them an opportunity to fine tune and continue to do things like bring the cost structure down. Jasmin and her team are enabling the food industry to not be constrained and to find the best ingredients to clean up their labels and the environment.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QsGEUxXS1v"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/06/startups-making-meat-alternatives-are-gaining-traction-worldwide/">Startups making meat alternatives are gaining traction worldwide</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startups making meat alternatives are gaining traction worldwide&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/06/startups-making-meat-alternatives-are-gaining-traction-worldwide/embed/#?secret=QsGEUxXS1v" data-secret="QsGEUxXS1v" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Meanwhile, with the plan to have ingredients ready for customers by next year, Hume forecasts that we could see the first commercial products containing Shiru’s ingredients on grocery store shelves as early as 2023.</p>
<p>The company was initially heads down working on the technology, and when it was validated, Hume began looking at another round of venture capital to continue to the next phase of scaling and build out Shiru’s infrastructure.</p>
<p>She intends to use the new funding to double Shiru’s 22-person workforce within the next 12 months in the areas of science, fermentation, marketing and business development. The company is also moving into a new headquarters in Alameda next year and will begin scaling its manufacturing.</p>
<p>“The biggest thing we need to do is produce a lot of ingredients,” Hume added. “The scaling challenge is going to be a big one, and we are seeking partnerships or building the facilities ourselves to use the fermentation at industrial scales. This will get us to the point where we can deliver the samples that food companies need for testing.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="J3pmtOTpG4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/the-enormous-challenges-and-abundant-opportunities-in-climate-tech/">The enormous challenges and abundant opportunities in climate tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The enormous challenges and abundant opportunities in climate tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/the-enormous-challenges-and-abundant-opportunities-in-climate-tech/embed/#?secret=J3pmtOTpG4" data-secret="J3pmtOTpG4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/biotech-startup-shiru-sprouting-plant-based-ingredients-with-new-capital-infusion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224644</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YETiCO raises Seed for its tap-a-device to simply divide the bill and tip restaurant staff</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/yetico-raises-seed-for-its-tap-a-device-to-simply-divide-the-bill-and-tip-restaurant-staff/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/yetico-raises-seed-for-its-tap-a-device-to-simply-divide-the-bill-and-tip-restaurant-staff/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this year European startup Sundayraised $100 million in a Series A raise led by US investors Coatue and DST Global, just five months after launching. The proposition was relatively simple and pretty much tailor-made for the Covid-19 era: diners scan a QR code to download an app, and then split the bill between friends [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this year European startup <a href="https://sundayapp.com/">Sunday</a>raised $100 million in a Series A raise led by US investors Coatue and DST Global, just five months after launching. The proposition was relatively simple and pretty much tailor-made for the Covid-19 era: diners scan a QR code to download an app, and then split the bill between friends as well as tip the staff, without needing to interact with wait staff. The proposition is that restaurants get to turn tables around faster, increase average spend, and wait staff generally get more tips.</p>
<p>Now a UK startup is entering the space, this time with a LOT less funding, but what appears to be an even more seamless user experience.</p>
<p>The ‘<a href="https://tableyeti.com/">Tap to Tip</a>’ device comes with pre-loaded software connected to the restaurant. The whole bill is paid by all diners via this device, just by them tapping it. It then captures data for the restaurant, and generates tips for the staff.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224808" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The startup behind the device, <a href="http://www.yetico.co">YETiCo</a>, has now raised a £300,000 Seed funding round, backed by Angels including DesignMyNight founder Nick Telson, Skimlinks co-founder Alicia Navarro, Masabi founder Ben Whitaker, Simon Squibb, Dot Major of the band London Grammar and Lego CTO Atul Bhardwaj.</p>
<p>Launched in 2019, YETiCo offers restaurants a bill splitting, pay-at-table restaurant device. The startup claims it’s driven £10m in transaction volume in its first year, with restaurant clients such as Maray Restaurants, Jones Family Kitchen, Wuns Tearoom and Cub.</p>
<p>The Tap to Tip TableYeti device now has an exclusive distribution deal with TiPJAR and is now available in over 300 bars and restaurants across the UK.   </p>
<p>Founder Oliver Pugh said: “We really bet on hospitality being about experience versus becoming an extension of Deliveroo just in a restaurant post COVID. That bet is now looking correct, as TableYeti alone has a run rate of £1m ARR with global brand name restaurants.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/yetico-raises-seed-for-its-tap-a-device-to-simply-divide-the-bill-and-tip-restaurant-staff/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224808</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Truepill’s latest funding boosts valuation to $1.6B as it works on B2B side of healthcare</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/truepills-latest-funding-boosts-valuation-to-1-6b-as-it-works-on-b2b-side-of-healthcare/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/truepills-latest-funding-boosts-valuation-to-1-6b-as-it-works-on-b2b-side-of-healthcare/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garry tan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initialized capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sid Viswanathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telehealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TI Platform Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Truepill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Umar Afrid]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The new funding represents a “hyper growth moment” for the company, which is in position to bring in some $300 million in revenue this year.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After developing a network of telehealth, diagnostics and pharmacies for consumers, digital health company <a href="http://truepill.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Truepill</a> is targeting healthcare incumbents like health payers, providers and employer groups.</p>
<p>The new focus is buoyed by the close of its $142 million Series D funding round, led by an undisclosed partner, with participation from existing investors Initialized Capital and TI Platform Management.</p>
<p>The latest investment nearly doubles the San Mateo-based company’s venture capital funding raised since its inception five years ago to $256 million — which includes a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/closing-on-75-million-in-new-cash-truepill-plans-at-home-testing-service-as-it-nears-175-million-in-annual-revenue/">$75 million Series C</a> round last August — and pushes Truepill into unicorn territory with a valuation of $1.6 billion.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224262" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Since its Series C, Truepill has been busy: it debuted its telehealth and diagnostic services, and launched its COVID-19 wellness program and virtual pharmacy e-commerce offerings. To date, it has shipped nearly 10 million prescriptions, processed approximately 1 million diagnostic tests and facilitated more than 50,000 telehealth visits per week.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HHzGHpbjgc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/closing-on-75-million-in-new-cash-truepill-plans-at-home-testing-service-as-it-nears-175-million-in-annual-revenue/">Update: Closing on $75 million in new cash, Truepill plans at-home testing service as it nears $200 million in annual revenue</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Update: Closing on $75 million in new cash, Truepill plans at-home testing service as it nears $200 million in annual revenue&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/closing-on-75-million-in-new-cash-truepill-plans-at-home-testing-service-as-it-nears-175-million-in-annual-revenue/embed/#?secret=HHzGHpbjgc" data-secret="HHzGHpbjgc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We were just launching our diagnostics and telehealth in August, and now we are building on that,” Umar Afridi, CEO and co-founder of Truepill, told TechCrunch. “We are now expanding who we work with. Initially it was direct-to-consumer, but now we want to work with larger entities, including health plans, payers, life science companies and providers.”</p>
<p>The company’s “big focus is continuing the vision of transforming healthcare,” said Sid Viswanathan, president and co-founder of Truepill. Going after the healthcare incumbents is a signal that the company is prepared to service the whole industry, but it may take a few years for some of these partnerships to actualize, he added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition to extending its customer base, the founders say the new funding represents a “hyper growth moment” for the company, which is in position to bring in some $300 million in revenue this year, Viswanathan said.</p>
<p>It will enable Truepill to add hundreds of new positions across its organization, including engineering, business development and pharmacy as it opens six new pharmacy and over-the-counter fulfillment facilities in California, Illinois, Michigan, North Carolina, Ohio and Pennsylvania by next year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FgJagXTdg3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/telemedicine-startups-are-positioning-themselves-for-a-post-pandemic-world/">Telemedicine startups are positioning themselves for a post-pandemic world</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Telemedicine startups are positioning themselves for a post-pandemic world&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/telemedicine-startups-are-positioning-themselves-for-a-post-pandemic-world/embed/#?secret=FgJagXTdg3" data-secret="FgJagXTdg3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>With regard to the company’s new valuation, Viswanathan explained that the company hasn’t been one to chase the unicorn milestone, but did say reaching the $1.6 billion valuation is “reflective of our ambition.” It also has a pipeline of new projects on the horizon.</p>
<p>“We still have a lot in store for 2022,” he added. “It is still early but if we start to show what we can do, we will be helping 330 million people in the U.S. that deal with healthcare, and we know where we want to see the change take place.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Garry Tan, founder and managing partner at Initialized Capital, says Truepill now has the reach and scale that it can work across the whole spectrum of healthcare, similar to what Stripe is doing in fintech.</p>
<p>He noted that he “was impressed” by how the company went from a core pharmacy service in 2016 to providing software now for telehealth and diagnostics, calling it “unusual” in healthcare to be able to find success in multiple areas.</p>
<p>In addition, Tan believes that what Truepill is doing in the direct-to-consumer market is giving people choices. They can continue to work with their primary care provider, but for different types of treatment, could tap into remote patient monitoring or another level of care through Truepill.</p>
<p>“We often worry about access, but Truepill is in an interesting spot,” he added. “We talk in technology that you are either arming the ‘rebels’ or the ‘empire,’ and in their case, they work with both. They are helping incumbents roll out a 50,000-person telehealth visit program, and on the flip side, enabling new startups, who can do this themselves, to be able to save time and money.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kjFfYfdmp8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/fintechs-growing-role-in-the-healthcare-revolution/">Fintech&#8217;s growing role in the healthcare revolution</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech&#8217;s growing role in the healthcare revolution&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/fintechs-growing-role-in-the-healthcare-revolution/embed/#?secret=kjFfYfdmp8" data-secret="kjFfYfdmp8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/truepills-latest-funding-boosts-valuation-to-1-6b-as-it-works-on-b2b-side-of-healthcare/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224262</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Skyryse brings in $200M to make flying an aircraft as simple as swiping a touchscreen</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/skyryse-brings-in-200m-to-make-flying-an-aircraft-as-simple-as-swiping-a-touchscreen/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/skyryse-brings-in-200m-to-make-flying-an-aircraft-as-simple-as-swiping-a-touchscreen/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fidelity Management & Research Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monashee Investment Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Skyryse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Five-year-old startup Skyryse has raised a $200 million Series B to develop FlightOS, a flight automation technology stack that the company says will help experienced pilots operate new types of aircraft and allow complete novices to quickly learn the ropes of flying. Most importantly, the company says FlightOS will be able to be retrofitted onto [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Five-year-old startup <a href="https://skyryse.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Skyryse</a> has raised a $200 million Series B to develop FlightOS, a flight automation technology stack that the company says will help experienced pilots operate new types of aircraft and allow complete novices to quickly learn the ropes of flying.</p>
<p>Most importantly, the company says FlightOS will be able to be retrofitted onto any aircraft &#8212; potentially unlocking flight controls to anyone that can operate a touchscreen and a joystick. Right now, that touchscreen is an iPad, but Skyryse told TechCrunch that will be replaced by “aviation certified touchscreens” in the finished product.</p>
<p>In addition to the screen and joystick, the FlightOS stack includes actuators and flight control computers, which would replace an aircraft’s existing mechanical systems. This one-to-one replacement means that the entire system is “cost neutral,” allowing OEMs to manufacture a vehicle with FlightOS at the same cost as they would for existing aircraft, the company said.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224558" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In its early years, Skyryse pursued a fully automated system, with the intention of launching its own urban air mobility service. But the company has scaled back from being an operator, and is instead moving full-force on the FlightOS stack.</p>
<p>FlightOS is not full automation; there still must be someone to operate the joystick, after all. But it’s close. Right now, CEO Mark Groden said the near-term goal was to boost the skills of certified pilots, but longer-term his plans are much more ambitious.</p>
<p>“Our near-term goal is to improve safety in aviation, give current pilots the confidence to fly in various weather conditions with their families and open up new types of aircraft to them,” Groden told TechCrunch. “Our long-term goal is to allow the 220 million licensed drivers to operate any aircraft safely and effectively.”</p>
<p>Still, the system does not account for things like communicating with air traffic control or an understanding of which conditions are unsafe to fly in &#8212; things that a certified pilot might learn. But Groden said the current certification process on its own does not ensure safe pilots, the same way getting a driver’s license to operate a vehicle does not ensure attentive driving.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2224602" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224602" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2224602" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RF1_4084.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RF1_4084.jpg 3600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RF1_4084.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RF1_4084.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RF1_4084.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RF1_4084.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RF1_4084.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RF1_4084.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RF1_4084.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224602" class="wp-caption-text">Skyryse CEO Mark Groden. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Skyryse</p></div></p>
<p>“The reality is that the FAA minimums for getting a pilot’s license are not sufficient to be safe and effective; our goal is to make that so,” he said. “On average people estimate it takes 50 hours of driving experience to get your license. In contrast the FAA only requires 40 hours to become a private pilot.”</p>
<p>It’s important to note that the 40-hour requirement is not for all types of aircraft operations; for example, to fly a commercial carrier a pilot needs 1,500 hours of total flight time. But with Skyryse’s system, a less-experienced pilot could potentially take on new types of aircraft without lengthy additional training hours.</p>
<p>Skyryse currently has partnerships with five fixed-wing and rotorcraft equipment manufacturers, including Robinsons Helicopters. Before FlightOS will start appearing in an eVTOL or helicopter, it first must be certified by the FAA. Integrating into existing aircraft will likely shorten the process, as the company won’t need to certify an entirely new vehicle (what eVTOL developers must do, for example).</p>
<p>The startup says that its tech could even help with the global pilot shortage, a situation that may only become exacerbated if air taxis become operational this decade.</p>
<p>The fresh funding brings the startup’s total raised to $250 million. This recent round was led by Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company and Monashee Investment Management, with additional participation from ArrowMark Partners, Republic Capital, Raptor Group, Infinite Capital, Embedded Ventures, Fortistar, K3 Ventures, Rosecliff, SV Pacific Ventures, Laurence Tosi, and Dmitry Balyasny. Prior investors Venrock, Eclipse Ventures, and Fontinalis Partners also participated.</p>
<p><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xJOe7J_Auuk" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/skyryse-brings-in-200m-to-make-flying-an-aircraft-as-simple-as-swiping-a-touchscreen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224558</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Extend raises $40M for its virtual card offering to help banks better compete with fintechs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/extend-raises-40m-for-its-virtual-card-offering2224564/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/extend-raises-40m-for-its-virtual-card-offering2224564/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[march capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’ve written a lot about fintechs that aim to help other fintechs and traditional banks launch products and services.  But it feels like we have written far less about fintechs that exist solely to help the incumbents better compete with fintechs. Extend is one such company. The New York-based startup, which provides digital payment infrastructure [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve written a lot about fintechs that aim to help other fintechs and traditional banks launch products and services. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But it feels like we have written far less about fintechs that exist solely to help the incumbents better compete with fintechs.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://paywithextend.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extend</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is one such company. The New York-based startup, which provides digital payment infrastructure for financial institutions so they can offer virtual cards to their users, has raised $40 million in a Series B funding round led by March Capital.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224564" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other investors include B Capital, Point72 Ventures, Fintech Collective, Reciprocal Ventures, Wells Fargo and Pacific Western Bank. The latest financing brings Extend’s total raised since its 2017 inception to $55 million.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extend has integrated directly with major networks and processors — including Global Payments/TSYS, Mastercard and Visa — with the intent of building technology that supports virtual cards on top of the infrastructure banks are built upon. This means that card issuers can combine Extend’s offering with their current products, with “no technical implementation required,” according to the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So far, Extend has more than 2,000 business customers currently using its applications, is growing 30% month-over-month and has a run rate of &#8220;close to $2 billion dollars” in processing volume, or the spend clients are making on its virtual cards, according to the company. It makes basis points on the transactions made on those cards.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last month, Extend </span><a href="https://about.americanexpress.com/all-news/news-details/2021/American-Express-and-Extend-Partner-to-Enable-Virtual-Cards-for-U.S.-Small-and-Mid-Sized-Businesses/default.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">inked a deal with American Express</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> which allows its millions of small and mid-sized business card members to access virtual cards through their existing physical cards “in minutes.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We have now exposed these digital capabilities to every existing cardholder,” said </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Andrew Jamison, CEO and co-founder of Extend. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is the first time that someone has turned virtual cards into a product in itself, rather than a feature on an existing piece of plastic.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most competitors require a customer to switch bank partners and open a new account, and existing virtual card offerings have only been accessible at an enterprise level, said Jamison.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extend, he claims, is the first company to deliver an issuer-agnostic solution for SMBs at scale with its “virtual card platform-as-a-service.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The appeal to businesses as opposed to turning to startups in the space, according to Jamison, is that they don’t have to create a new account “to get access to the digital capabilities that they’ve been wanting to get in the first place.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So in essence, we can add Extend to the growing list of companies focused on the corporate spend space, including Brex, Ramp, TripActions and others.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1axXH8PjHt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/brex-raises-300m-at-a-12-3b-valuation/">Brex just signed a term sheet for $300M at a $12.3B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Brex just signed a term sheet for $300M at a $12.3B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/brex-raises-300m-at-a-12-3b-valuation/embed/#?secret=1axXH8PjHt" data-secret="1axXH8PjHt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jamison previously worked at SAP and then American Express for a number of years, moving from London to the U.S. in 2009 to help the credit card giant incorporate new digital payment capabilities, one of which included virtual cards. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">got involved when it was half a million dollars in volume, and it doubled over the course of five years as we saw this shift to digital over the course of that period of time,” he recalled.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But it wasn’t easy. Virtual cards at the time were reserved for “only the biggest of all companies,” and the effort took engineers on both sides, Jamison said. Then, Marqeta started to power businesses directly with digital cards. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I realized then this was the better way to get cards to people, and that this was clearly to be the future of card issuance over time,” he told TechCrunch. “And that was the genesis of Extend. The company was founded based on the recognition that we could take virtual cards and use them as a stepping stone to helping with the $40 billion payment industry transformation.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the fact that legacy platforms were “incredibly robust,” Jamison knew they were not built for the digital era we find ourselves in today. So he set about creating digital assets, or a broader connectivity framework, that would allow Extend to help banks scale capabilities across their whole portfolio “and eventually all the way down to the consumer.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He emphasizes that Extend does not underwrite or process transactions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We represent a place where we&#8217;ll be able to create 21st century technology and make the traditional banks look and feel like they were actually born in the 21st century,” Jamison said. “We help the incumbents close the gap relative to those players.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extend also offers a number of API solutions for banks and third-party service providers that it says can help them create new products for customers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 42-person company has also developed a “developer-friendly” API catalog which Jamison says is giving issuers a way to offer APIs to its customers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So far, Extend has signed deals with seven traditional financial institutions, with the target of working with 20 by the end of next year. Citi National and PacWest are both customers and investors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sumant </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mandal, co-</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">founder and managing partner of March Capital, said he was impressed with Jamison’s having spent over a decade at Amex.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“He understands that enabling modern payment solutions has become a mission critical priority for banks, especially as fintechs continue to challenge banks,” Mandal wrote via email. “Customers repeatedly highlighted the frictionless and consumer-grade experience, with onboarding taking less than five minutes.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He believes the company is unique in that it has been able to upgrade bank payment infrastructure “without the need to rip and replace an entire system,” so that banks can offer the same level of products and features as fintechs in the virtual card issuing and corporate expense management space.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/extend-raises-40m-for-its-virtual-card-offering2224564/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224564</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fellow raises $24M; wants you to enjoy going to meetings again</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/fellow-raises-24m-wants-you-to-enjoy-going-to-meetings-again/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/fellow-raises-24m-wants-you-to-enjoy-going-to-meetings-again/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aydin Mirzaee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felicis Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fellow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Formentera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garage Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inovia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lainy Painter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meeting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SVB Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the last year, the company saw that list more than triple, as did the number of meetings hosted on the platform.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As more people venture back into the office, meetings have become more hybrid, with people at both home and in the office. <a href="https://fellow.app/">Fellow</a> aims to help managers have productive meetings no matter how their teams meet.</p>
<p>Fellow co-founder and CEO Aydin Mirzaee told TechCrunch that unproductive meetings — you know, the ones that really could be emails — <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/37-billion-is-lost-every-year-on-these-meeting-mistakes-2014-4">cost U.S. companies $37 billion annually</a>. Instead, he believes that productive meetings are about collaborative agendas, recording history and following a process.</p>
<p>“Before when we were all in-person, no one brought any devices into a meeting, and now every meeting is on a device, which has opened up the landscape,” he explained. “It’s crazy to think that people haven’t built software for meetings in the past, but now it makes sense to have a platform across the company to make sure all meetings are productive.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224489" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2224495" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224495" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2224495 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fellow-Founders-colour-hi-res-1.jpg?w=680" alt="Fellow. meeting" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fellow-Founders-colour-hi-res-1.jpg 8256w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fellow-Founders-colour-hi-res-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fellow-Founders-colour-hi-res-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fellow-Founders-colour-hi-res-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fellow-Founders-colour-hi-res-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fellow-Founders-colour-hi-res-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fellow-Founders-colour-hi-res-1.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fellow-Founders-colour-hi-res-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224495" class="wp-caption-text">Fellow founders, from left, Aydin Mirzaee, Samuel Cormier-Iijima, and Amin Mirzaee</p></div></p>
<p>The meeting management software company, founded in 2017, provides tools all in one place that are meant to support all kinds of meetings. Fellow’s SaaS business model includes a free plan and tiers for additional users and organizational features.</p>
<p>Some of the features include agenda templates, action item identification, analytics for insights into how often people are meeting and integrations with virtual meeting software for note-taking.</p>
<p>Fellow’s list of customers includes Shopify, Hopin and GoCardless. Over the last year, the company saw that list more than triple, as did the number of meetings hosted on the platform. In addition, over 2 million meeting agendas and notes were recorded, and the company is on track to quadruple its revenue this year, Mirzaee said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jGcpQ4ehHn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/28/3-views-on-the-future-of-meetings/">3 views on the future of meetings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 views on the future of meetings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/28/3-views-on-the-future-of-meetings/embed/#?secret=jGcpQ4ehHn" data-secret="jGcpQ4ehHn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>To continue on that trajectory, the company announced $24 million in Series A funding. Craft Ventures led the round and was joined by iNovia, Felicis, Garage Ventures, Formentera and SVB. The new funding will go toward product development, building its infrastructure and hiring in sales, marketing and customer success. It brings the company’s total funds raised to $30.5 million, according to the company.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/en/news-release/2021/08/12/2279446/0/en/Virtual-Meeting-Software-Market-to-Reach-41-58-Billion-by-2027-Availability-of-Low-cost-Cloud-Platforms-will-Emerge-in-Favor-of-Market-Growth-says-Fortune-Business-Insights.html">global virtual meeting software market</a> is forecasted to be valued at $41.6 billion by 2027. Meanwhile, the <a href="https://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/productivity-management-software-market">global productivity management software</a> market reached $43 billion in 2020 and will grow 14% annually through 2028.</p>
<p>This has startups lining up to get a piece of it, and Fellow is one of the latest on a list that attracted venture capital attention. Just in the past month this has included:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/hera-is-a-new-calendar-app-for-people-with-a-lot-of-virtual-meetings/">Hera</a>, a virtual meeting calendar</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/read-ai-raises-10m-creates-virtual-meeting-dashboard-to-show-you-when-you-talk-too-much/">Read AI</a>, a meeting dashboard to show engagement</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/virtual-meeting-platform-vowel-raises-13-5m-aims-to-cure-meeting-fatigue/">Vowel</a>, aiming to make meetings more useful before, during and after</li>
</ul>
<p>Mirzaee agrees there is competition but says there are few options that are purpose-built for meetings and Fellow’s approach is unique.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Our vision is to build a meeting productivity product aimed at helping managers have productive meetings and then manage their teams,” he added. “There are few solutions out there purpose-built for meetings.”</p>
<p>Lainy Painter, partner at Craft Ventures, also pointed out that Fellow has been able to start out with one team and rapidly expand within an organization once they see how productive they can be.</p>
<p>Painter is a user of the tool, and with remote work here to stay, the meeting is just one of the workflows that had not been optimized yet.</p>
<p>“I see Fellow dominating the meeting management category,” she added. “We are still in the early stage of shifting to how we will be working with remote work, and though we saw a lot of that move in the early months to a Zoom interface, a lot of optimization was left on the table. The future of work and meetings is adopting new tools that take advantage of being fully remote and not just taking an existing paradigm and replicating it.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="W0Bx04sZvt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/reform-your-startups-meeting-culture/">Reform your startup&#8217;s meeting culture</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Reform your startup&#8217;s meeting culture&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/reform-your-startups-meeting-culture/embed/#?secret=W0Bx04sZvt" data-secret="W0Bx04sZvt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/fellow-raises-24m-wants-you-to-enjoy-going-to-meetings-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224489</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ClickUp raises $400M at a $4B valuation to expand its all-in-one workplace productivity platform to Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/clickup-raises-400m-at-a-4b-valuation-to-expand-its-all-in-one-workplace-productivity-platform-to-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/clickup-raises-400m-at-a-4b-valuation-to-expand-its-all-in-one-workplace-productivity-platform-to-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Booking.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ClickUp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David George]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgian Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mcdonalds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meritech Capital partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[project management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san diego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zeb Evans]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Companies like Slack and Asana stormed into the world of tech to steal a march on incumbents like Microsoft in providing a new wave of point solutions to make it easier for workers respectively to chat with each other, plan projects and more. Now another startup is announcing a massive round of funding for a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Companies like Slack and Asana stormed into the world of tech to steal a march on incumbents like Microsoft in providing a new wave of point solutions to make it easier for workers respectively to chat with each other, plan projects and more. Now another startup is announcing a massive round of funding for a platform that it believes has its own unique role to play in disrupting enterprise IT: by providing a single, all-in-one solution covering various aspects of workplace productivity.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.clickup.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClickUp</a>, which provides set of tools that lets its users tackle project management, document collaboration, spreadsheets, chat, and goals from a single platform &#8212; a little like Workday but for productivity &#8212; has raised $400 million, a Series C funding that the company confirmed values it at $4 billion post-money.</p>
<p>ClickUp said that this is, to date, the single-largest Series C in the workplace productivity market (others like Slack have raised bigger single rounds&#8230; so still room to grow!). Andreessen Horowitz and Tiger Global are co-leading the round, with Lightspeed Venture Partners and Meritech Capital Partners also participating. Craft Ventures and Georgian Partners are among its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/productivity-platform-clickup-raises-35-million-from-craft-ventures/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">earlier backers</a>; the company has now raised $535 million.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224795" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>ClickUp &#8212; based out of San Diego &#8212; plans to use the funding to double down on growth in Europe, with 600 new jobs and a new HQ set for Ireland that will handle R&amp;D, operations and sales. The company counts the likes of Google (yes, the company behind its own productivity tools), McDonalds, Booking.com, and Netflix among its large enterprise customers. In all, ClickUp is being used by 800,000 teams &#8212; up from just 200,000 a year ago.</p>
<p>A significant proportion of ClickUp&#8217;s customers, some 40%, are already based outside of the U.S, with a large part of those users in Europe &#8212; some 275,000 teams in all, the company said &#8212; hence its interest in focusing more deeply in the region. It will also include localised versions of its platform for France, Germany and Spain, the company said.</p>
<p>The shift to cloud services and a rising appetite from knowledge workers to use tools in the office that work just as intuitively as their &#8220;fun&#8221; consumer mobile apps has led to a veritable revolution in the world of enterprise software.</p>
<p>Fueled by venture capital, startups have built out substantial businesses tackling different aspects of what &#8220;workplace productivity&#8221; can constitute, from tools to improve how to perform in a specific job like sales (Slack being now owned by the giant in that space, Salesforce), through to more specific workplace functionality like organising one&#8217;s calendar or meetings, writing and collaborating on documents, creating and managing a project, talking to each other about specific work tasks, and so much more. And big tech companies have not been outside of the game, either. Microsoft and the rest have all stepped up with their own takes on the same problems.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But all this has also created a new kind of productivity problem in the process. Enterprises are often now dealing with a much wider range of apps in their typical workflow. This predicament is not small: it has cost, efficiency, management, security, and attention implications in varying degrees.</p>
<p>The solution here is pretty obvious: move back to all-in-one solutions that take out some of the noise and make it easier to share and hand off work throughout the lifecycle of productivity. It&#8217;s something that Microsoft, of course, is already addressing, as are others. But in the wider scheme of things, sometimes building a new set of tools from scratch can yield a much fresher, and better result.</p>
<p>&#8220;ClickUp&#8217;s sole purpose has always been to make the world more productive. Time is our most valuable resource and we are committed to giving people more time to focus on what matters most to them,&#8221; says Zeb Evans, CEO and Founder of ClickUp, in a statement. &#8220;We believe software should make people more productive and efficient. I&#8217;m thrilled about our next chapter and accelerating the innovations that deliver on this promise to our customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Investors love almost nothing more than a fast-growing startup &#8212; and this one definitely fits the bill.</p>
<p>“ClickUp&#8217;s unique offering in the market has fueled their rise as one of the fastest-growing SaaS startups in the world. Their strong growth, product adoption, and customer retention reflect the tremendous value they&#8217;re providing to businesses looking to drive greater productivity and efficiency,” said David George, general partner at Andreessen Horowitz, in a statement. &#8220;ClickUp is synonymous with the future of work, and we&#8217;re thrilled to partner with a company that has shown such a strong commitment to its users and product. We look forward to building a more productive world together.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/clickup-raises-400m-at-a-4b-valuation-to-expand-its-all-in-one-workplace-productivity-platform-to-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224795</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gluware raises $43M for &#8216;RPA&#8217; tech that automatically detects and fixes anomalies in network configurations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/gluware-raises-43m-for-rpa-tech-that-automatically-detects-and-fixes-anomalies-in-network-configurations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/gluware-raises-43m-for-rpa-tech-that-automatically-detects-and-fixes-anomalies-in-network-configurations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 11:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acadia Woods Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bain Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cisco systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep packet inspection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gluware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacramento]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook&#8217;s network meltdown earlier this month &#8212; an outage that initially stemmed from a configuration error &#8212; was a huge pain for many users (and a big cost to Facebook). For enterprises, it also served as a poignant reminder about a salient fact of networks: The complexity and interdependency of systems today mean that when something [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook&#8217;s network meltdown earlier this month &#8212; an outage that initially <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-whatsapp-instagram-return/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stemmed from a configuration error</a> &#8212; was a huge pain for many users (and a big cost to Facebook). For enterprises, it also served as a poignant reminder about a salient fact of networks: The complexity and interdependency of systems today mean that when something doesn&#8217;t work between two entities &#8212; be it apps, servers or something else &#8212; the effects can be disastrous, unless those overlaps can be detected and mitigated ahead of a live deployment, or found and fixed quickly even if they are already out in the wild.</p>
<p>Today, a startup called <a href="https://gluware.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gluware</a> that has built a platform that aims to do just that &#8212; specifically by providing network orchestration and automation tools that identify and automatically fix when something is about to go awry on a network, described by the CEO to me as &#8220;RPA&#8221; for network ops &#8212; is announcing $43 million in funding to continue building out its business, in a growth round led by Bain Capital with participation from Acadia Woods Partners and other unnamed existing investors.</p>
<p>Gluware is not disclosing its valuation but from what we understand it is around $700 million, notable considering how little it&#8217;s raised to date (just under $47 million in the last 10 years, according to <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/51648-22/company/profile#deal-history" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PitchBook</a> data, and bootstrapped before that). It&#8217;s also notable for being based in California but <em>not</em> the Bay Area: it&#8217;s HQ is in Sacramento, <a href="https://bigtechnology.substack.com/p/where-tech-workers-are-moving-new" target="_blank" rel="noopener">apparently a newly-emerging location</a> for people leaving more established tech enclaves.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224725" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In a period where a number of enterprises have put the gas on network growth and operations to handle both increased traffic but also new working architectures for its people, Gluware said its ARR growth in the last year has been 400% (it does not disclose actual figures).</p>
<p>Gluware got its start originally as a Cisco shop, inking a strategic deal with the company early on to build orchestration and automation systems that ran specifically on its servers, specifically a software-defined wide-area network controller to work with Cisco kit. As networks evolved and became continually more complex, the opportunity changed and became about working in multi-vendor networks and for a variety of different enterprises that might not be the typical Cisco service provider customers. Its services now integrate, by way of APIs, to cover network operations across <a href="https://gluware.com/platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">more than 30</a> different platforms and operating systems. Gluware&#8217;s CEO and co-founder Jeff Gray estimates that Gluware&#8217;s coverage currently points to a $10.8 billion addressable market.</p>
<p>Currently, and in keeping with changing use cases and architectures, Gluware&#8217;s sweet spot up to now has been working with larger enterprises in highly regulated sectors like healthcare or finance that are heavily dependent on cloud or hybrid network architectures that bring in many disparate operations, may lack large enough in-house teams to build and operate their own automation and orchestration solutions, but have a lot of requirements to stay operational and protect user data in the process. The list is heavy of Fortune 500 and Global 2000 names, with Mastercard, EY and Merck among them.</p>
<p>Large tech companies &#8212; web scalers, as Gray described them &#8212; were out of Gluware&#8217;s sights simply because they typically build and operate those tools in-house, and the idea was that Gluware was building tools for the rest of the market that performed just as well. However, as Gray put it, incidents like Facebook&#8217;s definitely change the game.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p1">&#8220;We haven’t been targeting the web scalers, and we presented ourselves as an alternative to DIY. Traditionally I have always said that if you are a Google, a FB or a Goldman Sachs, you could pour a tremendous amount of resource into scripts and build you own automation software,&#8221; he said. &#8220;But Facebook&#8217;s audit tool issued a r<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ogue command and broke its network, at scale. So  even the large web scalers of the world are not immune. I</span> think we could be a great fit.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s focus on network operations has a natural synergy with security operations, since many, but not all, outages covering, say, border gate protocol or domain name server errors have been linked also to data breaches, and that lays the groundwork for how Gluware sees its role in the network operations IT stack. Its tools can be applied to device management, operating system management, configuration modeling, workflows and more to minimize downtime, speed up operations, to meet compliance requirements, and more.</p>
<p>That long list, and Gluware&#8217;s traction to date in meeting its demands, are what have attracted investors. “As enterprises continue to struggle with network automation progress, Gluware’s unique platform delivers enhanced network security and agility while creating real business value and outcomes for customers,” said Olof Bergqvist, a Managing Director at Bain Capital, in a statement. “We are excited to support Gluware’s next phase of growth and accelerate the company’s innovative technology and mission-critical solutions to continue meeting the modern needs of enterprises while strengthening its value-proposition to its customers, suppliers and partners.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/gluware-raises-43m-for-rpa-tech-that-automatically-detects-and-fixes-anomalies-in-network-configurations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224725</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Africa&#8217;s RecoMed raises $1.5M to scale its online healthcare marketplace</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/south-africas-recomed-raises-1-5m-to-scale-its-online-healthcare-marketplace/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/south-africas-recomed-raises-1-5m-to-scale-its-online-healthcare-marketplace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 11:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-pharmacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HealthTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telehealth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South African online healthcare marketplace RecoMed has raised a $1.5 million financing round, the company confirmed to TechCrunch. The round was led by South Africa-focused venture capital firm Vunani Fintech Fund. RecoMed says the firm invested $1 million; the rest shared between existing investors Japanese but Africa-focused VC firm AAIC, Growth Grid Venture Capital Partners [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">South African online healthcare marketplace <a href="https://www.recomed.co.za/">RecoMed</a> has raised a $1.5 million financing round, the company confirmed to TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The round </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was led by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> South Africa-focused venture capital firm Vunani Fintech Fund. RecoMed says the firm invested $1 million; the rest </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">shared</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> between existing investors Japanese but Africa-focused VC firm AAIC, Growth Grid Venture Capital Partners and Kenyan-based Push Ventures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was founded by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://za.linkedin.com/in/sheraanamod"> Sheraan Amod</a>, who, after a brief stay in the U.S. launching his first tech company, experienced for the first time what it was like to book medical appointments online, which wasn’t the case back in his home country South Africa.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224745" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amod felt an opportunity to fill this need and returned to South Africa to build RecoMed &#8212; the company he refers to as the “booking.com for healthcare.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RecoMed acts as a marketplace where patients can find and book services with healthcare professionals across South Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Patients can search through and browse practitioner profiles, check reviews and then book a physical or virtual telehealth appointment from the website or app.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the company, healthcare practitioners, enterprises, and insurers use the platform </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">differently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Practitioners adopt RecoMed’s platform as a standalone platform or via an integration with their external Practice Management System (PNS), a software program used to operate medical and healthcare practices.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For enterprises, RecoMed is white-labeled to allow booking and telehealth functionality for patient customer groups.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Health insurers such as Discovery have adopted RecoMed to power digital healthcare bookings into doctors, clinics and other health professionals for their members, the company said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RecoMed’s platform helps improve access and healthcare delivery for patients by cutting down the time it would typically take to book the service they need.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RecoMed’s business model is to earn a transactional “per booking” fee from healthcare providers for all bookings generated via the platform. The aggregated marketplace increases patient booking flow to RecoMed’s health provider customers.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2224779" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224779" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2224779" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/PhotoPictureResizer_211027_111427869_crop_3456x2464.jpg?w=680" alt="RecoMed" width="680" height="485" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/PhotoPictureResizer_211027_111427869_crop_3456x2464.jpg 3456w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/PhotoPictureResizer_211027_111427869_crop_3456x2464.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/PhotoPictureResizer_211027_111427869_crop_3456x2464.jpg?resize=300,214 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/PhotoPictureResizer_211027_111427869_crop_3456x2464.jpg?resize=768,548 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/PhotoPictureResizer_211027_111427869_crop_3456x2464.jpg?resize=680,485 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/PhotoPictureResizer_211027_111427869_crop_3456x2464.jpg?resize=1536,1095 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/PhotoPictureResizer_211027_111427869_crop_3456x2464.jpg?resize=2048,1460 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/PhotoPictureResizer_211027_111427869_crop_3456x2464.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224779" class="wp-caption-text">Sheraan Amod (CEO, RecoMed)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RecoMed, launched in 2013, has not raised more than $3 million but claims to be the largest and fastest-growing healthcare booking in South Africa. The startup says it powers over 200,000 bookings per month, which has grown 700% in 18 months.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform is one of the earliest adopters of telehealth in Africa, launching years before the advent of the COVID-19 pandemic when the need for such platforms became more evident.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although RecoMed did not raise the kind of eye-popping investments seen from its counterparts in other parts of the world, the company has benefited business-wise, positioning itself in assisting large corporates in conducting vaccinations across South Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of these companies include Discovery Health and Mediclinic. They have conducted over 550,000 bookings via RecoMed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> since last year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are facilitating over R250m [$16m] of healthcare spend </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">annually</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Whether a patient is looking for a convenient doctor appointment or the COVID-19 vaccine jab, we make it simple and easy to do,” Amod said in a statement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic also resulted in a net uplift for the usage of RecoMed, the CEO said. The company’s revenue has more than doubled since March this year, he adds.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Per other metrics, over 2,500 contracted health providers on RecoMed and more than 1 million customers use the platform annually</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RecoMed plans to use this funding to add new integrated products to its platform in 2022. Some include integrated online medical payments and e-pharmacy for delivering prescription medication to consumers across the country.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to new product releases, RecoMed is also targeting further geographic expansion, with the company launching in Kenya in January 2022.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Healthtech faces unique challenges around infrastructure in Africa. The market forces and the patchwork of systems used in healthcare </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">locally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have made it essential to devise local healthcare technology solutions to African problems.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amod believes the go-to-market approach for broad-based solutions in health-tech should involve a solid B2B2C element, using key partnerships with insurers, banks and telecommunication companies to reach a mass consumer audience &#8212; </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">essentially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> what RecoMed is executing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The future of health innovation is an exciting space for Africa as we continue to offer the global market a scalable solution at low cost-and where necessary with low bandwidth, which has never </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been done</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> anywhere else in the world,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lead investor Vunani Fintech Fund, optimistic about RecoMed’s proposed approach to meet identified market needs in South Africa, said via its director Mark Anderson, “We are still in the early days of leveraging technology as a utility in healthcare, so the potential here is massive. We are confident that this latest round of fundraising will make a major contribution towards promoting greater efficiencies in the health ecosystem that will benefit all stakeholders.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RNYcIXLjj2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/south-africas-quro-medical-comes-out-of-stealth-with-1-1m-to-expand-its-hospital-at-home-service/">South Africa&#8217;s Quro Medical comes out of stealth with $1.1M to expand its hospital-at-home service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;South Africa&#8217;s Quro Medical comes out of stealth with $1.1M to expand its hospital-at-home service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/south-africas-quro-medical-comes-out-of-stealth-with-1-1m-to-expand-its-hospital-at-home-service/embed/#?secret=RNYcIXLjj2" data-secret="RNYcIXLjj2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/south-africas-recomed-raises-1-5m-to-scale-its-online-healthcare-marketplace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224745</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goodyear Ventures, Porsche Ventures invest in virtual sensing company Tactile Mobility</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/goodyear-ventures-porsche-ventures-invest-in-virtual-sensing-company-tactile-mobility/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/goodyear-ventures-porsche-ventures-invest-in-virtual-sensing-company-tactile-mobility/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BMW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delek Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goodyear Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[porsche ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tactile mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tactile sensing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224628</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Israeli startup Tactile Mobility uses existing vehicle sensor data to enable cars to “feel” the road in a way that generates insights about both the vehicle and the road via its cloud platform. On Wednesday, Tactile announced a $27 million Series C raise which it will use to further develop its virtual sensors, expand its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Israeli startup <a href="https://tactilemobility.com/">Tactile Mobility</a> uses existing vehicle sensor data to enable cars to “feel” the road in a way that generates insights about both the vehicle and the road via its cloud platform. On Wednesday, Tactile announced a $27 million Series C raise which it will use to further develop its virtual sensors, expand its product offerings and bolster its cloud platform &#8212; all of which will require up to 20 new hires in R&amp;D this year, according to Shahar Bin-Nun, CEO of Tactile Mobility. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The funding round, which brings Tactile’s total funding to $47 million, was led by Delek Motors, with strategic investment from Goodyear Ventures and Porsche Ventures and support from Union Group, The Group Ventures, Zvi Neta (AEV), Giora Ackerstein and Doron Livnat.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our company is basically divided into two parts &#8212; the data acquisition and the data monetization,” Bin-Nun told TechCrunch. “We do data acquisition with a very unique piece of software that we call the Tactile Processor (TP), which is installed in the engine control unit of the chassis. With the TP, we are able to create numerous non-visual virtual sensors for the OEM that mostly improve safety, performance and enjoyability of the driving.”</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224628" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second part of Tactile’s business model revolves around its cloud platform, called Tactile Cloud (TC), which is where data from the virtual sensors are uploaded in order to create tactility maps that describe either vehicle DNA or road surface DNA. Those maps can then be sold to OEMs, transport authorities, municipalities, insurance companies, tire companies, Tier 1s and others. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Out of the 23 virtual sensors Bin-Nun says Tactile engages in vehicles, the major one the company has worked on is its tire grip estimation with BMW, which measures the grip between the car and the road while a car is cruising. Tactile’s TP is in 2.5 million BMW vehicles annually, according to the CEO, which means millions of vehicles are passively mapping road surfaces for the company. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mapping the roads by measuring tire grip enables Tactile to map things like potholes, cracks in the road, slipperiness, snowfall and more. The insights can be gathered in real time and downloaded to other vehicles roaming in a specific area, which might give drivers a heads-up to poor road conditions and improve safety. Analytics can also be shared via a report for third parties like mapping companies, road authorities or fleet managers to identify areas of distress on the road. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tactile has a revenue share model with the OEMs it works with so that it is able to monetize whatever data it collects in its cloud. Bin-Nun says the startup has done more than 30 proof of concepts and pilots with seven OEMs, but it has only reached production-level capabilities with BMW. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Up until now, we’ve been a company of 25; now we are 40 employees, so we were a bit limited in our ability to expand,” said Bin-Nun. “You can imagine that as a small company running a project for BMW, we were completely busy with the implementation and integration with BMW and all the tests we had to do to be compliant with their requests, so we want to now be able to work in parallel with many OEMs.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That means also developing its other sensors so the company can offer more services and insights to customers. For example, some OEMs are interested in tire health. Tactile says it can measure the tread depth of the tire extremely accurately while driving, which can tell OEMs if the tire needs to be replaced or how a driver should drive given the type of tire and the terrain. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Another important one and the reason Goodyear invested in the company is that we can accurately measure if the tire is too stiff or not,” said Bin-Nun. “They did a test with us just after they invested in this round. So the tire health family of virtual sensors is definitely an important type of virtual sensors that we develop. Other OEMs ask for things like weight estimation and center of gravity, things that our virtual sensors pick up on and we use machine learning and signal processing to clean up a lot of noise.”</span></p>
<p>Other sensors include weight estimation, aquaplaning, vehicle health sensors and micro collisions. With the Series C funding, Tactile hopes to be able to build out these sensors so it can be more appealing to OEMs. The startup&#8217;s goal is to be inside every major OEM, which will give it massive scores of data to collect, analyze and monetize, which will help it develop in tandem with burgeoning tech, like autonomous vehicles.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Connected and autonomous driving are key to the future of people and goods movement,&#8221; said Abhijit Ganguly, managing director, Goodyear Ventures, in a statement. &#8220;For improved safety and efficiency of connected and autonomous driving, tire data is key.” </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/goodyear-ventures-porsche-ventures-invest-in-virtual-sensing-company-tactile-mobility/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224628</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>QOA brings in seed round to do for chocolate what Oatly did for milk</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/qoa-brings-in-seed-round-to-do-for-chocolate-what-oatly-did-for-milk/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/qoa-brings-in-seed-round-to-do-for-chocolate-what-oatly-did-for-milk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 10:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[candy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cherry Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food supply]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maximilian Marquart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[munich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pioneer Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[QOA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sara Marquart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[switzerland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Its proprietary fermentation process will enable QOA to scale production by 2035 and be able to price its "chocolate" products the same or below the cost of traditional chocolate.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Munich-based QOA is gearing up to be among the first to bring a chocolate product to market that is 100% cocoa free.</p>
<p>It is also now backed by $6 million in seed funding in an investment round led by Cherry Ventures with participation by Fifty Years, World Fund, Nucleus Capital, Trellis Road, Pioneer Fund and Tet Ventures.</p>
<p>The company kicked off this year, founded by the sister-and-brother team of Drs. Sara and Maximilian Marquart. Sara Marquart is a food chemist with a specialty in flavor formation, while Max Marquart is a material scientist and now three-time entrepreneur.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224542" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2224575" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224575" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2224575 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg?w=680" alt="QOA, chocolate" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/QOA-Supermassive-Testkit-open-1024x1024-1.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224575" class="wp-caption-text">QOA&#8217;s product test kit</p></div></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.statista.com/topics/1638/chocolate-industry/">global chocolate confectionery industry</a> was valued at over $208 billion in 2020, and is the <a href="https://www.franchisehelp.com/industry-reports/chocolate-industry-analysis-2020-cost-trends/">largest part of the industry in the U.S</a>. Two-thirds of the world’s cocoa supply comes from West Africa, but is at risk — one of the reasons the Marquarts decided to focus on it. Currently, up to 50% of the current <a href="https://www.rainforest-alliance.org/in-the-field/global-climate-related-risks-in-cocoa-website-project/#:~:text=Global%20climate%20change%20already%20negatively,diseases%2C%20and%20more%20erratic%20rainfall.">cocoa supply is at risk</a> due to pathogens and climate change, and cocoa is playing a role in both <a href="https://engagethechain.org/cocoa">deforestation</a> and <a href="https://www.globalslaveryindex.org/2018/findings/importing-risk/cocoa/">forced child labor</a>.</p>
<p>“Our food supply is threatened due to the way we eat,” Max Marquart told TechCrunch. “We love chocolate, however, we realized that there are some sustainability risks and wanted to do something about it so we can still have it in the future.”</p>
<p>Companies, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/from-improving-cancer-treatments-to-saving-the-bees-these-are-the-companies-in-indiebios-latest-class/">California Cultured</a> and <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/disruptive-new-company-voyage-foods-tackles-the-worlds-biggest-issues-in-food-commoditization-301367787.html">Voyager Foods</a>, are also creating chocolate without the cocoa using different approaches. Meanwhile, QOA developed a fermentation process that uses natural byproducts from other food-making processes for its base material. It then uses proprietary microbactera and flavor formation to create a vegan product that mimics the texture and flavor of chocolate, but without any artificial additives, he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The fermentation process will enable the company to scale production by 2035 and be able to price its products the same or below the cost of traditional chocolate. In fact, Marquart is predicting that in the future, the chocolate market will have two pillars: one half that is exclusive, expensive products made with normal cocoa, and the other QOA products.</p>
<p>QOA was part of Y Combinator this year and was able to get its product test kit going so people can sample nine options. Marquart expects to have QOA’s first product on the market in 2022, and the new funding will go toward building out its first pilot production facility in Munich to complement one it has in Switzerland and hiring.</p>
<p>The company is in talks with its first business-to-business customers and expects to close some smaller contracts soon, Marquart  said.</p>
<p>“After that, we will go after our Series A so we can build out larger production lines,” he added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5r7UMIuq7G"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/iot-and-data-science-will-boost-foodtech-in-the-post-pandemic-era/">IoT and data science will boost foodtech in the post-pandemic era</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;IoT and data science will boost foodtech in the post-pandemic era&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/iot-and-data-science-will-boost-foodtech-in-the-post-pandemic-era/embed/#?secret=5r7UMIuq7G" data-secret="5r7UMIuq7G" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/qoa-brings-in-seed-round-to-do-for-chocolate-what-oatly-did-for-milk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224542</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
