<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 23:30:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Singapore-based Volopay raises $2.1 million seed round to build a &#8220;financial control center&#8221; for businesses</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/singapore-based-volopay-raises-2-1-million-seed-round-to-build-a-financial-control-center-for-businesses/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/singapore-based-volopay-raises-2-1-million-seed-round-to-build-a-financial-control-center-for-businesses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 22:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justin Mateen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rajesh Raikwar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rajith Shaiji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volopay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Volopay, a Singapore-based startup building a &#8220;financial control center&#8221; for businesses, announced today it has raised $2.1 million in seed funding. The round was led by Tinder co-founder Justin Mateen, and included participation from Soma Capital, CP Ventures, Y Combinator, VentureSouq, the founders of Razorpay and other angel investors. The funding will be used on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.volopay.co/">Volopay</a>, a Singapore-based startup building a &#8220;financial control center&#8221; for businesses, announced today it has raised $2.1 million in seed funding. The round was led by Tinder co-founder Justin Mateen, and included participation from Soma Capital, CP Ventures, Y Combinator, VentureSouq, the founders of Razorpay and other angel investors.</p>
<p>The funding will be used on hiring, product development, strategic partnerships and Volopay’s international expansion. It plans to launch operations in Australia later this month. The company currently has about 100 clients, including Smart Karma, Dathena, Medline, Sensorflow and Beam.</p>
<p>Launched in 2019 by Rajith Shaiji and Rajesh Raikwar, Volopay took part in Y Combinator’s accelerator program last year. It was created after chief executive officer Shaji, who worked for several fintech companies before launching Volopay, became frustrated by the process of reconciling business expenses, especially with accounting departments located in different countries. Shaiji and Raikwar also saw that many companies, especially startups and SMEs, struggled to track different kinds of spending, including subscriptions and vendor payments.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6uxlaBLWbF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/singapore-based-volopay-wants-to-be-the-brex-of-southeast-asia/">Singapore-based Volopay wants to be the &#8216;Brex of Southeast Asia&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Singapore-based Volopay wants to be the &#8216;Brex of Southeast Asia&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/singapore-based-volopay-wants-to-be-the-brex-of-southeast-asia/embed/#?secret=6uxlaBLWbF" data-secret="6uxlaBLWbF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Most of Volopay’s clients are in the tech sector and have about 15 to 150 employees. Volopay’s platform integrates multicurrency corporate cards (issued by Visa Corporate), domestic and international bank transfers, automated payments and expense and accounting software, allowing companies to save money on foreign exchange fees and reconcile expenses more quickly.</p>
<p>In order to speed up its development, Volopay integrated Airwallex’s APIs. Its corporate cards offer up to 2% cash back on software subscriptions, hosting and international travel, which Volopay says are the three top expense categories for tech companies, and it in November 2020, it launched a credit facility for corporate cards to help give SMEs more liquidity during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Compared to traditional credit products, like credit cards and working capital loans, Shaji said Volopay’s credit facility, which is also issued by Visa Corporate, has a more competitive fixed-free pricing structure that depends on the level of credit used. This means companies know how much they owe in advance, which in turn helps them manage their cashflows more easily. The average credit line provided by Volopay is about $30,000.</p>
<p>Since TechCrunch last covered Volopay in July 2020, it has grown 70% month on month in terms of total funds flowing through its platform, Shaji said. It also launched two new features: A bill pay feature that allows clients to transfer money domestically and internationally with low foreign exchange rates and transaction fees, and the credit facility. The bill pay feature now contributes about 40% to Volopay’s total payment volume, while the credit product makes up 30% of its card spending.</p>
<p>Shaji told TechCrunch that Volopay decided to expand into Australia because because not only is it a much larger market than Singapore, but “SMEs in Australia are very comfortable using paid digital software to streamline internal operations and scale their businesses.” He added that there is currently no other provider in Australia that offers both expense management and credit to SMEs like Volopay.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aIBxlwoVAY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/04/heres-why-so-many-fintech-startups-are-loaning-to-small-businesses/">Here&#8217;s why so many fintech startups are loaning to small businesses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Here&#8217;s why so many fintech startups are loaning to small businesses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/04/heres-why-so-many-fintech-startups-are-loaning-to-small-businesses/embed/#?secret=aIBxlwoVAY" data-secret="aIBxlwoVAY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/singapore-based-volopay-raises-2-1-million-seed-round-to-build-a-financial-control-center-for-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097607</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: Twitter+</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/gillmor-gang-twitter/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/gillmor-gang-twitter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097780</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The best thing about 2020 is we survived it. No need to say what the worst thing is, it’s hands down our collective stupidity in the choices we’ve made. That reality has forced us to refactor what we do moving forward. If we had correctly understood the massive changes ahead, we would not be wondering [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/K3zSbb1Sxe0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>The best thing about 2020 is we survived it. No need to say what the worst thing is, it’s hands down our collective stupidity in the choices we’ve made. That reality has forced us to refactor what we do moving forward.</p>
<p>If we had correctly understood the massive changes ahead, we would not be wondering when we will return to the old, new or any normal. The normal is what got us here. Unlimited air travel, freedom to do whatever we wanted without regard to the impact it would have on anybody else. Nationalism. What the hell is that all about? Keeping us in, everybody else out.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Take Twitter for one. When it first emerged, it felt like a pipe dream realized. For me, it still feels that way. Good people like it, so do bad people. Bad as in they use the global network to inflict damage on their political enemies. Does that mean the phone is a bad thing, too? Or cars, or popcorn butter? What about dramas? They’re sad, reward winners and losers? Do I wish Hollywood was only allowed to make rom-coms? Well, yes I do.</p>
<p>But only if it doesn’t abridge my rights, my freedom to pursue happiness. So when I see Twitter turn into a cesspool, I look for someone to blame. Let’s start with the bad guys. But what if they have a point about something? Their motives may be suspect, or just plain evil. What am I doing reading them anyway. It’s not like I chose them to follow. Well, apparently I did, by listening to people who retweet what these folks spew.</p>
<p>Retweets are another one of these things I love about Twitter. Let’s say I follow someone whose perspective I admire, and they in turn retweet others who they admire. A social cloud forms with interesting characteristics. Implicitly, the pattern of retweets, @mentions and likes can be plugged into readers or aggregators to reflect trends, emerging news, business analytics, and social dynamics of power, ethics, humor and stature.</p>
<p>So it’s not like a follow of the bad actors, but it is like I follow their relative position in the stream of those I follow. I can and do rationalize this monitoring of other than the chosen social group as a necessary early warning system for trouble ahead. These signals can be used prophylactically to measure how our message is carrying, but a typical impact is to pigeonhole our views as fodder for those who wish us ill.</p>
<p>Net net, this countervailing energy reduces the sense of fun I have with the global network. If I had to choose no Twitter over this problem, I still choose Twitter. In the early days of social media, I had a front row seat in observing how these little signals could have a surprising impact on the concerns of the day, on the projection of ideas around the network to and with others who together built support, and sometimes, business through the collective group mind.</p>
<p>Has this been lost in the partisan nature of our daily political noise? Of course, just try saying anything about anything and watch the nasty trolls rev up their schtick. Not fun. Also not effective, because the pushback creates a new rhythm of Pee Wee Herman yeah-but-what-am-I dynamics. What to do? How about a @botmention that argues with tagged trolls but silently removes the noise from the feeds of those who @like the @bot tag.</p>
<p>Implementing this semi-public stream is already doable inside a private network, with the “cost” of joining the agreement to provide access to an internal view that makes the stream less noisy and more responsive. We’ve been experimenting with just such a private/public backchannel to support production of the Gillmor Gang, but I’m not here to promote that. More usefully, the network functions efficiently in concert with Twitter.</p>
<p>The events of 2020, and the years leading up to the election and pandemic breakout, make clear that the kind of social media spread we have seen has consequences we should have countered but in fact exacerbated. Yet even in the volatile wind down of the election are some signs of a rebound from playing the chaos card. Whatever you think of Twitter’s history of or lack of backbone development, Jack Dorsey’s red line in the sand was a much needed call to arms against Trump’s bullying.</p>
<p>Even if the actual technology was limited in effect, the application of any pushback at all was a signal of what the world might look like if the election went the other way. The first amplification of that subtle shift came from social media’s biggest customer, mainstream media: pointed pushback in White House press conferences, silent movie montages of Republican senators refusing to answer shouted hallway questions, networks cutting away from events when the falsehood level reached fake mass.</p>
<p>Mitch McConnell’s move to tie additional stimulus help to Trump’s attempt to punish Twitter by repealing Section 230 protection proved effective in running out the clock. It also moved the ball from Trump’s control to the hard numbers of January 20. The Georgia runoff on January 5, followed the next day by the attempt to challenge the electoral college Biden win and the storming of the Capitol, changed everything. Twitter became Trump’s last super power. Note: This edition of the Gang was recorded minutes before Twitter permanently suspended the @realDonaldTrump account.</p>
<p>Well, there is Zoom too. Its swappable background feature lets the ex-resident broadcast to the faithful as though nothing has changed. That’s why he came back from vacation early, to pre-pardon his production staff and hire a shadow cabinet. Secretary of Streaming, Chief Acting Legal Officer, Secretary of Horror Stephen Miller, Secretary of Bacteria Giuliani.</p>
<p>Zoom lets you do this behind a subscription paywall, but now Trump+ is competing against Disney+, Netflix, Apple+ and the bundles designed to lock-in the market until the vaccines take root. Or how about an ACA+ bundle that gives you preexisting coverage, the latest iPhone and any three + networks on a rotating basis to encourage competition for stream retention.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>from the <a href="https://gillmorgang.substack.com"> Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, January 8, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><a href="https://gillmorgang.substack.com">Subscribe to the Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/gillmor-gang-twitter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097780</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cryptocat author gets insanely fast backing to build P2P tech for social media</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/cryptocat-author-gets-insanely-fast-backing-to-build-p2p-tech-for-social-media/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/cryptocat-author-gets-insanely-fast-backing-to-build-p2p-tech-for-social-media/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capsule]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free Speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nadim Kobeissi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[p2p]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The idea for Capsule started with a tweet about reinventing social media. A day later cryptography researcher, Nadim Kobeissi &#8212; best known for authoring the open-source E2E-encrypted desktop chat app Cryptocat (now discontinued) &#8212; had pulled in a pre-seed investment of $100,000 for his lightweight mesh-networked microservices concept, with support coming from angel investor and former [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The idea for <a href="https://capsule.social">Capsule</a> started with a tweet about reinventing social media.</p>
<p>A day later cryptography researcher, Nadim Kobeissi &#8212; best known for authoring the open-source E2E-encrypted desktop chat app Cryptocat (now discontinued) &#8212; had pulled in a pre-seed investment of $100,000 for his lightweight mesh-networked microservices concept, with support coming from angel investor and<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/03/coinbase-cto-balaji-srinivasan/">former Coinbase CTO</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> Balaji Srinivasan, William J. Pulte and <a href="https://wamdacapital.com">Wamda Capital</a>.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I&#39;m designing a decentralized social media solution where each user hosts their own microservice. These then connect to one another in a mesh, allowing following and sharing posts. It will be lightweight, user friendly and secure.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Are you interested in funding its development?</p>
<p>&mdash; Nadim Kobeissi (@kaepora) <a href="https://twitter.com/kaepora/status/1348216053030133762?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 10, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The nascent startup has a post-money valuation on paper of $10 million, according to Kobeissi, who is working on the prototype &#8212; hoping to launch an MVP of Capsule in March (as a web app), after which he intends to raise a seed round (targeting $1 million-$1.5 million) to build out a team and start developing mobile apps.</p>
<p>For now there&#8217;s nothing to see beyond Capsule&#8217;s <a href="https://capsule.social">landing page</a> and a pitch deck (which he shared with TechCrunch for review). But Kobeissi says he was startled by the level of interest in the concept.</p>
<p>&#8220;I posted that tweet and the expectation that I had was that basically 60 people max would retweet it and then maybe I&#8217;ll set up a Kickstarter,&#8221; he tells us. Instead the tweet &#8220;just completely exploded&#8221; and he found himself raising $100,000 &#8220;in a single day&#8221; &#8212; with $50,000 paid in there and then.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m not a startup guy. I&#8217;ve been running a business based on consulting and based on academic R&amp;D services,&#8221; he continues. &#8220;But by the end of the day &#8212; last Sunday, eight days ago &#8212; I was running a Delaware corporation valued at $10 million with $100,000 in pre-seed funding, which is insane. Completely insane.&#8221;</p>
<p>Capsule is just the latest contender for retooling Internet power structures by building infrastructure that radically decentralizes social platforms to make speech<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> more resilient to corporate censorship and control.</span></p>
<p>The list of decentralized/P2P/federated protocols and standards already out there is very long &#8212; even while usage remains low. Extant examples include ActivityPub, Diaspora, Mastodon, P2P Matrix, Scuttlebutt, Solid and Urbit, to name a few.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Interest in the space </span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">has been rekindled in recent weeks after mainstream platforms like Facebook and Twitter took decisions to shut down U.S. President Donald Trump&#8217;s access to their megaphones &#8212; a demonstration of private power that other political leaders have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/europe-seizes-on-social-medias-purging-of-trump-to-bang-the-drum-for-regulation/">described as problematic</a>. </span></p>
<p>Kobeissi also takes that view, while adding the caveat that he&#8217;s not &#8220;personally&#8221; concerned about Trump&#8217;s deplatforming. But he says he is concerned about giant private corporations having unilateral power to shape internet speech &#8212; whether takedown decisions are being made by Twitter&#8217;s trust and safety lead or Amazon Web Services (which recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/parler-is-officially-offline-after-aws-suspension/">yanked the plug on right-wing social network Parler</a> for failing to moderate violent views).</p>
<p>He also points to a <a href="https://coalitionsw.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/001_Complaint-and-Exhibits.pdf">lawsuit</a> that&#8217;s been filed in U.S. court seeking damages and injunctive relief from Apple for allowing Telegram, a messaging platform with 500 million+ users, to be made available through its iOS App Store &#8212; &#8220;despite Apple&#8217;s knowledge that Telegram is being used to intimidate, threaten and coerce members of the public&#8221; &#8212; raising concerns about &#8220;the odds of these efforts catching on.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;That is kind of terrifying,&#8221; he suggests.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YLjr1rFT6z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/09/the-deplatforming-of-a-president/">The deplatforming of President Trump</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The deplatforming of President Trump&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/09/the-deplatforming-of-a-president/embed/#?secret=YLjr1rFT6z" data-secret="YLjr1rFT6z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Capsule would seek to route around the risk of mass deplatforming via &#8220;easy to deploy&#8221; P2P microservices &#8212; starting with a forthcoming web app.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you deploy Capsule right now &#8212; I have a prototype that does almost nothing running &#8212; it&#8217;s basically one binary. And you get that binary and you deploy it and you run it, and that&#8217;s it. It sets up a server, it contacts Let&#8217;s Encrypt, it gets you a certificate, it uses SQLite for the database, which is a serverless database, all of the assets for the web server are within the binary,&#8221; he says, walking through the &#8220;really nice technical idea&#8221; that snagged $100,000 in pre-seed backing insanely fast.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are no other files &#8212; and then once you have it running, in that folder when you set up your capsule server, it&#8217;s just the Capsule program and a Capsule database that is a file. And that&#8217;s it. And that is so self-contained that it&#8217;s embeddable everywhere, that&#8217;s migratable &#8212; and it&#8217;s really quite impossible to get this level of simplicity and elegance so quickly unless you go this route. Then, for the mesh federation thing, we&#8217;re just doing HTTPS calls and then having decentralized caching of the databases and so on.&#8221;</p>
<p>Among the <a href="https://twitter.com/kaepora/status/1348229796489265153">Twitter back-and-forth</a> about how (or whether) Kobeissi&#8217;s concept differs to various other decentralized protocols, someone posted a link to this <a href="https://xkcd.com/927/">XKCD</a> cartoon &#8212; which lampoons the techie quest to resolve competing standards by proposing a tech that covers all use cases (yet is of course doomed to increase complexity by +1). So given how many protocols already offer self-hosted/P2P social media services it seems fair to ask what&#8217;s different here &#8212; and, indeed, why build another open decentralized standard?</p>
<p>Kobeissi argues that existing options for decentralizing social media are either: (a) not fully P2P (Mastodon is &#8220;self-hosted but not decentralized,&#8221; per a competitive analysis on Capsule&#8217;s pitch deck, ergo its servers are &#8220;vulnerable to Parler-style AWS takedowns&#8221;); or (b) not focused enough on the specific use case of social media (some other decentralized protocols like Matrix aim to support many more features/apps than social media and therefore can&#8217;t be as lightweight is the argument); or (c) simply aren&#8217;t easy enough to use to be more than a niche geeky option.</p>
<p>He talks about Capsule having the same level of focus on social media as Signal does on private messaging, for example &#8212; albeit intending it to support both short-form &#8220;tweet&#8221;-style public posts and long-form Medium-style postings. But he&#8217;s vocal about not wanting any &#8220;bloat.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8bIs5EkPuU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/21/automattic-pumps-4-6m-into-new-vector-to-help-grow-matrix-an-open-decentralized-comms-ecosystem/">Automattic pumps $4.6M into New Vector to help grow Matrix, an open, decentralized comms ecosystem</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Automattic pumps $4.6M into New Vector to help grow Matrix, an open, decentralized comms ecosystem&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/21/automattic-pumps-4-6m-into-new-vector-to-help-grow-matrix-an-open-decentralized-comms-ecosystem/embed/#?secret=8bIs5EkPuU" data-secret="8bIs5EkPuU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>He also invokes Apple&#8217;s &#8220;design for usability&#8221; philosophy. Albeit, it&#8217;s a lot easier to say you want to design something that &#8220;just works&#8221; versus actually pulling off effortless mainstream accessibility. But that&#8217;s the bar Kobeissi is setting himself here.</p>
<p>&#8220;I always imagine Glenn Greenwald when I think of my user,&#8221; he says on the usability point, referring to the outspoken journalist and Intercept co-founder who recently left to launch his own newsletter-based offering on Substack. &#8220;He&#8217;s the person I see setting this up. Basically the way that this would work is he&#8217;d be able to set this up or get someone to set it up really easily &#8212; I think Capsule is going to offer automated deployments as also a way to make revenue, by the way, i.e., for a bit extra we deploy the server for you and then you&#8217;re self-hosting but we also make a margin off of that &#8212; but it&#8217;s going to be open source, you can set it up yourself as well and that&#8217;s perfectly okay. It&#8217;s not going to be hindered at all in that sense.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the case of Capsule, each content creator has their own website &#8212; has their own address, like Capsule.Greenwald.com &#8212; and then people go there and their first discovery of the mesh is through people that they&#8217;re interested in hearing from.&#8221;</p>
<p>Individual Capsules would be decentralized from the risk of platform-level censorship since they&#8217;d be beyond the reach of takedowns by a single centralizing entity. Although they would <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">still be hosted on the web &#8212; and therefore could be subject to a takedown by their own web host. </span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">That means illegal speech on Capsule could still be removed. However there wouldn&#8217;t be a universal host that could be hit up with the risk of a whole platform being taken down at a sweep &#8212; as Parler just was by AWS.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;For every takedown it is entirely between that Capsule user and their hosting provider,&#8221; says <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Kobeissi. &#8220;Capsule users are going to have different hosting providers that they&#8217;re able to choose and then every time that there is a takedown it is going to be a decision that is made by a different entity. And with a different &#8212; perhaps &#8212; judgement, so there isn&#8217;t this centralized focus where only Amazon Web Services decides who gets to speak or only Twitter decides.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">And while the business of web hosting at platform giant level involves just a handful of cloud hosting giants able to offer the required scalability, he argues that that censorship-prone market concentration goes away once you&#8217;re dealing with scores of descentralized social media instances.   </span></p>
<p>&#8220;We have the big hosting providers &#8212; like AWS, Azure, Google Cloud &#8212; but aside from that we have a lot of tiny hosting providers or small businesses … Sure if you&#8217;re running a big business you do get to focus on these big providers because they allow you to have these insane servers that are very powerful and deployable very easily but if you&#8217;re running a Capsule instance, as a matter of fact, the server resource requirements of running a Capsule instance are generally speaking quite small. In most instances tiny.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Content would also be harder to scrub from Capsule because the mesh infrastructure would mean posts get mirrored across the network by the poster&#8217;s own followers (assuming they have any). So, for example, reposts wouldn&#8217;t just vanish the moment the original poster&#8217;s account was taken down by their hosting provider. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Separate takedown requests would likely be needed to scrub each reposted instance, adding a lot more friction to the business of content moderation versus the unilateral takedowns that platform giants can rain down now. </span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The aim is to &#8220;spare the rest of the community from the danger of being silenced,&#8221; as Kobeissi puts it.</span></p>
<p>Trump&#8217;s deplatforming does seem to have triggered a major penny-dropping moment for some that allowing a handful of corporate giants to own and operate centralized mass communication machines isn&#8217;t exactly healthy for democratic societies as this unilateral control of infrastructure gives them the power to limit speech. (As, indeed, their content-sorting algorithms determine reach and set the agenda of much public debate.)</p>
<p>Current social media infrastructure also provides a few mainstream chokepoints for governments to lean on &#8212; amplifying the risk of state censorship.</p>
<p>With concerns growing over the implications of platform power on data flows &#8212; and judging by how quickly <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Kobeissi&#8217;s tweet</span> turned heads &#8212; we could be on the cusp of an investor-funded scramble to retool internet infrastructure to redefine where power (and data) lies.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s certainly interesting to note that Twitter recently reupped its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/twitters-vision-of-decentralization-could-also-be-the-far-rights-internet-endgame/">own decentralized social media open standard push</a>, Bluesky, for example. It obviously wouldn&#8217;t want to be left behind any such shift.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;It seems to really have blown up,&#8221; Kobeissi adds, returning to his week-old Capsule concept. &#8220;I thought when I tweeted that I was maybe the only person who cared. I guess I live in France so I&#8217;m not really in tune with what&#8217;s going on in the U.S. a lot &#8212; but a lot of people care.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;I am not like a cypherpunk-style person these days, I&#8217;m not for full anonymity or full unaccountability online by any stretch,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;And if this is abused then sincerely it might even be the case that we would encourage &#8212; have a guidelines page &#8212; for hosting providers like on how to deal with instances of someone hosting an abusive Capsule instance. We do want that accountability to exist. We are not like a full-on, crazy town &#8216;free speech&#8217; wild west thing. We just think that that accountability has to be organic and decentralized &#8212; just as originally intended with the internet.&#8221;</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Y6TPQ8rD4X"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/twitters-vision-of-decentralization-could-also-be-the-far-rights-internet-endgame/">Twitter’s decentralized future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter’s decentralized future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/twitters-vision-of-decentralization-could-also-be-the-far-rights-internet-endgame/embed/#?secret=Y6TPQ8rD4X" data-secret="Y6TPQ8rD4X" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/cryptocat-author-gets-insanely-fast-backing-to-build-p2p-tech-for-social-media/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097687</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Station: CES trends and Uber plots another spinoff</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/the-station-ces-trends-and-uber-plots-another-spinoff/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/the-station-ces-trends-and-uber-plots-another-spinoff/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 17:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cadillac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[envisics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox. Hi friends and new readers, welcome back to The Station, a newsletter dedicated to all the present and future ways people and packages move from Point A to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hi friends and new readers, welcome back to The Station, a newsletter dedicated to all the present and future ways people and packages move from Point A to Point B.</p>
<p>Before I launch into the news of the week, let&#8217;s take care of some housekeeping. First, you might have noticed that The Station landed in your email inbox on Sunday, not Saturday.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>I have received some feedback that suggests the newsletter is typically read on Sundays. Do you have an alternate view? Please reach out with your opinion on this matter.</p>
<p>When would you like to see The Station? And what do you like and dislike about the newsletter?</p>
<p>One last item: I am now transportation editor at TechCrunch. The title change comes with more responsibility and a mission. I&#8217;ll be bringing on more freelancers to expand our &#8220;future of transportation&#8221; coverage. Mark Harris, an investigative reporter who has already delivered some wonderful articles for us, will be a more regular fixture here. Harris has a knack for rooting out news tucked inside legal documents and filings such as his <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/03/trumps-tariffs-could-knock-teslas-autopilot-off-course/">Tesla tariffs</a> article in 2019 and insights into the passenger capability of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/elon-musks-las-vegas-loop-might-only-carry-a-fraction-of-the-passengers-it-promised/">Elon Musk&#8217;s Las Vegas Loop</a> project.</p>
<p>I hope to add more faces to the transportation bureau in the weeks and months to come.</p>
<p>Email me at <a href="mailto:kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com">kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com</a> to share thoughts, criticisms, offer up opinions or tips. You can also send a direct message to me at Twitter — <a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec">@kirstenkorosec</a>.</p>
<h2>CES roundup</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2093070" style="width: 1290px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/21C0001_010.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2093070" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2093070 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/21C0001_010.jpg" alt="Mercedes-EQ. MBUX Hyperscreen" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/21C0001_010.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/21C0001_010.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/21C0001_010.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/21C0001_010.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/21C0001_010.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/21C0001_010.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2093070" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-EQ MBUX Hyperscreen. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mercedes</p></div></p>
<p>Maybe it was the virtual format, but autonomous vehicle technology didn&#8217;t play a starring role at CES this year as it has in the past.</p>
<p>Instead, several other themes emerged at CES, mostly around infotainment and advanced driver assistance systems. And continuing a trend in 2020, there were several gigantic screens, including the Mercedes Hyperscreen that is pictured above.</p>
<p>Pioneer, Harman and Panasonic all revealed future products aimed at bringing more audio and visual technology into the vehicle. Harman, for instance, unveiled three new &#8220;experience concepts&#8221; that can turn the infotainment system in a vehicle into a concert hall, recording studio or gaming center.</p>
<p>Panasonic also announced a partnership with U.K. startup Envisics to jointly develop and commercialize a new generation of head-up displays for cars, trucks and SUVs. Head-up displays, or HUDs, seemed to be everywhere this show. The technology isn&#8217;t new, but recent advances are pushing the capabilities of these systems, which are integrated in the dash of a vehicle and project images onto the windshield to aid drivers with navigation and provide other alerts.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2094016" style="width: 2512px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Envisics_Dashboard_Navigation_01.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2094016" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2094016 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Envisics_Dashboard_Navigation_01.jpg" alt="Envisics Navigation" width="2502" height="1669" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Envisics_Dashboard_Navigation_01.jpg 2502w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Envisics_Dashboard_Navigation_01.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Envisics_Dashboard_Navigation_01.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Envisics_Dashboard_Navigation_01.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Envisics_Dashboard_Navigation_01.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Envisics_Dashboard_Navigation_01.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Envisics_Dashboard_Navigation_01.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Envisics_Dashboard_Navigation_01.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2502px) 100vw, 2502px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2094016" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Envisics</p></div></p>
<p>GM had perhaps the biggest presence at the virtual 2021 CES, at least within the transportation sector. The automaker chose the tech trade show to announce a new business unit called BrightDrop that will focus on electric vans and other products and services for the commercial market. But that wasn&#8217;t all.</p>
<p>GM used the opportunity to tease its upcoming Chevrolet Bolt EUV — a vehicle that will have GM&#8217;s hands-free highway driving assist technology known as Super Cruise — as well as the Cadillac Celestiq dashboard and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/gm-launches-new-logo-to-show-its-serious-about-its-electric-future/">even a new logo</a>. The intent of this bouquet of announcements was clear: GM wants the world — and shareholders — to know it&#8217;s serious about electrification and connected car tech.</p>
<p>GM&#8217;s numerous announcements were hard to miss — there was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/the-cadillac-personal-drone-is-the-cadillac-of-personal-drones/">even an eVTOL</a>. <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Conversely, Mobileye&#8217;s announcements flew a bit under the radar, but are arguably as notable. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2095195" style="width: 1964px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-12-at-7.33.45-AM.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2095195" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2095195 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-12-at-7.33.45-AM.jpg" alt="" width="1954" height="996" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-12-at-7.33.45-AM.jpg 1954w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-12-at-7.33.45-AM.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-12-at-7.33.45-AM.jpg?resize=300,153 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-12-at-7.33.45-AM.jpg?resize=768,391 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-12-at-7.33.45-AM.jpg?resize=680,347 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-12-at-7.33.45-AM.jpg?resize=1536,783 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-12-at-7.33.45-AM.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1954px) 100vw, 1954px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2095195" class="wp-caption-text">GM showed off two concepts at CES 2021: an autonomous shuttle and a personal eVTOL. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> GM</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Mobileye outlined plans to expand its autonomous vehicles testing to more cities, which was expected and is in line with the company&#8217;s previously stated plans.</span></p>
<p>What stood out to me was a talk that Mobileye president and CEO Amnon Shashua gave that outlined the company&#8217;s vision and progress.</p>
<p>The recap: Mobileye is taking a three-pronged strategy to developing and deploying automated vehicle technology that combines a full self-driving stack — that includes redundant sensing subsystems based on camera, radar and lidar technology— with its REM mapping system and a rules-based Responsibility-Sensitive Safety (RSS) driving policy.</p>
<p>Mobileye’s REM mapping system essentially crowdsources data by tapping into nearly one million vehicles equipped with its tech to build high-definition maps that can be used to support ADAS and autonomous driving systems. Shashua said Mobileye’s technology can now map the world automatically with nearly eight million kilometers tracked daily and nearly one billion kilometers completed to date.</p>
<p>The company provided more details at CES about a new lidar system-on-a-chip product that is under development and will come to market in 2025. The lidar, which will use Intel’s specialized silicon photonics fab, is notable because Mobileye is known for its camera-based technology. To be clear, Mobileye is not backing away from that camera-first approach. Shashua explained Mobileye believes the best technological and business approach is to develop a camera-first system and use the lidar and radar as add-ons for redundancy.</p>
<p>In short: Mobileye has the money and existing network to commercialize automated vehicle technology and bring it to the masses.</p>
<p>Below is sampling of our transportation-related CES coverage:</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/mercedes-unveils-hyperscreen-a-curved-56-inch-screen-for-its-flagship-eqs-electric-vehicle/">Mercedes unveils Hyperscreen, a 56-inch screen for its flagship EQS electric vehicle</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/gm-targets-delivery-companies-with-new-ev-business-unit-brightdrop/">GM targets delivery with new EV business unit BrightDrop</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/mobileye-is-bringing-its-autonomous-vehicle-test-fleets-to-at-least-four-more-cities-in-2021/">Mobileye is bringing its autonomous vehicle test fleets to at least four more cities in 2021</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/sony-reveals-more-details-on-its-secretive-vision-s-sedan/">Sony reveal more details on its secretive Vision S sedan</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/holographic-startup-envisics-partners-with-panasonic-to-fast-track-in-car-ar-tech/">Holographic startup Envisics partners with Panasonic to fast track in-car AR tech</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/16/startups-look-beyond-lidar-for-autonomous-vehicle-perception/">Startups look beyond lidar for autonomous vehicle perception</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/bmw-previews-its-next-gen-idrive-infotainment-system/">BMW previews its next-generation iDrive infotainment system</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/sono-motors-plans-to-license-the-tech-that-powers-its-solar-electric-car/">Sono Motor plans to license the tech that powers it solar electric car</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/air-taxi-startup-archer-is-partnering-with-automaker-fca-on-production-of-its-electric-aircraft/">Air taxi startup Archer partners with FCA</a></p>
<h2>Another Uber spinoff is in the works</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1859990" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/POSTMATES-OUSTER-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1859990" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1859990 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/POSTMATES-OUSTER-1.jpg" alt="POSTMATES OUSTER 1" width="2000" height="1500" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/POSTMATES-OUSTER-1.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/POSTMATES-OUSTER-1.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/POSTMATES-OUSTER-1.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/POSTMATES-OUSTER-1.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/POSTMATES-OUSTER-1.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/POSTMATES-OUSTER-1.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/POSTMATES-OUSTER-1.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1859990" class="wp-caption-text">Postmates&#8217; Serve robot is equipped with cameras as well as lidar from Ouster. I<strong>mage Credits:</strong> Postmates</p></div></p>
<p>Remember when I predicted that autonomous delivery would gain momentum in 2021? It seems that sometimes I am right!</p>
<p>Postmates X, the robotics division of the on-demand delivery startup that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/uber-officially-completes-postmates-acquisition/">Uber acquired last year for $2.65 billion</a>, is seeking investors in its bid to become a separate company called Serve Robotics.</p>
<p>You might recall Serve, the yellow-and-black-emblazoned autonomous sidewalk delivery bot that was developed and piloted by Postmates X. This robot, which recently partnered with Pink Dot Stores for deliveries in West Hollywood, will likely be the centerpiece of the new startup.</p>
<p>I learned of a few important details of this plan, which is not yet settled. Uber will maintain a stake in this new startup. Uber&#8217;s stake was initially low, but has since popped to about 25%, according to sources familiar with the deal.</p>
<p>The company would be run by Ali Kashani, who heads up Postmates X and leads the Serve program. Anthony Armenta would lead the startup’s software efforts and Aaron Leiba would be in charge of hardware — keeping the same positions they hold at Postmates X.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll fill y&#8217;all in with more details as I learn them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/the-station-ces-trends-and-uber-plots-another-spinoff/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097696</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calling Bucharest VCs: Be featured in The Great TechCrunch Survey of European VC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/calling-bucharest-vcs-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/calling-bucharest-vcs-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 16:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch is embarking on a major project to survey the venture capital investors of Europe and their cities. Our survey of VCs in Bucharest and Romania will capture how the country is faring, and what changes are being wrought amongst investors by the coronavirus pandemic. We’d like to know how Romania&#8217;s startup scene is evolving, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch is embarking on a major project to <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey</a> the venture capital investors of Europe and their cities.</p>
<p>Our <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey of VCs in Bucharest and Romania</a> will capture how the country is faring, and what changes are being wrought amongst investors by the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>We’d like to know how Romania&#8217;s startup scene is evolving, how the tech sector is being impacted by COVID-19, and, generally, how your thinking will evolve from here.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Our survey will only be about investors, and <strong>only the contributions of VC investors will be included.</strong> More than one partner is welcome to fill out the survey. (Please note, if you have filled the survey out already, there is no need to do it again).</p>
<p>The shortlist of questions will require only brief responses, but the more you can add, the better.</p>
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6"><strong>You can fill out the survey here.</strong></a></p>
<p><em>The deadline is January 22, 2021.</em></p>
<p>Obviously, investors who contribute will be featured in the final surveys, with links to their companies and profiles.</p>
<p>What kinds of things do we want to know? Questions include: Which trends are you most excited by? What startup do you wish someone would create? Where are the overlooked opportunities? What are you looking for in your next investment, in general? How is your local ecosystem going? And how has COVID-19 impacted your investment strategy?</p>
<p>This survey is part of a broader <a href="https://techcrunch.com/extra-crunch/investor-surveys/">series of surveys</a> we’re doing to help founders find the right investors.</p>
<p>For example, here is the recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/14-vcs-discuss-covid-19-and-londons-future-as-a-tech-hub/">survey of London</a>.</p>
<p>Are you not in Romania, but would like to take part? That&#8217;s fine! Any European VC investor can STILL fill out the survey, as we probably will be putting a call out to your country next anyway! We will use the data for future surveys on vertical topics.</p>
<p>The survey is covering almost every country on in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Union_for_the_Mediterranean">Union for the Mediterranean</a>, so just look for your country and city on the <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey</a> and please participate (<em>if</em> you&#8217;re a venture capital investor).</p>
<p>Thank you for participating. If you have questions you can email <a href="mailto:mike@techcrunch.com">mike@techcrunch.com.</a></p>
<p>(Please note: Filling out the survey is not a guarantee of inclusion in the final published piece).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/calling-bucharest-vcs-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097698</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It may not be as glamorous as D2C, but beauty tech is big money</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/it-may-not-be-as-glamorous-as-d2c-but-beauty-tech-is-big-money/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/it-may-not-be-as-glamorous-as-d2c-but-beauty-tech-is-big-money/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 16:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Billie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[direct to consumer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dollar shave club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perfect Corp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procter & gamble]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shifting consumer demands within beauty and retail are creating rich opportunities for U.S.-based beauty/consumer tech SaaS companies.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sindhya Valloppillil</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/sindhya">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sindhya/">Sindhya Valloppillil</a> is the founder and CEO of Skin Dossier, a venture partner at Next Gen Ventures, a freelance writer and formerly a beauty industry executive and marketing professor.

	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Last week, Procter &amp; Gamble (P&amp;G) announced that it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/pg-terminates-plan-to-acquire-razor-startup-billie-following-ftc-lawsuit/">terminating plans to acquire razor startup Billie</a> following a U.S. Federal Trade Commission lawsuit to stop the deal.</p>
<p>Last year, Edgewell Personal Care ditched its debt-heavy $1.37 billion deal for Harry&#8217;s, Inc, formerly valued at $1 billion <a href="https://www.businessoffashion.com/articles/news-analysis/ftc-moves-to-block-edgewells-acquisition-of-shaving-startup-harrys">after the FTC sought to block the acquisition</a>.</p>
<p>In addition to these FTC challenges, it is also now becoming clear that relying on VC-subsidized products and celebrating outrageous valuations can be problematic for D2C brands. With a few wonderful and rare exceptions such as <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/amyfeldman/2019/07/16/rothys-shoes/#6506632779d5">Rothy’s</a> (which raised $42 million but was profitable from the beginning and generated $140 million in revenue within two years of launching), D2C unicorns are addicted to the cycle of venture funding to feed growth in order to maintain a high valuation multiple.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			The path to profitability has become a more important part of the startup story versus growth at all costs.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>This works for a while; however, when the path to profitability appears murky and exit options either don’t appear or only appear from nontech companies with very conservative multiples, the walls start crumbling.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://wwd.com/business-news/financial/fashion-beauty-startup-investment-vc-odile-roujol-fab-ventures-1203688530/">WWD article</a>, Odile Roujol, the former CEO of Lancôme who launched venture fund <a href="https://www.fabcocreationstudio.com/">FAB Ventures</a>, said, &#8220;Generally speaking, the era of $1 billion valuations for beauty companies is over. The people that struggle have been the companies that spend so much money in just a few years.&#8221; She went on to say, “The big corporations now … are not ready to spend $1.2 billion, $1.5 billion on such a brand like Glossier.”</p>
<p>This change in sentiment from acquirers is further fueled by recent research on the challenges of turning hypergrowth companies profitable. In his Harvard Business School case study<a href="https://store.hbr.org/product/direct-to-consumer-brands/520060?sku=520060-PDF-ENG"> &#8220;Direct to Consumer Brands</a>,&#8221; Professor Sunil Gupta wrote, “Acquiring DTC brands is easy for incumbent conglomerates, but making them profitable is challenging. More than three years after Unilever acquired Dollar Shave Club, it was still unprofitable.”</p>
<p>Unilever executives learned that the average cost of acquiring a new customer online was about the same as in stores. David Taylor, CEO of P&amp;G, said his company was still figuring out how to turn recently acquired direct-to-consumer brands into profitable businesses.</p>
<p>Taylor summarized this dilemma, saying, “There are many, many launches that grow fast … a business model that makes money is a higher challenge.” Since making these realizations, incumbent conglomerates will be more cautious when considering the acquisition of hyped D2C brands that raised lots of venture capital.</p>
<h2>Beauty tech is a better bet: Meitu and Perfect Corp.</h2>
<p>What’s cooler than beauty companies that are (or were) valued at $1 billion? Beauty tech SaaS companies that are worth $5.2 billion at IPO. We don’t hear much about the leading global beauty tech companies such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meitu">Meitu</a> and Perfect Corp. because their founders are not celebrity influencers, they don’t have massive Instagram followings here in the U.S. and they are not celebrated in our media. Although their companies are based in Asia and they raised money mostly from Chinese investors, their companies are global successes.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/it-may-not-be-as-glamorous-as-d2c-but-beauty-tech-is-big-money/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097179</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bustle CEO Bryan Goldberg explains his plans for taking the company public</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/bustle-ceo-bryan-goldberg-explains-his-plans-for-taking-the-company-public/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/bustle-ceo-bryan-goldberg-explains-his-plans-for-taking-the-company-public/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 15:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bleacher report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bryan goldberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bustle Digital Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buzzfeed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason Wagenheim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Now, you know, we did six acquisitions in 2019. I don't know if we'll do six acquisitions in 2021. But I want to do a lot more than one acquisition in 2021."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Bustle Digital Group — owner of Bustle, Inverse, Input, Mic and other titles — could eventually join the ranks of startups going public via a special purpose acquisition company (SPAC).</p>
<p>During an interview about the state of BDG and the digital media industry at the end of 2020, founder and CEO Bryan Goldberg laid out ambitious goals for the next few years.</p>
<p>&#8220;Where do I want to see the company in three years? I want to see three things: I want to be public, I want to see us driving a lot of profits and I want it to be a lot bigger, because we&#8217;ve consolidated a lot of other publications,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He added that those goals connect, because by going public, BDG can raise &#8220;hundreds of millions dollars,&#8221; which Goldberg wants to use to &#8220;buy a lot of media companies.&#8221;</p>
<p>That might seem like bluster after a year in which many digital media companies (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/03/bdg-layoffs/">including BDG</a>) had to make serious cuts. But Goldberg said that the company would be profitable in 2020, with revenue that&#8217;s &#8220;a little bit under $100 million.&#8221; And it won&#8217;t be the first digital media company to take a similar route — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/group-nines-spac-goes-public/">Group Nine created a SPAC that went public last week</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;I want to prove that we can be highly profitable,&#8221; he said. &#8220;A lot of startups don&#8217;t have that goal. A lot of VCs tell their startups: Don&#8217;t worry about profits, don&#8217;t worry about losing money. I don&#8217;t believe in that.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition to his plans to go public, Goldberg also discussed how acquisitions have helped Bustle&#8217;s business, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/13/fashion/w-magazine-deal-bustle-digital-group.html">his joint venture to purchase W Magazine</a> and digital media&#8217;s &#8220;overcapitalization&#8221; problem. You can read our full conversation, edited for length and clarity, below.</p>
<p><strong>TechCrunch: The last time I caught up with someone at BDG, it was with [<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/06/how-will-digital-media-survive-the-ad-crash/">the company&#8217;s president Jason Wagenheim</a>] and that was when you guys were dealing with the initial fallout [from the pandemic]. Now we&#8217;re a lot further into whatever this new world is, so what is your sense of where BDG is now, versus where it was in the early days of the pandemic?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bryan Goldberg:</strong> It might be the craziest, most eventful six months for many of us in our lives. And certainly, for those of us in this industry, the difference between April and October, it&#8217;s really hard to fathom, it&#8217;s complete night and day. April was a very frightening time for everyone, personally and professionally across the country, across the world.</p>
<p>From an advertising standpoint, it was a really scary time, because we have clients across every industry, and every industry was impacted differently. We have clients who were greatly impacted — theme parks, car makers, hotel companies, airlines — and then we had clients who were not as badly affected, such as a lot of CPG clients, who everybody depended upon so much during the pandemic.</p>
<p>There was a huge pause in our business in in March, April and May. For a lot of clients, tossing advertising was a sort of knee-jerk reaction to the sudden shock of COVID, and so we saw a huge negative impact in our second quarter. What we started to see in the third quarter, and especially now in the fourth quarter, is now that the shock of COVID is behind us, the macro trends that were catalyzed by COVID are now moving into the forefront.</p>
<p>The story of media is no longer about the shock of COVID. The story of media is now about all of the changes to our world, and changes to our industry that were brought about as a consequence of COVID.</p>
<p>The good news for our company, and the good news for other digital media companies, is it looks like the future is being accelerated. It looks like people are watching less television, and so advertisers are moving their budgets into digital faster than they would have had it not been for COVID. Even things like live sports, [their] TV ratings are way down. And a lot of advertisers are saying, “Is there efficacy anymore in cable television or broadcast television?” And the magazine industry was heavily impaired, simply because magazines are a physical medium, and people didn&#8217;t want to pass around magazines or read magazines at the dentist&#8217;s office, so we probably saw some print budget move into digital as well.</p>
<p>Industry analysts now are going to take up their estimates of what digital revenue is going to look like in 2021, 2022 and beyond. I also think we&#8217;ve seen a world in which a lot of brand advertisers are starting to think about what happens when they start to spend beyond Facebook and Google. For most of the last three years, there&#8217;s been so much talk about the duopoly, the idea that Facebook and Google are going to eat almost every last dollar of advertising. What we&#8217;ve seen in the last three months is advertisers saying that this needs to be the moment in which they learn how to deploy advertising spend digitally beyond Facebook or Google.</p>
<p>No, it doesn&#8217;t mean they&#8217;re all pulling out of Facebook — Facebook and Google are doing just fine. But there are still tens of billions of dollars that need to be deployed outside of Facebook and Google. And you&#8217;re seeing winners such as Snapchat, Pinterest. Both had incredibly strong earnings. They&#8217;re benefiting from the same thing that benefits Bustle Digital Group and a lot of other digital media players who aren&#8217;t Facebook and Google, which is you&#8217;re seeing big ad spenders finally deciding that now&#8217;s the time to find other ways to deploy advertising spend.</p>
<p>I think those are the two big trends: Dollars moving to digital out of TV faster than we thought, and major advertisers using now as a time to find other channels beyond Facebook and Google.</p>
<p><strong>So when you look at how that is impacting Bustle’s business, has it returned to pre-COVID levels?</strong></p>
<p>For us, when we reflect upon the year 2020, we see that we had a great first quarter, we see that we&#8217;re having an incredible fourth quarter, and we have a big, epic crater in the second and third quarters. So when we look at the year, we basically have to say to ourselves, if it were not for that crater in the second and third quarters, what would this year have looked like? We would have had revenue well in excess of $100 million. Now, we&#8217;re gonna have revenue a little bit under $100 million.</p>
<p>But when we think about how we prepare for 2021 and set goals for 2021, we have to set goals for 2021 as though COVID had never happened, we have to set goals for 2021 without using Q2 and Q3 as a sort of excuse for lowering expectations. Because the fourth quarter, the quarter we&#8217;re currently in, has exceeded our wildest expectations.</p>
<p><strong>People sort of sat up and took notice of the company because you had a pretty aggressive acquisition strategy. I imagine that strategy had to change a little bit in 2020. To what extent do you feel that ambition is something that you can pick up again?</strong></p>
<p>So to be clear, not only do we feel great about our strategy, our strategy was critical in helping our company survive and ultimately thrive in the wake of the virus. You know, we made two acquisitions [in 2019] — in the science and technology category, we bought Inverse, which is a science and technology publication, and then Josh Topolsky launched a tech-and-gadget publication for us called Input Magazine that&#8217;s growing very quickly.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s critical that we had that strategy, because no single advertiser category has performed better for us in 2020 than tech — we more than tripled our revenue from technology clients this year, because technology has thrived through COVID. Had we not had an acquisition strategy, had we not diversified into tech media publishing, we certainly would not have had the outcome we had in 2020. That&#8217;s just the reality.</p>
<p>Categories like beauty, fashion, retail were very hard hit. Those have traditionally been our bread and butter, and they&#8217;re going to be great again, in 2021. But this spring, beauty companies weren&#8217;t doing so well, because people weren&#8217;t leaving the house. So the strategy worked, in part, because we diversified the categories in which we created content, which allowed us to diversify the advertiser base. And we&#8217;re gonna continue full speed ahead in 2021.</p>
<p>Now, you know, we did six acquisitions in 2019. I don&#8217;t know if we&#8217;ll do six acquisitions in 2021. But I want to do a lot more than one acquisition in 2021.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/bustle-ceo-bryan-goldberg-explains-his-plans-for-taking-the-company-public/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096469</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch Virgin Orbit launch a rocket to space from a modified 747 for the first time</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/watch-virgin-orbit-launch-a-rocket-to-space-from-a-modified-747-for-the-first-time/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/watch-virgin-orbit-launch-a-rocket-to-space-from-a-modified-747-for-the-first-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 13:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[launch services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LauncherOne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit scored a major success on Sunday, with a test flight that not only achieved its goals of reaching space and orbit, but also of delivering payloads on board for NASA, marking its first commercial mission, too. The launch was a success in every possible regard, which puts Virgin Orbit on track to become [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Virgin Orbit scored a major success on Sunday, with a test flight that not only achieved its goals of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/virgin-orbit-reaches-orbit-for-the-first-time/">reaching space and orbit, but also of delivering payloads on board for NASA</a>, marking its first commercial mission, too. The launch was a success in every possible regard, which puts Virgin Orbit on track to become an active launch provider for small payloads for both commercial and defense customers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Today&#39;s sequence of events for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LaunchDemo2?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#LaunchDemo2</a> went exactly to plan, from safe execution of our ground ops all the way through successful full duration burns on both engines. To say we&#39;re thrilled would be a massive understatement, but 240 characters couldn&#39;t do it justice anyway. <a href="https://t.co/ZKpoi7hkGN">pic.twitter.com/ZKpoi7hkGN</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Virgin Orbit (@Virgin_Orbit) <a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_Orbit/status/1350960438444511232?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 18, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Above, you can watch the actual launch itself — the moment the LauncherOne rocket detaches from &#8220;Cosmic Girl,&#8221; a modified Boeing 747 airliner that takes off normally from a standard aircraft runway, and then climbs to a cruising altitude to release the rocket, which then ignites its own engines and flies the rest of the way to space. Virgin Orbit&#8217;s launch model was designed to reduce the barriers to carrying small payloads to orbit versus traditional vertical takeoff vehicles, and this successful test flight proves the model works.</p>
<p>Virgin Orbit now joins a small but growing group of private launch companies who have actually reached space and made it to orbit. That should be great news for the small satellite launch market, which still has much more demand than there is supply. Virgin Orbit also offers something very different from current launch providers like SpaceX, which typically serves larger payloads or which must offer rideshare model missions for those with smaller spacecraft. The LauncherOne design potentially means more on-demand, response and quick-turnaround launch services for satellite operators.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fPAzGR0kVO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/virgin-orbit-reaches-orbit-for-the-first-time/">Virgin Orbit reaches orbit for the first time</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Virgin Orbit reaches orbit for the first time&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/virgin-orbit-reaches-orbit-for-the-first-time/embed/#?secret=fPAzGR0kVO" data-secret="fPAzGR0kVO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/watch-virgin-orbit-launch-a-rocket-to-space-from-a-modified-747-for-the-first-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097667</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WhatsApp-Facebook data-sharing transparency under review by EU DPAs after Ireland sends draft decision</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/whatsapp-facebook-data-sharing-transparency-under-review-by-eu-dpas-after-ireland-sends-draft-decision/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/whatsapp-facebook-data-sharing-transparency-under-review-by-eu-dpas-after-ireland-sends-draft-decision/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 12:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU data protection law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platform regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A long-running investigation in the European Union focused on the transparency of data-sharing between Facebook and WhatsApp has taken the first major step toward a resolution. Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC) confirmed Saturday it sent a draft decision to fellow EU DPAs toward the back end of last year. This will trigger a review process [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A long-running investigation in the European Union focused on the transparency of data-sharing between Facebook and WhatsApp has taken the first major step toward a resolution. Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC) confirmed Saturday it sent a draft decision to fellow EU DPAs toward the back end of last year.</p>
<p>This will trigger a review process of the draft by other DPAs. Majority backing for Facebook&#8217;s lead EU data supervisor&#8217;s proposed settlement is required under the bloc&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) before a decision can be finalized.</p>
<p>The DPC&#8217;s draft WhatsApp decision, which it told us was sent to the other supervisors for review on December 24, is only the second such draft the Irish watchdog has issued to date in cross-border GDPR cases.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The first case to go through the process was an investigation into a Twitter security breach &#8212; which led to the company being issued with a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/">$550,000 fine last month</a>.</p>
<p>The WhatsApp case may look very timely, given <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/">the recent backlash over an update to its T&amp;Cs</a>, but it actually dates back to 2018, the year GDPR begun being applied &#8212; and relates to WhatsApp Ireland’s compliance with Articles 12-14 of the GDPR (which set out how information must be provided to data subjects whose information is being processed in order that they are able to exercise their rights).</p>
<p>In a statement, the DPC said:</p>
<blockquote><p>As you are aware, the DPC has been conducting an investigation into WhatsApp Ireland’s compliance with Articles 12-14 of the GDPR in terms of transparency, including in relation to transparency around what information is shared with Facebook, since 2018. The DPC has provisionally concluded this investigation and we sent a draft decision to our fellow EU Data Protection Authorities on December 24, 2020 (in accordance with Article 60 of the GDPR in order to commence the co-decision-making process) and we are waiting to receive their comments on this draft decision.</p></blockquote>
<p>&#8220;When the process is completed and a final decision issues, it will make clear the standard of transparency to which WhatsApp is expected to adhere as articulated by EU Data Protection Authorities,&#8221; it added.</p>
<p>A WhatsApp spokesperson added: “We continue to cooperate with the IDPC and await its final decision.”</p>
<p>Ireland has additional<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/lack-of-big-tech-gdpr-decisions-looms-large-in-eu-watchdogs-annual-report/"> ongoing GDPR investigations</a> into other aspects of the tech giant&#8217;s business, including related to complaints filed back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/25/facebook-google-face-first-gdpr-complaints-over-forced-consent/">May 2018 by the EU privacy rights not-for-profit, noyb</a> (over so-called &#8220;forced consent&#8221;). In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/22/first-major-gdpr-decisions-looming-on-twitter-and-facebook/">May 2020</a> the DPC said that separate investigation was at the decision-making phase &#8212; but so far it has not confirmed sending a draft decision for review.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also notably that the time between the DPC&#8217;s Twitter draft and the final decision being issued &#8212; after gaining majority backing from other EU DPAs &#8212; was almost seven months.</p>
<p>The Twitter case was relatively straightforward (a data breach) versus the more complex business of assessing &#8220;transparency.&#8221; So a final decision on WhatsApp seems unlikely to come to a swifter resolution. There are clearly substantial differences of opinion between DPAs on how the GDPR should be enforced across the bloc. (In the Twitter case, for example, German DPAs suggested a fine of up to $22 million versus Ireland&#8217;s initial proposal of a maximum of $300,000). Although there is some hope that GDPR enforcement of cross-border cases will speed up as DPAs gain experience of the various mechanisms and processes involved in making these co-decisions (even if major ideological gaps remain).</p>
<p>Returning to WhatsApp, the messaging platform has had plenty of problems with transparency in recent weeks &#8212; garnering lots of unwelcome attention and concern over the privacy implications of a confusing mandatory update to its T&amp;Cs which has contributed to a major migration of users to alternative chat platforms, such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/signal-brian-acton-talks-about-exploding-growth-monetization-and-whatsapp-data-sharing-outrage/">Signal</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/e2e-encrypted-email-providers-also-see-sign-ups-surge-as-chat-app-users-flock-to-signal-and-telegram-in-search-of-privacy/">Telegram</a>.</p>
<p>The backlash led WhatsApp to announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/whatsapp-delays-new-data-sharing-policy-enforcement-to-may-15/">last week</a> that it was delaying enforcement of the new terms by three months. Last week Italy&#8217;s data protection agency also issued a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/">warning</a> over a lack of clarity in the T&amp;Cs &#8212; saying it could intervene using an emergency process allowed for by EU law (which would be in addition to the ongoing DPC procedure).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="baipchOJZY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/">Confusion over WhatsApp&#8217;s new T&#038;Cs triggers privacy warning from Italy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Confusion over WhatsApp&#8217;s new T&#038;Cs triggers privacy warning from Italy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/embed/#?secret=baipchOJZY" data-secret="baipchOJZY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>On the WhatsApp T&amp;Cs controversy, the DPC&#8217;s deputy commissioner Graham Doyle told us the regulator had received &#8220;numerous queries&#8221; from confused and concerned stakeholders that he said led it to reengage with the company. The regulator previously obtained a commitment from WhatsApp that there is &#8220;no change to data-sharing practices either in the European Region or the rest of the world.&#8221; But it subsequently confirmed it would delay enforcement of the new terms.</p>
<p>&#8220;The updates made by WhatsApp last week are about providing clearer, more detailed information to users on how and why they use data. WhatsApp have confirmed to us that there is no change to data-sharing practices either in the European Region or the rest of the world arising from these updates. However, the DPC has received numerous queries from stakeholders who are confused and concerned about these updates,&#8221; Doyle said.</p>
<p>&#8220;We engaged with WhatsApp on the matter and they confirmed to us that they will delay the date by which people will be asked to review and accept the terms from February 8 to May 15. In the meantime, WhatsApp will launch information campaigns to provide further clarity about how privacy and security works on the platform. We will continue to engage with WhatsApp on these updates.&#8221;</p>
<p>While there&#8217;s no doubt Europe&#8217;s record of enforcement of its much vaunted data protection laws against tech giants remains <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">a major weak point of the regulation</a>, there are signs that increased user awareness of rights and, more broadly, concern for privacy, is causing a shift in the balance of power in favor of users.</p>
<p>Proper privacy enforcement is still sorely lacking but Facebook being forced to put a T&amp;C update on ice for three months &#8212; as its business is subject to ongoing regulatory scrutiny &#8212; suggests the days of platform giants being able to move fast and break things are firmly on the wain.</p>
<p>Similarly, for example, Facebook recently had to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/facebook-dating-launches-in-europe-after-9-month-delay-over-privacy-concerns/">delay the launch of a dating feature in Europe</a> while it consulted with the DPC. It also remains limited in the data it can share between WhatsApp and Facebook because of the existence of the GDPR &#8212;<a href="https://twitter.com/DPCIreland/status/973985987876573184"> so still can&#8217;t</a> share data for ad targeting and product enhancement purposes, even under the new terms.</p>
<p>Europe, meanwhile, is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">coming with ex ante rules for platform giants</a> that will place further obligations on how they can operate &#8212; with the aim of counteracting abusive/unfair business behaviors and bolstering competition in digital markets.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Kbpvyky6CO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/">GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/embed/#?secret=Kbpvyky6CO" data-secret="Kbpvyky6CO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="X7bMt4svpY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/embed/#?secret=X7bMt4svpY" data-secret="X7bMt4svpY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>This report was updated with comment from WhatsApp.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/whatsapp-facebook-data-sharing-transparency-under-review-by-eu-dpas-after-ireland-sends-draft-decision/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097623</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tencent-backed Hike, once India&#8217;s answer to WhatsApp, has given up on messaging</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/tencent-backed-hike-once-indias-answer-to-whatsapp-has-given-up-on-messaging/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/tencent-backed-hike-once-indias-answer-to-whatsapp-has-given-up-on-messaging/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 11:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India’s answer to WhatsApp has completely moved on from messaging. Hike Messenger, backed by Tencent, Tiger Global and SoftBank and valued at $1.4 billion in 2016, earlier this month announced that it was shutting down StickerChat, its messaging app. (StickerChat users saw notifications about it late last week.) The startup, founded by Kavin Bharti Mittal, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India’s answer to WhatsApp has completely moved on from messaging.</p>
<p>Hike Messenger, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/16/indias-whatsapp-rival-hike-raises-175m-led-by-tencent-at-a-1-4b-valuation/">backed by Tencent, Tiger Global and SoftBank</a> and valued at $1.4 billion in 2016, earlier this month announced that it was shutting down StickerChat, its messaging app. (StickerChat users saw notifications about it late last week.)</p>
<p>The startup, founded by Kavin Bharti Mittal, this month pivoted to two virtual social apps called Vibe and Rush, said Mittal, who is the son of telecom giant Airtel’s chairman Sunil Bharti Mittal.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In a series of tweets earlier this month, Kavin said that India will never have a homegrown messenger that makes inroads in the world’s second-largest market unless it chooses to ban Western companies from operating in the nation. “Global network effects are too strong,” he said. WhatsApp has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/youtube-and-whatsapp-inch-closer-to-half-a-billion-users-in-india/">amassed over 450 million users</a> in India, its biggest market by users.</p>
<p>Mittal described opportunities in building virtual worlds as a “much better approach for today’s world that is unconstrained by cheap, fast data and powerful smartphones.”</p>
<p>The end of Hike&#8217;s messenger service comes at a time when Signal and Telegram have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/whatsapp-delays-new-data-sharing-policy-enforcement-to-may-15/">added tens of millions of users in recent weeks</a>. A planned update to WhatsApp&#8217;s data-sharing policy has prompted many of its loyal fans to explore alternatives this month. &#8220;Both [Telegram and Signal] are very good. As entities they have the right incentives (more aligned with consumers) unlike Facebook products,&#8221; <a href="https://twitter.com/kavinbm/status/1348279445233168385">tweeted</a> Mittal earlier this month.</p>
<p>In recent years, Hike made bets on stickers and emojis to cater to the younger population in India. In a meeting with TechCrunch in late 2019, Mittal said that the startup was overwhelmed with the engagement stickers on its platform and was working to automate development of personalized stickers.</p>
<p>In a different meeting last year, Mittal showcased emojis that replicated human expressions and a virtual hangout place called HikeLand. Vibe is the rebranded version of HikeLand and the emojis Hike developed will continue to be available to users on both the newer apps, Mittal said earlier this month.</p>
<p>Hike, which has raised more than $260 million to date, had enough runway last year, Mittal said, who hinted that the startup may raise more capital a year later.</p>
<p>Hike also attempted to build its own operating system through acquisition of a startup called Creo. In 2018, Hike launched Total OS that aimed to cater to users with low-cost Android smartphones and slow internet data.</p>
<p>The startup later shut down the project. Mittal told TechCrunch that the arrival of Reliance Jio, which prompted Airtel and Vodafone to lower mobile data tariff on their networks, solved the data issues in the country and Total OS was no longer needed in the market.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8KQAD7mVqv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/16/indias-whatsapp-rival-hike-raises-175m-led-by-tencent-at-a-1-4b-valuation/">India&#8217;s WhatsApp rival Hike raises $175M led by Tencent at a $1.4B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India&#8217;s WhatsApp rival Hike raises $175M led by Tencent at a $1.4B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/16/indias-whatsapp-rival-hike-raises-175m-led-by-tencent-at-a-1-4b-valuation/embed/#?secret=8KQAD7mVqv" data-secret="8KQAD7mVqv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/tencent-backed-hike-once-indias-answer-to-whatsapp-has-given-up-on-messaging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097629</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>proSapient raises $10M Series A led by Smedvig Capital to expand expert network platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/prosapient-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-smedvig-capital-to-expand-expert-network-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/prosapient-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-smedvig-capital-to-expand-expert-network-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 11:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guy hands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Margo Polishchuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proSapient]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rob Toms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smedvig Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For several years there has been talk about how to leverage &#8220;experts&#8221; online. How do you &#8220;suck their brains&#8221; for information in an efficient manner, whether it be for research into companies or sectors, often for investment purposes. Major players in this arena include GLG, Third Bridge, Guidepoint and Alphasights. With the pandemic destroying many [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For several years there has been talk about how to leverage &#8220;experts&#8221; online. How do you &#8220;suck their brains&#8221; for information in an efficient manner, whether it be for research into companies or sectors, often for investment purposes. Major players in this arena include GLG, Third Bridge, Guidepoint and Alphasights. With the pandemic destroying many means of hearing experts — conferences and events for instance — and turning the entire world into a remote-working experiment, platforms like these are now far more relevant than they ever were before.</p>
<p>So it’s perhaps unsurprising that the expert network and primary research platform, <a href="https://prosapient.com">proSapient</a>, has now closed a $10 million Series A investment led by <a href="https://smedvigcapital.com">Smedvig Capital</a>. Noted high-profile investor <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guy_Hands">Guy Hands</a> and existing investors 24 Haymarket also participated in the round. This brings the total raised by proSapient to date to $18 million. The company will use the cash to expand internationally.</p>
<p>proSapient is essentially a SaaS platform for managing expert networks. It’s aimed mainly at investors and consultants to gather data. The platform matches experts to projects and provides transcripts. You can gather insight over the phone or in-person; launch bespoke surveys; conduct small strategy projects with a small group of experts. You can search, filter messaging and also collaborate internally on the platform. It now claims to be servicing over 100 clients across Europe and the USA, with revenue up over 100% year on year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Margo Polishchuk, co-founder of proSapient, said in a statement: &#8220;This funding round will facilitate our strategic objective of being a leading primary research platform for the private equity and consulting sectors.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rob Toms, managing director at Smedvig Capital, commented: &#8220;We’re excited to be working with Margo and Jordan to continue their impressive growth and international expansion. They have a great team, strong market position and a clear vision of where the business is going.&#8221;</p>
<p>Additionally, proSapient recently appointed Mike Wroe, former group CFO of Just Eat plc, as chairman.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/prosapient-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-smedvig-capital-to-expand-expert-network-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097627</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Samsung vice chairman Jay Y. Lee sent back to prison in bribery case</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/samsung-vice-chairman-jay-y-lee-sent-back-to-prison-in-bribery-case/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/samsung-vice-chairman-jay-y-lee-sent-back-to-prison-in-bribery-case/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 09:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bribery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jay Y. Lee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Samsung Electronics vice chairman Jay Y. Lee is back in prison following a retrial of his 2017 conviction in a bribery case that helped lead to the downfall of former South Korean president Park Geun-hye. The Seoul High Court sentenced Lee to 30 months on Monday. Lee was originally convicted of bribery in 2017 and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Samsung Electronics vice chairman Jay Y. Lee is back in prison following a retrial of his 2017 conviction in a bribery case that helped lead to the downfall of former South Korean president Park Geun-hye. The Seoul High Court sentenced Lee to 30 months on Monday.</p>
<p>Lee was originally convicted of bribery in 2017 and sentenced to five years, but was released in 2018 after the sentence was reduced and suspended on appeal. In August 2019, however, South Korea’s Supreme Court overturned the appeals court, ruling that it was too lenient and ordered the case to be retried.</p>
<p>Lee was expected to become chairman of Samsung after the death of his father, Lee Kun-hee, in October 2020. He has served as the chaebol&#8217;s de facto leader since his father suffered a stroke in 2014. With Lee’s sentencing today, it is unclear who will take over his responsibilities at Samsung.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6rTln7UVcI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/samsung-vice-chairman-jay-y-lee-faces-nine-year-sentence-in-bribery-case/">Samsung vice chairman Jay Y. Lee faces nine-year sentence in bribery case</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Samsung vice chairman Jay Y. Lee faces nine-year sentence in bribery case&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/samsung-vice-chairman-jay-y-lee-faces-nine-year-sentence-in-bribery-case/embed/#?secret=6rTln7UVcI" data-secret="6rTln7UVcI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Charges against Lee included bribing Park to gain support for deals that would have helped Lee inherit control of Samsung from his father. The illegal payments played a major role in the corruption scandal that led to Park’s impeachment, arrest and 25-year prison sentence.</p>
<p>The bribery case is separate from another one Lee is involved in, over alleged accounting fraud and stock manipulation. Hearings in that case begun in October.</p>
<p>TechCrunch has contacted Samsung for comment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z4bHtlUbdN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/hearings-begin-in-samsung-vice-chairman-jay-y-lees-accounting-fraud-trial/">Hearings begin in Samsung vice chairman Jay Y. Lee&#8217;s accounting fraud trial</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hearings begin in Samsung vice chairman Jay Y. Lee&#8217;s accounting fraud trial&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/hearings-begin-in-samsung-vice-chairman-jay-y-lees-accounting-fraud-trial/embed/#?secret=Z4bHtlUbdN" data-secret="Z4bHtlUbdN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/samsung-vice-chairman-jay-y-lee-sent-back-to-prison-in-bribery-case/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097611</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goama lets developers integrate a social gaming platform into their apps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/goama-lets-developers-integrate-a-social-gaming-platform-into-their-apps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/goama-lets-developers-integrate-a-social-gaming-platform-into-their-apps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 07:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Go Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097594</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Goama (also known as Go Games) lets developers quickly integrate social games into their apps. Some of Goama’s clients have used it for promotional campaigns, while others rely on the platform, which introduces new games every week, to add a full-fledged gaming function to their app. The startup, which recently took part in SOSV’s accelerator [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://goama.com/">Goama</a> (also known as Go Games) lets developers quickly integrate social games into their apps. Some of Goama’s clients have used it for promotional campaigns, while others rely on the platform, which introduces new games every week, to add a full-fledged gaming function to their app.</p>
<p>The startup, which recently took part in SOSV’s accelerator program, presented last week during CES at the Taiwan Tech Arena pavilion. The event is over, but Goama&#8217;s <a href="https://livetour.istaging.com/d5777826-f405-40de-bfd5-b684605fafc8?index=1">virtual booth is still up</a>.</p>
<p>Some of Goama&#8217;s clients are &#8220;super apps,&#8221; or apps that offer several services and want to include games, too. To better serve super apps, Goama recently introduced a tournament model in addition to its subscription model for users.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>[gallery columns="2" size="medium" ids="2097598,2097599"]</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The startup says that integrating Goama&#8217;s platform can help apps grow brand awareness when people share their results or invite other players tournaments. It also increases user engagement, with players typically spending more than 16 minutes per session playing games. So far, the platform has a combined total of 2.5 million unique users.</p>
<p>The company currently focuses on Asia and Latin America, where mobile penetration is growing quickly, and works with more than 15 partners, including GCash and Rappi, to enable digital payments and communications. Its gaming platform&#8217;s user interface can be customized to match host apps and rewards can include points and other prizes that can be spent inside the app. Some companies that have used Goama include food delivery app FoodPanda, Snickers and money transfer app WavePay.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ces-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/goama-lets-developers-integrate-a-social-gaming-platform-into-their-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097594</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter is bringing Moments to Indian social app Dailyhunt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/twitter-moments-dailyhunt-india/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/twitter-moments-dailyhunt-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 07:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dailyhunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter moments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Five years after its launch, Twitter Moments is growing beyond the American social networking platform. On Monday, Twitter said it had partnered with Dailyhunt to bring Moments to the Indian social app. Dailyhunt app now has a dedicated tab called &#8220;Twitter Moments India&#8221; to showcase curated tweets pertaining to news and other events in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Five years after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/06/project-glacier/">its launch</a>, Twitter Moments is growing beyond the American social networking platform.</p>
<p>On Monday, Twitter said it had partnered with Dailyhunt to bring Moments to the Indian social app. Dailyhunt app now has a dedicated tab called &#8220;Twitter Moments India&#8221; to showcase curated tweets pertaining to news and other events in the world’s second largest internet market.</p>
<p>The partnership will allow Twitter to extend its reach in India, where according to mobile insight firm App Annie (data of which an industry executive shared with TechCrunch), it had fewer than 75 million monthly active users last month. Dailyhunt, which last month <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/google-leads-145-million-investment-in-indias-glance/">raised $100 million from Google, Microsoft and AlphaWave</a> among others, in comparison, claims to reach over 285 million users each day.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Unlike Twitter, Dailyhunt is also popular in smaller Indian cities and towns. The Indian social app, which serves users in 14 local languages, termed its partnership with Twitter as its &#8220;biggest collaboration&#8221; to date. The companies did not disclose financial terms of the deal.</p>
<p>“At Twitter, we are committed to doing what we can to ensure people can keep up with what the world is talking about at any given time. Moments &#8212; a curated set of Tweets about a particular topic &#8212; are a powerful way to do so. With this partnership with Dailyhunt, a platform that caters to diverse languages and readers from all parts of India, we are thrilled to extend Twitter Moments to the Dailyhunt app,&#8221; said Manish Maheshwari, managing director of Twitter India, in a statement. (Twitter is also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/15/sharechat-twitter-seriesd/">an investor in Indian social app ShareChat</a>, which in some ways, competes with Dailyhunt.)</p>
<p>Umang Bedi, co-founder of Dailyhunt and former head of Facebook India, said, “the past year has shown us the power of public opinion and awareness and it is incumbent upon us to mobilize this discourse by making information more accessible, more reliable and more engaging. When a trusted partner with our shared vision of enabling consumers to create and share information without barriers validates our platform with their presence, we know we are on the right path.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yIEhcfBj7S"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/15/sharechat-twitter-seriesd/">Twitter leads $100M round in top Indian regional social media platform ShareChat</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter leads $100M round in top Indian regional social media platform ShareChat&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/15/sharechat-twitter-seriesd/embed/#?secret=yIEhcfBj7S" data-secret="yIEhcfBj7S" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/twitter-moments-dailyhunt-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097591</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flipkart doubles down on rewards program, partners with 5,000 retail outlets in India</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/flipkart-supercoin-pay-loyalty-rewards-program-india-amazon/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/flipkart-supercoin-pay-loyalty-rewards-program-india-amazon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 07:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097588</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Flipkart on Monday launched SuperCoin Pay that its customers will be able to use across thousands of retail stores across the country as Walmart-owned e-commerce giant bets on its loyalty program to win and sustain its user base in the world’s second-largest internet market. The Bangalore-headquartered e-commerce giant said it had partnered with over 5,000 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Flipkart on Monday launched SuperCoin Pay that its customers will be able to use across thousands of retail stores across the country as Walmart-owned e-commerce giant bets on its loyalty program to win and sustain its user base in the world’s second-largest internet market.</p>
<p>The Bangalore-headquartered e-commerce giant said it had partnered with over 5,000 retail outlets including TimesPoints, Peter England, Cafe Coffee Day and Flying Machine across India to give its customers a “greater value and choice” to cash in on their Flipkart loyalty program, called SuperCoin Rewards. Flipkart customers earn these SuperCoins when they make purchases on the e-commerce platform.</p>
<p>Customers will be able to pay up to 100% of the bill value through SuperCoins, Flipkart said, pointing out that traditional loyalty programs have struggled to gain traction because they locked customers to their platform and made it difficult to convert reward points to cash.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Its retail partners operate in a wide range of categories including fashion, grocery, food and beverages, travel, health and wellness. These retail partners will offer a QR code to make it easier for Flipkart customers to redeem their rewards points.</p>
<p>The move comes as giant e-commerce firms in India aggressively <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/from-indias-richest-man-to-amazon-and-100s-of-startups-the-great-rush-to-win-neighborhood-stores/">partner with physical and digital stores</a> across the country. Amazon, too, has broadened its offering in recent years to offer coupons and discounts that Amazon Pay customers can redeem when making purchases at Urban Company, Domino’s, BigBazaar, More, Oyo Rooms, Licious, BookMyShow, Swiggy, and RedBus, for instance.</p>
<p>“The lines between online and offline shopping are becoming increasingly blurred, and our intention is to make the consumers&#8217; shopping experience more rewarding, no matter where they shop,” said Prakash Sikaria, vice president of Growth and Monetization at Flipkart, in a statement.</p>
<p>“Being a part of the SuperCoin programme enables our partners to reap the benefits of Flipkart’s 300 million customer base through a truly integrated rewards initiative,” he added.</p>
<p>Flipkart said customers on its platform have earned over a billion SuperCoin to date.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zpZFY1PEGV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/from-indias-richest-man-to-amazon-and-100s-of-startups-the-great-rush-to-win-neighborhood-stores/">From India&#8217;s richest man to Amazon and 100s of startups: The great rush to win neighborhood stores</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;From India&#8217;s richest man to Amazon and 100s of startups: The great rush to win neighborhood stores&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/from-indias-richest-man-to-amazon-and-100s-of-startups-the-great-rush-to-win-neighborhood-stores/embed/#?secret=zpZFY1PEGV" data-secret="zpZFY1PEGV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/flipkart-supercoin-pay-loyalty-rewards-program-india-amazon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097588</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Personio raises $125M on a $1.7B valuation for an HR platform targeting SMEs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/personio-raises-125m-on-a-1-7b-valuation-for-an-hr-platform-targeting-smes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/personio-raises-125m-on-a-1-7b-valuation-for-an-hr-platform-targeting-smes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 07:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the last year changing how (and where) many of us work, organizations have started to rethink how well they manage their employees, and what tools they use to do that. Today, one of the startups that is building technology to address this challenge is announcing a major round of funding that underscores its traction [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With the last year changing how (and where) many of us work, organizations have started to rethink how well they manage their employees, and what tools they use to do that. Today, one of the startups that is building technology to address this challenge is announcing a major round of funding that underscores its traction to date.</p>
<p><a href="http://personio.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Personio</a> &#8212; the German startup that targets small- and medium-sized businesses (10-2,000 employees) with an all-in-one HR platform covering recruiting and onboarding, payroll, absence tracking and other major HR functions &#8212; has picked up $125 million in funding at a $1.7 billion post-money valuation.</p>
<p>The Series D is being co-led by Index Ventures and Meritech, with previous backers Accel, Lightspeed Venture Partners, Northzone, Global Founders Capital and Picus all participating.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The $1.7 billion valuation is a big jump on the company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/20/personio-the-german-hr-platform-for-smes-raises-75m-series-c/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$500 million valuation a year ago</a>, and it comes after a year where the startup has doubled its revenues and was not on the hunt to raise, with much of its previous fundraising still in the bank.</p>
<p>Personio currently counts some 3,000 SMEs in Europe as customers.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">In an interview, Hanno Renner, the co-founder and CEO of Personio, said that the startup would be using the funding to continue building out the product &#8212; which operates a little like Workday, but built for much smaller organizations &#8212; as well as expanding its presence in Europe.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Although SMEs can be a notoriously challenging customer segment, Renner said that a new opportunity has emerged: A new wave of people in the SME sector have started to realise the value of having a modern and integrated HR platform.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;We started Personio in 2016 wanting to become the leading HR platform for midmarket companies, and we knew it could be a great company, but we realize it can be hard to grasp what HR really means,&#8221; he said. &#8220;But I think what has driven our business in the past year has been the realization that HR is not just an important part, but maybe the most important part, of any business.&#8221;</p>
<p>It may take one magic turn to convert users, he said, by providing (as one example) tools to recruit, sign contracts and onboard new employees remotely. Still, he acknowledges that the midmarket &#8212; especially those companies not built around technology &#8212; has been &#8220;lagging for years,&#8221; with many still working off Excel<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> spreadsheets, or even more surprisingly, pen and paper. &#8220;Supporting them by helping them to digitize in a more efficient way has been driving our business.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Personio is not the only startup hopeful that the shift in how we work will bring a new appreciation (and appetite) for purchasing HR tools. Others like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/hibob-raises-70m-on-a-500m-valuation-for-its-new-take-on-hr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hibob</a> have also seen a big boost in their business and have also been raising money to tap into the opportunity more aggressively.</p>
<p>Hibob is looking to build in more training tools, underscoring the feature race that Personio will also have to run to keep up.</p>
<p>But given the sheer numbers of SMBs in the European market &#8212; more than 25 million, and accounting for more than 99% of all enterprises, according to research from the <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/docsroom/documents/38365/attachments/2/translations/en/renditions/native" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">European Union</a> &#8212; the fact that many of them have yet to adopt any kind of HR platform at all, there remains a lot of growth for a number of players.</p>
<p>&#8220;SMEs are the backbone of the European economy, employing 100 million people across the continent, but it is also a sector that has been neglected by software companies focused predominantly on large enterprises,&#8221; Martin Mignot, a partner at Index who sits on Personio&#8217;s board, said in a statement. &#8220;Personio changes that, having created a set of powerful tools tailored to address the needs of small businesses.&#8221;</p>
<p>“We have had the pleasure of working with some of the most successful SaaS companies in the world, and given Personio&#8217;s success over the past five years and the immense market potential, we strongly believe in Personio’s ability to build an equally successful and impactful business,&#8221; added Alex Clayton, general partner at Meritech Capital, in his own statement. &#8220;After many great discussions with Hanno over recent years, we are now excited to be joining the journey.” Clayton is also joining the board with this round.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KeCeBcHHAT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/20/personio-the-german-hr-platform-for-smes-raises-75m-series-c/">Personio, the German HR platform for SMEs, raises $75M Series C at a $500M valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Personio, the German HR platform for SMEs, raises $75M Series C at a $500M valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/20/personio-the-german-hr-platform-for-smes-raises-75m-series-c/embed/#?secret=KeCeBcHHAT" data-secret="KeCeBcHHAT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/personio-raises-125m-on-a-1-7b-valuation-for-an-hr-platform-targeting-smes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097564</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Startups at CES showed how tech can help elderly people and their caregivers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/startups-at-ces-showed-how-tech-can-help-elderly-people-and-their-caregivers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/startups-at-ces-showed-how-tech-can-help-elderly-people-and-their-caregivers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 06:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Age tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seniors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The COVID-19 pandemic shined a harsh spotlight on the challenges many elderly people face. Older adults are among the highest-risk groups for developing cases that need hospitalization and nursing homes were especially vulnerable to outbreaks. While dealing with COVID-19, the elderly have also faced many other problems, including the difficulty of accessing medical care for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The COVID-19 pandemic shined a harsh spotlight on the challenges many elderly people face. Older adults are <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/aging/covid19-guidance.html">among the highest-risk groups</a> for developing cases that need hospitalization and nursing homes were especially vulnerable to outbreaks. While dealing with COVID-19, the elderly have also faced many other problems, including the difficulty of accessing medical care for chronic conditions during lockdowns and <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/hidden-covid-19-health-crisis-elderly-people-are-dying-isolation-n1244853">isolation</a>.</p>
<p>Many of these issues won’t go away after the pandemic. <a href="https://www.un.org/en/sections/issues-depth/ageing/">According to the United Nations</a>, the global population of people 65 and over is growing faster than any other age group. At the same time, there is a critical shortage of caregivers, especially for elderly people who <a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/10/why-home-could-be-the-safest-place-for-seniors-during-the-pandemic/">want to continue living at home </a>instead of moving into nursing homes.</p>
<p>Tech can help in many ways: By helping caregivers (and reducing burnout), allowing seniors to perform health monitoring at home and creating tools to combat isolation. During CES, there were several &#8220;age-tech&#8221; presentations. One of the most notable was AARP Innovation Lab, the nonprofit’s startup accelerator program. It presented nine companies at the virtual show.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2097583" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-2.29.28-PM.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2097583" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2097583" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-2.29.28-PM.png?w=680" alt="Zibrio's smart scale for assessing postural stability, or balance" width="680" height="666" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-2.29.28-PM.png 760w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-2.29.28-PM.png?resize=150,147 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-2.29.28-PM.png?resize=300,294 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-2.29.28-PM.png?resize=680,666 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-2.29.28-PM.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-2.29.28-PM.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-2.29.28-PM.png?resize=64,64 64w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2097583" class="wp-caption-text">Zibrio&#8217;s smart scale for assessing postural stability or balance. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Zibrio</p></div></p>
<p>One common theme among AARP&#8217;s group was tech that helps elderly people &#8220;age in place,&#8221; or stay in their homes or communities instead of moving into a nursing home. For example, <a href="https://www.wheelpad.com/">Wheel Pad </a>designs accessible home and work spaces that can be installed into existing structures and sites. <a href="https://www.mightyhealth.com/">Mighty Health</a> is an app that pairs users with health coaches, certified trainers and personalized nutrition plans, while <a href="https://www.zibrio.com/">Zibrio</a>, a scale that assesses users’ balance to predict if they are at risk for a fall, can also be incorporated into at-home routines.</p>
<p>Other startups from AARP Innovation Lab focus on helping caregivers, too. For example,<a href="https://www.fallcall.com/"> FallCall Solutions</a>’ creates Apple Watch apps that send alerts if a fall is detected and help family members check on users. Another app, called <a href="https://www.ianacare.com/">Ianacare</a>, helps family members coordinate caregiving tasks and ask for support. End-of-life planning is one of the most emotionally difficult processes for families, and <a href="https://www.joincake.com/">Cake</a>, an &#8220;end-of-life platform&#8221; helps by providing tools for estate and health care planning, as well as resources to help relatives cope with caregiving issues and grief.</p>
<p>Other startups center on medical care. For people with chronic conditions, <a href="https://www.foliahealth.com/">Folia Health</a> helps monitor the progress of treatments. On the clinical side, <a href="https://embleema.com/">Embleema</a>’s software allows clinical investigators to share data and design studies, making pharmaceutical research more efficient.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TJSZ5WGI7X"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/nobis-smart-lamp-alerts-caregivers-when-a-fall-is-detected/">Nobi’s smart lamp alerts caregivers when a fall is detected</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nobi’s smart lamp alerts caregivers when a fall is detected&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/nobis-smart-lamp-alerts-caregivers-when-a-fall-is-detected/embed/#?secret=TJSZ5WGI7X" data-secret="TJSZ5WGI7X" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Other noteworthy age-tech startups at CES included <a href="https://nobi.life/">Nobi</a>, a smart lamp that automatically turns on when users stand up and sends alerts to family members if they fall. Nobi can also be used in residences and nursing homes.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2097578" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.07.31-PM.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2097578" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2097578" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.07.31-PM.png?w=680" alt="Caregiver Smart Solution's app for caregivers to coordinate tasks" width="680" height="414" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.07.31-PM.png 1216w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.07.31-PM.png?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.07.31-PM.png?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.07.31-PM.png?resize=768,467 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.07.31-PM.png?resize=680,414 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.07.31-PM.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2097578" class="wp-caption-text">Caregiver Smart Solution&#8217;s app for caregivers to coordinate tasks. <strong>image Credits</strong>: Ianacare</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.caregiversmartsolutions.com/">Caregiver Smart Solutions</a> is a multifaceted platform that makes it easier for seniors to stay at home with a machine-learning-based app for early detection of potential health issues, fall sensors, monitors and emergency buttons. For people with incontinence, <a href="https://www.dfreeus.biz/">DFree</a>, a wearable device, can reduce stress by monitoring how full their bladder is with an ultrasound sensor and keeping track of their average time between bathroom visits. It’s available for both consumers and healthcare facilities.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2097584" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.02.31-PM.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2097584" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2097584" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.02.31-PM.png?w=680" alt="A diagram of companion robot Cutii's features" width="680" height="463" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.02.31-PM.png 1708w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.02.31-PM.png?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.02.31-PM.png?resize=300,204 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.02.31-PM.png?resize=768,523 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.02.31-PM.png?resize=680,463 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.02.31-PM.png?resize=1536,1047 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-18-at-12.02.31-PM.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2097584" class="wp-caption-text">A diagram of companion robot Cutii&#8217;s features. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Cutii</p></div></p>
<p>For elderly people living in nursing homes, <a href="https://rendever.com/">Rendever</a> is a virtual reality platform that wants to help reduce isolation. It can be used with reminiscence therapy, which guides individuals with dementia through experiences that remind them of their pasts and to allow virtual travel to landmarks. <a href="https://www.cutii.io/en">Cutii</a>, a companion robot, also seeks to reduce loneliness. While companion robots have been a mainstay of CES for years, Cutii sets itself apart with entertainment like music, games and live events. It also has video call and night patrol features.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uM9pvSkjME"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/03/venture-investing-in-eldertech/">Venture investing in elder tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture investing in elder tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/03/venture-investing-in-eldertech/embed/#?secret=uM9pvSkjME" data-secret="uM9pvSkjME" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ces-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/startups-at-ces-showed-how-tech-can-help-elderly-people-and-their-caregivers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097577</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Signal and Telegram are also growing in China — for now</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/telegram-and-signal-china/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/telegram-and-signal-china/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 06:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play Store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeChat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096915</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As fears over WhatsApp&#8217;s privacy policies send millions of users in the West to Signal and Telegram, the two encrypted apps are also seeing a slight user uptick in China, where WeChat has long dominated and the government has a tight grip on online communication. Following WhatsApp&#8217;s pop-up notification reminding users that it shares their [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As fears over WhatsApp&#8217;s privacy policies send millions of users in the West to Signal and Telegram, the two encrypted apps are also seeing a slight user uptick in China, where WeChat has long dominated and the government has a tight grip on online communication.</p>
<p>Following WhatsApp&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/daily-crunch-whatsapp-responds-to-privacy-backlash/">pop-up notification</a> reminding users that it shares their data with its parent Facebook, people began fleeing to alternate encrypted platforms. Telegram added 25 million just between January 10-13, the company said on its official Telegram channel, while Signal surged to the top of the App Store and Google Play Store in dozens of countries, TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/signal-brian-acton-talks-about-exploding-growth-monetization-and-whatsapp-data-sharing-outrage/">learned earlier</a>.</p>
<p>The migration was accelerated when, on January 7, Elon Musk <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/elon-musk-dunks-on-facebook-and-recommends-signal-in-wake-of-u-s-capitol-insurrection-attempt/">urged his 40 million Twitter followers to install Signal</a> in a tweet that likely stoked more interest in the end-to-end encryption messenger.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The growth of Telegram and Signal in China isn&#8217;t nearly as remarkable as their soaring popularity in regions where WhatsApp has been the mainstream chat app, but the uplift is a reminder that WeChat alternatives still exist in China in various capacities.</p>
<p>Signal amassed 9,000 new downloads from the China App Store between January 8 and 12, up 500% from the period between January 3 and 7, according to data from research firm Sensor Tower. Telegram added 17,000 downloads during January 8-12, up 6% from the January 3-7 duration. WhatsApp&#8217;s growth stalled, recording 10,000 downloads in both periods.</p>
<p>Sensor Tower estimates that Telegram has seen about 2.7 million total installs on China&#8217;s App Store, compared to 458,000 downloads from Signal and 9.5 million times from WhatsApp.</p>
<p>The fact that Telegram, Signal and WhatsApp are accessible in China might come as a surprise to some people. But China&#8217;s censorship decisions can be arbitrary and inconsistent. As censorship monitoring site Apple Censorship <a href="https://applecensorship.com/app-store-monitor/test/signal?l=">shows</a>, all major Western messengers are still available on the China App Store.</p>
<p>The situation for Android is trickier. Google services are largely blocked in China and Android users revert to Android app stores operated by local companies like Tencent and Baidu. <a href="https://medium.com/%E9%85%B8%E8%8F%9C%E6%94%B6%E8%97%8F%E9%A4%A8/signal-%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8%E4%BD%93%E9%AA%8C%E6%8A%A5%E5%91%8A-7372ccce4fdb">Neither Telegram nor Signal</a> is available on these third-party Android stores, but users with a tool that can bypass China&#8217;s Great Firewall, such as a virtual private network (VPN), can access Google Play and install the encrypted messengers.</p>
<p>The next challenge is actually using these apps. The major chat apps all get slightly different treatment from Beijing&#8217;s censorship apparatus. Some, like Signal, work perfectly without the need for a VPN. The catch is to sign up for Signal, a user must activate their account with a phone number, and Chinese phone numbers are tied to people&#8217;s real identities. Users have reported that WhatsApp occasionally works in China without a VPN, though it loads very slowly. And Facebook doesn&#8217;t work at all without a VPN.</p>
<p>&#8220;Some websites and apps can remain untouched until they reach a certain threshold of users at which point the authorities will try to block or disrupt the website or app,&#8221; said Charlie Smith, the pseudonymous head of Great Fire, an organization monitoring the Chinese internet that also runs Apple Censorship.</p>
<p>&#8220;Perhaps before this mass migration from WhatsApp, Signal did not have that many users in China. That might have changed over the last week in which case the authorities could be pondering restrictions for Signal,&#8221; Smith added.</p>
<p>To legally operate in China, companies must store their data within China and submit information to the authorities for security spot-checks, according to a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/01/chinas-strict-cybersecurity-laws-took-effect-today-potentially-impacting-foreign-businesses/">cybersecurity law enacted in 2017</a>. Apple, for instance, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/17/apples-icloud-user-data-in-china-is-now-handled-by-a-state-owned-mobile-operator/">partners with a local cloud provider</a> to store the data of its Chinese users.</p>
<p>The requirement raises questions about the type of interaction that Signal, Telegram and other foreign apps have with the Chinese authorities. Signal <a href="https://twitter.com/signalapp/status/1280166087577997312">said</a> it never turned over data to the Hong Kong police and had no data to turn over when concerns grew over Beijing&#8217;s heightened controls over the former British colony.</p>
<p>The biggest challenges for apps like Signal in China, according to Smith, will come from Apple, which is constantly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/apple-removes-two-rss-feed-readers-from-china-app-store/">under fire by investors</a> and activists for submitting to the Chinese authorities.</p>
<p>In recent years, the American giant has stepped up app crackdown in China, zeroing in on services that grant Chinese users access to unfiltered information, such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/29/apple-removes-vpn-apps-from-the-app-store-in-china/">VPN providers</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/apple-removes-two-rss-feed-readers-from-china-app-store/">RSS feed readers</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/pocket-castro-podcast-removed-from-china/">podcast apps</a>. Apple has also purged tens of thousands of unlicensed games in recent quarters<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/01/china-roundup-apple-closes-app-store-loophole/"> after a years-long delay</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Apple has a history of preemptively censoring apps that they believe the authorities would want censored,&#8221; Smith observed. &#8220;If Apple decides to remove Signal in China, either on its own initiative or in direct response to a request from the authorities, then Apple customers in China will be left with no secure messaging options.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="C60Ton2dLp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/17/apples-icloud-user-data-in-china-is-now-handled-by-a-state-owned-mobile-operator/">Apple&#8217;s iCloud user data in China is now handled by a state-owned mobile operator</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple&#8217;s iCloud user data in China is now handled by a state-owned mobile operator&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/17/apples-icloud-user-data-in-china-is-now-handled-by-a-state-owned-mobile-operator/embed/#?secret=C60Ton2dLp" data-secret="C60Ton2dLp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/telegram-and-signal-china/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096915</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK&#8217;s Bloom &#038; Wild raises $102M to seed its flower delivery service across Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/uks-bloom-wild-raises-102m-to-seed-its-flower-delivery-service-across-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/uks-bloom-wild-raises-102m-to-seed-its-flower-delivery-service-across-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097556</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bloom &#38; Wild, a London-based startup that takes an updated and online approach to the very traditional business of ordering and delivering flowers, has seen business blossom in the last year. And today, it is announcing a big round of funding to help it double down on the opportunity ahead. The company has raised £75 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.bloomandwild.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bloom &amp; Wild</a>, a London-based startup that takes an updated and online approach to the very traditional business of ordering and delivering flowers, has seen business blossom in the last year. And today, it is announcing a big round of funding to help it double down on the opportunity ahead.</p>
<p>The company has raised £75 million ($102 million), a Series D that it plans to use to continue expanding across Europe (in addition to the UK, it operates today in Ireland, France, Germany and Austria) as it also continues to build out the business through technology, hiring new talent, thinking up more ideas and new partnerships, such as a new deal with supermarket giant Sainsbury&#8217;s to spearhead a new brick-and-mortar push.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We’ve been extremely fortunate to have been able to continue trading when we know how tough the past nine months or so has been for many,&#8221; said Aron Gelbard, Bloom &amp; Wild&#8217;s co-founder &amp; CEO, in an emailed interview. &#8220;It’s been a real joy &amp; privilege to help keep our customers connected with their loved ones when we’ve all been missing being able to see our friends &amp; family. We’ve certainly seen strong sales during periods of national restrictions across our markets, but sales have held strong during periods of relatively limited restrictions as we’ve retained new customers and converted many of our new recipients too.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding is being led by General Catalyst, with Index Ventures, Novator, Latitude Ventures, D4 Ventures (established by Hanzade Dogan), and existing investors such as Burda Principal Investments also participating.</p>
<p>Bloom &amp; Wild is not disclosing its valuation, but rumors of the round that were floating last week (<a href="https://news.sky.com/story/online-florist-bloom-wild-blossoms-with-100m-fundraising-12179326" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">per Sky News</a>) pegged sources that said the valuation was around $500 million.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s funding round, in any case, comes on the heels of some very strong growth. Revenues for the company were up 160% in 2020, with some 4 million deliveries of flowers in that period &#8212; more than had ever been made in the lifetime of the company previously, it said. That helped push the company into the black, its first profitable year.</p>
<p>Founded in 2014, Bloom &amp; Wild had only raised around $35 million before this, according to <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/82588-51/company/profile" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PitchBook</a>, which estimated its pre-money valuation at just $88 million following its last round in 2018. In that context, $500 million represents a massive jump.</p>
<p>Now, you might be asking yourself, &#8220;How can people think about flowers at a time like this? We&#8217;re in the midst of a global pandemic, for crying out loud.&#8221;</p>
<p>And indeed, that is so. But it seems that there is a special place for flower-based gifts, whether for other people or just for ourselves, that are appreciated especially when times are hard.</p>
<p>And while we&#8217;ve also seen people move quickly past that extra toilet paper, face masks and other practical purchases to click buy on many not-totally-essential indulgences &#8212; from fancy food and drinks through to nicer furniture since they&#8217;re spending so much time at home &#8212; I&#8217;d argue flowers have a unique position in the indulgence/gifting pantheon.</p>
<p>In the midst of a health pandemic that has severely curtailed how people can interact with each other in person, getting flowers from a person can take on a new and sometimes deeper meaning. The physical presence &#8212; the colors, the smells, the rustle of life &#8212; they convey can be a proxy for the human interaction that we&#8217;re missing.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re privileged to have played our part in keeping people connected in this difficult period, and I’m proud of our growing team for scaling our operations whilst maintaining the signature thought and care we put into every order,&#8221; said Gelbard in a statement. &#8220;With this new backing from General Catalyst and Index we start 2021 with renewed energy to pursue our vision of becoming the world&#8217;s leading and most loved flower company.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever ordered flowers for someone or for yourself, you know there is no shortage of options for doing so. In the UK alone there are some 7,500 florists according to the British Florist Association, and that&#8217;s not counting thousands more online-only retailers (like Bloom &amp; Wild) or the many services that knit these together into wider delivery networks such as Interflora or FTD. FTD has been something of a consolidator here: in 2018 it acquired a US flower delivery startup called BloomThat (which likened itself to an Uber for flowers).</p>
<p>While some people still prefer to shop for tangible things like flowers in person, a lot of that has moved into the virtual world over the years &#8212; especially for those ordering flowers to be delivered to someone &#8212; making it in some ways much easier to launch and grow online-only flower businesses.</p>
<p>Bloom &amp; Wild&#8217;s product approach is to sell flowers as bouquets, and to give people the option of making the smaller of those bouquets extremely easy to deliver, by designing a box that fits through the typical UK mail slot (either in your front door or elsewhere).</p>
<p>The bouquets it sells, meanwhile, are Instagrammably eye-catching, created for the kind of person who might discover them on that social network (where it has around 250,000 followers), and targeted at our modern predicament. (For example, the bouquet pictured above is called &#8220;The Ezra&#8221;. Its description: &#8220;This cocktail of vibrant oranges and soft lilacs reminds us of holidays in the sun. And the people we’d spend them with. Missing your travel buddy? Send them this instant day-brightener.&#8221;)</p>
<p>There are options for ordering flowers for offices &#8212; although these are almost certainly not getting ordered as much days &#8212; and to build subscriptions, as you might with any other D2C product you order online. And once Bloom &amp; Wild gets to know you and what you like, that will inform how and which flowers on the service are presented to you. Over time it&#8217;s moved into more than flowers &#8212; it sold Christmas trees this season, and offers a few gifts alongside its bouquets &#8212; and it is gradually building out a brick-and-mortar presence, too.</p>
<p>But most of all, it seems the company has seen a surge of interest not just because of the efficiency and targeting of its service, but because it has gotten the product right &#8212; specifically delivering flowers that people like.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Gelbard points out that the company has &#8220;the most direct supply chain in the flower industry, sourcing directly from growers. This means our customers get excellent value and their flowers last longer, arriving in bud and regularly blooming for up to ten days or more.&#8221;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">He also notes that the company has built a &#8220;bespoke technology and data science platform&#8221; focused on a quick and easy ordering experience on app or web. Lastly, &#8220;in a traditionally commoditised industry reliant on paid search, we’ve taken an innovative approach to product and brand development,&#8221; he notes, pointing to the &#8220;letterbox flower&#8221; invention.</p>
<p>“Bloom &amp; Wild has infused the traditional flower giving experience with predictive analytics and technology to deliver a fresher, less-travelled bouquet to the people you care most about,” said Adam Valkin, MD, General Catalyst, in a statement. “What’s most impressive about Aron and his team has been their duality of focus since launch. They’re bringing industry-leading efficiency to the intricate supply chain challenges of flower delivery while simultaneously building a beloved experience that connects with consumers in a remarkably authentic way.”</p>
<p>Martin Mignot, Partner at Index Ventures added: “Bloom &amp; Wild team have reinvented every aspect of flower delivery and gifting, challenging the status quo at every stage. Through relentless execution, Aron and his team have created a delightful experience for customers, becoming the fastest growing flower business in Europe. We’re thrilled to partner with them as they scale internationally.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/uks-bloom-wild-raises-102m-to-seed-its-flower-delivery-service-across-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097556</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virgin Orbit reaches orbit for the first time</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/virgin-orbit-reaches-orbit-for-the-first-time/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/virgin-orbit-reaches-orbit-for-the-first-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 19:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aircraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boeing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LauncherOne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit launched its LauncherOne rocket to orbit for the first time today, with a successful demonstration mission that carried a handful of satellites and delivered them successfully to low-Earth orbit on behalf of NASA. It&#8217;s a crucial milestone for the small satellite launch company, and the first time the company has shown that its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Virgin Orbit launched its LauncherOne rocket to orbit for the first time today, with a successful demonstration mission that carried a handful of satellites and delivered them successfully to low-Earth orbit on behalf of NASA. It&#8217;s a crucial milestone for the small satellite launch company, and the first time the company has shown that its hybrid carrier aircraft/small payload orbital delivery rocket works as intended, which should set the company up to begin commercial operations of its launch system very soon.</p>
<p>This is the second attempt at reaching orbit for Virgin Orbit, after a first try in late May <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/25/virgin-orbits-first-orbital-test-flight-cut-short-after-rocket-released-from-carrier-aircraft/">ended with the LauncherOne rocket initiating an automatic safety shutdown</a> of its engines shortly after detaching from the &#8220;Cosmic Girl&#8221; carrier aircraft, a modified Boeing 747 that transports the rocket to its launch altitude. The company said that it learned a lot from that attempt, including identifying the error that caused the failsafe engine shut down, which it corrected in advance of today&#8217;s mission.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MzfIXT4psb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/25/virgin-orbits-first-orbital-test-flight-cut-short-after-rocket-released-from-carrier-aircraft/">Virgin Orbit&#8217;s first orbital test flight cut short after rocket released from carrier aircraft</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Virgin Orbit&#8217;s first orbital test flight cut short after rocket released from carrier aircraft&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/25/virgin-orbits-first-orbital-test-flight-cut-short-after-rocket-released-from-carrier-aircraft/embed/#?secret=MzfIXT4psb" data-secret="MzfIXT4psb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Virgin&#8217;s Cosmic Girl took off at just before 2 p.m. EST, and then released LauncherOne from its wing at roughly 2:40 p.m. EST. LauncherOne had a &#8220;clean separation&#8221; as intended, and then ignited its own rocket engines and quickly accelerated to the point where it was undergoing the maximum amount of aerodynamic pressure (called max q in the aerospace industry). LauncherOne&#8217;s main engine then cut off after its burn, and its payload stage separated, crossing the Karman line and entering space for the first time.</p>
<p>It achieved orbit at around 2:49 p.m. EST and released its payload of satellites to their target orbit sometime later on schedule, making the mission a complete success.</p>
<p>Virgin Orbit&#8217;s unique value proposition in the small launch market is that it can take off and land from traditional runways thanks to its carrier aircraft and midair rocket launch approach. That should provide flexibility in terms of launch locations, allowing it to be more responsive to customer needs in terms of geographies and target orbital deliveries.</p>
<p>In 2017, Virgin Orbit was spun out of Virgin Galactic, to focus exclusively on small payload orbital launch. Virgin Galactic then devoted itself entirely to its own mission of offering commercial human spaceflight. Virgin Orbit itself create its own subsidiary earlier this year, called VOX Space, which intends to use LauncherOne to deliver small satellites to orbit specifically for the U.S. national security market.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/virgin-orbit-reaches-orbit-for-the-first-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097522</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
