<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 22:02:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>With an eye for what&#8217;s next, longtime operator and VC Josh Elman gets pulled into Apple</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/with-an-eye-for-whats-next-longtime-operator-and-vc-josh-elman-gets-pulled-into-apple/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/with-an-eye-for-whats-next-longtime-operator-and-vc-josh-elman-gets-pulled-into-apple/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 21:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greylock Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Elman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Josh Elman is moving over to Apple, he announced on Twitter today, saying he will be focused on the company&#8217;s App Store and helping &#8220;customers discover the best apps for them.&#8221; Asked for more details about his new role, Elman referred us to Apple, which confirmed his employment but declined to offer more, including about [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/josh-elman" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="josh-elman">Josh Elman <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is moving over to Apple, he announced on Twitter today, saying he will be focused on the company&#8217;s App Store and helping &#8220;customers discover the best apps for them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Asked for more details about his new role, Elman referred us to <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="apple">Apple, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> which confirmed his employment but declined to offer more, including about his new title. (This is typical operating procedure for the tech giant.)</p>
<p>Certainly, Elman has plenty of experience with fast-growing technologies and popular apps in particular.  One of his first jobs out of Stanford was with RealNetworks, a bubble-era internet streaming company that <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/realnetworks-launches-hot-ipo/">went public</a> in 1997, three years after it was founded. (It remains publicly traded, though its market cap is just $60 million these days.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>After RealNetworks, it was on to LinkedIn, which Elman joined in 2004 as a senior product manager when the company was just two years old.  From there, Elman worked in product management at the custom apparel and accessories company Zazzle, then at Facebook, then Twitter.</p>
<p>Perhaps unsurprisingly, the venture firm Greylock brought Elman into the fold in 2011 as a principal, and by 2013, he was a general partner, investing in social networking deals throughout like Musical.ly (Bytedance <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/09/chinas-toutiao-is-buying-musical-ly-in-a-deal-worth-800m-1b/">acquired</a> the company and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-bytedance-musically/chinas-bytedance-scrubs-musical-ly-brand-in-favor-of-tiktok-idUSKBN1KN0BW">turned it into TikTok</a>); Nextdoor (which is reportedly <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-10-16/nextdoor-is-said-to-eye-public-listing-5-billion-valuation">eyeing ways to go public</a>); Houseparty (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/12/18662708/epic-games-houseparty-acquisition-fortnite-video-chat">acquired</a> last year by Epic Games, which is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/24/21531873/epic-apple-fortnite-app-store-lawsuit">now suing Apple</a>); and Discord (which is sewing up a private funding deal at a valuation of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/discord-is-close-to-closing-a-round-that-would-value-the-company-at-up-to-7b/">roughly $7 billion</a>).</p>
<p>Somewhat unexpectedly, in 2018, Elman <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/14/robinhood-hires-josh-elman-as-vp-of-product-wholl-stay-at-greylock/">left</a> his full-time role with Greylock to join a company notably not in the firm&#8217;s portfolio, the stock-trading platform Robinhood. As interesting, though he took on the role of VP of product at the popular and fast-growing startup, he didn&#8217;t cut ties with Greylock entirely, taking on the title of venture partner and remaining on as a board member to his companies.</p>
<p>Asked about the move, Elman told TC at the time that he had &#8220;started talking with a few of my partners about how I want to spend the next decade of my professional life. What gets me the most energized is when I can dig in on product with a hyper-growth company.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ultimately, the role didn&#8217;t last long, with Elman <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/josh-elman-robinhood-greylock-fintech-2019-11">leaving last November</a> after less than two years on the job. Now Elman &#8212; who said he&#8217;s stepping away from some of his Greylock-related board seats &#8212;  has a new chance to do what he loves most that from one of the most powerful perches in the world, the App Store.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m really excited to get to build ways to help over a billion customers and millions of developers connect,&#8221; he <a href="https://twitter.com/joshelman/status/1333471689183662081">tweeted earlier</a>. He added in the same thread: &#8220;I recently found my college resume. My career objective was &#8216;To create great technology that changes people’s lives&#8217;. Still at it :)&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/with-an-eye-for-whats-next-longtime-operator-and-vc-josh-elman-gets-pulled-into-apple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080596</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vista acquires Gainsight for $1.1B, adding to its growing enterprise arsenal</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/vista-acquires-gainsight-for-1-1b-adding-to-its-growing-enterprise-arsenal/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/vista-acquires-gainsight-for-1-1b-adding-to-its-growing-enterprise-arsenal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 20:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gainsight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vista equity partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vista Equity Partners hasn&#8217;t been shy about scooping up enterprise companies over the years, and today it added to a growing portfolio with its purchase of Gainsight. The company&#8217;s software helps clients with customer success, meaning it helps create a positive customer experience when they interact with your brand, making them more likely to come [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.vistaequitypartners.com/">Vista Equity Partners</a> hasn&#8217;t been shy about scooping up enterprise companies over the years, and today it added to a growing portfolio with its purchase of <a href="http://gainsight.com">Gainsight</a>. The company&#8217;s software helps clients with customer success, meaning it helps create a positive customer experience when they interact with your brand, making them more likely to come back and recommend you to others. Sources pegged the price tag at $1.1 billion.</p>
<p>As you might expect, both parties are putting a happy face on the deal, talking about how they can work together to grow <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/gainsight" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="gainsight">Gainsight <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> further. Certainly, other companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/12/ping-shapes-new-identity-after-600-million-acquisition/">like Ping Identity</a> seem to have benefited from joining forces with Vista. Being part of a well-capitalized firm allowed them to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/02/ping-identity-expands-mission-to-customers-with-unboundid-acquisition/">make some strategic investments</a> along the way to eventually <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/23/ping-identity-files-for-100m-ipo/">going public last year</a>.</p>
<p>Gainsight and Vista are certainly hoping for a similar outcome in this case. Monti Saroya, co-head of the Vista Flagship Fund and senior managing director at the firm, sees a company with a lot of potential that could expand and grow with help from Vista&#8217;s consulting arm, which helps portfolio companies with different aspects of their business like sales, marketing and operations.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We are excited to partner with the Gainsight team in its next phase of growth, helping the company to expand the category it has created and deliver even more solutions that drive retention and growth to businesses across the globe,&#8221; Saroya said in a statement.</p>
<p>Gainsight CEO Nick Mehta likes the idea of being part of Vista&#8217;s portfolio of enterprise companies, many of whom are using his company&#8217;s products.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve known Vista for years, since 24 of their portfolio companies use Gainsight. We&#8217;ve seen Gainsight clients like JAMF and Ping Identity partner with Vista and then go public. We believe we are just getting started with customer success, so we wanted the right partner for the long term and we&#8217;re excited to work with Vista on the next phase of our journey,&#8221; Mehta told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Brent Leary, principle analyst at CRM Essentials, who covers the sales and marketing space, says that it appears that Vista is piecing together a sales and marketing platform that it could flip or go public in a few years.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not only the power that&#8217;s in the platform, it&#8217;s also the money. And Vista seems to be piecing together an engagement platform based on the acquisitions of Gainsight, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/european-unicorns-are-no-longer-a-pipe-dream/">Pipedrive</a> and even last year&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/24/vista-equity-partners-buys-acquia-for-1b/">Acquia</a> purchase. Vista isn&#8217;t afraid to spend big money, if they can make even bigger money in a couple years if they can make these pieces fit together,&#8221; Leary told TechCrunch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="J5KVkvO0GO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/24/vista-equity-partners-buys-acquia-for-1b/">Vista Equity Partners buys Acquia for $1B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Vista Equity Partners buys Acquia for $1B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/24/vista-equity-partners-buys-acquia-for-1b/embed/#?secret=J5KVkvO0GO" data-secret="J5KVkvO0GO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While Gainsight exits as a unicorn, the deal might not have been the outcome it was looking for. The company raised more than $187 million, according to <a href="https://pitchbook.com/">PitchBook data</a>, though its fundraising had slowed in recent years. Gainsight raised $50 million in April of 2017 at a post-money valuation of $515 million, again per PitchBook. In July of 2018 it added $25 million to its coffers, and the final entry was a small debt investment raised in 2019.</p>
<p>It could be that the startup saw its growth slow down, leaving it somewhere between ready for new venture investment and profitability. That’s a gap that PE shops like Vista look for, write a check, shake up a company and hopefully exit at an elevated price.</p>
<p>Gainsight hired <a href="https://www.gainsight.com/press/release/gainsight-welcomes-new-chief-revenue-officer-jeff-depa/">a new chief revenue officer</a> last month, notably. <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexkonrad/2020/11/30/gainsight-acquired-by-vista-at-1-billion-price/?sh=2eb1b1ca7c70">Per Forbes</a>, the company was on track to reach “about” $100 million ARR by the end of 2020, giving it a revenue multiple of around 11x in the deal. That’s under current market norms, which could imply that Gainsight had either lower gross margins than comparable companies, or as previously noted, that its growth had slowed.</p>
<p>A $1.1 billion exit is never something to bemoan &#8212; and every startup wants to become a unicorn &#8212; but Gainsight and Mehta are well known, and we were hoping for the details only an S-1 could deliver. Perhaps one day with Vista&#8217;s help that could happen.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="j1hfNETaXN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/private-equity-firms-can-offer-enterprise-startups-a-viable-exit-option/">Private equity firms can offer enterprise startups a viable exit option</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Private equity firms can offer enterprise startups a viable exit option&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/private-equity-firms-can-offer-enterprise-startups-a-viable-exit-option/embed/#?secret=j1hfNETaXN" data-secret="j1hfNETaXN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/vista-acquires-gainsight-for-1-1b-adding-to-its-growing-enterprise-arsenal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080599</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Infogrid raises $15.5M from Northzone to retrofit buildings with &#8216;smart&#8217; IoT</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/infogrid-raises-15-5m-from-northzone-to-retrofit-buildings-with-smart-iot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/infogrid-raises-15-5m-from-northzone-to-retrofit-buildings-with-smart-iot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 20:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ambient intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facilities management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infogrid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeppe zink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northzone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080634</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Infogrid, an IoT startup which can retrofit an existing building to make it &#8220;smart&#8221;, has raised $15.5 million. The Series A funding round was led by Northzone, with participation from JLL Spark, Concrete VC, The Venture Collective, Jigsaw VC, an unnamed real estate investment group and an unnamed large international asset owner, although one report [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.infogrid.io/">Infogrid</a>, an IoT startup which can retrofit an existing building to make it &#8220;smart&#8221;, has raised $15.5 million. The Series A funding round was led by Northzone, with participation from JLL Spark, Concrete VC, The Venture Collective, Jigsaw VC, an unnamed real estate investment group and an unnamed large international asset owner, although <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/ex-army-officer-marches-on-with-10m-funding-for-ai-firm-infogrid-12147171">one</a> report speculated that it is Starwood Capital, the property-focused investor.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/infogrid-d81e" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="infogrid-d81e">Infogrid’s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> platform combines IoT sensors with proprietary AI analysis and has had some success re-vamping facilities management (FM) for some of the world’s largest FM providers, such as global banks, supermarkets, restaurant chains and the NHS. Infogrid also has an &#8220;impact-style&#8221; mission to enable businesses to reduce the environmental and social cost of their buildings while simultaneously benefitting their bottom line and asset values.</p>
<p>Infogrid’s system can detect when refrigerated products are being kept outside the required temperature range, measure air quality and check for virus risk indicators such as Legionnaires&#8217; disease in water pipes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>William Cowell de Gruchy, founder/CEO and a former British Army officer, said in a statement: “Until now, the lack of viable and scalable technology has meant that facilities management is one of the last industries to be enhanced by digitization, despite covering the world’s largest asset class. Infogrid’s end-to-end smart building system finally arms organizations with insight to take control and take action. This new era of insight and automation will bring about a positive impact on the efficiencies of businesses, the wellbeing of employees, and the environmental footprint of buildings.”</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/jeppe-zink" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="jeppe-zink">Jeppe Zink, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> partner at Northzone added: “With the world undergoing the largest wave of urban growth in history, the built environment already generates 39% of annual global carbon emissions. We were instantly drawn to Infogrid for its ability to future-proof buildings in the long-term.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/infogrid-raises-15-5m-from-northzone-to-retrofit-buildings-with-smart-iot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080634</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Union Labs believes uniting VC and corporate expertise can help startups solve &#8216;hard tech&#8217; problems</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/union-labs-believes-uniting-vc-and-corporate-expertise-can-help-startups-solve-hard-tech-problems/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/union-labs-believes-uniting-vc-and-corporate-expertise-can-help-startups-solve-hard-tech-problems/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 20:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078778</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chris Kim and Nate Williams formed Union Labs with the conviction that investors and companies aren&#8217;t collaborating closely enough to ensure the success of the startups they back. Kim is the former co-founder and chief technology officer at the automatic lock company August. He first met Williams when the company was attempting to create a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chris Kim and Nate Williams formed <a href="https://unionlabs.com/">Union Labs</a> with the conviction that investors and companies aren&#8217;t collaborating closely enough to ensure the success of the startups they back.</p>
<p>Kim is the former co-founder and chief technology officer at the automatic lock company August. He first met Williams when the company was attempting to create a consortium of stakeholders for the Internet of Things market.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">Nate loved the go-to-market side when he came on board. He led the charge for us getting into retail,&#8221; Kim said. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Later, when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/19/swedish-lock-maker-assa-abloy-set-to-acquire-august-home/">August was acquired in 2017</a>, the two men continued to work together after Williams took a role as an entrepreneur in residence at Kleiner Perkins. Kim would assist in due diligence as the two continued to refine the thesis that they&#8217;d worked on at August &#8212; that uniting stakeholders was a critical component of success for new technology companies.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That thesis became the organizing principle for their Union Labs fund, which has raised $29 million of a targeted $50 million fund. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re starting to see this bifurcation between really, really hard deep tech firms versus other firms that might [have] one out of five of their deals being deep tech. Chris and I saw a lane for &#8216;applied&#8217; deeptech,&#8221; said Williams.</p>
<p>This lane runs through the early-stage technology firms that need guidance from operators at hardware companies rather than the software-as-a-service experts that Williams and Kim said populate most venture capital firms. &#8220;Educating a SaaS partnership about &#8216;hard tech&#8217; is super hard,&#8221; said Williams.</p>
<p>In addition to Williams and Kim, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/union-lab" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="union-lab">Union Labs <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has two directors: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomastlee/">Thomas Lee</a>, who spent years working at Enphase Energy, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/leannie/">Annie Le</a>, a former chief operating officer at Pryze.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One example of the kinds of startups that the new Union Labs fund is hoping to back is Strella Biotechnology, a company that has developed sensors to monitor the ethylene gas emitted by produce to determine the freshness of fruits and vegetables.<br />
</span></p>
<p>Union Labs is targeting 20 investments with the first fund, including 15 direct investments and another three-to-five companies that it intends to incubate.</p>
<p>The other public investments in the company&#8217;s portfolio include the car rental optimization service Carnect and a toolkit for home safety called Encircle Labs (that&#8217;s not revealing too much about its business).</p>
<p>A fourth portfolio company, that has yet to publicly reveal its services, is working on solving problems in field service management related to training.</p>
<p>While these issues have presented challenges for industry, with the exception of the sensor business, none of them could be considered &#8220;hard tech&#8221; from a hardware perspective&#8230; and indeed, many of them resemble the software-as-a-service businesses that many firms are writing checks to support.</p>
<p>For its part, Union Labs is writing pre-seed and seed-stage checks with an average size of $890,000 for an 11% ownership stake. Williams says the firm will invest anywhere from $500,000 to $1.5 million.</p>
<p>For startups, one selling point for the firm is the connection it still maintains with the Internet of Things consortium Williams helped to establish for August Homes. Through the consortium Williams has been able to pull together corporate backers in telecommunications, utilities, consumer electronics and insurance, along with Kleiner Perkins and GV (which Williams said are investors).</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;One of the things we’ve seen is the rise of corporate venture capital firms,&#8221; said Williams. And both Kim and Williams want their firm to act as a hybrid, between corporate venture capital and a traditional venture firm. </span></p>
<p>Time will tell if they can turn their mission into something more than a marketing message.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/union-labs-believes-uniting-vc-and-corporate-expertise-can-help-startups-solve-hard-tech-problems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078778</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strike first, strike hard, no mercy: How emerging managers can win</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/strike-first-strike-hard-no-mercy-how-emerging-managers-can-win/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/strike-first-strike-hard-no-mercy-how-emerging-managers-can-win/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 20:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valuation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the pursuit of striking first, striking hard and never letting up, it’s critical to avoid getting caught up in the day-to-day execution and losing sight of the bigger picture.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">TX Zhuo</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/TXZhuo">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tianxiangzhuo">TX Zhuo</a> is the managing partner of <a href="http://fika.vc/">Fika Ventures</a>, focusing on fintech, enterprise software and marketplace opportunities.
	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/03/a-covid-19-resilience-test-for-b2b-companies/">A COVID-19 resilience test for B2B companies</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/30/discovering-that-deckhands-make-great-waiters-and-why-this-matters/">Discovering that deckhands make great waiters &#8212; and why this matters</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Huston Collins</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/hustoncollins">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/huston-collins/">Huston Collins</a> is an investor at <a href="http://www.fika.vc/">Fika Ventures</a>. He was previously an associate at Greenspring Associates where he started the firm’s machine learning platform.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Like many of us during COVID-19, I’ve found myself watching a bit more TV than I’m typically accustomed to. My latest binge? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/22/youtube-reds-karate-kid-sequel-cobra-kai-drops-new-trailer/">&#8220;The Karate Kid&#8221; series continuation &#8220;Cobra Kai&#8221;</a> on Netflix.</p>
<p>A long-time fan of &#8220;The Karate Kid,&#8221; I find my style’s a bit more <em>Miyagi-Do</em>, but, in reflecting upon my last few years as a founding GP at a young VC firm, I see some parallels between what it takes to win as an emerging manager and the mantras by which the Cobra Kai school abides.</p>
<p>Before diving into that, let me quickly set the stage for what the competitive landscape looks like for emerging managers these days. I’ll focus primarily on the seed landscape here, but the Cobra Kai framework applies just as readily to later stage funds as well.</p>
<p>Leading up to the coronavirus pandemic, the venture industry saw a record number of dollars raised by seed funds less than $100 million in size. As is the case across stages however, there has been a notable decline in seed volume in the wake of COVID-19.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2079663" style="width: 1018px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2079663" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2079663" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/usfundraising.png" alt="US fundraising activity for sub $100M seed rounds" width="1008" height="256" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/usfundraising.png 1008w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/usfundraising.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/usfundraising.png?resize=300,76 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/usfundraising.png?resize=768,195 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/usfundraising.png?resize=680,173 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/usfundraising.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1008px) 100vw, 1008px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2079663" class="wp-caption-text">U.S. fundraising activity for sub-$100M seed rounds. Data source: PitchBook-NVCA Venture Monitor. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fika Ventures</p></div></p>
<p>The opposing dynamics of a contraction in deal volume and an unprecedented amount of readily available investable capital has led to a tremendous amount of competition for the highest-quality deals. This flight to quality can be clearly seen in the rise of seed valuations in the upper quartile compared to the decline in other cohorts. Amid a backdrop of COVID chaos, upper quartile valuations have hit an all-time high.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2079690" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2079690" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2079690" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/premoneyvaluations.png" alt="angel/seed pre-money valuations by quartile" width="1024" height="701" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/premoneyvaluations.png 1166w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/premoneyvaluations.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/premoneyvaluations.png?resize=300,205 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/premoneyvaluations.png?resize=768,526 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/premoneyvaluations.png?resize=680,465 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/premoneyvaluations.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2079690" class="wp-caption-text">Angel/seed pre-money valuations by quartile. Data source: PitchBook-NVCA Venture Monitor. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fika Ventures</p></div></p>
<p>Due to their smaller fund size and prescriptive portfolio construction mandates, emerging managers have little leeway in terms of the valuations at which they can invest — their ownership requirements and check size limits impose a hard ceiling to which their investors hold them strictly accountable.</p>
<p>If budging on valuation is not a viable tactic to compete against established firms — which, in addition to their ability to be less price sensitive <em>also</em> boast more recognizable brand names, larger teams and higher AUM that affords them higher budgets for platform resources — how can emerging managers win? Enter Cobra Kai.</p>
<h2>Strike first</h2>
<p>Let’s face it. As an emerging manager, the chances of you winning a deal once the established players start to circle drops precipitously. In order to win, you need to have a first-mover advantage.</p>
<p>On a practical level, there are two windows of opportunity to achieve this:<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/strike-first-strike-hard-no-mercy-how-emerging-managers-can-win/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079570</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EveryAction acquires Mobilize, the Democratic volunteering platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/everyaction-acquires-mobilize/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/everyaction-acquires-mobilize/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 20:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[democrats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EveryAction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobilize]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nonprofit donor management platform EveryAction is buying Mobilize, a company that connects Democratic campaigns to volunteers and helps marshal activists toward progressive causes. Mobilize, formerly known as MobilizeAmerica, grew out of Higher Ground Labs, an incubator focused on leveraging tech for left-leaning political causes and campaigns. With the acquisition, EveryAction can now extend Mobilize&#8217;s organizing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nonprofit donor management platform <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/everyaction" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="everyaction">EveryAction <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is buying <a href="https://join.mobilize.us/">Mobilize</a>, a company that connects Democratic campaigns to volunteers and helps marshal activists toward progressive causes. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/mobilizeamerica" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="mobilizeamerica">Mobilize, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> formerly known as MobilizeAmerica, grew out of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/03/higher-ground-labs-2018-dnc-startups/">Higher Ground Labs</a>, an incubator focused on leveraging tech for left-leaning political causes and campaigns.</p>
<p>With the acquisition, EveryAction can now extend <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/mobilize-census-civic-tech-getoutthecount/">Mobilize&#8217;s organizing tools</a> to its existing base of more than 15,000 clients, which includes the Sierra Club and the Human Rights Campaign. EveryAction is a nonprofit-focused wing of NGP VAN, a company that provides much of the digital infrastructure for the Democratic Party. The terms of the Mobilize deal were not disclosed.</p>
<p>Mobilize, founded in early 2017, rode the wave of Trump-era activism on the left to become a ubiquitous tool helping progressive campaigns translate online interest and energy into action. The platform powered outreach for many candidates in 2020&#8217;s Democratic primary, including now President-elect Joe Biden&#8217;s campaign, who continued to use Mobilize into the general election.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>After Trump&#8217;s surprise win in 2016 — and the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/oct/08/trump-digital-director-brad-parscale-facebook-advertising">surprising strategies</a> that got the campaign there — Democrats turned to the startup scene to hone new tools. If the last four years served as a testing ground for Democratic political startups, 2020 sees them on the cusp of a new era altogether.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Mobilize raised a $3.75 million Series A round led by progressive tech incubator Higher Ground Labs. Chris Sacca’s Lowercase Capital and LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman, a prominent Democratic donor, also participated in the Series A. Mobilize&#8217;s acquisition follows another recent exit connected to Higher Ground Labs: In August, Social Capital, founded by billionaire ex-Facebooker Chamath Palihapitiya, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/18/social-capital-chamath-palihapitiyas-next-big-hustle/">picked up text banking platform Hustle</a>.</p>
<p>Within EveryAction, Mobilize will become its own unit led by Mobilize CEO and co-founder Alfred Johnson. The company&#8217;s existing team will move over into the new division under EveryAction&#8217;s umbrella. Mobilize co-founder and president Allen Kramer will also move over to EveryAction as deputy general manager of organizing.</p>
<p>&#8220;EveryAction is the leading software provider to nonprofits with clients like the National Audubon Society, Planned Parenthood Federation of America, and the United Nations Foundation,&#8221; Johnson told TechCrunch. &#8220;They are uniquely poised to bring our best-in-class offering for events and volunteer management to these very deserving organizations.&#8221;</p>
<p>Prior to the acquisition, EveryAction was already connected to Mobilize as an integration on its platform, and Johnson called the news a &#8220;natural evolution&#8221; of that relationship. &#8220;Our two companies are extremely aligned in mission: to help cause-driven organizations build bigger movements by driving and deepening supporter engagement,&#8221; Johnson said. &#8220;Together, we can help more people do more good.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="V5re0yJ2Ri"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/01/higher-ground-labs/">Higher Ground Labs is betting tech can help sway the 2020 elections for Democrats</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Higher Ground Labs is betting tech can help sway the 2020 elections for Democrats&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/01/higher-ground-labs/embed/#?secret=V5re0yJ2Ri" data-secret="V5re0yJ2Ri" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/everyaction-acquires-mobilize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080586</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 reasons you don’t want to miss out on TC Sessions: Space 2020</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/5-reasons-you-dont-want-to-miss-out-on-tc-sessions-space-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/5-reasons-you-dont-want-to-miss-out-on-tc-sessions-space-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 19:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2020]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’re just about two weeks away from launching TC Sessions: Space 2020, our first focused foray into early-stage space startups and the essential satellite industries that support them. Buy your pass and join us on December 16-17 for two days packed with all the right stuff, including untapped opportunity. Still looking for a reason to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We’re just about two weeks away from launching <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_source=&amp;promo=5reasonspost&amp;display=">TC Sessions: Space 2020</a>, our first focused foray into early-stage space startups and the essential satellite industries that support them. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_source=&amp;promo=5reasonspost&amp;display=true">Buy your pass and join us</a> on December 16-17 for two days packed with all the right stuff, including untapped opportunity.</p>
<p>Still looking for a reason to initiate your launch sequence? We’ll go you four better. Here are five stellar reasons to attend <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_source=&amp;promo=5reasonspost&amp;display=true">TC Sessions: Space 2020</a>.</p>
<p><strong>1. Top innovators in the space scene</strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>You’ll hear from and engage with the top minds, makers and investors in the space community. We’re talking the leaders of public, private and government agencies; the people making it happen and looking to share their expertise and insight with you — the up-and-coming minds and makers.</p>
<p>A quick for instance includes General Jay Raymond (U.S. Space Force), Lisa Callahan (Lockheed Martin), Jim Bridenstine (NASA), Peter Beck (Rocket Lab) and investors like Chris Boshuizen (Data Collective DCVC), Mike Collett (Promus Ventures) and Tess Hatch (Bessemer Venture Partners).</p>
<p><strong>2. Out-of-this-world networking</strong></p>
<p>Connect and build relationships and opportunities with the global space startup community. CrunchMatch, our free, AI-powered platform, simplifies finding and connecting with the people who align with your goals. Send invitations, schedule 1:1 video calls, meet VCs, founders, engineers, potential customers or employees — you never know who you’ll meet or where one connection can take your business.</p>
<p><strong>3. Fast Money for your startup</strong></p>
<p>An early-stage space startup burns through money like a rocket burns through, well, rocket fuel. Don’t miss Fast Money — a series of six breakout sessions. Presenters from leading space accelerators and funding programs will talk about government accelerators, partnering with the Air Force and how to access grant money. Afterward, you can schedule individual appointments with representatives from each program. Look for the Fast Money sessions in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_source=&amp;promo=5reasonspost&amp;display=/#2f65e915-5963-4a04-be6a-667c01da1e6d">the event agenda</a>.</p>
<p><strong>4. Space expo</strong></p>
<p>Explore more than 30 early-stage startups pushing the boundaries of space technology in the expo area. Check out the competition, start a conversation or kick off a collaboration. Hold up, are you a boundary-pushing founder, too? Then get yourself a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_source=&amp;promo=5reasonspost&amp;display=true">Space Startup Exhibitor Package</a>, showcase your talent and take advantage of two expo-only opportunities. See details in reason No. 5 below!</p>
<p><strong>5. Pitch, pitch, pitch</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Founders who exhibit in the expo area get five minutes to pitch live to attendees tuning in from around the globe. Increase your exposure, spotlight your technology and open the door to opportunities.</li>
<li>Looking for ways to improve your pitch? On December 16 from 2:30 &#8211; 3:30 p.m., Stephan Reckie, Executive Director of GEN Space, will moderate a pitch feedback session for startup founders exhibiting in the expo area.</li>
<li>Are you feeling lucky? Your promising early-stage space startup might be one of 10 selected for a pitch competition — a joint mission between TechCrunch and Starburst Aerospace — called <strong>Pitch Me to the Moon</strong>. Starburst will choose the competitors, who will each pitch live to a panel of high-profile judges from across the industry.</li>
</ul>
<p>Spend two days learning, connecting and engaging with the space startup community. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_source=&amp;promo=5reasonspost&amp;display=true">Buy your pass</a> and tap into a galaxy of opportunity at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2020&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_source=&amp;promo=5reasonspost&amp;display=true">TC Sessions: Space 2020</a>.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring TC Sessions: Space 2020? </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>Click here</em></a><em> to talk with us about available opportunities.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-63a70c19e197308b71b19a195112a25c"
			width="99%"
			height="1200"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/63a70c19e197308b71b19a195112a25c"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-63a70c19e197308b71b19a195112a25c')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-63a70c19e197308b71b19a195112a25c'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/5-reasons-you-dont-want-to-miss-out-on-tc-sessions-space-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077741</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reminder: Last chance to save 25% on Extra Crunch membership</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/reminder-last-chance-to-save-25-on-extra-crunch-membership/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/reminder-last-chance-to-save-25-on-extra-crunch-membership/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Travis Bernard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 18:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscriptions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2080087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today is the final day of the Green Days Sale. Don&#8217;t miss out on an opportunity to save 25% on annual Extra Crunch membership. You can claim the deal here. Extra Crunch helps you spot technology trends and opportunities, build better startups, get ahead at your job and stay connected to a growing community of founders, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today is the final day of the Green Days Sale. Don&#8217;t miss out on an opportunity to save 25% on annual Extra Crunch membership.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">You can claim the deal <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=greendayssale">here</a>.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch helps you spot technology trends and opportunities, build better startups, get ahead at your job and stay connected to a growing community of founders, investors and startup teams. It features thousands of articles, including weekly investor surveys, daily market analysis and expert interviews on fundraising, growth, monetization and other work topics.</p>
<p>Find answers to your burning questions about startups and investing through <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/announcing-the-extra-crunch-live-event-series/">Extra Crunch Live</a>, and stay informed with our members-only Extra Crunch newsletters. Other benefits include an improved TechCrunch.com experience, 20% off future <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/techcrunch" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="organization" data-entity="techcrunch">TechCrunch </a> events and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/">savings on software services</a> from DocSend, Crunchbase and more.</p>
<p>Join our growing community at a discounted rate <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=greendayssale">here</a>.</p>
<p>The Green Days sale is our biggest discount of the year, so don’t snooze on the savings. The sale ends on November 30. If you have questions about the sale or Extra Crunch membership, please contact our customer support team at extracrunch@techcrunch.com.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/reminder-last-chance-to-save-25-on-extra-crunch-membership/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2080087</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virgin Orbit targets launch window on December 19 for second orbital test launch</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/virgin-orbit-targets-launch-window-on-december-19-for-second-orbital-test-launch/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/virgin-orbit-targets-launch-window-on-december-19-for-second-orbital-test-launch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 18:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LauncherOne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocketry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit has announced the target timing for its next orbital flight attempt, which follows a demonstration launch earlier this year that went mostly well — right up until its rocket separated from the carrier launch craft and fired up its own engines for the crucial rest of the trip to space. The company says [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/virgin-orbit" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="virgin-orbit">Virgin Orbit <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has <a href="https://virginorbit.com/the-latest/announcing-the-window-for-launch-demo-2/">announced</a> the target timing for its next orbital flight attempt, which follows a demonstration launch earlier this year that went mostly well — right up until its rocket separated from the carrier launch craft and fired up its own engines for the crucial rest of the trip to space. The company says that it&#8217;s undertaken a number of upgrades based on that first try, however, including updates to the engine systems, carrier aircraft and data systems to hopefully have a better demo flight the second time around.</p>
<p>The new launch window is December 19, between the hours of 10 a.m. to 2 p.m. PST. There&#8217;s also a backup window set for December 20 ranging across similar hours, the company says, and others in the following weeks, in case it needs to be rescheduled for any reason. This demonstration will involve a full launch cycle of the entire Virgin Orbit launch system, including its Cosmic Girl launch aircraft (a modified 747 passenger airliner) and LauncherOne, the rocket that detaches from Cosmic Girl at cruising altitude before firing up its own engines to make the rest of the trip to space with small satellite payloads on board.</p>
<p>Virgin Orbit&#8217;s system is unique because it takes off and lands from a traditional airport, eliminating the need for specialized launch sites and opening up the potential of relatively low-lift global launch flexibility. It also has the potential to offer cost and scheduling advantages to small satellite companies looking to launch just one or a few spacecraft, without having to wait for timing on a ride-share mission on a larger rocket like one from <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-exploration-technologies" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-exploration-technologies">SpaceX, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> or pay a premium for something like Rocket Lab&#8217;s offering.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Last time around in May, Virgin Orbit&#8217;s flight went perfectly from takeoff through the separation of LauncherOne from the carrier aircraft. The rocket even fired up its engines on time as planned, but the engines cut off essentially right away due to a built-in safety system that also worked as planned when it detected some unusual readings.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7idl9ASooo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/virgin-orbit-provides-more-details-about-what-went-right-with-its-first-launch-demo/">Virgin Orbit provides more details about what went right with its first launch demo</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Virgin Orbit provides more details about what went right with its first launch demo&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/virgin-orbit-provides-more-details-about-what-went-right-with-its-first-launch-demo/embed/#?secret=7idl9ASooo" data-secret="7idl9ASooo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>With this second attempt, Virgin Orbit wants to show that it&#8217;s system works from that point on, as well, with a full first-stage powered flight and operation of the upper stage. Stakes are a bit higher this time around, as on board will be actual customer satellites, even though this is technically still a demonstration mission — the primary purpose of which is to collect data.</p>
<p>The 10 payloads on board are from NASA and represent a number of different scientific and educational programs created entirely by U.S.-based universities and academic institutions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/virgin-orbit-targets-launch-window-on-december-19-for-second-orbital-test-launch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079614</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: What I&#8217;m thankful for</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/dear-sophie-what-im-thankful-for/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/dear-sophie-what-im-thankful-for/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 18:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079408</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This Thanksgiving, I hope you caught a glimpse of this feeling of appreciation for people and experiences in your life.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/dear-sophie-can-an-h-1b-co-founder-own-a-delaware-c-corp/">Dear Sophie: Can an H-1B co-founder own a Delaware C Corp?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/dear-sophie-what-does-a-biden-win-for-tech-immigration/">Dear Sophie: What does Biden&#8217;s win mean for tech immigration?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<hr />
<p>Dear Reader,</p>
<p>Thank you so much for being a part of the genesis of &#8220;Dear Sophie&#8221; over the course of this year. As I reflect on the Thanksgiving holiday weekend, I’m appreciative of how much all of us around the world have come to know in 2020. We are all interconnected, regardless of where we were born or wherever we currently reside. This year has included major, transformative events. These changes serve us to better know what we want and what we don’t. As a result, I am positive that our future experiences will be enhanced.</p>
<p>Looking back over the last year, I’m appreciative of President Trump’s digitization effort to improve the H-1B lottery process.</p>
<p>Looking forward, it’s exhilarating that increasing access to immigration opportunities is a major priority for President-elect Biden. I’m confident the Biden-Harris administration will support the U.S. embracing our roots as a land of opportunity. Moving into 2021 we will recognize our immigrant heritage, welcome newcomers and recognize the important contributions of immigrants for a better world.</p>
<p>There’s so much to be thankful for:</p>
<p>I’m appreciative of you, my readers, and the messages and feedback I receive from you about this column, questions you have and topics you would like to see covered. I appreciate TechCrunch and Extra Crunch for this platform to share my thoughts, experiences and knowledge.</p>
<p>I’m appreciative of all of our clients from around the world who we’ve been able to successfully support. Many moments this year seemed bleak, but we were able to come through. I appreciate their many contributions to the U.S. and creating health solutions and jobs as they have gone on to launch and scale innovative startups in Silicon Valley and beyond.</p>
<p>I’m appreciative of my amazing team at Alcorn Immigration Law and for our successes in supporting folks to come to live and work in the U.S. and achieve their dreams. And I’m appreciative of our team to compile a “<a href="https://witty-author-184.ck.page/307dfc5d7b">64 Questions to Ask Your Immigration Attorney</a>,” a checklist of questions you should ask when interviewing immigration attorneys before starting the immigration process. I’m appreciative for having the opportunity to share my knowledge on my podcast, Immigration Law for Tech Startups — this week’s <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/045-thanksgiving-appreciation/">podcast</a> is all about appreciation!</p>
<p>And finally, I’m appreciative of my amazing job. I have the privilege of supporting people from all around the world to create their dreams. It’s humbling and inspiring to listen to my clients’ stories, hopes and dreams. It’s the most magnificent chess game to identify and tailor immigration strategies that best fit their unique situation, priorities and timing.</p>
<p>Part of why being an immigration attorney inspires me is because our amazing clients entrust us to support them in navigating the U.S. immigration system to make their dream a reality. We had many major legal victories this year:</p>
<p>I appreciate the client who was on an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/e-2-visa-treaty-investors/">E-2 Visa for Treaty Investors</a> as an employee. He was desperate to join an early-stage startup and was in a difficult bind of needing to get expedited approval in the pandemic and be able to provide his contractual notice to his current employer. We all knew it was risky, so I’m proud of our team for successfully petitioning for the startup to sponsor him in <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/o-1a-extraordinary-ability/">O-1A Visa for Extraordinary Ability</a> status.</p>
<p>I also appreciate the aspiring startup founder we helped to gain independence from a corporate employer by assisting him with self-petitioning his green card. We succeeded in getting him approved for an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/eb-2-niw-startup-green-card-dhanasar-national-interest-waiver/">EB-2 NIW (National Interest Waiver) exceptional ability green card</a>.</p>
<p>I am also appreciating that we successfully supported a prospective startup co-founder to remain in the U.S. while maintaining his position in line for a green card. A prominent VC required that he immediately leave his current employer and begin working full time for the very early-stage startup prior to investing $6 million. This founder had been bound at a prior company in <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/l-1a-visa-intracompany-transferee-executives/">L-1A Visa for Intracompany Transferee Managers and Executives</a>, and he didn’t want to lose his midstream green card process. We successfully transitioned him to the new company quickly and secured him green card portability. He can now focus on the startup and spending time with his family.</p>
<p>While most U.S. consulates remained closed, I appreciate that we were able to support our client to get an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/e-3-visa/">E-3 Visa</a> interview, have her visa approved and be able to move to the U.S., even in the middle of the pandemic.</p>
<p>Notably, we helped a client avoid having to return to her home country for <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/j-1-waiver-2-year-foreign-residency-requirement/">two years</a> after her <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/j-1-educational-cultural-exchange-visa/">J-1 Educational and Cultural Exchange Visa</a> was set to expire, and her employer was about to do a round of layoffs. We guided her through the green card process, including helping her prepare for an interview at U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS), as well as accompanying her to the interview. Instead of being banished from the U.S., now she is celebrating that it is her permanent home.</p>
<p>And there are so many more stories like these.</p>
<p>I’m also appreciative that we launched our first online immigration course, <a href="https://alcorn-immigration-law.teachable.com/p/extraordinary-ability-bootcamp">Extraordinary Ability Bootcamp</a>. Many of our client successes stem from options such as the O-1A nonimmigrant visa, as well as the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/eb-1a-green-card/">EB-1A extraordinary ability green card</a> and the EB-2 NIW green card. I’m grateful to have had the opportunity to record a series of classes that can help anybody meet the criteria for U.S. immigration.</p>
<p>This Thanksgiving, I hope you caught a glimpse of this feeling of appreciation for people and experiences in your life. I feel exhilarated and eager about the future and to see what’s ahead. 2020 has taught me that we are empowered at this moment because we have the freedom to choose how we feel. We can always choose to love and appreciate unconditionally. New opportunities are ahead that will support us all.</p>
<p>Thank you for being a part of &#8220;Dear Sophie<em>.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Joyfully,</p>
<p>Sophie</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">Have a question? Ask it here.</a> We reserve the right to edit your submission for clarity and/or space. The information provided in “Dear Sophie” is general information and not legal advice. For more information on the limitations of “Dear Sophie,” please view our full disclaimer <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/attorney-advertising">here</a>. You can contact Sophie directly at Alcorn Immigration Law.</p>
<p>Sophie&#8217;s podcast, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/immigration-law-for-tech-startups/id1497746915">Immigration Law for Tech Startups</a>, is available on all major podcast platforms. If you&#8217;d like to be a guest, <a href="https://forms.gle/TsCtSJabKStwiUk88">she&#8217;s accepting applications!</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5i0sjP1rle"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/dear-sophie-can-an-h-1b-co-founder-own-a-delaware-c-corp/">Dear Sophie: Can an H-1B co-founder own a Delaware C Corp?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dear Sophie: Can an H-1B co-founder own a Delaware C Corp?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/dear-sophie-can-an-h-1b-co-founder-own-a-delaware-c-corp/embed/#?secret=5i0sjP1rle" data-secret="5i0sjP1rle" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/dear-sophie-what-im-thankful-for/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079408</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>C3.ai&#8217;s initial IPO pricing guidance spotlights the public market&#8217;s tech appetite</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/c3-ais-initial-ipo-pricing-guidance-spotlights-the-public-markets-tech-appetite/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/c3-ais-initial-ipo-pricing-guidance-spotlights-the-public-markets-tech-appetite/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 18:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C3.AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitchbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the heels of news that DoorDash is targeting an initial IPO valuation up to $27 billion, C3.ai also dropped a new S-1 filing detailing a first-draft guess of what the richly valued company might be worth after its debut. C3.ai posted an initial IPO price range of $31 to $34 per share, with the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On the heels of news that <a href="https://www.doordash.com/">DoorDash</a> is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/doordash-aims-to-add-11-billion-to-its-valuation-during-public-offering/">targeting an initial IPO valuation up to $27 billion</a>, <a href="https://c3.ai/">C3.ai</a> also dropped a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1577526/000162828020016868/c3ais-1a2.htm">new S-1 filing</a> detailing a first-draft guess of what the richly valued company might be worth after its debut.</p>
<p>C3.ai posted an initial IPO price range of $31 to $34 per share, with the company anticipating a sale of 15.5 million shares at that price. The enterprise-focused artificial intelligence company is also selling $100 million of stock at its IPO price to Spring Creek Capital, and another $50 million to Microsoft at the same terms. And there are 2.325 million shares reserved for its underwriters as well.</p>
<p>The total tally of shares that C3.ai will have outstanding after its IPO bloc is sold, Spring Creek and Microsoft buy in, and its underwriters take up their option, is 99,216,958. At the extremes of its initial IPO price range, the company would be worth between $3.08 billion and $3.37 billion using that share count.</p>
<p>Those numbers decline by around $70 and $80 million, respectively, if the underwriters do not purchase their option.</p>
<p>So is the IPO a win for the company at those prices? And is it a win for <em>all</em> C3.ai investors? Amazingly enough, it feels like the answers are yes and no. Let&#8217;s explore why.</p>
<h2>Slowing growth, rising valuation</h2>
<p>If we just look at C3.ai&#8217;s revenue history in chunks, you can argue a growth story for the company; that it grew from $73.8 million in the the two quarters of 2019 ending July 31, to $81.8 million in revenue during the same portion of 2020. That&#8217;s growth of just under 11% on a year-over-year basis. Not great, but positive.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/c3-ais-initial-ipo-pricing-guidance-spotlights-the-public-markets-tech-appetite/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079397</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter&#8217;s Audio Spaces test includes transcriptions, speaker controls and reporting features</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/twitters-audio-spaces-test-includes-transcriptions-speaker-controls-and-reporting-features/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/twitters-audio-spaces-test-includes-transcriptions-speaker-controls-and-reporting-features/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 18:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this month, Twitter announced it would soon begin testing its own Clubhouse rival, called Audio Spaces. The new product will allow Twitter users to gather in dedicated spaces for live conversations with another person or with groups of people. While the company showed off a handful of screenshots of the product at the time [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this month, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/twitter" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="twitter">Twitter <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> announced it would soon begin <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/twitter-rolls-out-stories-aka-fleets-to-all-users-will-also-test-a-clubhouse-rival/">testing its own Clubhouse rival,</a> called Audio Spaces. The new product will allow Twitter users to gather in dedicated spaces for live conversations with another person or with groups of people. While the company showed off a handful of screenshots of the product at the time of the announcement, there were few specifics about how Audio Spaces would work. Now, we know a bit more about Audio Spaces&#8217; feature set, thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1332703770535366659">some digging</a> by reverse engineer <a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane">Jane Manchun Wong. </a></p>
<p>Wong enabled the private beta in the Twitter app and took screenshots that show how Audio Spaces and its features would look in action. Of course, these features could change before the feature later rolls out to the public, but it gives an idea about how Twitter is currently thinking about the product.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Twitter is internally testing Audio Spaces Beta, here’s another look:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8211; Uses Periscope as backend</p>
<p>&#8211; Reactions: <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f4af.png" alt="💯" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/270b.png" alt="✋" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/270a.png" alt="✊" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/270c.png" alt="✌" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f44b.png" alt="👋" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>&#8211; “Who can speak” can be adjusted in the middle</p>
<p>&#8211; Transcriptions available</p>
<p>&#8211; Spaces can be reported</p>
<p>&#8211; “Share feedback” sends DM to <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@TwitterSpaces</a> <a href="https://t.co/hbyiJuEWw5">pic.twitter.com/hbyiJuEWw5</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Jane Manchun Wong (@wongmjane) <a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1332703770535366659?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 28, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The images show that users will be able to apply the same sort of conversation controls <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/twitter-now-lets-everyone-limit-replies-to-their-tweets/">that are today available for tweets</a> to Audio Spaces, as well. This will allow users to configure their Audio Space to be open to anyone who wants to join, only to people they follow or only to people they specifically invite to join.</p>
<p>Users can invite others to their space in a number of ways, too, including via DM (direct message), by posting a tweet or copying a link that can be shared elsewhere.</p>
<p>When joining a space, people will enter the space with their microphone disabled to limit noise. As the conversation progresses, they can react to what&#8217;s being said with a variety of emoji, like the &#8220;100,&#8221; raised hand, fist, peace sign and waving hand.</p>
<p>In addition, the Audio Space&#8217;s creator will be able to adjust who can speak at any time after the dedicated room has been created. From an in-app menu, they&#8217;ll be able to manage the speakers, adjust other settings, view the rules, as well as share feedback or report the space, among other things.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2079579" style="width: 594px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2079579" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2079579 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.30-PM.jpg?w=584" alt="" width="584" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.30-PM.jpg 1188w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.30-PM.jpg?resize=129,150 129w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.30-PM.jpg?resize=258,300 258w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.30-PM.jpg?resize=768,895 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.30-PM.jpg?resize=584,680 584w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.30-PM.jpg?resize=43,50 43w" sizes="(max-width: 584px) 100vw, 584px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2079579" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1332703770535366659" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jane Manchun Wong <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>One interesting finding is that Audio Spaces will include transcriptions of the chat, according to this menu. That&#8217;s a differentiating feature, compared with some other audio chat room services. While ostensibly a feature designed for accessibility, it could also prove useful in keeping the conversations appropriate and respectful, since users would know their words were being written down.</p>
<p>This could help address one issue with the private chat room model, where live conversations have proven to be hard to moderate. Despite being in an invite-only beta, Clubhouse, for example, already experienced a handful of incidents of moderation failure, including the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/7/8/21316172/clubhouse-content-moderation-taylor-lorenz-harassment-abuse?scrolla=5eb6d68b7fedc32c19ef33b4">harassment of a New York Times reporter</a> and another conversation that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/30/21495419/clubhouse-conversation-antisemitism-content-moderation">delved into anti-Semitism</a>.</p>
<p>Twitter, which has struggled for years to combat abuse on its platform, was a questionable place to be testing this unproven new format for online socializing.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2079577" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2079577" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2079577 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.42-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="352" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.42-PM.jpg 1508w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.42-PM.jpg?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.42-PM.jpg?resize=300,155 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.42-PM.jpg?resize=768,397 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.42-PM.jpg?resize=680,352 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-12.45.42-PM.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2079577" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1332703770535366659" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jane Manchun Wong <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>It wasn&#8217;t clear how Twitter will approach moderation for these audio chat rooms, but it appears the transcription feature could be a deterrent to toxic speech while the in-app reporting feature allows for a more direct solution to problems that crop up. When users choose the &#8220;Report this Space&#8221; option, they can then choose to report across a variety of categories, including self-harm, violence, sexual content, child safety, private information or abusive behavior.</p>
<p>Because Audio Spaces is in private beta, testers will also have access to a &#8220;Share Feedback&#8221; option that allows them to DM the account @TwitterSpaces.</p>
<p>Wong also noted Audio Spaces is using Periscope for its back-end, according to her digging in the app&#8217;s code.</p>
<p>Twitter earlier said Audio Spaces would be launching to a small group of users. During tests, those users would include a group of people who are &#8220;disproportionately impacted by abuse and harm on the platform: women and those from marginalized backgrounds,&#8221; Twitter Staff Product Designer Maya Gold Patterson had noted, when introducing the feature in a briefing for reporters this month.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, a Twitter spokesperson said: &#8220;We&#8217;ll have more to share on Spaces closer to the public beta experiment launch.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/twitters-audio-spaces-test-includes-transcriptions-speaker-controls-and-reporting-features/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079418</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FCC Chairman Ajit Pai will step down to make way for the Biden administration</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/fcc-chairman-ajit-pai-will-step-down-to-make-way-for-the-biden-administration/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/fcc-chairman-ajit-pai-will-step-down-to-make-way-for-the-biden-administration/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 17:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ajit pai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The chairman of the FCC, Ajit Pai, has announced he will leave his position on January 20 as President-elect Biden is sworn in. Pai&#8217;s tenure has been a controversial one, and while he would almost certainly like to be remembered for his efforts to &#8220;bridge the digital divide,&#8221; as he was fond of saying, it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The chairman of the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/federal-communications-commission" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="federal-communications-commission">FCC, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/ajit-pai" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="ajit-pai">Ajit Pai, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has announced he will leave his position on January 20 as President-elect Biden is sworn in. Pai&#8217;s tenure has been a controversial one, and while he would almost certainly like to be remembered for his efforts to &#8220;bridge the digital divide,&#8221; as he was fond of saying, it is the dismantling of net neutrality that will be his legacy.</p>
<p>It is traditional at the FCC for the chairman to leave when the administration changes parties. Pai took over when Tom Wheeler, who chaired the commission at the end of the Obama years, resigned upon Trump&#8217;s election. The Biden administration has not announced its pick for the new leader of the communications agency.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/chairman-pai-announces-intent-depart-fcc-january">In an official FCC memo</a>, Pai thanked his colleagues and summarized the accomplishments of his four years at the helm (as, it must also be said, the first commissioner of Asian descent):</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>Together, we’ve delivered for the American people over the past four years: closing the digital divide; promoting innovation and competition, from 5G on the ground to broadband from space; protecting consumers; and advancing public safety.</p>
<p>I am proud of how productive this commission has been, from commencing five spectrum auctions and two rural broadband reverse auctions in four years, to opening 1,245 megahertz of midband spectrum for unlicensed use, to adopting more than 25 orders through our Modernization of Media Regulation Initiative, to aggressively protecting our communications networks from national security threats at home and abroad, to designating 988 as the three-digit number for the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline, and much, much more.</p></blockquote>
<p>Notably absent from that list is Pai&#8217;s unfortunate magnum opus and arguably the effort that got him the job: The elimination of 2015&#8217;s net neutrality rules. The tremendously dishonest and partisan campaign to overturn these popular and important curbs on broadband companies put a stink on Pai&#8217;s tenure at the outset that no amount of good work could wash out.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Sbc3xZdob9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/13/commission-impossible-part-two-how-enemies-gathered-around-net-neutrality/">Commission Impossible, part two: How enemies gathered around net neutrality</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Commission Impossible, part two: How enemies gathered around net neutrality&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/13/commission-impossible-part-two-how-enemies-gathered-around-net-neutrality/embed/#?secret=Sbc3xZdob9" data-secret="Sbc3xZdob9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>For as always, the bulk of the FCC&#8217;s duties fly under the public&#8217;s radar, and a great deal of work <em>was</em> done under Pai, as under any other administration, invisibly and thanklessly. (Though in some cases less invisibly than before — Pai&#8217;s FCC did make improvements to transparency, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/06/fcc-admits-it-was-never-actually-hacked/">in some ways anyhow</a>.)</p>
<p>Surely Pai&#8217;s greatest priority was, as indeed he often stated, ameliorating the &#8220;digital divide&#8221; that prevents millions of Americans from enjoying affordable, fast internet. Numerous new programs and funds were created to improve this situation, but Pai was hampered by bad information — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/29/fccs-broadband-deployment-report-called-fundamentally-at-odds-with-reality/">essentially provided on the honor system</a> by ISPs themselves — and the seemingly endless rollout of 5G, which we&#8217;re all still waiting on.</p>
<p>His final effort, alas, will not much improve the opinion of him at large. As Trump raged impotently about Section 230, a law that shields internet companies from liability for the actions of their users, Pai took up that flag and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/with-absurd-timing-fcc-announces-intention-to-revisit-section-230/">announced his intention to revisit and perhaps change the interpretation of it</a> — a month before the election. The simpering, plainly political nature of the effort, almost certain now to be aborted entirely, attracted considerable criticism, makes for a poor final chapter in an already troubling story.</p>
<p>The next step for the FCC is the nomination and confirmation of a new chairman and replacement commissioners, and though several names have been floated by political insiders, no one has emerged yet as the heir apparent.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="j1bkeJBDQE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/with-absurd-timing-fcc-announces-intention-to-revisit-section-230/">With &#8216;absurd&#8217; timing, FCC announces intention to revisit Section 230</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With &#8216;absurd&#8217; timing, FCC announces intention to revisit Section 230&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/with-absurd-timing-fcc-announces-intention-to-revisit-section-230/embed/#?secret=j1bkeJBDQE" data-secret="j1bkeJBDQE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/fcc-chairman-ajit-pai-will-step-down-to-make-way-for-the-biden-administration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079429</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook buys Kustomer for $1B to expand into customer service tools</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/facebook-confirms-it-has-acquired-kustomer-sources-say-for-1b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/facebook-confirms-it-has-acquired-kustomer-sources-say-for-1b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 17:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kustomer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today Facebook made one of its biggest plays yet to build out the services it provides to businesses on its platform: It is acquiring Kustomer, a startup founded with the aim of disrupting the customer services industry with a new approach to providing agents with better data and a more unified picture of users by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> made one of its biggest plays yet to build out the services it provides to businesses on its platform: It is <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/11/kustomer-to-join-facebook/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">acquiring Kustomer</a>, a startup founded with the aim of disrupting the customer services industry with a new approach to providing agents with better data and a more unified picture of users by bringing together the many social media and other channels and longer history between them and the company in question.</p>
<p>Terms are not being disclosed, but we have confirmed with sources very close to the deal that it was for $1 billion. Reports of the deal (and alleged price) were published earlier today by the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-nears-purchase-of-startup-in-deal-that-values-it-at-1-billion-11606750196?mod=djemalertNEWS" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSJ</a>.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/kustomer" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="kustomer">Kustomer <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> &#8212; co-founded by CEO Brad Birnbaum and Jeremy Suriel (the two worked together across a range of other places, including Airtime and AOL and had sold a previous startup to Salesforce) &#8212; had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/04/kustomer-raises-60m-for-its-omnichannel-based-crm-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">raised around $174 million</a> in private funding from investors that included Coatue, Tiger Global Management, Battery Ventures, Redpoint Ventures, Cisco Investments, Canaan Partners, Boldstart Ventures and Social Leverage. It was last valued at $710 million, according to estimates from <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/gs/all" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PitchBook</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Facebook&#8217;s interest in Kustomer is very straightforward, while at the same time a very significant sign of what it hopes to do strategically.</p>
<p>The social network has been slowly building up a big business providing customer services to businesses on its platform, and the plan now is to double down on that with a platform that will do much more of that, potentially as a paid service.</p>
<p>There are some 175 million people using Facebook this way today, covering both those who use Facebook to engage with businesses that use Facebook as their primary online &#8220;identity&#8221; &#8212; in place of a website or mobile app of their own, companies today often simply have a Page on Facebook &#8212; and those businesses that provide conversation channels on Facebook-owned messaging apps like Instagram, Messenger and WhatsApp as a complement to other ways (and sometimes the sole way) to contact them.</p>
<p>Considering that Facebook has upwards of 2 billion users, 175 million doesn&#8217;t sound like a lot.</p>
<p>But as the company starts to see more keen competition from the likes of Snapchat, TikTok and likely others over time, having a better product to sell businesses alongside their other services will give Facebook a better way of locking them into the Facebook ecosystem. It will also give the company a stronger shot at a newer revenue stream to complement advertising, which remains its biggest cash cow by a big margin.</p>
<p>Indeed, customer service is an interesting play for Facebook to be making. The company has been investing in and building a number of additional features for businesses on its messaging apps &#8212; most recently on WhatsApp, for example, it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/facebook-adds-hosting-shopping-features-and-pricing-tiers-to-whatsapp-business/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">started to make it easier for businesses to let people shop and do more on the app</a>. Within that customer service is a huge industry that stretches well beyond the Facebook walled garden.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IgXp9X7vqY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/facebook-adds-hosting-shopping-features-and-pricing-tiers-to-whatsapp-business/">Facebook adds hosting, shopping features and pricing tiers to WhatsApp Business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook adds hosting, shopping features and pricing tiers to WhatsApp Business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/facebook-adds-hosting-shopping-features-and-pricing-tiers-to-whatsapp-business/embed/#?secret=IgXp9X7vqY" data-secret="IgXp9X7vqY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Indeed, the specific term Kustomer and other CRM companies use to describe what they do is &#8220;omni-channel&#8221; customer relations. That is to say, it gives the Kustomer business users a complete picture of the many disparate places where &#8220;conversations&#8221; might be happening with customers &#8212; be it on apps, on social media, in websites, via chatbots, or email, etc. The logic is that this makes the agent more efficient and gives him/her a better picture of both how the business is faring across those channels, and more context about a specific user contacting the company from one of those channels, as well as a more complete picture of the customers themselves.</p>
<p>For Facebook, its &#8220;customer relations&#8221; profile up to now has been about users within its app walls. This gives it a much bigger opportunity to essentially control that bigger picture and bigger relationship, regardless of the platform being used.</p>
<p>Coincidentally, it was only earlier this month that I reported that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/snap-acquired-voca-ai-which-makes-ai-based-voice-agents-for-call-centers-for-120m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Snap acquired Voca.ai</a>, which makes customer support voice bots.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4GyiApjPko"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/snap-acquired-voca-ai-which-makes-ai-based-voice-agents-for-call-centers-for-120m/">Snap acquired Voca.ai, which makes AI-based voice agents for call centers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Snap acquired Voca.ai, which makes AI-based voice agents for call centers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/snap-acquired-voca-ai-which-makes-ai-based-voice-agents-for-call-centers-for-120m/embed/#?secret=4GyiApjPko" data-secret="4GyiApjPko" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While we have no idea how Snap will use that tech &#8212; some have speculated it could be to build more voice commands and audio-based tech for its Spectacles &#8212; I wrote at the time that it would make a lot of sense to bring this into a bigger product portfolio providing more tools to businesses already using Snapchat to market themselves. This Kustomer acquisition feels very timely in that regard.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/facebook-confirms-it-has-acquired-kustomer-sources-say-for-1b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079439</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>French administration suspects Wish of selling counterfeit products</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/french-administration-suspects-wish-of-selling-counterfeit-products/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/french-administration-suspects-wish-of-selling-counterfeit-products/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 17:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[counterfeit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DGCCRF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wish]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A French administration in charge of consumer rights and fraud has investigated Wish, the mobile e-commerce platform that recently filed to go public. While the company generated $1.9 billion in revenue in 2019, the French administration believes Wish could be selling products, such as sneakers and perfumes, with images incorrectly showing the logos of famous [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A French administration in charge of consumer rights and fraud has investigated <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/wish" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="wish">Wish, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> the mobile e-commerce platform that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/wish-ipo/">recently filed to go public</a>. While the company generated $1.9 billion in revenue in 2019, the French administration believes Wish could be selling products, such as sneakers and perfumes, with images incorrectly showing the logos of famous brands.</p>
<p>In addition to those wrongly labeled products, the administration says Wish pretends products are on sale while they aren’t. The platform could be displaying -70%, -80% or -90% on some products even though the original price is completely made up.</p>
<p>The administration in charge of the investigation is the <em> direction générale de la concurrence, de la consommation et de la répression des fraudes</em> (DGCCRF), an administration that reports to the French Ministry for the Economy and Finance. They have transmitted <a href="https://www.economie.gouv.fr/files/files/directions_services/dgccrf/presse/communique/2020/CP-DGCCRF-wish.pdf">the report</a> to a court in Paris.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Now, it’s up to the court to decide whether the allegations are right or unfounded. “The court can subpoena Wish or offer to plead guilty. We should know in the coming days,” France’s digital minister Cédric O told me.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/cedric_o/status/1333298201290530817">On Twitter</a>, Cédric O highlighted one case in particular. “Wish already stood out during the first lockdown by selling facemasks that don’t meet safety standards. French people who are using the app to find low-cost products should know that they’ll mostly find scams,” he tweeted.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="fr" dir="ltr">.<a href="https://twitter.com/WishShopping?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WishShopping</a> s’était déjà distinguée pendant le 1er confinement en vendant des masques ne respectant pas les normes. Les Français-e-s qui utilisent l&#39;application pour y trouver du low-cost doivent savoir qu&#39;ils y trouveront surtout des arnaques. <a href="https://twitter.com/alaingriset?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@alaingriset</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/BrunoLeMaire?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BrunoLeMaire</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Cédric O (@cedric_o) <a href="https://twitter.com/cedric_o/status/1333298201290530817?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 30, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>If Wish is found guilty, the company could risk up to 10% of its annual revenue in France. In particular, it’s going to be interesting to see whether Wish is responsible for products sold by third-party merchants.</p>
<p>The timing of the case is a bit odd as Europe’s upcoming Digital Services Act should overhaul the e-commerce directive from 2000. All eyes are on content moderation, but the Digital Services Act should also focus on counterfeit sellers, the liability of marketplaces and more.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hlMS3hlN4w"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/wish-ipo/">Wish files to go public with 100M monthly actives, $1.75B in 2020 revenue thus far</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wish files to go public with 100M monthly actives, $1.75B in 2020 revenue thus far&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/wish-ipo/embed/#?secret=hlMS3hlN4w" data-secret="hlMS3hlN4w" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/french-administration-suspects-wish-of-selling-counterfeit-products/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079443</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cyber Monday: Up to $12.7B will be spent online, marking biggest-ever US shopping day</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/cyber-monday-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/cyber-monday-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 17:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyber monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thanksgiving and Black Friday online shopping this year had big gains on 2019, but both still fell somewhat short of expectations in what is proving to be a good if more muted holiday shopping season without the usual physical crowds to help enforce COVID-19 social distancing and many feeling the economic strain of the health [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Thanksgiving and Black Friday online shopping this year had big gains on 2019, but both still fell somewhat short of expectations in what is proving to be a good if more muted holiday shopping season without the usual physical crowds to help enforce COVID-19 social distancing and many feeling the economic strain of the health pandemic.</p>
<p>Now all eyes are on &#8220;Cyber Monday,&#8221; which for the last several years has been the biggest online shopping day of the four-day stretch. Adobe predicts that it will be the biggest shopping day yet in the U.S., with between $10.8 billion and $12.7 billion spent, while Salesforce&#8217;s forecast is in the middle of that range at $11.8 billion. Globally, Salesforce believes the figure will be $46 billion.</p>
<p>The Adobe figure of 40% of sales on smartphones has been relatively steady all week. Shopify, which typically works with smaller merchants, has put the figure closer to 70%.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For some context, Black Friday came in at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/28/black-friday-online-sales-numbers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$9 billion</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/thanksgiving-on-track-for-a-record-6b-in-us-online-sales-says-adobe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Thanksgiving at $5.1 billion</a> this year, according to Adobe&#8217;s figures. And last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/cyber-monday-on-track-to-deliver-9-4b-in-u-s-online-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$9.4 billion was spent on Cyber Monday</a>.</p>
<p>Salesforce was <a href="https://www.salesforce.com/solutions/industries/retail/holiday-insights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more optimistic</a>: It said that digital revenues on Black Friday were $12.8 billion, with global figures coming in at $62 billion, while Thanksgiving was closer to $6.8 billion in online sales in the U.S., with the global figure around $30.4 billion.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eEK7ET62L6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/thanksgiving-on-track-for-a-record-6b-in-us-online-sales-says-adobe/">Thanksgiving online shopping hits record $5.1B, up 21.5% on 2019, 47% of sales via mobile</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Thanksgiving online shopping hits record $5.1B, up 21.5% on 2019, 47% of sales via mobile&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/thanksgiving-on-track-for-a-record-6b-in-us-online-sales-says-adobe/embed/#?secret=eEK7ET62L6" data-secret="eEK7ET62L6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“Cyber Monday is on track to break all previous records for online sales. Consumers will likely take advantage of the best discounted items today like TVs, toys and computers before price levels start creeping back up throughout the rest of the season,&#8221; said Taylor Schreiner, director, Adobe Digital Insights. &#8220;Shoppers are encouraged to do their gift buying soon as shipping in time for Christmas will get more expensive in the coming weeks.”</p>
<p>We will continue to update these figures as we get more data in. Adobe, for example, said that it believes that a whopping 29% of today&#8217;s revenue will come only between 7 p.m. and 11 p.m. Pacific (after work is over for the day).</p>
<p>(Part of the disparity in the two companies&#8217; figures is based on methodology. Adobe bases its figures on 80 of the top 100 retailers in the U.S., covering some 1 trillion transactions. Salesforce is using data gleaned from its Commerce Cloud, covering billions of engagements and millions of social media conversations, which it then combines with further analytics in its Shopping Index.)</p>
<p>One thing that is clear from both companies is that Cyber Monday continues to be the biggest day of them all. Why? It&#8217;s a perfect storm: The big rush of sales for the holiday season are up, but everyone is back at work, so they shop online instead of in person. Hence, big numbers on Cyber Monday.</p>
<p>As with the other days of the long weekend, one thing that has been impacting sales numbers is the fact that sales are starting earlier and earlier, but Adobe said that many consumers still believe that big bargains are laid on for the specific day. Some of the most popular shopping categories have included computers (marked down 30% on average), toys (20% discount), appliances (21%) and electronics (26%).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1Od7y9zjuW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/28/black-friday-online-sales-numbers/">Black Friday online shopping comes in $9B, $3.6B on smartphones</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Black Friday online shopping comes in $9B, $3.6B on smartphones&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/28/black-friday-online-sales-numbers/embed/#?secret=1Od7y9zjuW" data-secret="1Od7y9zjuW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Bigger businesses continue to reap the biggest spoils in online shopping &#8212; not least because they still provide the best range of delivery, pickup and return options to consumers, which become an even bigger set of priorities as you move further away from more amenable early adopters and into the more general population and potentially less experienced online shoppers. The conversion rates for big retailers (over $1 billion in revenues annually) are typically 70% higher than for smaller businesses.</p>
<p>Still, small businesses have tried to spend years catching up, boosted by various startups and companies like Shopify building tools for them to &#8220;be like Amazon&#8221; in their fulfillment, delivery and other features. Adobe said that Small Business Saturday, the newest of the Thanksgiving shopping holidays, saw $4.7 billion spent, a record for the day and up 30.2% on 2019. And to underscore just how tough times are for small businesses, Adobe said that the money small businesses were bringing in online this year was a whopping 294% higher than an average day in October.</p>
<p>So far some $23.5 billion has been spent during the holiday weekend.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/cyber-monday-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079370</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Salut raises $1.25M for its virtual fitness service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/salut-raises-1-25m-for-its-virtual-fitness-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/salut-raises-1-25m-for-its-virtual-fitness-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 17:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charles hudson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peloton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[precursor ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Salut, an app-based service that allows fitness trainers to host classes virtually, announced that it has raised $1.25 million in a new financing event. The round was led by Charles Hudson, an investor at Precursor Ventures. Founder Matthew DiPietro, formerly of Twitch, told TechCrunch that Salut soft-launched in mid-September, with a wider release [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://www.joinsalut.com/">Salut</a>, an app-based service that allows fitness trainers to host classes virtually, announced that it has raised $1.25 million in a new financing event. The round was led by <a href="https://twitter.com/chudson">Charles Hudson</a>, an investor at <a href="https://precursorvc.com/">Precursor Ventures</a>.</p>
<p>Founder <a href="https://twitter.com/mjdipietro">Matthew DiPietro</a>, formerly of Twitch, told TechCrunch that Salut soft-launched in mid-September, with a wider release coming today.</p>
<p>DiPietro thought up the concept behind Salut before the pandemic hit, he said during an interview, but after COVID-19 appeared the idea took on new urgency. The company put together what DiPietro described as a no-code alpha version of the service in May to test the market, allowing the then-nascent startup to validate demand on both sides of its marketplace &#8212; it&#8217;s famously difficult to jumpstart two-sided marketplaces, as demand tends to follow supply, and vice-versa.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The test allowed the company to get to confidence on demand existing from both trainers and exercise fans, and in its initial economic model.</p>
<p>With the new round in the bank and its product now formally launched, it&#8217;s up to Salut to scale rapidly. The company currently has 55 registered trainers on its platform, a reasonable start for the seed-stage startup. It will need to grow that figure by a few orders of magnitude if it wants to generate enough revenue to reach an eventual Series A.</p>
<p>But Salut is not focused on early-revenue generation, taking no cut of trainer revenue today. Indeed, per an email the company sent out to its users this morning, the startup is passing along 100% of post-Apple income that trainers generate, or 85% of the gross.</p>
<p>Currently users can donate to, or tip, trainers that host classes. DiPietro told TechCrunch that subscription options are coming in a quarter or two. The startup also announced today that trainers can now allow their classes to be replayed, what the startup called one of its &#8220;most requested features.&#8221;</p>
<p>Anyone familiar with <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/peloton-interactive" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="peloton-interactive">Peloton <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> understands why this matters; only a fraction of classes on the Peloton ecosystem are live at any point in time, but the bike comes with a library of content that users can simply load up whenever they like. This also allows Peloton to release more niche content than it otherwise might, as even the heavy metal-themed rides can accrete a reasonable ridership over time (something they might not be able to manage if all classes on the platform were only live once and then gone forever).</p>
<p>DiPietro is bullish on building income streams for trainers, especially during a pandemic that has locked many gyms, leaving fitness processionals with little to no income in many cases.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s some early signal that users are willing to pay, the company said, with early users willing to pay $5 or $10 for an hour of fitness training. And with a focus on the long-tail of trainers who can&#8217;t attract 10,000 fans to a single class, Salut thinks there are a large number of trainers who have enough pull to generate more income from its service, in time, than they could at a traditional studio.</p>
<p>Salut supports group video classes, of course, so trainers can collect monies from cohorts of users at a time.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s fundraising is largely earmarked for engineering, with the company having what its founder called an ambitious product roadmap.</p>
<p>The startup also announced a new project with <a href="https://www.fitnessmentors.com/">Fitness Mentors</a>, a company that helps trainers get certified, to create what the two companies are calling &#8220;the industry’s first Virtual Group Fitness Instructor (V-GFI) course and certification.&#8221;</p>
<p>You can see why Salut would want the certification to exist; its existence will allow users of its service to find trainers that are worth their time on its service, and may raise the overall level of quality of classes provided.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s see how far Salut can get with $1.25 million.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2mSO8gRZej"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/gift-guide-smart-exercise-gear-to-hunker-down-and-get-fit-with/">Gift Guide: Smart exercise gear to hunker down and get fit with</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gift Guide: Smart exercise gear to hunker down and get fit with&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/gift-guide-smart-exercise-gear-to-hunker-down-and-get-fit-with/embed/#?secret=2mSO8gRZej" data-secret="2mSO8gRZej" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/salut-raises-1-25m-for-its-virtual-fitness-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079318</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Curio Wellness launches $30M fund to help women and minorities own a cannabis dispensary</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/curio-wellness-launches-30m-fund-to-help-women-and-minorities-own-a-cannabis-dispensary/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/curio-wellness-launches-30m-fund-to-help-women-and-minorities-own-a-cannabis-dispensary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 16:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cannabis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Curio Wellness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079375</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;We think of diversity as a keystone issue for the cannabis industry,&#8221; said Curio WMBE Fund managing director Jerel Registre in a conversation with TechCrunch. Registre&#8217;s conviction around this program is obvious as he explains the problem the fund is addressing. The new fund, started by the Maryland-based medical cannabis company Curio Wellness, aims to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;We think of diversity as a keystone issue for the cannabis industry,&#8221; said Curio WMBE Fund managing director Jerel Registre in a conversation with TechCrunch. Registre&#8217;s conviction around this program is obvious as he explains the problem the fund is addressing.</p>
<p>The new fund, started by the Maryland-based medical cannabis company <a href="https://curiowellness.com">Curio Wellness</a>, aims to help underserved entrepreneurs entering the cannabis market. With $30 million to invest, the Curio WMBE Fund is looking to invest in up to 50 women, minority and <a href="https://rewirenewsgroup.com/article/2016/09/14/say-disabled-person-instead-person-disabilities/">disabled veterans</a> seeking to open and operate a Curio Wellness franchise with a path to 100% ownership in three years.</p>
<p>Registre tells TechCrunch the goal is to create more diverse ownership through a proven business model. Participants of this program gain access to capital and operational resources.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Curio made a name for itself in Maryland, where it&#8217;s the largest cannabis cultivator by market share. Founded in 2014, the family-owned business operates dispensaries rooted in a patient-centric approach. While a legally separate but affiliated entity from Curio Wellness, the Curio WMBE Fund aims to give franchisees access to Curio&#8217;s secret sauce.</p>
<p>&#8220;In looking at the systemic barriers that women, minorities and disabled veterans face in accessing capital, we decided to develop a solution that directly addresses this massive economic disparity,&#8221; said Michael Bronfein, CEO of Curio Wellness. &#8220;The Fund provides qualifying entrepreneurs with the investment capital they need to become a Curio Wellness Center franchisee while ensuring their success through our best in class business operations.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Let&#8217;s bottle the success we have,&#8221; Registre added. He likens the franchise model to McDonald&#8217;s, where the national corporation gives operators a proven standard operating procedure and ongoing support.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our fund is unlike any other in the industry,&#8221; Registre said, &#8220;as eligible entrepreneurs will have a clear path to 100% ownership in as little as three years. Many other funds rely on a model that utilizes minority entrepreneurs as a vehicle to achieve licenses: The Curio approach flips this model by empowering diverse entrepreneurs and supporting them along the way. If something happens and an investment-funded franchisee defaults, they must be replaced by another minority or woman owner. This ensures these licensees can get the financial support they need to launch while ensuring that the fund&#8217;s ultimate mission of supporting diverse entrepreneurs is achieved.&#8221;</p>
<p>Registre explained that diversity is central to Curio Wellness, too. Of the company&#8217;s 200 employees, 40% are female, and more than half are minorities. At the leadership level, 38% of management is female, and 44% identify as a member of a minority community.</p>
<p>&#8220;Diversity is a core asset that we recognize as integral to our success and our future, and that is why we decided to create this investment fund,&#8221; Registre said.</p>
<p>The fund provides two phases of support. The first provides capital to franchisees to open their Curio Wellness Center and assist them in obtaining licenses, selecting a location and hiring and training employees. Once the location is operational, the fund intends to provide ongoing support around managing, sales and marketing, store operations, and ensuring employees stay updated on product information.</p>
<p>Curio sees its locations as more than cannabis dispensaries. The company calls them Wellness Centers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Curio locations go beyond the traditional experience people have at a medical cannabis dispensary &#8212; they are total wellness destinations, under the leadership of a licensed pharmacist,&#8221; Registre explains. &#8220;Patient wellness is at the center of everything we do and is exemplified by a diverse array of holistic health products, services and educational programming we offer. While additive to the medical cannabis patient experience, these features open the store up to the entire community, not limiting the healthcare experience to only those with a medical cannabis card. This practice, of a patient-first mindset through a pharmacist-led model, allows us to truly lead the pursuit of wellness for everyone who walks in the front door.&#8221;</p>
<p>As of writing, the fund has raised half of its $30 million target. The company says the fund intentionally targeted, pitched and secured an investment pool that includes women and minorities. The fund expects to close by the end of 2020, and applications are expected to open in early 2021.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="W8EEN2H7V0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/weed-stocks-are-hitting-new-highs-after-biden-win/">Weed stocks are hitting new highs after Biden win</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Weed stocks are hitting new highs after Biden win&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/weed-stocks-are-hitting-new-highs-after-biden-win/embed/#?secret=W8EEN2H7V0" data-secret="W8EEN2H7V0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ojedr2UvrL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/04/cannabis-legalization-measures-set-to-pass-in-5-states/">Cannabis legalization measures set to pass in 5 states</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cannabis legalization measures set to pass in 5 states&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/04/cannabis-legalization-measures-set-to-pass-in-5-states/embed/#?secret=ojedr2UvrL" data-secret="ojedr2UvrL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="L7puWObtXZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/meadow-launches-a-powerful-mobile-marketing-tool-for-cannabis-dispensaries/">Meadow launches a powerful mobile marketing tool for cannabis dispensaries</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Meadow launches a powerful mobile marketing tool for cannabis dispensaries&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/meadow-launches-a-powerful-mobile-marketing-tool-for-cannabis-dispensaries/embed/#?secret=L7puWObtXZ" data-secret="L7puWObtXZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/curio-wellness-launches-30m-fund-to-help-women-and-minorities-own-a-cannabis-dispensary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079375</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Station: COVID&#8217;s effect on car ownership</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/the-station-covids-effect-on-car-ownership/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/the-station-covids-effect-on-car-ownership/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 16:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gatik AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MetroMile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox. Hello and welcome back to The Station, a newsletter dedicated to all the present and future ways people and packages move from Point A to Point B. For [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to The Station, a newsletter dedicated to all the present and future ways people and packages move from Point A to Point B.</p>
<p>For all my American readers, I hope you&#8217;re happy and satiated from the Thanksgiving holiday in this oddest of years. My hope for all Station readers, no matter where you reside, is a safe and healthy remainder of the year (and beyond!). While I took some time off last week, the news wheel kept on turning. A few items got my attention last week, notably an EY study that examined how views on public transit, mobility as a service and car ownership are changing due to COVID-19. Let&#8217;s get reading!</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Email me anytime at <a href="mailto:kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com">kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com</a> to share thoughts, criticisms, opinions or tips. You can also send a direct message to me at Twitter — <a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec">@kirstenkorosec</a>.</p>
<h2>Micromobbin&#8217;</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1894192 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png" alt="the station scooter1a" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Lime is adding another 1,000 scooters in San Francisco, an action it is able to take because the company also holds Jump&#8217;s permit in the city. For those who might have forgotten, Lime now owns Jump through a complex deal with Uber.</p>
<p>The company also released San Francisco scooter ridership data that shows how trip start and ends have moved outside of the downtown core and into neighborhoods like the Mission, Castro and Hayes Valley. Lime said this changing ridership pattern is consistent with its findings across the country, with more trips moving to residential neighborhoods since the COVID-19 pandemic swept across the globe.</p>
<p><strong>In other news &#8230;</strong></p>
<p><strong>CAKE</strong>, the Swedish maker of lightweight electric motorcycles, and the European battery supplier Northvolt have partnered to develop new battery cells for CAKE&#8217;s range of electric motorcycles. Research, development and testing will take place in 2021, with product slated to grace 2022 models.</p>
<h2>Deal of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896226 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png" alt="money the station" width="1600" height="400" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=1536,384 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Another day, another SPAC. Anyone else looking forward to a good old-fashioned S-1 filing?</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/metromile" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="metromile">Metromile, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> the pay-per-mile auto insurer, is credited with disrupting some of the inefficiencies of the auto insurance business model, notably how consumers are charged. Instead of a standard flat fee, the company charges customers based on their mileage, which it is able to measure via a device plugged into the vehicle.</p>
<p>That sounds like the kind of business model that might see an uptick in new customers during COVID pandemic times. And that did eventually happen. However, during the space between existing customers reducing their driving time and new drivers signing up with Metromile, the company was forced to lay off about one-third of its workforce.</p>
<p>The company has since recovered and now it&#8217;s taking the SPAC path to the public markets. Metromile plans to merge with special purpose acquisition company INSU Acquisition Corp. II, with an equity valuation of $1.3 billion. The company raised $160 million in private investment in public equity, or PIPE, in an investment round led by Chamath Palihapitiya&#8217;s firm Social Capital.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DiGNt7XI8j"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/pay-per-mile-auto-insurer-metromile-is-heading-to-public-markets-via-spac/">Pay-per-mile auto insurer Metromile is heading to public markets via SPAC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pay-per-mile auto insurer Metromile is heading to public markets via SPAC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/pay-per-mile-auto-insurer-metromile-is-heading-to-public-markets-via-spac/embed/#?secret=DiGNt7XI8j" data-secret="DiGNt7XI8j" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Metromile plans to use those proceeds to reduce existing debt and accelerate growth, specifically to hire employees to support its consumer insurance and enterprise businesses, and grow beyond its eight-state geographic footprint to a goal of 21 states by the end of next year, and nationwide coverage by the end of 2022.</p>
<p>For details on the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/pay-per-mile-auto-insurer-metromile-is-heading-to-public-markets-via-spac/">Metromile SPAC</a> head on over to my story. For a deeper dive into the insurance tech business, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/insurtechs-big-year-gets-bigger-as-metromile-looks-to-go-public/">check out Alex Wilhelm&#8217;s article</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HSPwNl5RU7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/insurtechs-big-year-gets-bigger-as-metromile-looks-to-go-public/">Insurtech&#8217;s big year gets bigger as Metromile looks to go public</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Insurtech&#8217;s big year gets bigger as Metromile looks to go public&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/insurtechs-big-year-gets-bigger-as-metromile-looks-to-go-public/embed/#?secret=HSPwNl5RU7" data-secret="HSPwNl5RU7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3><strong>Another giant deal </strong></h3>
<p>Manbang — described as the Chinese Uber for trucks — was formed in 2017 through a merger between rivals Yunmanman and Huochebang. The company&#8217;s app matches truck drivers and merchants transporting cargo and provides financial services to truckers.</p>
<p>Apparently, investors can&#8217;t get enough of these kinds of freight app businesses. Manbang is the latest example, with a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/manbang-1-7-billion-funding/">$1.7 billion haul</a> from Softbank Vision Fund, Sequoia Capital China, Permira and Fidelity, a consortium that co-led the round. Other participants were Hillhouse Capital, GGV Capital, Lightspeed China Partners, Tencent, Jack Ma&#8217;s YF Capital and more.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SG73aGDTeB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/manbang-1-7-billion-funding/">Google-backed Chinese truck-hailing firm Manbang raises $1.7 billion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google-backed Chinese truck-hailing firm Manbang raises $1.7 billion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/manbang-1-7-billion-funding/embed/#?secret=SG73aGDTeB" data-secret="SG73aGDTeB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This is just two years after the company raised $1.9 billion. Manbang said it achieved profitability this year. Its valuation was reportedly on course to reach $10 billion in 2018.</p>
<h3>It&#8217;s raining dollars!</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_1996432" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1236085488.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996432" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1996432 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1236085488.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1236085488.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1236085488.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1236085488.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1236085488.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1236085488.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1236085488.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1996432" class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>For <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tesla-motors" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tesla-motors">Tesla, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> that is.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;re all aware, but in case you missed it, Tesla&#8217;s market cap surpassed $500 billion last week. As of today (Monday), it sits at $547 billion — a more than fivefold increase since the start of the year.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s likely that price will push higher thanks to its imminent inclusion on the S&amp;P 500 Index. When Tesla joins the S&amp;P 500 on December 21, it will be among the most valuable companies on the benchmark. Its weighting will be so influential that the S&amp;P DJI is mulling whether to add the stock at the full float-adjusted market capitalization weight all at once or in two tranches.</p>
<p>Tesla&#8217;s addition to the S&amp;P 500 isn&#8217;t just a symbolic nod. Joining the S&amp;P 500 has real financial benefits, as investors that have index-tracked funds will be forced to buy shares. With share prices already popping, that will mean investors will have to sell other stocks to make room for Tesla.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XpjzWWoO1k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/tesla-gets-a-spot-on-the-sp-500/">Tesla gets a spot on the S&#038;P 500</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tesla gets a spot on the S&#038;P 500&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/tesla-gets-a-spot-on-the-sp-500/embed/#?secret=XpjzWWoO1k" data-secret="XpjzWWoO1k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The rise of the car</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s nearing December, which means I&#8217;ve been — and will continue to be — flooded with year-end surveys, studies and forecasts for 2021.</p>
<p>One study from EY, which <a href="https://www.ey.com/en_gl/automotive-transportation/how-mobility-can-help-build-a-better-post-covid-19-world">examined data from nine countries</a>, suggests that mobility as a service (MaaS) is losing momentum to the car, truck and SUV.</p>
<p>And millennials are driving the trend. The 2020 EY Mobility Consumer Index, which surveyed more than 3,300 consumers across nine countries, found that 31% of people without a car intend to buy one in the next six months, and 45% of those will be millennials. The study also found that just 6% of non-car owners surveyed are looking to buy an all-electric vehicle.</p>
<p>More than three-quarters (78%) of respondents said they&#8217;re going to be more likely to use their cars for travel in a post-pandemic world with millennials making more than half of that number (52%), according to EY.</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t just a U.S. phenomenon. Respondents from Italy (47%) and Germany (46%) said they&#8217;re more likely to purchase a new car. Respondents from China were most likely to increase their car usage (90% of respondents), closely followed by India (85%) and Germany (81%).</p>
<p>Meanwhile, public transport use is expected to decline by around 30%.</p>
<p>John Simlett, EY Global Future of Mobility Leader, raises several questions in the study:</p>
<blockquote><p>With more people buying cars and car usage expected to increase, this leaves policymakers with some very difficult questions to answer: How to accommodate all these cars on our roads aim for a more diverse mobility mix? How will this trend impact public transport investment? Quite simply, is this sustainable, and if not, what needs to be done and by whom?</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Readers: What are your answers? Send them my way.</strong></p>
<h2>Notable reads and other tidbits</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2037863 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png" alt="the-station-delivery" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>And finally, the news smorgasbord you&#8217;ve been waiting for.</p>
<p><strong>Ford&#8217;s</strong> all-electric Mustang Mach-E has an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/the-epa-says-the-ford-mustang-mach-es-electric-range-is-a-lackluster-211-300-miles/">estimated EPA range</a> of between 211 miles to 300 miles, depending on the model. While the Mach-E matched Ford&#8217;s range target, it&#8217;s well under that found in competing vehicles.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="l9ojyBRTTX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/the-epa-says-the-ford-mustang-mach-es-electric-range-is-a-lackluster-211-300-miles/">The EPA says the Ford Mustang Mach-E&#8217;s electric range is a lackluster 211-300 miles</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The EPA says the Ford Mustang Mach-E&#8217;s electric range is a lackluster 211-300 miles&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/the-epa-says-the-ford-mustang-mach-es-electric-range-is-a-lackluster-211-300-miles/embed/#?secret=l9ojyBRTTX" data-secret="l9ojyBRTTX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Gatik</strong>, the autonomous vehicle startup focused on the &#8220;middle mile,&#8221; is expanding into Canada through a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gatiks-self-driving-box-trucks-to-shuttle-groceries-for-loblaw-in-canada/">partnership with retail giant Loblaw</a>. The company, which also announced $25 million in fresh funding, already uses its self-driving box trucks to deliver customer online grocery orders for Walmart.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="apzlAQl44M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gatiks-self-driving-box-trucks-to-shuttle-groceries-for-loblaw-in-canada/">Gatik&#8217;s self-driving box trucks to shuttle groceries for Loblaw in Canada</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gatik&#8217;s self-driving box trucks to shuttle groceries for Loblaw in Canada&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gatiks-self-driving-box-trucks-to-shuttle-groceries-for-loblaw-in-canada/embed/#?secret=apzlAQl44M" data-secret="apzlAQl44M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Gatik is deploying five autonomous box trucks in Toronto to deliver goods for Loblaw starting in January 2021. The fleet will be used seven days a week on five routes along public roads. All vehicles will have a safety driver as a co-pilot. This deployment, which follows a 10-month pilot in the Toronto area, marks the first autonomous delivery fleet in Canada.</p>
<p><strong>General Motors</strong> changed sides in a battle over whether states &#8212; and specifically California &#8212; can set tailpipe emissions regulations and other rules meant to mitigate climate change that are stricter than the federal government. The automaker said it will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gm-dumps-trump-to-side-with-california-in-emissions-rules-fight/">no longer back the Trump administration&#8217;s lawsuit</a> to prevent California from setting its own rules.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ETZn4yU2zu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gm-dumps-trump-to-side-with-california-in-emissions-rules-fight/">GM dumps Trump to side with California in emissions rules fight</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GM dumps Trump to side with California in emissions rules fight&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gm-dumps-trump-to-side-with-california-in-emissions-rules-fight/embed/#?secret=ETZn4yU2zu" data-secret="ETZn4yU2zu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>May Mobility</strong>, the autonomous shuttle startup backed by Toyota, has a new partnership with on-demand shuttle platform Via. (I missed this item in the last newsletter.) The aim is for the companies to combine their expertise to expand services to new cities in 2021. May Mobility will use Via&#8217;s fleet platform for booking, routing, passenger and vehicle assignment and identification, customer experience and fleet management of its autonomous vehicles.</p>
<p><strong><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/ola" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="ola">Ola</strong>, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Uber and other ride-hailing firms in India will be only able draw a fee of up to 20% on ride fares. The new rules are  a setback for the SoftBank-backed firms, which are already struggling to improve their finances in the key overseas market.</p>
<p>The guidelines, which for the first time bring modern-age app-based ride-hailing firms under a regulatory framework in the country, also put a cap on the so-called surge pricing, the fare Uber and Ola charge during hours when their services see peak demands, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/india-sets-rules-for-commissions-surge-pricing-for-uber-and-ola/">TechCrunch&#8217;s Manish Singh reports</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8gsahFPk7Q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/india-sets-rules-for-commissions-surge-pricing-for-uber-and-ola/">India sets rules for commissions, surge pricing for Uber and Ola</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India sets rules for commissions, surge pricing for Uber and Ola&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/india-sets-rules-for-commissions-surge-pricing-for-uber-and-ola/embed/#?secret=8gsahFPk7Q" data-secret="8gsahFPk7Q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/the-station-covids-effect-on-car-ownership/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079386</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Sketchboard Pro for iPad</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/review-sketchboard-pro-for-ipad/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/review-sketchboard-pro-for-ipad/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bryce Durbin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 16:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sketchboard Pro]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2079388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Sketchboard Pro is an iPad stand designed for artists.

It’s compatible with over 30 sizes of iPad. It retails for $119.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2079389" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2079389" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2079389" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-01.jpg" alt="Review: Sketchboard Pro for iPad" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-01.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-01.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-01.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-01.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-01.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-01.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-01.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-01.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2079389" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sketchboard Pro</p></div></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2079390" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-02.jpg" alt="[text] The Sketchboard Pro is an iPad stand designed for artists. It’s compatible with over 30 sizes of iPad. It retails for $119. There are spots for placing an Apple Pencil upright or connected to the iPad for charging as well as openings for the camera and power cable. The iPad fits snugly so the entire surface is flat. [image: Three views of the Sketchboard Pro from overhead, one empty, one with an iPad being inserted as well as a power cord and one with an iPad in place.]" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-02.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-02.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-02.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-02.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-02.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-02.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-02.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-02.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><br />
<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2079391" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-03.jpg" alt="[text] There are four pop-out legs on the back so the board can stand (with two legs at a time) at an angle in any direction. The board measures 19.5 x 17 inches (49.5 x 43.2 cm). [image: two back views of the Sketchboard Pro, one with legs collapsed and one with legs out.]" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-03.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-03.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-03.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-03.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-03.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-03.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-03.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-03.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><br />
<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2079392" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-04.jpg" alt="[text] The Sketchboard Pro sits at a 20 degree angle and weighs 4.5 lbs (about 2 kg). It can also stand upright like an easel, but I found this position to be less stable. [image: side views of the Sketchboard Pro to demonstrate a 20 degree angle]" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-04.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-04.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-04.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-04.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-04.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-04.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-04.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-04.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><br />
<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2079393" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-05.jpg" alt="[text] I tested the Sketchboard Pro with a 12.9” iPad (2019). Combined, they weighed about 5.6 lbs (2.54 kg). I found the board easy to use at a desk or table, but more cumbersome in casual settings such as a couch. [image: illustrations of holding the Sketchboard Pro by the handle and sitting and drawing]" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-05.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-05.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-05.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-05.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-05.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-05.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-05.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-05.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><br />
<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2079394" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-06.jpg" alt="[text] The Sketchboard Pro is a handy accessory for artists who work extensively on the iPad. I’d recommend it if you’re looking for a digital drawing setup to mimic a traditional drafting table and hoping to save your posture. [image: an illustration of the Sketchboard Pro]" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-06.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-06.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-06.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-06.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-06.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-06.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-06.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sketchboard-pro-review-06.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><a href="https://sketchboardpro.com/">Sketchboard Pro</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/review-sketchboard-pro-for-ipad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2079388</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
