<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 14:11:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>A new climate calculator for livestock aims to help ranchers reduce emissions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/a-new-climate-calculator-for-livestock-aims-to-help-ranchers-reduce-emissions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/a-new-climate-calculator-for-livestock-aims-to-help-ranchers-reduce-emissions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Riggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 14:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2161653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When it comes to sustainable livestock production and agriculture, measurement is the first, and sometimes most elusive, step in the process of turning our food system from a carbon emitter into a carbon sink.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to sustainable livestock production and agriculture, measurement is the first &#8212; and sometimes most elusive &#8212; step in the process of turning our food system from a carbon emitter into a carbon sink. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So <a href="https://www.dsm.com/corporate/home.html">DSM</a>, a science-based company that focuses on agriculture and other parts of our food systems, and <a href="https://www.blonkconsultants.nl/">Blonk</a>, a data analytics for sustainability consultancy, developed </span><a href="https://sustell.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sustell</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a combination software and practical service for ranchers to understand and improve the sustainability of their operations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While sustainable and regenerative agriculture doesn’t have a universally agreed-upon definition, it usually involves changing land management practices to sequester more carbon in the soil, using more environmentally friendly animal feeds and reducing fossil fuel usage of tractors and other farm equipment among many other changes. The goal is to reduce the 7.1 gigatonnes of CO2 released into the atmosphere, about </span><a href="http://www.fao.org/news/story/en/item/197623/icode/#:~:text=Total%20emissions%20from%20global%20livestock,of%20all%20anthropogenic%20GHG%20emissions."><span style="font-weight: 400;">14.5%</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of all greenhouse gas emissions, created by the livestock industry.  </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There’s this tremendous need for accurate footprinting of animal production down to the individual farm level,” said David Nickell, vice president of sustainability and business solutions at DSM. “And each farm, of course, is very different. And you have to have a system which is able to use actual farm data, and to get an accurate picture of that particular farm.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The system analyzes the environmental impact of a farm’s activity on 19 different categories, including climate change, resource use, water scarcity, runoff and ozone depletion. Farmers provide data on their daily operations, including feed composition and use, manure management practices, animal mortality, the electricity system and the other infrastructure, transportation logistics and mitigation technologies employed, like scrubbers or excess heat circulation systems, and sometimes packaging to the software. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blonk’s environmental footprint technology then produces a life cycle assessment of the farm, an analysis of the environmental impact of rearing an animal from inception to when it exits the farm gate. DSM and Blonk have created Sustell modules for most land farm animals, including chickens, pigs and dairy and egg production, and plans to extend it to cover beef and aquaculture. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What is really key is that we were able to build on this momentum of methodologies and standards that have been developed,” said Hans Blonk, CEO of Blonk Consultants and Blonk Sustainability Tools. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pLbvyUXclB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/yard-stick-provides-measurement-technology-to-combat-climate-change/">Yard Stick provides measurement technology to combat climate change</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Yard Stick provides measurement technology to combat climate change&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/yard-stick-provides-measurement-technology-to-combat-climate-change/embed/#?secret=pLbvyUXclB" data-secret="pLbvyUXclB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blonk was able to combine agriculture environmental standards from the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, European Commission and many others in one place to create the vast library of background data needed for the software to produce useful and actionable insights.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Customers at the moment really want to understand what they&#8217;re doing,” Nickell said. “They want to understand their baseline [footprint] and rank them. Understand what&#8217;s good, and what’s not so good. Customers want to understand how they rate compared to peer benchmarking, whether it&#8217;s a country or an industry benchmark.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once the Sustell software gives farmers clarity on the emissions on their farms, they can then identify where improvements need to be made and DSM helps implement ways of reducing those emissions, creating an end-to-end service for customers and hopefully a positive impact on the planet. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Practical interventions make change happen,” Nickell said. “We’ve invested in technologies which reduce the footprint of animal products production. The service is measurement and marry that up with bringing solutions, which make a difference. That’s the complete solution to making this much-needed change happen.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But in order for Sustell to create that change, it needs to be adopted widely and the learnings need to be shared between competitors. Right now, DSM and, in some ways, the capitalist system, isn’t set up for that. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Nickell, DSM is first focusing Sustell on big integrated livestock companies. This is a common challenge with new innovative environmental technologies that can be adopted by big farming conglomerates or co-ops with money and resources to spend, while smaller family farms get left behind. But Nickell hopes that Sustell can scale to work with smaller farms, as well. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second issue is around data sharing. While Nickell was very clear that Sustell will be following all applicable data privacy and ownership rules &#8212; and that’s usually a good thing &#8212; in order to really create meaningful environmental change, transparency is actually key. Competitors need to share the best ways for reducing emissions so everyone can adopt them and save the planet, but many companies are very data protective. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think maybe that [data sharing] develops in time,” Nickell said. “I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re there yet. Maybe it will get to that level as more and more customers are transparent on their footprint and their reporting.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HIUHbx3ag4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/17/outdoor-startups-see-supercharged-growth-during-covid-19-era/">Outdoor startups see supercharged growth during COVID-19 era</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Outdoor startups see supercharged growth during COVID-19 era&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/17/outdoor-startups-see-supercharged-growth-during-covid-19-era/embed/#?secret=HIUHbx3ag4" data-secret="HIUHbx3ag4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/a-new-climate-calculator-for-livestock-aims-to-help-ranchers-reduce-emissions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2161653</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Croatia&#8217;s Gideon Brothers raises $31M for its  3D vision-enabled autonomous warehouse robots</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/croatias-gideon-brothers-raises-31m-for-its-%e2%80%a83d-vision-enabled-autonomous-warehouse-robots/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/croatias-gideon-brothers-raises-31m-for-its-%e2%80%a83d-vision-enabled-autonomous-warehouse-robots/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 13:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[central europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[croatia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DB Schenker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Director]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eastern europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fetch Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gideon Brothers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Koch Disruptive Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[massachusetts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[munich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OTTO Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taavet Hinrikus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teradyne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TransferWise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zagreb]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Proving that Central and Eastern Europe remains a powerhouse of hardware engineering matched with software, Gideon Brothers (GB), a Zagreb, Croatia-based robotics and AI startup, has raised a $31 million Series A round led by Koch Disruptive Technologies (KDT), the venture and growth arm of Koch Industries Inc., with participation from DB Schenker, Prologis Ventures, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Proving that Central and Eastern Europe remains a powerhouse of hardware engineering matched with software, <a href="https://www.gideonbros.ai/">Gideon Brothers</a> (GB), a Zagreb, Croatia-based robotics and AI startup, has raised a $31 million Series A round led by Koch Disruptive Technologies (KDT), the venture and growth arm of Koch Industries Inc., with participation from DB Schenker, Prologis Ventures, and Rite-Hite.</p>
<p>The round also includes participation from several of Gideon Brothers&#8217; existing backers: Taavet Hinrikus (co-founder of TransferWise), Pentland Ventures, Peaksjah, HCVC (Hardware Club), Ivan Topčić, Nenad Bakić, and Luca Ascani.</p>
<p>The investment will be used to accelerate the development and commercialization of GB’s AI and 3D vision-based ‘autonomous mobile robots’ or ‘AMRs’. These perform simple tasks such as transporting, picking up, and dropping off products in order to free up humans to perform more valuable tasks.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company will also expand its operations in the EU and US by opening offices in Munich, Germany and Boston, Massachusetts, respectively.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162980" style="width: 508px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162980" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gideon-Brothers-founders.jpg" alt="Gideon Brothers founders" width="498" height="332" class="size-full wp-image-2162980" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gideon-Brothers-founders.jpg 498w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gideon-Brothers-founders.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gideon-Brothers-founders.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gideon-Brothers-founders.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 498px) 100vw, 498px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162980" class="wp-caption-text">Gideon Brothers founders</p></div></p>
<p>Gideon Brothers make robots and the accompanying software platform that specializes in horizontal and vertical handling processes for logistics, warehousing, manufacturing, and retail businesses. For obvious reasons, the need to roboticize supply chains has exploded during the pandemic.</p>
<p>Matija Kopić, CEO of Gideon Brothers, said: “The pandemic has greatly accelerated the adoption of smart automation, and we are ready to meet the unprecedented market demand. The best way to do it is by marrying our proprietary solutions with the largest, most demanding customers out there. Our strategic partners have real challenges that our robots are already solving, and, with us, they’re seizing the incredible opportunity right now to effect robotic-powered change to some of the world’s most innovative organizations.”</p>
<p>He added: “Partnering with these forward-thinking industry leaders will help us expand our global footprint, but we will always stay true to our Croatian roots. That is our superpower. The Croatian start-up scene is growing exponentially and we want to unlock further opportunities for our country to become a robotics &amp; AI powerhouse.”</p>
<p>Annant Patel, Director at Koch Disruptive Technologies said: “With more than 300 Koch operations and production units globally, KDT recognizes the unique capabilities of and potential for Gideon Brothers&#8217; technology to substantially transform how businesses can approach warehouse and manufacturing processes through cutting edge AI and 3D AMR technology.”</p>
<p>Xavier Garijo, Member of the Board of Management for Contract Logistics, DB Schenker added: “Our partnership with Gideon Brothers secures our access to best in class robotics and intelligent material handling solutions to serve our customers in the most efficient way.”</p>
<p>GB’s competitors include Seegrid, Teradyne (MiR), Vecna Robotics, Fetch Robotics, AutoGuide Mobile Robots, Geek+ and Otto Motors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/croatias-gideon-brothers-raises-31m-for-its-%e2%80%a83d-vision-enabled-autonomous-warehouse-robots/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162977</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Compose.ai raises $2.1M to help everyone write faster</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/compose-ai-raises-2-1m-to-help-everyone-write-faster/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/compose-ai-raises-2-1m-to-help-everyone-write-faster/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 13:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Compose.ai, which built its own language model to help folks write faster, landed a $2.1 million seed round led by Craft Ventures.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In today&#8217;s GPT-3 world, it&#8217;s not uncommon to hear about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/gpt-3-powered-copy-ai-raises-2-9m-in-a-round-led-by-craft-ventures/">new software services</a> that deal with text. <a href="https://www.compose.ai/">Compose.ai</a> is one such company, though it built its own language model to help folks write faster. Its early product work was enough for it to land a $2.1 million seed round led by Craft Ventures, it announced this morning.</p>
<p>Compose.ai is essentially an auto-complete function that works wherever you browse the web. The company is also building the capability for its AI-powered backend to learn your voice, imbibe context to help provide better responses, and, in time, absorb a company&#8217;s larger voice to help align its aggregate writing output.</p>
<p>Co-founders Landon Sanford and Michael Shuffett told TechCrunch that Compose.ai believes that in five years, average folks won&#8217;t type every word that they write. They want to bring that future to more people through the Compose.ai Chrome extension, which hopefully workers can access without having to get corporate permission.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sanford and Shuffett described their language algorithm as a multi-tier product. Its first tier learns from reading the internet itself, learning English. The second tier deals with specific domains, like email. The third tier learns a user&#8217;s voice, and, in time, a fourth tier will deal with a company&#8217;s generalized approach to language.</p>
<p>The ability for a company to provide its workers with a shared language model that could offer linguistic and word-choice preferences as they write is an interesting concept. The idea of such a strong, centrally held tone lands somewhere between helpful and intellectually rigid. But lots of folks don&#8217;t want to put their own spin on writing; many people don&#8217;t like writing at all. So perhaps having more central support won&#8217;t be onerous to most &#8212; but rather a time-saving hack.</p>
<p>Regardless, Compose.ai is going to staff up modestly with its new raise. The company currently has three full-time workers and some contract help. Sanford and Shuffett told TechCrunch that the company intends to stay small, hiring a few experienced engineering and machine-learning staff to help flesh out its product team.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s ahead for Compose? Its founders told TechCrunch that they are starting to talk to the corporate world a bit more than before and are planning on launching a paid service toward the end of the quarter. That could mean early revenue, extending the startup&#8217;s runway substantially.</p>
<p>What Compose is building isn&#8217;t technically simple, and the company has interesting work ahead of it to get its economics properly tuned. The company&#8217;s founders told TechCrunch that the personalization work that its product will execute for customers can be expensive if done incorrectly; the pair said that they could make a future, $10/month plan attractive economically, but if done in a &#8220;naive&#8221; fashion, Compose.ai could spend $500 in compute costs to support the same account.</p>
<p>That would be bad.</p>
<p>But the company is confident that its impending paid plans should shake out well in financial terms, which makes us all the more interested in giving that version of its product a spin when we get the chance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/compose-ai-raises-2-1m-to-help-everyone-write-faster/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lifted raises $6.2M Series A round led by Fuel Ventures for its long-term social care platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/lifted-raises-6-2m-series-a-round-led-by-fuel-ventures-for-its-long-term-social-care-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/lifted-raises-6-2m-series-a-round-led-by-fuel-ventures-for-its-long-term-social-care-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 13:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caregiving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dementia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fuel.Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Pearson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trustpilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As people live longer and longer and have long-term health issues like cancer and dementia, caring for elderly relatives is becoming a huge societal and political issue. Right now this care is antiquated and run by incumbents, many of which still run off paper and Excel. We are now seeing a new wave of startups [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As people live longer and longer and have long-term health issues like cancer and dementia, caring for elderly relatives is becoming a huge societal and political issue. Right now this care is antiquated and run by incumbents, many of which still run off paper and Excel. We are now seeing a new wave of startups turn up to tackle this space by applying Apple’s age-old model of owning the experience end-to-end and running everything on a platform.</p>
<p>The latest to join this race is UK startup <a href="https://www.liftedcare.com/">Lifted</a>, which has now raised $6.2 million in a Series A funding round led by Fuel Ventures. Also participating were existing investor 1818 Venture Capital as well as new investors Novit Ventures, Perivoli Innovations, the J.B. Ugland family office, and a number of Angels. This latest funding round takes the total raised by Lifted to $11.2M.</p>
<p>Lifted says its UK market is increasing and claims the number of people caring for adult loved ones has risen exponentially during the pandemic, with almost 1 in 2 people supporting people outside their household.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup is entering a perfect storm of increasing need, unpopular care homes, and the UK Government still without a long-term plan for social care.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162968" style="width: 586px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162968" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lifted-tech-1.png" alt="Lifted app" width="576" height="686" class="size-full wp-image-2162968" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lifted-tech-1.png 576w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lifted-tech-1.png?resize=126,150 126w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lifted-tech-1.png?resize=252,300 252w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lifted-tech-1.png?resize=571,680 571w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Lifted-tech-1.png?resize=42,50 42w" sizes="(max-width: 576px) 100vw, 576px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162968" class="wp-caption-text">Lifted app</p></div></p>
<p>In contrast to a raft of agencies and freelancers, Lifted directly employs its care workforce and uses its platform to “gamify and improve the experience of carers to make them perform better in people&#8217;s lives and also to restore respect to the caring profession” with its  Care Management Platform, says the company.</p>
<p>Lifted has also acquired the ‘Live Better With Dementia’ website and launched the Lifted Dementia Hub, an online community with a marketplace of products.</p>
<p>Rachael Crook co-founded Lifted with Sam Cohen. She says she was inspired to get into the sector when, at the age of 24, she had to care for her mother, who was diagnosed with dementia at age 56.</p>
<p>Rachael Crook, Lifted CEO sold me at an interview: “I was in that position much younger than most people. And it seemed abundantly clear to me that it was an experience that was hugely emotionally important to me, and financially expensive, was really convoluted and frustrating. It made an already really difficult time, more difficult. My mum brought me up to really fight for the underdog and I felt like the carers themselves were getting a really poor deal. And yet, it&#8217;s a huge colossal market. The care market is set to double in the next 20 years, and for the next 10 years, we will look to compete against traditional care companies. We want to transform the care experience. This is a product that is worth four and a half times your mortgage. And yet, it&#8217;s predominantly bought in a really antiquated way with paper and pen systems. It’s really hard to keep up to date with your loved ones’ care. We&#8217;re also competing against new entrants.”</p>
<p>She added: “In 12 months, we have tripled revenue, launched the first App in the world to offer free care advice, and cut Carer churn to half the industry average, all while maintaining exclusively 5-star reviews on Trustpilot.”</p>
<p>Mark Pearson, Managing Partner of Fuel Ventures said: “Rachael, Sam and their team have delivered exceptional growth in the past year. They have a unique vision of the future for care and their model is delivering clear results for both sides of the marketplace.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/lifted-raises-6-2m-series-a-round-led-by-fuel-ventures-for-its-long-term-social-care-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162958</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Liteboxer, the Peloton of boxing, raises $20 million Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/liteboxer-the-peloton-of-boxing-raises-20-million-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/liteboxer-the-peloton-of-boxing-raises-20-million-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 13:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liteboxer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162930</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Liteboxer, the Peloton for boxing, has announced the close of a $20 million Series A funding round led by Nimble Ventures. B. Riley Venture Capital participated, alongside existing investors Raptor Group and Will Ventures. Liteboxer launched publicly to the world in July of 2020, announcing an in-home device that brings gamification, hit music, and a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://liteboxer.com/">Liteboxer</a>, the Peloton for boxing, has announced the close of a $20 million Series A funding round led by Nimble Ventures. B. Riley Venture Capital participated, alongside existing investors Raptor Group and Will Ventures.</p>
<p>Liteboxer launched publicly to the world in July of 2020, announcing an in-home device that brings gamification, hit music, and a touch of entertainment to a boxing workout. The patented hardware includes a system of lights that smartly pair with music to give the user an intense workout that feels more like a game. Hit where the light goes off, on beat with the music, until your ass has sufficiently been kicked.</p>
<p>Content is a big piece of the puzzle with Liteboxer. For $29/month, users get access to unlimited training sessions and workouts led by Liteboxer trainers. The Liteboxer also has a Quick Play option, that forgoes the trainer content and lets users workout based on the song they choose.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This comes by way of an exclusive partnership with Universal Music. Liteboxer always has a rotation of 100 Universal Music songs available to users, and the system is able to automatically pair the lighting with the beat of the music for lighter-weight workouts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Zh2o9Znhnb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/liteboxer-the-peloton-for-boxing-enters-the-ring/">Liteboxer, the Peloton for boxing, enters the ring</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Liteboxer, the Peloton for boxing, enters the ring&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/liteboxer-the-peloton-for-boxing-enters-the-ring/embed/#?secret=Zh2o9Znhnb" data-secret="Zh2o9Znhnb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Not only are users competing with themselves, but they can also connect with other friends to compete against one another.</p>
<p>Engagement is the name of the game for Liteboxer, according to cofounders Jeff Morin (CEO) and Todd Dagres (Chairman). They say that since shipping equipment in October, they&#8217;re seeing users, on average, doing a Liteboxer workout four to five times a week.</p>
<p>Since launch, the company has made some tweaks. For one, the original focus on the trainer side was on the technique of boxing. But given. the importance of music to the workouts, Liteboxer has realized the impact that an entertaining trainer can have.</p>
<p>&#8220;Rhythm has been so important,&#8221; said Morin. &#8220;We&#8217;ve learned that you can&#8217;t train rhythm if someone doesn&#8217;t have that. We&#8217;ve seen trainers with more spin class experience be able to feel the cadence. of the music, and know when the beat drop is coming, and craft these programs that are basically an art piece or performance.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company is also looking at its employment of these trainers, shifting from 1099 to part-time employment and seriously considering full-time W2 employment for them, as well.</p>
<div></div>
<div>This latest round of funding is meant to fuel growth and power initiatives aimed at getting the device out in the wild so more people can see and experience it. The cofounders explained that this was one of the big challenges of launching during the pandemic with a product like this.</div>
<div></div>
<div>This brings the company&#8217;s total funding to $28.5 million.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/liteboxer-the-peloton-of-boxing-raises-20-million-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162930</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Version One launches $70M Fund IV and $30M Opportunities Fund II</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/version-one-launches-70m-fund-iv-and-30m-opportunities-fund-ii/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/version-one-launches-70m-fund-iv-and-30m-opportunities-fund-ii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boris Wertz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laura Behrens Wu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Version One]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[version one ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early stage investor Version One, which consists of partners Boris Wertz and Angela Tran, has raised its fourth fund, as well as a second opportunity fund specifically dedicated to making follow-on investments. Fund IV pools $70 million from LPs to invest, and Opportunities Fund II is $30 million, both up from the $45 million Fund [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Early stage investor Version One, which consists of partners Boris Wertz and Angela Tran, has <a href="https://versionone.vc/announcing-fund-iv-and-opportunities-fund-ii/">raised its fourth fund</a>, as well as a second opportunity fund specifically dedicated to making follow-on investments. Fund IV pools $70 million from LPs to invest, and Opportunities Fund II is $30 million, both up from the $45 million Fund III and roughly $20 million original Opportunity Fund.</p>
<p>Version One is unveiling this new pool of capital after a very successful year for the firm, which is based in Vancouver and San Francisco. 2021 saw its first true blockbuster exit, with Coinbase&#8217;s IPO. The investor also saw big valuation boosts on paper for a number of its portfolio companies, including Ada (which raises at a $1.2 billion valuation in May); Dapper Labs (valued at $7.5 billion after riding the NFT wave); and Jobber (no valuation disclosed but raised a $60 million round in January).</p>
<p>I spoke to both Wertz and Tran about their run of good fortune, how they think the fund has achieved the wins it recorded thus far, and what Version One has planned for this Fund IV and its investment strategy going forward.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We have this pretty broad focus of mission-driven founders, and not necessarily just investing in SaaS, or just investing in marketplaces, or crypto,&#8221; Wertz said regarding their focus. &#8220;We obviously love staying early — pre-seed and seed — we&#8217;re really the investors that love investing in people, not necessarily in existing traction and numbers. We love being contrarian, both in terms of the verticals we go in to, and and the entrepreneurs we back; we&#8217;re happy to be backing first-time entrepreneurs that nobody else has ever backed.&#8221;</p>
<p>In speaking to different startups that Version One has backed over the years, I&#8217;ve always been struck by how connected the founders seem to the firm and both Wertz and Tran — even much later in the startups&#8217; maturation. Tran said that one of their advantages is following the journey of their entrepreneurs, across both good times and bad.</p>
<p>&#8220;We get to learn,&#8221; she said. &#8220;It&#8217;s so cool to watch these companies scale [&#8230;] we get to see how these companies grow, because we stick with them. Even the smallest things we&#8217;re just constantly thinking about— we&#8217;re constantly thinking about Laura [Behrens Wu] at Shippo, we&#8217;re constantly thinking about Mike [Murchison] and David [Hariri] at Ada, even though it&#8217;s getting harder to really help them move the needle on their business.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wertz also discussed the knack Version One seems to have for getting into a hot investment area early, anticipating hype cycles when many other firms are still reticent.</p>
<p>&#8220;We we went into crypto early in 2016, when most people didn&#8217;t really believe in crypto,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We started investing pretty aggressively in in climate last year, when nobody was really invested in climate tech. Having a conviction in in a few areas, as well as the type of entrepreneurs that nobody else really has conviction is what really makes these returns possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>Since climate tech is a relatively new focus for Version One, I asked Wertz about why they&#8217;re betting on it now, and why this is not just another green bubble like the one we saw around the end of the first decade of the 2000s.</p>
<p>&#8220;First of all, we deeply care about it,&#8221; he said. Secondly, we think there is obviously a new urgency needed for technology to jump into to what is probably one of the biggest problems of humankind. Thirdly, is that the clean tech boom has put a lot of infrastructure into the ground. It really drove down the cost of the infrastructure, and the hardware, of electric cars, of batteries in general, of solar and renewable energies in general. And so now it feels like there&#8217;s more opportunity to actually build a more sophisticated application layer on top of it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tran added that Version One also made its existing climate bet at what she sees as a crucial inflection point — effectively at the height of the pandemic, when most were focused on healthcare crises instead of other imminent existential threats.</p>
<p>I also asked her about the new Opportunity Fund, and how that fits in with the early stage focus and their overall functional approach.</p>
<p>&#8220;It doesn&#8217;t require much change in the way we operate, because we&#8217;re not doing any net new investments,&#8221; Tran said. &#8220;So we recognize we&#8217;re not growth investors, or Series A/Series B investors that need to have a different lens in the way that they evaluate companies. For us, we just say we want to double down on these companies. We have such close relationships with them, we know what the opportunities are. It&#8217;s almost like we have information arbitrage.&#8221;</p>
<p>That works well for all involved, including LPs, because Tran said that it&#8217;s appealing to them to be able to invest more in companies doing well without having to build a new direct relationship with target companies, or doing something like creating an SPV designated for the purpose, which is costly and time-consuming.</p>
<p>Looking forward to what&#8217;s going to change with this fund and their investment approach, Wertz points to a broadened international focus made possible by the increasingly distributed nature of the tech industry following the pandemic.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think that the thing that probably will change the most is just much more international investing in this one, and I think it&#8217;s just direct result of the pandemic and Zoom investing, that suddenly the pipeline has opened up,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve certainly learned a lot about ourselves over the past year and a half,&#8221; Tran added. &#8220;I mean, we&#8217;ve always been distributed, [&#8230;] and being remote was one of our advantages. So we certainly benefited and we didn&#8217;t have to adjust our working style too much, right. But now everyone&#8217;s working like this, [&#8230;] so it&#8217;s going to be fun to see what advantage we come up with next.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/version-one-launches-70m-fund-iv-and-30m-opportunities-fund-ii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162883</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BuyerAssist launches with $2M in funding to help B2B sales team keep their buyers engaged</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/buyerassist-launches-with-2m-in-funding-to-help-b2b-sales-team-keep-their-buyers-engaged/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/buyerassist-launches-with-2m-in-funding-to-help-b2b-sales-team-keep-their-buyers-engaged/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b2b sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buyer engagement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BuyerAssist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BuyerAssist.io]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Selling enterprise software is much more complicated than convincing a potential customer that your solution is the best and signing a contract. A recent Gartner study found that buying groups for B2B solutions can involve up to six to 10 decision makers, and that the majority of buyers said their most recent purchase was “very [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2162834" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/L-to-R-Shyam-Amit-and-Shankar-BuyerAssist.io-Founders.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162834" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2162834" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/L-to-R-Shyam-Amit-and-Shankar-BuyerAssist.io-Founders.jpg" alt="A group photo of BuyerAssist founders Shyam HN, Amit Dugar and Shankar Ganapathy" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/L-to-R-Shyam-Amit-and-Shankar-BuyerAssist.io-Founders.jpg 3427w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/L-to-R-Shyam-Amit-and-Shankar-BuyerAssist.io-Founders.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/L-to-R-Shyam-Amit-and-Shankar-BuyerAssist.io-Founders.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/L-to-R-Shyam-Amit-and-Shankar-BuyerAssist.io-Founders.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/L-to-R-Shyam-Amit-and-Shankar-BuyerAssist.io-Founders.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/L-to-R-Shyam-Amit-and-Shankar-BuyerAssist.io-Founders.jpg?resize=1536,965 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/L-to-R-Shyam-Amit-and-Shankar-BuyerAssist.io-Founders.jpg?resize=2048,1286 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/L-to-R-Shyam-Amit-and-Shankar-BuyerAssist.io-Founders.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2162834" class="wp-caption-text">BuyerAssist founders Shyam HN, Amit Dugar and Shankar Ganapathy</p></div></p>
<p>Selling enterprise software is much more complicated than convincing a potential customer that your solution is the best and signing a contract. A <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/sales/insights/b2b-buying-journey">recent Gartner study </a>found that buying groups for B2B solutions can involve up to six to 10 decision makers, and that the majority of buyers said their most recent purchase was “very complex or difficult” as they came to a consensus while negotiating with vendors.</p>
<p><a href="https://buyerassist.io/">BuyerAssist</a>, a new startup founded by former employees of sales readiness platform MindTickle, wants to make the buying process as smooth as possible. The company is launching its beta product to the public today with $2 million in seed funding led by Stellaris Venture Partners and Emergent Ventures, with participation from angel investors. The capital will be used for hiring in the U.S. and India, with plans to bring BuyerAssist’s platform out of beta later this year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Headquartered in San Francisco, with an office in Pune, India, BuyerAssist.io was founded last year by Amit Dugar, Shankar Ganapathy and Shyam HN, all alumni of SoftBank Vision 2-backed MindTickle, a platform that enables companies to train their sales staff at scale. The philosophy behind BuyerAssist draws on HN and Ganapathy’s experience on the sales and marketing side of MindTickle: Ganapathy was its director of strategic accounts, while HN served as head of global sales development.</p>
<p>“We’ve sold half a million dollar deals, and deals where you have anywhere form 10 to 25 people involved from the buyer side,” HN told TechCrunch. “There’s a core team of about five to 10 people, but then there is also an extended team that comes and goes during the process.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nt4K7isZs6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/15/sales-readiness-platform-mindtickle-raises-100-million-led-by-softbank-vision-fund-2/">Sales readiness platform MindTickle raises $100 million led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sales readiness platform MindTickle raises $100 million led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/15/sales-readiness-platform-mindtickle-raises-100-million-led-by-softbank-vision-fund-2/embed/#?secret=nt4K7isZs6" data-secret="nt4K7isZs6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The pandemic added an extra layer of complexity to B2B sales, because many deals were done remotely. Furthermore, sales representatives get less time to interact with buyers. The Gartner report found that when B2B buying teams consider a purchase, they spend only 17% of that time meeting with potential suppliers, and the amount of time they spend interacting with any sales representative may be only 5% to 6%. This means vendors have to find ways to keep potential buyers engaged, while making the process easier for them.</p>
<p>BuyerAssist describes itself as a &#8220;operating system for B2B companies to deliver the most effective buying experience.&#8221; It helps by providing a centralized place to gather information that would usually be buried in emails and notes, and make it searchable. It also lets both vendors and buyers share information about their needs (like pricing, information security reviews and when they want to deploy software by), creating more transparency for each side, and stores important files like proposals, contracts and legal documentation.</p>
<p>For vendors, having information and questions from potential buyers organized in one place can help them better understand their deals pipeline and meet revenue goals. BuyerAssist also provides analytics that can help them retain more contracts. For example, it alerts vendors when buyers become less engaged, which may mean they are losing interest.</p>
<p>During its beta stage, BuyerAssist worked with four companies. The platform is currently focused on enterprise software and SaaS companies that do a lot of their sales remotely, but can be used for any complex sales process that involves multiple calls and emails. Other sectors BuyerAssist wants to enter include manufacturing and financial services.</p>
<p>BuyerAssist is part of a new crop of startups focused on helping vendors and buyers work together on complicated sales. Others include Accord, MetaCX, Dealpoint and Recapped.io. HN said that the space is still very new, so companies are still figuring out their positioning. In BuyerAssist’s case, this means focusing on buyer engagement, instead of mutual success plans or collaborations, from the beginning. HN said the company will double down on investing in two key areas of product development: building its enterprise grade product to support complex sales and becoming the preferred way for buying teams to engage with BuyerAssist’s clients.</p>
<p>In statement about the investment, Stellaris Venture Partners partner Alok Goyal said, “As a venture capitalist focusing on the SaaS space, we get to see hundreds of teams. But it is very rare to find teams that create a perfect storm of domain expertise, functional expertise in different areas of building SaaS companies and at the same time bringing the perfect complementarity between the founders.”</p>
<p>Anupam Rastogi, a partner at Emergent Ventures, said “What excites me about BuyerAssist is that it focuses on reducing friction between buyers and sellers. Buyers want more flexibility and less noise. Sellers want to run a more consistent sales process. BuyerAssist facilitates this, and enables both to build a long term partnership. This is where we see the industry heading in the years and decades to come.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WtaVRhYFbg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/saas-companies-can-grow-to-20m-arr-by-selling-exclusively-to-developers/">SaaS companies can grow to $20M+ ARR by selling exclusively to developers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SaaS companies can grow to $20M+ ARR by selling exclusively to developers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/saas-companies-can-grow-to-20m-arr-by-selling-exclusively-to-developers/embed/#?secret=WtaVRhYFbg" data-secret="WtaVRhYFbg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/buyerassist-launches-with-2m-in-funding-to-help-b2b-sales-team-keep-their-buyers-engaged/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162833</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Relativity Space launches its valuation to $4.2B with $650M in new funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/relativity-space-launches-its-valuation-to-4-2b-with-650m-in-new-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/relativity-space-launches-its-valuation-to-4-2b-with-650m-in-new-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[additive manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relativity Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tim ellis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162689</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3D-printed rocket startup Relativity Space has raised a $650 million Series E, bringing its total raised to over $1.2 billion. Relativity’s post-money valuation now stands at $4.2 billion, a source familiar with the matter told TechCrunch. The round was led by Fidelity Management &#38; Research Company, with participation from new investors with funds and accounts [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">3D-printed rocket startup Relativity Space has raised a $650 million Series E, bringing its total raised to over $1.2 billion. Relativity’s post-money valuation now stands at $4.2 billion, a source familiar with the matter told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The round was led by Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company, with participation from new investors with funds and accounts managed by BlackRock, Centricus, Coatue, and Soroban Capital, and participation from existing investors Baillie Gifford, K5 Global, Tiger Global, Tribe Capital, XN, Brad Buss, Mark Cuban, Jared Leto, and Spencer Rascoff.</p>
<p>The funds from the Series E will go toward accelerating the production of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/relativity-space-unveils-plans-for-a-new-much-larger-and-fully-reusable-rocket/">Terran R, the company’s heavy-lift, fully reusable two-stage rocket</a>. Terran R joins Terran 1, Relativity’s debut rocket, which will conduct its first orbital flight at the end of 2021.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company has been pretty tight-lipped about Terran R, but are now releasing further details alongside the funding announcement. As expected, Terran 1 and Terran R differ in pretty significant ways: the former is expendable, the latter reusable; the former is designed for small payloads, the latter for large. Even the Terran R’s payload fairing is reusable, and Relativity has devised a system that makes it easier to recover and recycle as it stays attached to the second stage.</p>
<p>The larger rocket will clock in at 216 feet tall with a maximum payload capacity of 20,000 pounds to low Earth orbit. (For comparison, SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket stands at around 230 feet with a maximum payload to LEO of 22,800 pounds.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162730" style="width: 4454px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/29.1018_BLACK_WPERSON_Logo.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162730" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2162730 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/29.1018_BLACK_WPERSON_Logo.png" alt="" width="4444" height="2500" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/29.1018_BLACK_WPERSON_Logo.png 4444w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/29.1018_BLACK_WPERSON_Logo.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/29.1018_BLACK_WPERSON_Logo.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/29.1018_BLACK_WPERSON_Logo.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/29.1018_BLACK_WPERSON_Logo.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/29.1018_BLACK_WPERSON_Logo.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/29.1018_BLACK_WPERSON_Logo.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/29.1018_BLACK_WPERSON_Logo.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4444px) 100vw, 4444px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2162730" class="wp-caption-text">Relativity&#8217;s Terran 1 on the left, and Terran R on the right. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Relativity</p></div></p>
<p>Terran R will use seven of its new Aeon R engines on the first stage, each capable of 302,000 pounds of thrust. The same 3D printers that will produce Terran R&#8217;s engines and rockets also currently make the nine Aeon 1 engines that power the Terran 1, which means Relativity doesn&#8217;t have to drastically reconfigure its production line to build the new launch vehicle.</p>
<p>A single Terran R should take around 60 days to build, Ellis estimated. That&#8217;s an incredible pace for a rocket with this kind of payload capacity.</p>
<p>Even though Terran 1 has not seen a launch yet, Relativity shows no signs of slowing down Terran R’s development: Ellis said the company will also launch Terran R from its launch site at Cape Canaveral as early as 2024 and that it signed its first anchor customer, “a well-known blue-chip company,” for the new rocket.</p>
<p>Relativity has printed around 85% of the rocket that will perform the company’s first orbital flight at the end of this year. The Terran 1 that will perform that mission will not be carrying any payload. Terran 1’s second launch is scheduled to take place in June &#8217;22, and will carry cubesats to LEO as part of NASA’s Venture Class Launch Services Demonstration 2 (VCLS Demo 2) contract.</p>
<p>Relativity CEO Tim Ellis in an interview with TechCrunch likened 3D printing to a paradigm shift in manufacturing. “I think really the thing people haven&#8217;t gotten about our approach, or 3D printing in general, is it&#8217;s actually more like transitioning from gas internal combustion engines to electric, or on-premise service to cloud,” Ellis said. “3D printing is a cool technology but more than that, it&#8217;s actually software and data-driven manufacturing and automation technology.”</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/9BhkjEc6Q64?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Because the core of 3D printing is a technology stack, the company can produce algorithmically generated structures with “geometries that couldn’t be possible” with traditional manufacturing, Ellis said. And the design can be easily adjusted to fit market demand.</p>
<p>Ellis, who started the metal 3D printing division at Blue Origin before founding Relativity, said that the strategy from day one was to design and build Terran 1 and a heavy-lift counterpart.</p>
<p>The actual mechanisms involved in 3D printing can technically occur in environments even when gravity is much lower – like the gravity on Mars, which is only about 38% of the gravity on Earth. But more importantly, Ellis said it’s an approach that’s “inevitably required” in an uncertain off-planet environment.</p>
<p>“When we founded Relativity, the inspiration was watching SpaceX land rockets and dock with the space station. They were 13 years old and they were, despite all of that pretty inspiring success, the only company that wanted to make humanity a multi-planetary and go to Mars,” Ellis said. “And I thought that 3D printing tech was inevitable to actually build an industrial base on another planet. No one else had actually even tried to go to Mars or said that was their core mission. And that&#8217;s still true today, actually, even five years later, it&#8217;s still just us and SpaceX. And I really do hope to inspire dozens to hundreds of companies to go after that mission.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5N1DwdW8Wd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/relativity-space-unveils-plans-for-a-new-much-larger-and-fully-reusable-rocket/">Relativity Space unveils plans for a new, much larger and fully reusable rocket</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Relativity Space unveils plans for a new, much larger and fully reusable rocket&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/relativity-space-unveils-plans-for-a-new-much-larger-and-fully-reusable-rocket/embed/#?secret=5N1DwdW8Wd" data-secret="5N1DwdW8Wd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/relativity-space-launches-its-valuation-to-4-2b-with-650m-in-new-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162689</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whatfix nabs $90M to help workers onboard and get the most out of their IT stacks</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/whatfix-nabs-90m-to-help-workers-onboard-and-get-the-most-out-of-their-it-stacks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/whatfix-nabs-90m-to-help-workers-onboard-and-get-the-most-out-of-their-it-stacks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 12:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatbots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital adoption platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital assistants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whatfix]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Digital transformation&#8221; has been on the mind of many an organization in the last year: the pandemic and the shift it&#8217;s brought to how we work are speeding up investments in new apps, infrastructure and work practices to improve productivity regardless of where we sit all day. Now, it looks like we&#8217;re on to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;Digital transformation&#8221; has been on the mind of many an organization in the last year: the pandemic and the shift it&#8217;s brought to how we work are speeding up investments in new apps, infrastructure and work practices to improve productivity regardless of where we sit all day. Now, it looks like we&#8217;re on to the next stage of that journey: actually figuring out how to adopt and run with all that new tech.</p>
<p>In a sign of the times, today a startup called <a href="https://whatfix.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Whatfix</a> &#8212; which has built a platform that helps make better use of tech investments by giving chatbot-style guidance to users on how to use apps, with the option also to apply AI to understand what a person is doing to suggest what actions to take next &#8212; is announcing $90 million in funding. It will use the money to continue expanding its tech platform and hiring more talent to meet demand, said CEO Khadim Batti, who co-founded the company with Vara Kumar (CTO), in an interview this week.</p>
<p>Sources close to the company &#8212; co-headquartered in San Jose and Bangalore &#8212; confirmed that the Series D round was made at a valuation of around $600 million, triple Whatfix&#8217;s value in its Series C round last year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That sharp rise is due in part to the state of the market today, but also the company&#8217;s growth within that bigger trend. Whatfix today has some 500 global customers on its books, The Netherlands Red Cross, Experian, Sentry Financial Services, Cardinal Health Canada, BMC Software Inc., and Bausch &amp; Lomb among them. Some 75% of its business is coming out of the U.S., with another 18% from Europe. Revenues in the last six months have been growing at a rate of 100% quarter-on-quarter.</p>
<p>&#8220;This pandemic has proven an inflection point for adoption,&#8221; said Batti (pictured above, left with Kumar, right).</p>
<p>This latest tranche of equity funding is coming from a mix of financial and strategic investors.</p>
<p>SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund 2 is leading the round, with Eight Roads Ventures, Sequoia Capital India, Dragoneer Investment Group, F-Prime Capital and Cisco Investments also investing. The company has raised just under $140 million in total.</p>
<p>&#8220;Digital adoption solutions&#8221; &#8212; the general term describing what Whatfix has built &#8212; have become a popular solution for enterprises that have found themselves in an IT pickle, Batti said.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve seen more than $500 billion spent on enterprise software, with areas like SaaS growing very fast. There is so much there, and every employee has access to do better work. But most are not adopting or using that software. This means a lot [of inefficiency] in &#8216;digital transformation,'&#8221; said Batti. &#8220;We are focusing on fixing this problem.&#8221;</p>
<p>Digital adoption and digital experience overall can come in many forms these days.</p>
<p>They include assistants that are embedded directly into apps themselves (with some versions of this &#8212; such as Clippy on Word &#8212; nearly as old as software itself). The category also includes separate platforms that integrate at the back end with the apps that you use, providing not just a single ingestion point for data but intelligence on how best to use it, and what to use. (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/dooly-raises-80m-more-for-its-ai-tools-to-help-salespeople-manage-their-busywork/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dooly</a> for sales teams is an example of that, although I don&#8217;t know if it would describe itself as a &#8220;digital adoption solution&#8221; per se.)</p>
<p>Others like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/17/pendo-scores-100m-series-e-on-1-billion-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pendo</a> are geared more at observing how your sites and apps are being adopted and used by others. And there are a number of others out there specifically looking at digital adoption by enterprises and competing directly with Whatfix: they include Apty, Userlane, Applearn.</p>
<p>One of the biggest &#8212; WalkMe &#8212; yesterday <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/walkme-announces-launch-of-initial-public-offering-301306903.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced an IPO</a> at an estimated $2.5 billion valuation.</p>
<p>Overall digital adoption and digital experience are big businesses: one analyst <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/digital-experience-platform-market-size-to-be-valued-at-15-80-billion-by-2025--owing-to-adoption-of-digital-platforms-for-developing-marketing-strategies-by-industry-participants--million-insights-301259286.html#:~:text=All%20Products-,Digital%20Experience%20Platform%20Market%20Size%20To%20Be%20Valued%20At%20%2415.80,By%20Industry%20Participants%20%7C%20Million%20Insights" target="_blank" rel="noopener">estimates</a> that the market is growing currently at a rate of just under 11% annually and will be worth $15.8 billion by 2025.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2162943" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.49.04-PM.png?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="86" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.49.04-PM.png 770w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.49.04-PM.png?resize=150,43 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.49.04-PM.png?resize=300,86 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.49.04-PM.png?resize=768,219 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.49.04-PM.png?resize=680,194 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.49.04-PM.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Whatfix is built around the premise that it sits on top of whatever apps a company may choose to use, and will work with just about any piece of modern software, Batti said. That includes Whatfix being able to provide assistance on apps even when they have been customised for a particular workplace. It most commonly appears like a little chatbot on the user&#8217;s screen, like the one in this paragraph, which can expand with more details and information as needed, like this:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2162944" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.51.03-PM.png?w=179" alt="" width="179" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.51.03-PM.png 706w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.51.03-PM.png?resize=89,150 89w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.51.03-PM.png?resize=179,300 179w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.51.03-PM.png?resize=405,680 405w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-1.51.03-PM.png?resize=30,50 30w" sizes="(max-width: 179px) 100vw, 179px" /></p>
<p>The company works with the most popular software packages &#8212; including Salesforce, MS Dynamics, Oracle&#8217;s CRM platform, ServiceNow, SuccessFactors, SharePoint, Workday &#8212; but, since it is used in the form of a browser extension or an overlay integrated by a company&#8217;s IT department, it can be used to help guide people with any application that&#8217;s available over the web. Batti said that one priority the startup has is to build deeper integrations with specific apps so that Whatfix can be used better across mobile and with local apps in future, not just via the web.</p>
<p>Many might think of &#8220;digital adoption&#8221; as training someone to use a particular software package, and while Whatfix is used for that, the company has also found a lot of traction as a tool beyond it, providing support on a more regular basis and across a wider variety of use cases, whether it&#8217;s to help guide people through app usage, or to monitor what they are doing in order to help suggest what to do next, and even populate relevant fields if &#8220;next&#8221; means using a different app.</p>
<p>The platform can be used to create usage guides, multilingual support, multi-device support, user tracking and more, and it comes with low-code options (it can be intergrated into an app with a single line of code, the company says).</p>
<p>The company claims its assistants can increase employee productivity by 35%, reduce training time and costs by 60%, reduce employee case tickets by 50% and increase application data accuracy by 20%.</p>
<p>While the field for digital adoption is very crowded today, it&#8217;s numbers like these, Whatfix&#8217;s own growth, and the fact that software is continuing to get more capable, but also more complex, that have interested investors.</p>
<p>“Digital Adoption Solutions are enhancing the growth and importance of SaaS products for enterprises globally,” said Munish Varma, Managing Partner, SoftBank Investment Advisers, in a statement. &#8220;Whatfix makes it easier for companies to use SaaS products, which increases productivity. Whatfix, with its roster of global clients, is well placed to become a DAS leader, and we are excited to be part of their journey.” Sumer Juneja, Partner, SoftBank Investment Advisers, added: “Enterprises spend billions on applications across multiple functions and yet employee adoption is low. Quick adoption ensures payback on software investments. Whatfix’s solutions will be a key driver for enterprises to achieve this goal, which is reflected in their growth.”</p>
<p>What will be interesting to watch is how platforms like Whatfix&#8217;s will evolve over time, and what further functions they might take on. For example, in enterprises, one of the biggest vulnerabilities in security has been how people mistakenly click on dodgy links in emails or otherwise inadvertently pass on information to malicious hackers. Could there be a role for digital adoption assistants to identify when this might happen and alert people before they click the wrong way? Regardless, the question and very existence of loopholes like that are signals for why we&#8217;ll probably why we&#8217;ll continue to see tools like Whatfix&#8217;s around for some time to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/whatfix-nabs-90m-to-help-workers-onboard-and-get-the-most-out-of-their-it-stacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162861</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Art app SketchAR to allow artists to list their artworks on NFT marketplaces directly</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/art-app-sketchar-to-allow-artists-to-list-their-artworks-on-nft-marketplaces-directly/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/art-app-sketchar-to-allow-artists-to-list-their-artworks-on-nft-marketplaces-directly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 12:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distributed computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An update to an existing art app that allows artists to access NFT marketplaces directly, could have the potential to democratize access to the NFT world for artists not currently in crypto. SketchAR, is an existing mobile app that allows artists to turn photos into illustrations using its AI-based computer vision. It is now is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">An update to an existing art app that allows artists to access NFT marketplaces directly, could have the potential to democratize access to the NFT world for artists not currently in crypto. <a href="https://sketchar.io/">SketchAR</a>, is an existing mobile app that allows artists to turn photos into illustrations using its AI-based computer vision. It is now is launching a new feature that allows users to turn their art into NFTs directly inside the app, and then sell it. Content produced on the app can also include a public community feed and digital learning courses.</p>
<p>The app, which boasts it has almost a million users already, will start off selecting a single ‘Creator of the Week’ from its community for their art to be NFT’d on the OpenSea marketplace. But a new feature will shortly enable any artist using the platform to create and auction an NFT on-demand.</p>
<p>However, there a catch. The artwork will have to be created directly in the SketchAR app in order to prove the artist is the legitimate rights holder, says the startup. This is, however, an advantage, says the startup, since very few marketplaces monitor the derivation and authenticity of artworks uploaded proactively.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>And for now, it looks like there is no real equivalent app on the market, although there are of course plenty of ways to create an artwork and then upload it to an NFT marketplace in a separate process.</p>
<p>Andrey Drobitko, CEO and founder told me: “It’s a unique offer since it allows even amateur designers to create an art piece and turn it into an NFT without diving deep into the ecosystem, connecting their wallet to their OpenSea account and paying significant gas fees to minting.”</p>
<p>He said: “Since the art piece comes from the app SketchAR, it also ensures it’s authentic and wasn’t stolen &#8211; something that happened quite a few times with NFTs.&#8221;</p>
<p>SketchAR said it also built its own infrastructure that allows it to use Ethereum and other 2-layer solutions like Flow, Immutable, or Binance Smart Chain, to reduce costs.</p>
<p>“Basically it competes with artists and designers learning a lot about blockchain, how to work with it, and working directly with marketplaces like OpenSea or Rarible” added Drobitko.</p>
<p>&#8220;15 years ago I realized I couldn’t make much money as an artist and only continued to make art for pleasure. It’s different now and we’re excited to support artists, help them develop creative skills, and successfully monetize their artworks,” he said.</p>
<p>It’s estimated there are roughly 50 million artists globally, but fewer than 10% are able to make it their primary source of income.</p>
<p>According to NonFungible.com more than $2 billion was spent on NFTs during the first quarter of 2021 representing an increase of about 2,100% from Q4 2020.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/art-app-sketchar-to-allow-artists-to-list-their-artworks-on-nft-marketplaces-directly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162928</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nuggs creator Simulate raises $50M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/nuggs-creator-simulate-raises-50m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/nuggs-creator-simulate-raises-50m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 12:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[776]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat alternative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Simulate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2161729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New York-based Simulate today announced a $50 million fundraise. Led by Alexis Ohanian’s 776, the Series B brings the meat alternative’s total funding to north of $60 million and values it at $260 million. Simulate’s first product, Nuggs (formerly also the startup&#8217;s name), has already caused a splash, thanks in no small part to aggressive [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">New York-based Simulate today announced a $50 million fundraise. Led by Alexis Ohanian’s 776, the Series B brings the meat alternative’s total funding to north of $60 million and values it at $260 million.</p>
<p>Simulate’s first product, Nuggs (formerly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/nuggs-rebrands-as-simulate-with-new-cash-a-new-cto-and-an-expanded-line-of-faux-meat-foods/">also the startup&#8217;s name</a>), has already caused a splash, thanks in no small part to aggressive online advertising. The company notes a massive push in retail availability in the last six months. The chicken nugget alternative was available direct to consumers through online ordering when it launched in Summer 2019 &#8212; availability that moved the needle during U.S. shutdowns over the past year.</p>
<p>“During the height of the pandemic, people really wanted frozen food shipped directly to their door,” founder and CEO Ben Pasternak tells TechCrunch. “At the time, we were DTC only, so we saw a lot of growth there prior to our pivot to retail.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He adds that the majority of the company’s sales now currently come from retail, due to accessibility and more restrictive DTC pricing. Currently, the product is available in 5,000 retail locations, a list that includes pretty massive retail names like Walmart/ Sam’s Club, Target and Whole Foods.</p>
<p>“We are getting ready to launch in restaurants and in fast food,” says Pasternak. “Internationally, we recently launched across Canada, and have plans to expand to other countries too.”</p>
<p>Funding will also go toward expanding the company’s headcount. Currently at 20, Simulate expects to expand employment to 50 people by 2022. “Over half of that expansion will be focused on growing our engineering team,” Pasternak says.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="m2KBcWUQhq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/nuggs-rebrands-as-simulate-with-new-cash-a-new-cto-and-an-expanded-line-of-faux-meat-foods/">Nuggs rebrands as Simulate with new cash, a new CTO and an expanded line of faux-meat foods</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nuggs rebrands as Simulate with new cash, a new CTO and an expanded line of faux-meat foods&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/nuggs-rebrands-as-simulate-with-new-cash-a-new-cto-and-an-expanded-line-of-faux-meat-foods/embed/#?secret=m2KBcWUQhq" data-secret="m2KBcWUQhq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PnV7tIb11S"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/06/startups-making-meat-alternatives-are-gaining-traction-worldwide/">Startups making meat alternatives are gaining traction worldwide</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startups making meat alternatives are gaining traction worldwide&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/06/startups-making-meat-alternatives-are-gaining-traction-worldwide/embed/#?secret=PnV7tIb11S" data-secret="PnV7tIb11S" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/nuggs-creator-simulate-raises-50m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2161729</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Airbase raises $60M as the corporate spend market segments, matures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/airbase-raises-60m-as-the-corporate-spend-market-segments-matures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/airbase-raises-60m-as-the-corporate-spend-market-segments-matures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate spend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menlo ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Airbase, a corporate spend startup, announced that it has closed a $60 million Series B led by Menlo Ventures. The deal&#8217;s announcement comes after Divvy, another corporate-spend focused startup, sold to Bill.com for several billion dollars, and other unicorns in the space like Brex and Divvy each raised nine-figure rounds. According to Airbase CEO [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://www.airbase.com/">Airbase</a>, a corporate spend startup, announced that it has closed a $60 million Series B led by Menlo Ventures. The deal&#8217;s announcement comes after Divvy, another corporate-spend focused startup, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/why-did-bill-com-pay-2-5b-for-divvy/">sold to Bill.com for several billion dollars</a>, and other unicorns in the space like Brex and Divvy each raised nine-figure rounds.</p>
<p>According to Airbase CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/thejo?lang=en">Thejo Kote</a>, his company&#8217;s round is not a response to the Divvy sale. Instead, he told TechCrunch in an interview, his company kicked off its fundraising process before that deal was announced.</p>
<p>Not that what Airbase undertook was a process in the traditional sense; Kote did not spend months schlepping a deck along Sand Hill Road, imbibing mediocre architecture, overdressed MBAs and good weather in equal quantities. Instead, he decided that his firm was open to raising more capital in April despite having capital in the bank from previous investments, and 10 days later had signed a term sheet with Menlo.</p>
<p>Menlo partner and new Airbase board member Matt Murphy told TechCrunch in a separate interview that his firm had had its eye on the company for some time before its deal, allowing it to move quickly when Kote opened the door to more funding. (Murphy was candid in sharing that he had spent quite some time getting in front of Airbase, which we pass along as evidence of just how competitive the venture capital market can be in 2021.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="O3IpjLhLG2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/why-did-bill-com-pay-2-5b-for-divvy/">Why did Bill.com pay $2.5B for Divvy?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why did Bill.com pay $2.5B for Divvy?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/why-did-bill-com-pay-2-5b-for-divvy/embed/#?secret=O3IpjLhLG2" data-secret="O3IpjLhLG2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>According to Kote, his firm&#8217;s new capital was raised on a $600 million valuation, post-money, which means that the Menlo-led transaction involved 10% of the company&#8217;s shares.</p>
<h2>A segmenting market</h2>
<p>TechCrunch&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/as-corporate-cards-are-subsumed-into-software-airbase-posts-rapid-growth/">coverage of the corporate spend market</a> has largely focused on the revenue growth of the competing players, and their decision to either charge for the software that they offer along with corporate cards or not. But Kote views the market as segmenting in a somewhat different manner, namely along target customer scale. Divvy, for example, went after SMBs, while Airbase has more of a mid-market focus.</p>
<p>The customer targeting matters, with Kote telling TechCrunch that mid-market companies are looking for a single solution to replace various point-services that they have traditionally paid for. In the case of corporate spend, that could mean that many companies are willing to pay for new software so long as it can replace several services that they were buying discretely before; say, corporate cards and expense management software.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WyG5dem4Xp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/spend-management-startup-ramp-confirms-115m-raise-1-6b-valuation/">Spend management startup Ramp confirms $115M raise at a $1.6B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Spend management startup Ramp confirms $115M raise at a $1.6B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/spend-management-startup-ramp-confirms-115m-raise-1-6b-valuation/embed/#?secret=WyG5dem4Xp" data-secret="WyG5dem4Xp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Kote said that the Divvy-Bill.com news was a &#8220;massive validation&#8221; of his company&#8217;s thesis that software would prove key in the market formerly focused on corporate cards, and that offering cards was itself a &#8220;race to the bottom.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the view of Airbase&#8217;s CEO, his company has a six to eight quarter lead on its competitors in product terms. The market will vet that perspective, but the company&#8217;s confidence in its vision and new capital should provide it with ample opportunity to prove out its thesis in the coming quarters, and see whether where it views its product in terms of market positioning viz. demand and competitors is correct.</p>
<h2>The investor perspective</h2>
<p>Menlo Ventures seems to think so, to the tune of its largest single check to date from a non-growth fund. What did Murphy et al. find so compelling about the company? In the investor&#8217;s view, Airbase has a shot at replacing point-solutions in mid-market companies, precisely as Kote imagines:</p>
<blockquote><p>Airbase consolidates all the different spend apps which greatly decreases complexity in workflows as finance teams previously had to jump from app to app and don’t have a real time, holistic view in one place. [&#8230;] Of course there is an advantage in not having to pay for multiple apps, but the biggest benefits are simplicity of workflows which is where we heard most of the product love.</p></blockquote>
<p>Murphy continued, adding that at many companies &#8220;a manager won’t know until after [a quarter ends] whether the team for example spent above or below budget,&#8221; which makes integrated solutions more attractive.</p>
<p>Why does the viewpoint matter? It implies that the market that Airbase can sell into is rather large; instead of considering the aggregate non-payroll spend that its possible customer companies may generate and then applying an interchange vig to the total to calculate its potential scale, we might tabulate mid-market software spend on expenses, accounting and other categories as the startup&#8217;s true TAM. And as Airbase can still generate top-line from interchange and other sources, it could be well-situated for long-term growth.</p>
<p>Of course, its competitors are not interested in letting Airbase have all the fun. Ramp <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/spend-management-startup-ramp-confirms-115m-raise-1-6b-valuation/">recently raised lots of capital</a>, and is investing in its own software stack. With a free price point, it&#8217;s perhaps the most aggressive player on the interchange-first side of its market. And Brex is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/22/2156073/">working to make lots of public noise</a>, again, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/brex-raises-425m-at-a-7-4b-valuation-as-the-corporate-spend-war-rages-on/">has its own tower of cash</a>, software focus and recently launched paid-SaaS service.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bGT5VIbNsw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/brex-raises-425m-at-a-7-4b-valuation-as-the-corporate-spend-war-rages-on/">Brex raises $425M at a $7.4B valuation, as the corporate spend war rages on</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Brex raises $425M at a $7.4B valuation, as the corporate spend war rages on&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/brex-raises-425m-at-a-7-4b-valuation-as-the-corporate-spend-war-rages-on/embed/#?secret=bGT5VIbNsw" data-secret="bGT5VIbNsw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Now Airbase has more cash than it has ever had in its accounts, and has been busy hiring. The company has picked up a CFO, a general counsel and a VP of sales, from Mattermost, Robinhood and Dropbox, respectively.</p>
<p>Which all sounds very much like the long-term prep work for an eventual IPO. Set your timers for 2024.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/airbase-raises-60m-as-the-corporate-spend-market-segments-matures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162215</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fintech all-star Nubank raises a $750M mega round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/fintech-all-star-nubank-raises-a-750m-mega-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/fintech-all-star-nubank-raises-a-750m-mega-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marcella McCarthy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berkshire Hathaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bradesco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colombia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Velez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Itaú Unibanco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nubank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[p2p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santander]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162712</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 2013, Colombian businessman David Velez decided to reinvent the Brazilian banking system. He didn’t speak Portuguese, nor was he an engineer or a banker, but he did have the conviction that the system was broken and that he could fix it. And as a former Sequoia VC, he also had access to capital. His [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2013, Colombian businessman David Velez decided to reinvent the Brazilian banking system. He didn’t speak Portuguese, nor was he an engineer or a banker, but he did have the conviction that the system was broken and that he could fix it. And as a former Sequoia VC, he also had access to capital.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">His gut instinct and market analysis were right. Today, </span><a href="https://nubank.com.br/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nubank</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> announced a $750 million extension to its Series G (which rang in at $400 million this past January), bringing the round to a total of $1.15 billion and their valuation to $30 billion &#8212; $5 billion more than </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/fintech-darling-nubank-raises-blockbuster-400m-series-g-at-25b-valuation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">when we covered them in January.</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The extension funding was led by Berkshire Hathaway, which put in $500 million, and a number of other investors.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Velez and his team decided now was a good time to raise again, because, “We saw a great opportunity in terms of growth rate and we’re very tiny when compared to the incumbents,” he told TechCrunch.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nubank is the biggest digital bank in the world by number of customers: 40 million. The company started as a tech company in Brazil that offered only a fee-free credit card with a line of credit of R$50 (about USD$10). </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lX85R2M1dP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/fintech-darling-nubank-raises-blockbuster-400m-series-g-at-25b-valuation/">Fintech darling Nubank raises blockbuster $400M Series G at $25B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech darling Nubank raises blockbuster $400M Series G at $25B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/fintech-darling-nubank-raises-blockbuster-400m-series-g-at-25b-valuation/embed/#?secret=lX85R2M1dP" data-secret="lX85R2M1dP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It now offers a variety of financial products, including a digital bank account, a debit card, insurance, P2P payment via Pix (the Brazilian equivalent of Zelle), loans, rewards, life insurance and an account and credit card for small business owners. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nubank serves unbanked or underserviced citizens in Brazil &#8212; about 30% of the population &#8212; and this approach can be extremely profitable because there are many more clients available.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The banking system in Brazil is one of the few bureaucracies in the country that is actually quite skillful, but the customer service remains unbearable, and banks charge exorbitant fees for any little transaction. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Traditionally, the banking industry has been dominated by five major traditional banks: Itaú Unibanco, Banco do Brasil, Bradesco, Santander and Caixa Economica Federal. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Brazil remains Nubank’s primary market, the company also offers services in Colombia and Mexico (services launched in Mexico in 2018). The company still only offers the credit card in both countries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The momentum we’re seeing in Mexico is terrific. Our Mexican credit card net promoter score (NPS) is 93, which is the highest we’ve had in Nubank history. In Brazil the highest we’ve had was 88,” Velez said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company has been on a hiring spree in the last few months, and brought on two heavyweight executives. Matt Swann replaced Ed Wible (the original CTO and co-founder). Wible continues to be an important player in the company, but more in a software developer capacity. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Swann previously served as CTO at Bookings.com and StubHub, and as CIO of the Global Consumer Bank at Citi, so he brings years of experience of scaling tech businesses, which is what Nubank is focused on now, though Velez wouldn’t confirm which countries are next.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The other major hire, Arturo Nunez, fills the new role of chief marketing officer. Nunez was head of marketing for Apple Latin America, amongst other roles with Nike and the NBA. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It may sound a little odd for a tech company not to have had a head of marketing, but Nubank takes pride in having a $0 cost of acquisition (CAC). Instead of spending money on marketing, they spend it on customer service and then rely on word of mouth to get the word out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since we last spoke with Velez in January regarding the $400 million Series G, the company went from having 34 million customers to now having 40 million in a span of roughly 6 months. The funds will be used to grow the business, including hiring more people.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’ve seen the entire market go digital, especially people who never thought they would,” Velez said. “There is really now an avalanche of all backgrounds [of people] who are getting into digital banking.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DSxGuAaPaG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/which-neobanks-will-rise-or-fall/">Which neobanks will rise or fall?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Which neobanks will rise or fall?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/which-neobanks-will-rise-or-fall/embed/#?secret=DSxGuAaPaG" data-secret="DSxGuAaPaG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/fintech-all-star-nubank-raises-a-750m-mega-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162712</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitch, Pinterest, Reddit and more go down in Fastly CDN outage (Update: Outage resolved after 1 hour)</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/numerous-popular-websites-are-facing-an-outage/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/numerous-popular-websites-are-facing-an-outage/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 10:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fastly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO Max]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hulu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[StackOverflow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vimeo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Countless popular websites including Reddit, Spotify, Twitch, Stack Overflow, GitHub, gov.uk, Hulu, HBO Max, Quora, PayPal, Vimeo, Shopify, Stripe, and news outlets CNN, The Guardian, The New York Times, BBC and Financial Times are currently facing an outage. A glitch at Fastly, a popular CDN provider, is thought to be the reason, according to a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Countless popular websites including Reddit, Spotify, Twitch, Stack Overflow, GitHub, gov.uk, Hulu, HBO Max, Quora, PayPal, Vimeo, Shopify, Stripe, and news outlets CNN, The Guardian, The New York Times, BBC and Financial Times are currently facing an outage. A glitch at <a href="https://www.fastly.com">Fastly</a>, a popular CDN provider, is thought to be the reason, according to a product manager at Financial Times. Fastly has <a href="https://status.fastly.com">confirmed it&#8217;s facing an outage</a> on its status website.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re currently investigating potential impact to performance with our CDN services,&#8221; the firm said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Fastly, the CDN provider, is having a massive outage, resulting in Twitch, Pinterest, Reddit, The Guardian, and the FT returning 503 errors.<a href="https://t.co/parKGKwrSU">https://t.co/parKGKwrSU</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; Matt &#39;TK&#39; Taylor (@MattieTK) <a href="https://twitter.com/MattieTK/status/1402203886790889473?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><b>Update at 3:50 AM PT:</b> Some websites are slowly coming back up. &#8220;The issue has been identified and a fix is being implemented,&#8221; San Francisco-headquartered Fastly says on its <a href="https://status.fastly.com">status page</a>.</p>
<p><b>Update at 4:02 AM PT:</b> The issue seems to be resolved as affected websites and services now load normally. The company hasn&#8217;t communicated about the source of the outage yet. Overall, it lasted around an hour.</p>
<p>Content delivery networks (CDNs) are a key part of the internet infrastructure. These companies run global networks of servers to improve performance and availability of web services. CDNs act as proxy servers and cache some data as close to the end user as possible. For instance, media content is often cached at a CDN server near you so that it doesn&#8217;t have to be fetched on the original server every time a user loads a web page.</p>
<p>Even though the web is a digital platform, it’s very physical by nature. When you load a page on a server on the other side of the world, it’s going to take hundreds of milliseconds to get the page. Over time, this latency adds up and it feels like a sluggish experience. When a page is already cached, a CDN can usually start sending the content of the page in less than 25 milliseconds.</p>
<p>Over time, CDNs have added more features, such as load balancing, DDoS protection, web application firewalls and other security features. Popular CDNs include Fastly, Cloudflare, CloudFront on Amazon Web Services and Akamai.</p>
<p>Fastly in particular is quite popular with media websites. The company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/17/fastly-pops-in-public-offering-showing-that-theres-still-money-for-tech-ipos/">went public</a> in 2019. Fastly shares (NYSE:FSLY) are currently <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/FSLY/">trading</a> at $48.06, down 5.21% compared to yesterday&#8217;s closing price.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s issue isn&#8217;t limited to a data center in particular. Fastly calls it a &#8220;global CDN disruption&#8221; and it sounds like it is affecting the company&#8217;s network globally.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2162890" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-12.40.27-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="514" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-12.40.27-PM.png 1728w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-12.40.27-PM.png?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-12.40.27-PM.png?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-12.40.27-PM.png?resize=768,386 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-12.40.27-PM.png?resize=680,342 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-12.40.27-PM.png?resize=1536,772 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-08-at-12.40.27-PM.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><i>(This story has been updated to reflect new information.)</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/numerous-popular-websites-are-facing-an-outage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162817</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ford unveils Maverick, a compact hybrid pickup truck for under $20,000</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/ford-unveils-maverick-a-compact-hybrid-pickup-truck-for-under-20000/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/ford-unveils-maverick-a-compact-hybrid-pickup-truck-for-under-20000/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ford unveiled on Tuesday the Maverick, a new compact hybrid pickup truck for people who didn&#8217;t know they needed one. The truck&#8217;s smaller more approachable size and its base price of $19,995 is geared towards entry-level customers who want that SUV or truck lifestyle as well as the ease of navigating and parking in tight [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ford unveiled on Tuesday the Maverick, a new compact hybrid pickup truck for people who didn&#8217;t know they needed one.</p>
<p>The truck&#8217;s smaller more approachable size and its base price of $19,995 is geared towards entry-level customers who want that SUV or truck lifestyle as well as the ease of navigating and parking in tight urban centers. And while its not an all-electric truck like the upcoming Ford F-150 Lightning, the Maverick is part of the company&#8217;s recently expanded plan to invest <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/fords-30b-investment-in-electric-revs-up-in-house-battery-rd/">$30 billion investment in electrification by 2025</a>.</p>
<p>The Maverick also has the distinction of being equipped with the first electric motor designed, developed, tested and manufactured in-house at Ford&#8217;s Van Dyke Transmission Plant.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2162827" style="width: 542px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162827" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2162827" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ford-Maverick_Hybrid_XLT_13.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="532" height="294" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ford-Maverick_Hybrid_XLT_13.jpg 3981w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ford-Maverick_Hybrid_XLT_13.jpg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ford-Maverick_Hybrid_XLT_13.jpg?resize=300,166 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ford-Maverick_Hybrid_XLT_13.jpg?resize=768,425 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ford-Maverick_Hybrid_XLT_13.jpg?resize=680,377 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ford-Maverick_Hybrid_XLT_13.jpg?resize=1536,851 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ford-Maverick_Hybrid_XLT_13.jpg?resize=2048,1134 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ford-Maverick_Hybrid_XLT_13.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 532px) 100vw, 532px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162827" class="wp-caption-text">The compact pickup can more easily maneuver city parking.</p></div></p>
<p>The electric motor and accompanying 2.5 liter engine produces 191 horsepower, 155 pound-feet of torque, and it can tow up to 2,000 pounds. That might not be attractive to those looking to haul one of the larger fifth-wheel campers on the market today. But with a targeted EPA fuel economy of 40 mpg in the city, Ford should find takers. Ford is also offering an option of the EcoBoost engine with an 8-speed automatic, that gives the Maverick 250 horsepower, 277 pound-feet of torque and towing capabilities of up to 4,000 pounds.</p>
<p>The Maverick will come standard as a front-wheel drive and be available in three trims, including the XL, XLT and the Lariat — similar to the F-Series variants. All-wheel drive upgrades are available.</p>
<h2>A bed that&#8217;s also a &#8216;makerspace&#8217;</h2>
<p>[gallery ids="2162823,2162824,2162825"]</p>
<p>The bed of the truck comes in at a polite size of 4.5 feet height by 4 feet wide – as opposed to the F-150&#8217;s 5.5 by 4.3 foot bed — is designed to be flexible. Ford, which wanted to be sure to get that message across, has branded it &#8220;flexbed,&#8221; because it&#8217;s, well, flexible to a range of needs.</p>
<p>Ford&#8217;s most popular pickup trucks, the F-150 series, are geared towards utility by providing plenty of wattage and storage for power tools. The Maverick is made with the DIY driver in mind. Ford has placed 12 available anchor points and slots that lets the owner subdivide as they might want. This so-called flexbed is equipped with two 12-volt 20-amp prewired sources, plus two 110-volt outlets for powering a &#8220;laptop or tailgate party,&#8221; as Ford suggests in a statement announcing the new vehicle.</p>
<p>Speaking of tailgates, the Maverick&#8217;s is multi-positional, so the driver can adjust it to hold open at whatever position best suits whatever they&#8217;re hauling, giving the truck a bed extender functionality.</p>
<p>Another neat feature of the pickup being so small is that the bed is designed to be accessible by reaching over the bedside, and the designers specifically focused on ensuring things were within reach for the fifth percentile of female.</p>
<h2>Let&#8217;s talk about tech</h2>
<p>The Maverick is a fully connected vehicle, as we&#8217;ve come to expect with any new vehicle these days. Ford&#8217;s latest pickup has its own hotpot that can give blessed internet to up to 10 devices and it comes standard with Apple CarPlay and Android Auto. By connecting a smartphone, customers can access the FordPass app, which can be used to remote start the vehicle, lock and unlock doors, locate the truck and check fuel levels.</p>
<p>The compact pickup also has features of the Ford Co-Pilot 360, such as pre-collision assist with auto emergency braking, which alerts the driver through audio and visual signals. There are also high beam headlamps which flip on when no other cars are in front of you, a blindspot information system in case you just drift into another lane without checking over your shoulder, lane keep assist and adaptive cruise control. This tech also allows for five standard drive modes including normal, eco, sport, slippery and tow/haul.</p>
<h2>Inside the Maverick</h2>
<p>The pickup&#8217;s interior a has colorful accents that are used to denote a place that&#8217;s intended for human interface such as the center mat with a charging pad or the vents. Rather than fake leather and fake wood, the Maverick features stone-face textures and speckled plastic.</p>
<p>There are some Ford Integrated Tether Slots which allows for customers to mix and match with different accessories they want to add to the interior, like extra cupholders or an iPad holder to entertain the kiddos in the backseat. Because the fuel tank is located behind the cabin, rather than under the bench, customers have far more under-seat storage space. Apparently that cabin can even hold buckets of ice for that tailgate Ford was talking about earlier.</p>
<p>The Maverick has also done away with the arm rests on the doors and speakers on the back doors, allowing more space for those tall S&#8217;well water bottles everyone loves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/ford-unveils-maverick-a-compact-hybrid-pickup-truck-for-under-20000/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162794</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI pioneer Raquel Urtasun launches self-driving technology startup with backing from Khosla, Uber and Aurora</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/ai-pioneer-raquel-urtasun-launches-self-driving-vehicle-startup-with-backing-from-khosla-uber-and-aurora/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/ai-pioneer-raquel-urtasun-launches-self-driving-vehicle-startup-with-backing-from-khosla-uber-and-aurora/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khosla Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raquel Urtasun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber ATG]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2161906</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the lingering mysteries from Uber&#8217;s sale of its Uber ATG self-driving unit to Aurora has been solved. Raquel Urtasun, the AI pioneer who was the chief scientist at Uber ATG, has launched a new startup called Waabi that is taking what she describes as an &#8220;AI-first approach&#8221; to speed up the commercial deployment [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">One of the lingering mysteries from Uber&#8217;s sale of its Uber ATG self-driving unit to Aurora has been solved.</p>
<p>Raquel Urtasun, the AI pioneer who was the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/08/uber-hires-raquel-urtasun-to-lead-a-new-atg-self-driving-unit-in-toronto/">chief scientist at Uber ATG</a>, has launched a new startup called Waabi that is taking what she describes as an &#8220;AI-first approach&#8221; to speed up the commercial deployment of autonomous vehicles, starting with long-haul trucks. Urtasun, who is the sole founder and CEO, already has a long list of high-profile backers, including separate investments from Uber and Aurora. Waabi has raised $83.5 million in a Series A round led by Khosla Ventures with additional participation from Uber, 8VC, Radical Ventures, OMERS Ventures, BDC, Aurora Innovation as well as leading AI researchers Geoffrey Hinton, Fei-Fei Li, Pieter Abbeel, Sanja Fidler and others.</p>
<p>Urtasun described <a href="https://waabi.ai/">Waabi</a>, which currently employs 40 people and operates in Toronto and California, as the culmination of her life&#8217;s work to bring commercially viable self-driving technology to society. The name of the company —  Waabi means &#8220;she has vision&#8221; in Ojibwe and &#8220;simple&#8221; in Japanese —  hints at her approach and ambitions.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Autonomous vehicle startups that exist today use a combination of artificial intelligence algorithms and sensors to handle the tasks of driving that humans do such as detecting and understanding objects and making decisions based on that information to safely navigate a lonely road or a crowded highway. Beyond those basics are a variety of approaches, including within AI.</p>
<p>Most self-driving vehicle developers use a traditional form of AI. However, the traditional approach limits the power of AI, Urtasun said, adding that d<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">evelopers must manually tune the software stack, a complex and time-consuming task. The upshot, Urtasun says: Autonomous vehicle development has slowed and the limited commercial deployments that do exist operate in small and simple operational domains because scaling is so costly and</span> technically challenging.</p>
<p>&#8220;Working in this field for so many years and, in particular, the industry for the past four years, it became more and more clear along the way that there is a need for a new approach that is different from the traditional approach that most companies are taking today,&#8221; said Urtasun, who is also a professor in the Department of Computer Science at the University of Toronto and a co-founder of the Vector Institute for AI.</p>
<p>Some developers do use deep neural nets, a sophisticated form of artificial intelligence algorithms that allows a computer to learn by using a series of connected networks to identify patterns in data. However, developers typically wall off the deep nets to handle a specific problem and use a machine learning and rules-based algorithms to tie into the broader system.</p>
<p>Deep nets have their own set of problems. A long-standing argument is that they can&#8217;t be used with any reliability in autonomous vehicles in part because of the &#8220;black box&#8221; effect, in which the <em>how</em> and the <em>why</em> the AI solved a particular task is not clear. That is a problem for any self-driving startup that wants to be able verify and validate its system. It is also difficult to incorporate any prior knowledge about the task that the developer is trying to solve, like, oh, driving for instance. Finally, deep nets require an immense amount of data to learn.</p>
<p>Urtasun says she solved these lingering problems around deep nets by combining them with probabilistic inference and complex optimization, which she describes as a family of algorithms. When combined, the developer can trace back the decision process of the AI system and incorporate prior knowledge so they don&#8217;t have to teach the AI system everything from scratch. The final piece is a closed loop simulator that will allow the Waabi team to test at scale common driving scenarios and safety-critical edge cases.</p>
<p>Waabi will still have a physical fleet of vehicles to test on public roads. However, the simulator will allow the company to rely less on this form of testing. &#8220;We can even prepare for new geographies before we drive there,&#8221; Urtasun said. &#8220;That&#8217;s a huge benefit in terms of the scaling curve.&#8221;</p>
<p>Urtasun&#8217;s vision and intent isn&#8217;t to take this approach and disrupt the ecosystem of OEMs, hardware and compute suppliers, but to be a player within it. That might explain the backing of Aurora, a startup that is developing its own self-driving stack that it hopes to first deploy in logistics such as long-haul trucking.</p>
<p>&#8220;This was the moment to really do something different,&#8221; Urtasun said. &#8220;The field is in need of a diverse set of approaches to solve this and it became very clear that this was the way to go.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yYFgbZ9O32"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/uber-sells-self-driving-unit-uber-atg-in-deal-that-will-push-auroras-valuation-to-10b/">Uber sells self-driving unit Uber ATG in deal that will push Aurora&#8217;s valuation to $10B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uber sells self-driving unit Uber ATG in deal that will push Aurora&#8217;s valuation to $10B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/uber-sells-self-driving-unit-uber-atg-in-deal-that-will-push-auroras-valuation-to-10b/embed/#?secret=yYFgbZ9O32" data-secret="yYFgbZ9O32" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/ai-pioneer-raquel-urtasun-launches-self-driving-vehicle-startup-with-backing-from-khosla-uber-and-aurora/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2161906</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are we overestimating the ransomware threat?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/are-we-overestimating-the-ransomware-threat/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/are-we-overestimating-the-ransomware-threat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 08:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colonial pipeline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FBI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recorded future]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday afternoon, the U.S. Justice Department said it has seized much of the cryptocurrency ransom that  U.S. pipeline operator Colonial Pipeline paid last month to a Russian hacking collective called DarkSide by tracking the payment as it moved through different accounts belonging to the hacking group and finally breaking into one of those accounts [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On Monday afternoon, the U.S. Justice Department said it has seized much of the cryptocurrency ransom that  U.S. pipeline operator Colonial Pipeline paid last month to a Russian hacking collective called DarkSide by tracking the payment as it moved through different accounts belonging to the hacking group and finally <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/06/07/us/biden-news-today#colonial-pipeline-ransom-justice-department">breaking into one of those accounts</a> with the blessing of a federal judge.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a feel-good twist to a saga that began with a cyberattack on Colonial and resulted in a fuel shortage made worse by the panic-purchasing of gasoline last month after the company shut down one of its major pipelines (and later suffered a second pipeline shutdown owing to what it described as an overworked internal server). But Christopher Alhberg, a <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/06/02/recorded-future-ceo-richard-ahlberg-interview-after-780-million-sale.html">successful</a> serial entrepreneur and the founder of <a href="https://www.recordedfuture.com/">Recorded Future</a>, a security intelligence company that tracks threats to the government and corporations and runs its own <a href="https://therecord.media/">media arm</a>, suggests that Americans have overestimated DarkSide all along. He explained a lot about the way its operations work last week in an interview that you can <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/intelligence-expert-serial-entrepreneur-christopher/id1498270180?i=1000524313050">hear here</a>. Shorter excerpts from that conversation follow, edited lightly for length.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Broadly, how does your tech work?</strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>CA: What we do is try to index the internet. We try to get in the way of data from everything that&#8217;s written on the internet, down to the electrons moving, and we try and index that in a way that it can be used for for people who are defending companies and defending organizations. . .  We try to get into the heads of the bad guys, get to the where the bad guys hang out, and understand that side of the equation. We try to understand what happens on the networks where the bad guys operate, where they execute their stuff, where they basically transmit data, where they run the illicit infrastructure &#8212; all of those things. And we also try to get in the way of the traces that the bad guys leave behind, which could be in all kinds of different interesting places.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Who are your customers?</strong></p>
<p>CA: We have about 1,000 of them in total, and they range from the Department of Defense to some of the largest companies in the world. Probably a third of our business is [with the] government, one third of our businesses are in the financial sector, then the rest [comprise] a whole set of verticals, including transportation, which has been big.</p>
<p><strong>TC: You&#8217;re helping them predict attacks or understand what happened in cases where it&#8217;s too late?</strong></p>
<p>CA: It can go both ways.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What are some of the clues that inform your work?</strong></p>
<p>CA: One is understanding the adversary, the bad guys, and they largely fall in two buckets: You&#8217;ve got cyber criminals, and you&#8217;ve got adversary intelligence agencies.</p>
<p>The criminals over the last month or two here that the world and us, too, have been focused on are these ransomware gangs. So these are Russian gangs, and when you hear &#8216;gang,&#8217; people tend to think about large groups of people [but] it&#8217;s typically a guy or two or three. So I wouldn&#8217;t over estimate the size of these gangs.</p>
<p>[On the other hand] intelligence agencies can be very both well-equipped and [involve] large sets of people. So one piece is about tracking them. Another piece is about tracking the networks that they operate on . . Finally, [our work involves] understanding the targets, where we get data on the potential targets of a cyber attack without having access to the actual systems on premises, then tying the three buckets together in an automated fashion.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Do you see a lot of cross pollination between intelligence agencies and some of these Russian cutouts?</strong></p>
<p>CA: The short answer is these groups are not, in our view, being tasked on a daily or monthly or maybe even yearly basis by Russian intelligence. But in a series of countries around the world &#8212; Russia, Iran, North Korea is a little bit different, to some degree in China &#8212; what we&#8217;ve seen is that government has encouraged a growing hacker population that&#8217;s been able, in an unchecked way, to be able to pursue their interest &#8212; in Russia, largely &#8212; in cyber crime. Then over time, you see intelligence agencies in Russia &#8212; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foreign_Intelligence_Service_(Russia)">FSB</a>, <a href="https://www.rferl.org/a/russia-svr-denies-solarwinds/31260606.html">SVR</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GRU">GRU</a> &#8212;  being able to poach people out of these groups or actually task them. You can find in official documents how these guys have mixed and matched over a long period of time.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What did you think when DarkSide came out soon after the cyberattack and said it could no longer access its Bitcoin or payment server and that it was <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/14/business/darkside-pipeline-hack.html">shutting down</a>?</strong></p>
<p>CA: If you did this hack, you probably had zero idea what Colonial Pipeline actually was when you did it. You&#8217;re like, &#8216;Oh, shit, I&#8217;m all over the American newspapers.&#8217; And there are probably a couple of phone calls starting to happen in Russia, where basically, again, &#8216;What the hell did you just do? How are you going to try to cover that up?&#8217;</p>
<p>One of the simplest first things you&#8217;re going to do is to basically say either, &#8216;It wasn&#8217;t me&#8217; or you&#8217;re going to try to say, &#8216;We lost the money; we lost access to our servers.&#8217; So I think that was probably fake that whole thing [and that] what they were doing was just to try to cover their tracks, [given that] we found them later come back and try to do other things. I think we overestimated the ability of the U.S. government to come rapidly right back at these guys. That will just not happen <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/14/business/darkside-pipeline-hack.html">that fast</a>, though this is pure conjuring. I&#8217;m not saying that with access to any inside government information or anything of the sort.</p>
<p><strong>TC: I was just reading that DarkSide <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/02/hacker-group-darksides-operates-in-a-similar-way-to-a-franchise-new-york-times-reporter-says.html">operates like a franchise</a> where individual hackers can come and receive software and use it like a turnkey process. Is that new and does that mean that it opens up hacking to a much broader pool of people?</strong></p>
<p>CA:  That&#8217;s right. One of the beauties of the Russian hacker underground is in its distributed nature. I&#8217;m saying &#8216;beauty&#8217; with a little bit of sarcasm, but some people will write the actual ransomware. Some will use the services that these guys provide and then be the guys who might do the hacking to get into the systems. Some other guys might be the ones who operate the Bitcoin transactions through the Bitcoin tumbling that gets needed . . . One of the interesting points is that to get the cash out in the end game, these guys need to go through one of these exchanges that ended up being more civilized businesses, and there might be money mules involved, and there are people who run the money mules. A lot of these guys do credit card fraud; there&#8217;s a whole set of services there, too, including testing if a card is alive and being able to figure out how you get money out of it. There are probably 10, 15, maybe  20 different types of services involved in this. And they&#8217;re all very highly specialized, which is very much why these guys have been able to be so successful and also why it&#8217;s hard to go at it.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Do they share the spoils and if so, how?</strong></p>
<p>CA: They do. These guys run pretty effective systems here. Obviously, Bitcoin has been an incredible enabler in this because there is a way to do payments [but] these guys have whole systems for ranking and rating of themselves much like an eBay seller. There&#8217;s a whole set of these underground forums that have historically has been the places that these guys have been operating and they&#8217;ll including include services there for being able to say that somebody is a scammer [meaning in relation to the] thieves who are among the cyber criminals. It&#8217;s much like the internet. Why does the internet work so well? Because it&#8217;s super distributed.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What&#8217;s your advice to those who aren&#8217;t your customers but want to defend themselves?</strong></p>
<p>CA: A colleague produced a pie chart to show what industries are being hit by ransomware and what&#8217;s amazing is that it was just super distributed across 20 different industries. With Colonial Pipeline, a lot of people were like, &#8216;Oh, they&#8217;re coming from the oil.&#8217; But these guys could care less. They just want to find the slowest moving target. So make sure you&#8217;re not the easiest target.</p>
<p>The good news is that there are plenty of companies out there doing the basics and making sure that your systems are patched [but also] hit that damn update button. Get as much of your stuff off the internet so that it&#8217;s not facing out. Keep as little surface area as you can to the outside world. Use good passwords, use multiple two-factor authentication on everything and anything that you can get your hands on.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a checklist of 10 things that you&#8217;ve got to do in order to not be that easy target. Now, for some of these guys &#8212; the really sophisticated gangs &#8212; that&#8217;s not enough. You&#8217;ve got to do more work, but the basics will make a big difference here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/are-we-overestimating-the-ransomware-threat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162847</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cabify launches &#8216;Cabify Go!&#8217;, a multi-modal subscription service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/cabify-launches-cabify-go-a-multi-modal-subscription-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/cabify-launches-cabify-go-a-multi-modal-subscription-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 08:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscription services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2161921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cabify wants to own the way people in cities move. The Spanish-born ride-hailing company is rolling out a pilot multi-modal subscription model to 40,000 users in Madrid this week, with plans to expand to its other markets throughout Spain and Latin America. The &#8220;Cabify Go!&#8221; subscription service appears to have something for everyone. All of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cabify wants to own the way people in cities move. The Spanish-born ride-hailing company is rolling out a pilot multi-modal subscription model to 40,000 users in Madrid this week, with plans to expand to its other markets throughout Spain and Latin America.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The &#8220;Cabify Go!&#8221; subscription service appears to have something for everyone. All of Cabify’s different mobility offerings &#8212; ride-hailing service, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/10/movo-grabs-22-5m-to-get-more-cities-in-latam-scooting/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">electric micromobility subsidiary MOVO</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, bike subscription service Bive and courier service &#8212; are already available under one app, but now customers will also be able to select one of three plans that reflect the mobility needs of different users. Select users will now see a &#8220;Go!&#8221; button on the top-right corner of the screen. This is a step toward making the Cabify name ubiquitous among city dwellers planning a trip, whether they’re taking an old-fashioned taxi ride to the airport or are riding a scooter to work. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The subscription scheme ‘Cabify Go!’ is born to make our app their recurring platform, with diverse available services,” </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leonor Barrueco, Cabify&#8217;s VP of growth,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> told TechCrunch. “This approach is strongly aligned with our goal of becoming the leading multi-mobility platform. At this stage there&#8217;s an opportunity to get closer to our users&#8217; multiple and varying needs. We want to offer our users convenient, diverse and sustainable ways to move around the city at an affordable monthly fee.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main subscription offering, &#8220;Cabify Go! Todo en uno&#8221; or &#8220;Everything in one&#8221; plan, costs €6.95 per month and gives users a blanket 10% discount on all their Cabify trips, as well as 30% off Cabify Envíos, its courier service. Subscribers also get two free cancellations each month and are exempt from the additional fee incurred from high demand. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cabify is also offering the &#8220;A dos ruedas&#8221; or &#8220;On two wheels&#8221; plan, which costs €19.95 per month and includes 10 free MOVO rides of up to €6 without any additional cost. The mobility company expects subscriptions to help bring on new users. Currently, the rate of new users in Cabify&#8217;s moped segment is nearly 1.5 times higher than the ride-hailing services&#8217; rate, according to Barrueco. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Given the convergence of the platform space where customers can demand a variety of booming multi-mobility services, some users might be new to alternative options whilst some are new to the whole multi-mobility ecosystem,&#8221; said Barrueco.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jS9MbrsarT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/unagi-expands-e-scooter-subscriptions-with-10-5m-in-new-funding/">Unagi expands e-scooter subscriptions with $10.5M in new funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Unagi expands e-scooter subscriptions with $10.5M in new funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/unagi-expands-e-scooter-subscriptions-with-10-5m-in-new-funding/embed/#?secret=jS9MbrsarT" data-secret="jS9MbrsarT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, its &#8220;Pedelea&#8221; or &#8220;Pedal&#8221; plan includes the Bive long-term rental service for electric or mechanical bikes, with a competitive monthly price of €49.95 and €28.95, respectively. Servicing and maintenance is included, as well as a 10% discount on ride-hailing trips. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bive, which Cabify introduced about a year ago, has already spread from Madrid to Valencia, Sevilla and Barcelona. By integrating the service into Cabify’s subscription offerings, the company hopes to promote the Bive service through another outlet, an idea borne out by internal insights. Barrueca says that 50% of Bive’s user base are new users to the Cabify platform. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are no sign-up or cancellation fees for any of the services, and users can cancel at any time, according to Barrueco. But that&#8217;s par for the course when it comes to mobility subscriptions, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">which seem to be on the rise as the subscription business model grows to answer shifting consumption habits. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to monetization tech developer <a href="https://www.telecoming.com/blog/subscronomics-the-subscription-economy-will-surpass-228-billion-during-2021/">Telecoming&#8217;s 2021 Subscronomics Report</a>, in the European market, &#8220;with a base of 353 million households and more than 2,100 connected devices (22% of the total worldwide), 560 million subscriptions will be purchased this year (25% of the worldwide total).&#8221; This is expected to contribute to a global subscriptions industry of almost $228 billion, which is 31% higher than in 2020, with an average YOY growth of 23% from now until 2025. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other companies that have jumped on the monthly rental train early include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/unagi-expands-e-scooter-subscriptions-with-10-5m-in-new-funding/">Unagi</a> with its e-scooters, Swapfiets with bikes and e-bikes and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/ev-subscription-service-onto-partners-with-shell-to-expand-access-to-charging/">Onto with electric vehicles</a>.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="S7CaWds4Tt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/ev-subscription-service-onto-partners-with-shell-to-expand-access-to-charging/">EV subscription service Onto partners with Shell to expand access to charging</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;EV subscription service Onto partners with Shell to expand access to charging&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/ev-subscription-service-onto-partners-with-shell-to-expand-access-to-charging/embed/#?secret=S7CaWds4Tt" data-secret="S7CaWds4Tt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Barrueco says one of Cabify&#8217;s goals in increasing its own business is to contribute to the transformation of cities to be more people-centric and environmentally friendly by making shared modes of transport more accessible.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;One of the company’s top priorities is to ramp up and consolidate our multimobility service proposition which provides our users with diverse sustainable alternatives and aims to replace the dominance of the private car,&#8221; said Barrueco.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the global share of EVs over Cabify&#8217;s entire fleet is only about 1%, with hybrid vehicles accounting for 3%, Cabify is targeting 2025 for full electrification for collaborating fleets in Spain, and 2030 in Latin America. The company is collaborating with a number of stakeholders, including IDB Invest, the Ministry of Energy in Chile and car brands to test suitable EV models.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;This common journey to the general adoption of EVs entails tackling a number of urban and sector-wide challenges such as the scarcity of EV models that are autonomy-wise compatible with ride-hailing services, battery life spans, legal certainty in access to credit or the characteristics and availability of charging points,&#8221; said Barrueco.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uMSWzwEuX9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/will-ride-hailing-profits-ever-come/">Will ride-hailing profits ever come?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will ride-hailing profits ever come?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/will-ride-hailing-profits-ever-come/embed/#?secret=uMSWzwEuX9" data-secret="uMSWzwEuX9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/cabify-launches-cabify-go-a-multi-modal-subscription-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2161921</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese lidar maker Hesai lands $300M led by Hillhouse, Xiaomi, Meituan</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/china-lidar-hesai-300-million-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/china-lidar-hesai-300-million-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 04:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baidu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bosch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hillhouse Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lidar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lightspeed Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meituan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qiming Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shanghai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temasek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xiaomi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The rush to back lidar companies continues as more automakers and robotaxi startups include the remote sensing method in their vehicles. Latest to the investment boom is Hesai, a Shanghai-based lidar maker founded in 2014 with an office in Palo Alto. The company just raised over $300 million in a Series D funding round led [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The rush to back lidar companies continues as more automakers and robotaxi startups include the remote sensing method in their vehicles.</p>
<p>Latest to the investment boom is Hesai, a Shanghai-based lidar maker founded in 2014 with an office in Palo Alto. The company just raised over $300 million in a Series D funding round led by GL Ventures, the venture capital arm of storied private equity firm Hillhouse Capital, smartphone maker Xiaomi, on-demand services giant Meituan and CPE, the private equity platform of Citic.</p>
<p>Hesai <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/SIj9Hh7X2qzFauVX9mnFEA">said</a> the new proceeds will be spent on mass-producing its hybrid solid-state lidar for its OEM customers, the construction of its smart manufacturing center, and research and development on automotive-grade lidar chips. The company said it has accumulated &#8220;several hundred million dollars&#8221; in funding to date.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Other participants in the round included Huatai Securities, Lightspeed China Partners and Lightspeed Venture Capital, as well as Qiming Venture Partners. Bosch, Baidu, and ON Semiconductor are also among its shareholders.</p>
<p>Another Chinese lidar startup Innovusion, a major supplier to electric vehicle startup Nio, raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/innovusion-64-millions-series-b/">$64 million round led by Temasek</a> in May. Livox is another emerging lidar maker that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/innovusion-64-millions-series-b/">was an offshoot of DJI</a>.</p>
<p>Lidar isn&#8217;t limited to powering robotaxis and passenger EVs, and that&#8217;s why Hesai got Xiaomi and Meituan onboard. Xiaomi makes hundreds of different connected devices through its manufacturing suppliers that could easily benefit from industrial automation, to which sensing technology is critical. But the phone maker also unveiled plans this year to<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/xiaomi-ev-subsidiary/"> make electric cars</a>.</p>
<p>Meituan, delivering food to hundreds of millions of consumers in China, could similarly benefit from replacing human riders with<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/meituan-jd-com-and-neolix-begin-autonomous-deliveries-in-beijing/"> lidar-enabled unmanned vans and drones</a>.</p>
<p>Hesai, with a staff of over 500 employees, says its clients span 70 cities across 23 countries. The company touts Nuro, Bosch, Lyft, Navya, and Chinese robotaxi operators Baidu, WeRide and AutoX among its customers. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Last year, it kickstarted a </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/22/scale-ai-releases-free-lidar-dataset-to-power-self-driving-car-development/">partnership with Scale AI</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, a data labeling company, to launch an open-source data set for training autonomous driving algorithms, with data collected using Hesai&#8217;s lidar in California. </span></p>
<p>Last July, Hesai and lidar technology pioneer Velodyne <a href="https://www.hesaitech.com/en/media/46">entered a long-term licensing agreement</a> as the two dismissed legal proceedings in the U.S., Germany and China.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N16XuxZR75"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/innovusion-64-millions-series-b/">Lidar startup Innovusion closes $64M round led by Temasek</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lidar startup Innovusion closes $64M round led by Temasek&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/innovusion-64-millions-series-b/embed/#?secret=N16XuxZR75" data-secret="N16XuxZR75" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/china-lidar-hesai-300-million-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162808</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple&#8217;s new encrypted browsing feature won&#8217;t be available in China, Saudi Arabia and more: report</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-private-relay-unavailable-in-china/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-private-relay-unavailable-in-china/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 02:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belarus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colombia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craig Federighi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firewall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[great firewall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kazakhstan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vpn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple announced a handful of privacy-focused updates at its annual software developer conference on Monday. One called Private Relay particularly piques the interest of Chinese users living under the country&#8217;s censorship system, for it encrypts all browsing history so nobody can track or intercept the data. As my colleague Roman Dillet explains: When Private Relay [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple announced a handful of privacy-focused updates at its annual software developer conference on Monday. One called Private Relay particularly piques the interest of Chinese users living under the country&#8217;s censorship system, for it encrypts all browsing history so nobody can track or intercept the data.</p>
<p>As my colleague Roman Dillet <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">explains</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>When Private Relay is turned on, nobody can track your browsing history — not your internet service provider, anyone standing in the middle of your request between your device and the server you’re requesting information from. We’ll have to wait a bit to learn more about how it works exactly.</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The excitement didn&#8217;t last long. Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/apple-privacy/apples-new-private-relay-feature-will-not-be-available-in-china-idUSL2N2NP2UK">told Reuters</a> that Private Relay won&#8217;t be available in China alongside Belarus, Colombia, Egypt, Kazakhstan, Saudi Arabia, South Africa, Turkmenistan, Uganda and the Philippines.</p>
<p>Apple couldn&#8217;t be immediately reached by TechCrunch for comment.</p>
<p>Virtual private networks or VPNs are popular tools for users in China to bypass the &#8220;great firewall&#8221; censorship apparatus, accessing web services that are otherwise blocked or slowed down. But VPNs <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/free-vpn-bad-for-privacy/">don&#8217;t necessarily protect users&#8217; privacy</a> because they simply funnel all the traffic through VPN providers&#8217; servers instead of users&#8217; internet providers, so users are essentially entrusting VPN firms with protecting their identities. Private Relay, on the other hand, doesn&#8217;t even allow Apple to see one&#8217;s browsing activity.</p>
<p>In an <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90643627/apple-privacy-wwdc-private-relay-vpn-icloud-plus-macos-monterey">interview</a> with Fast Company, Craig Federighi, Apple&#8217;s senior vice president of software engineering, explained why the new feature may be superior to VPNs:</p>
<p>&#8220;We hope users believe in Apple as a trustworthy intermediary, but we didn’t even want you to have to trust us [because] we don’t have this ability to simultaneously source your IP and the destination where you’re going to–and that’s unlike VPNs. And so we wanted to provide many of the benefits that people are seeking when in the past they’ve decided to use a VPN, but not force that difficult and conceivably perilous privacy trade-off in terms of trusting it a single intermediary.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear whether Private Relay will simply be excluded from system upgrades for users in China and the other countries where it&#8217;s restricted, or it will be blocked by internet providers in those regions. It also remains to be seen whether the feature will be available to Apple users in Hong Kong, which has seen an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hong-kong-security-censorship-idUSKBN29K0ZM">increase in online censorship</a> in the past year.</p>
<p>Like all Western tech firms operating in China, Apple is trapped between antagonizing Beijing and flouting the values it espouses at home. Apple has a history of caving in to Beijing&#8217;s censorship pressure, from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/tesla-china-user-data-storage/">migrating all user data in China </a>to a state-run cloud center, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/29/apple-removes-vpn-apps-from-the-app-store-in-china/">cracking down on independent VPN apps</a> in China, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/04/apple-restricts-chinese-podcasts/">limiting free speech in Chinese podcasts</a>, to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/apple-removes-two-rss-feed-readers-from-china-app-store/">removing RSS feed readers from the China App Store</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="J5xCN4EYrU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/free-vpn-bad-for-privacy/">Free VPNs are bad for your privacy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Free VPNs are bad for your privacy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/free-vpn-bad-for-privacy/embed/#?secret=J5xCN4EYrU" data-secret="J5xCN4EYrU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-private-relay-unavailable-in-china/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162797</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
