<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 14:21:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Tumblr&#8217;s subscription product Post+ enters open beta after much scrutiny from users</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/tumblrs-subscription-product-post-enters-open-beta-after-much-scrutiny-from-users/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/tumblrs-subscription-product-post-enters-open-beta-after-much-scrutiny-from-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 14:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automattic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patreon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paywall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tumblr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Website]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205722</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tumblr is entering open beta for its subscription product Post+, meaning that all U.S. users can now try out the monetization feature. The product launched in closed beta in July, allowing users hand-picked by Tumblr to place some of their content behind a monthly paywall. This marked the first time that Tumblr allowed bloggers to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tumblr is entering <a href="https://postplus.tumblr.com/post/662944143853715456/its-for-tumblr-you-its-from-tumblr-us-its">open beta</a> for its subscription product Post+, meaning that all U.S. users can now try out the monetization feature. The product <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/tumblr-debuts-post-a-subscription-service-for-gen-z-creators/">launched in closed beta</a> in July, allowing users hand-picked by Tumblr to place some of their content behind a monthly paywall. This marked the first time that Tumblr allowed bloggers to monetize their content directly on the platform, but the feature was met with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/tumblr-community-lash-out-post-plus-subscription/">backlash from users</a> who worried about how the feature would change the site&#8217;s culture.</p>
<p>Now, Tumblr has responded to user feedback by removing the blue Post+ badge that appeared next to the names of users who enabled the feature. Tumblr differentiates itself from other sites by not revealing users&#8217; follower and following counts, so users were concerned that this distinction, which looked like a Twitter verification badge, contradicted that key aspect of Tumblr culture. Tumblr is also adding a $1.99/month price point in open beta &#8212; before, subscriber-only content could be priced at $3.99, $5.99, and $9.99. Tumblr will only take 5% of creator profits &#8212; comparatively, Patreon takes <a href="https://www.patreon.com/pricing">between 5% and 12%</a> depending on the tier. Payments will be processed through Stripe.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Wbg5LHr1xy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/tumblr-community-lash-out-post-plus-subscription/">Trouble in fandom paradise: Tumblr users lash out against its beta subscription feature</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Trouble in fandom paradise: Tumblr users lash out against its beta subscription feature&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/tumblr-community-lash-out-post-plus-subscription/embed/#?secret=Wbg5LHr1xy" data-secret="Wbg5LHr1xy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Still, Tumblr users were dismayed by the way Post+ was rolled out. Many bloggers were concerned that in the closed beta, Post+ users didn&#8217;t have the ability to block paying subscribers without first contacting support &#8212; this could potentially expose users to harassment without the tools to manage it. Tumblr corrected that mistake in the open beta, so now, users can block subscribers themselves. Creators can also put existing content behind the Post+ paywall.</p>
<p>Some users upset with the Post+ rollout <a href="https://postplus-protest.tumblr.com/post/657433316725833728/post-plus-is-coming-whether-you-want-it-or-not">staged a protest</a>, which &#8212; with over 98,000 notes &#8212; is the first thing that shows up when you <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/tagged/post+plus?sort=top">search</a> &#8220;post plus&#8221; on Tumblr. Many people on Tumblr have amassed followings by posting iterative fan content, like fanfiction. Tumblr cited fanfiction as an example of the kind of content that creators can put behind a paywall, but users remain concerned that they will be subject to legal action if they were to do so. Archive of Our Own, a major fanfiction site, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/8/18072622/fanfic-ao3-free-speech-censorship-fandom">prohibits its users</a> from linking to sites like Patreon or Ko-Fi, since some intellectual property rights holders can be litigious about the monetization of fanfiction. While it&#8217;s considered fair use to make fan content, profiting from it can be considered a violation of copyright.</p>
<p>When Tumblr<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/13/tumblrs-back-in-the-app-store-following-porn-ban-announcement/"> banned pornographic content</a> in 2018, monthly page views <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/tumblr-debuts-post-a-subscription-service-for-gen-z-creators/">decreased by 29%</a> &#8212; to date, the blogging platform hasn&#8217;t regained that traffic. After being <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/12/verizon-is-selling-tumblr-to-wordpress-parent-automattic/">sold to Automattic</a> in 2019, Tumblr has committed to capturing the attention of Gen Z audiences, who the platform says make up about 48% of its users. Tumblr says it&#8217;s catering Post+ to serve Gen Z audiences, but the results of the open beta will begin to reveal whether or not this is what users on the platform want.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/tumblrs-subscription-product-post-enters-open-beta-after-much-scrutiny-from-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205722</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Niio announces $15M Series A following strategic partnership with Samsung Displays</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/niio-announces-15m-series-a-funding-following-strategic-partnership-with-samsung-displays/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/niio-announces-15m-series-a-funding-following-strategic-partnership-with-samsung-displays/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L Catterton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Niio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Niio, a Tel Aviv-based digital art platform featuring work ranging from contemporary artists and galleries through to NFTs, announced today it has closed $15 million Series A funding in the wake of a strategic partnership with Samsung Displays, announced last week. The round was co-led by L Catterton, a joint venture between LVMH and Catterton, Entrée Capital [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.niio.com/site/">Niio</a>, a <span lang="EN-US">Tel Aviv-based </span>digital art platform featuring work ranging from contemporary artists and galleries through to NFTs, announced today it has closed $15 million Series A funding in the wake of a <a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/how-samsung-displays-realize-best-in-class-presentation-of-digital-artworks-with-global-niio-art-partnership">strategic partnership with Samsung Displays, announced last week.</a></p>
<p>The round was co-led by L Catterton, a joint venture between LVMH and Catterton, Entrée Capital and Pico Venture Partners. Additional investors also joined, including Saga VC, as well as leading artists, art collectors, museums, gallerists and trustees at institutions such as MOMA and Guggenheim as well as Shalom McKenzie, an online gambling entrepreneur and investor who also invests in NFTs. Prior to the Series A round, Niio had raised $8 million, initially from strategic angels, followed by a seed round from institutions in 2017.</p>
<p>Niio will use its capital to grow its artist community and scale its app-enabled subscription and purchase platform, which is blockchain<span lang="EN-US">&#8211;</span>based and will include a trading-enabled marketplace for NFTs and other digital art assets.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sZIYy3hTN9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/the-nft-market-is-just-getting-started-but-where-is-it-headed/">The NFT market is just getting started, but where is it headed?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The NFT market is just getting started, but where is it headed?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/the-nft-market-is-just-getting-started-but-where-is-it-headed/embed/#?secret=sZIYy3hTN9" data-secret="sZIYy3hTN9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Digital art has become an accepted, mainstream medium with the market accelerating largely due to the explosive growth of NFTs,&#8221; <span lang="EN-US">said </span>Niio CEO and co-founder Rob Anders. &#8220;The transformation <span lang="EN-US">people</span> are experiencing is the most significant and consequential moment for culture in decades, making new kinds of art accessible and experienced on screens in ways like never before.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Niio</span><span lang="EN-US" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">’s technology enables users to stream digital artwork on any digital screen, </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">bridging the gap between art and creating a platform similar to what music and entertainment streaming services have done for albums and movies.</span></p>
<p>Niio<span lang="EN-US">,</span> founded by Rob Anders and Oren Moshe in 2014<span lang="EN-US">,</span> combines an accessible streaming subscription service alongside the ability for people to purchase editioned NFT artwork directly from artists, galleries and content owners, through its public marketplace or via private transactions, Anders <span lang="EN-US">told TechCrunch.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Niio is launching its subscription service at the end of 2021 followed by its NFT marketplace &#8212; which makes Niio, backed by a global community of art professionals, the most comprehensive end-to-end solution for the digital art medium and ensuring that premium digital art is easily accessible by anyone on any screen, Anders continued.</p>
<p>By providing Niio’s tools to a global community of 6,000 galleries, institutions and artists, Niio’s platform and blockchain enables artists to distribute, manage, monetize and preserve their work.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-bcf51165adb1224460558483f2f879a3"
			width="560"
			height="315"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/bcf51165adb1224460558483f2f879a3"
			scrolling=""
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-bcf51165adb1224460558483f2f879a3')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-bcf51165adb1224460558483f2f879a3'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
<p>Niio claims it will be free for all artists, forever, to respect and support the creative community and artists’ ability for publishing, managing and protecting their life’s work.</p>
<p>“We have realized our vision for a platform that first and foremost empowers artists and enables their work to be experienced digitally and available globally. We are gratified by the trust that more than 6,000 artists have placed in us &#8212; as we enable them to publish, manage protect and monetize their life’s work,” Niio<span lang="EN-US"> co-founder</span> Oren Moshe said.</p>
<p>Approximately 10,000 global business customers have been using the Niio platform for the past two to three years<span lang="EN-US">, Anders said</span>. Clients range from art professionals, including galleries, museums, studios and art schools, to luxury brands, hotel chains and real estate developers, who subscribe and display curated art streams from the 15,000 premium works available on the platform, to millions of people across public spaces and places in over 30 countries, Anders<span lang="EN-US"> said</span>.</p>
<p>“There are over 1 billion smart TVs in the market and our partner Samsung has 30-40% of the market contributing to our ability to offer a ‘last mile’ proposition,” Anders said.</p>
<p>The digital art market <span lang="EN-US">is projected to be approximately</span> $50 – $100 billion by 2025, according to Anders.</p>
<p>“Digital art has long been on our radar at L Catterton. We are very bullish on its future, and our ongoing evaluation of the sector brought us to Niio,” said Michael Farello, managing partner at L Catterton’s Growth Fund. “We are convinced that their platform approach including both subscription and an NFT offering combined with the reputation they have built in the critical artist community and the validation from their partnership with Samsung – will make them a market leader.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/niio-announces-15m-series-a-funding-following-strategic-partnership-with-samsung-displays/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205434</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEX raises $25M, launches Active Arcade to get people moving</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/nex-a-motion-based-entertainment-company-announces-25b-series-b-round-and-its-motion-game-app-active-arcade-launch/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/nex-a-motion-based-entertainment-company-announces-25b-series-b-round-and-its-motion-game-app-active-arcade-launch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 14:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david lee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nex]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is a physical activity deficit in our world. Three fourths of adults say staying in shape is very important for health benefits. Yet, one in four adults and 81% of adolescents are insufficiently physically active, according to the World Health Organization. Even before COVID-19, less than 24% of children 6 to 17 years of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There is a physical activity deficit in our world. Three fourths of adults say staying in shape is very important for health benefits. Yet, one in four adults and 81% of adolescents are insufficiently physically active, <a href="https://www.who.int/health-topics/physical-activity#tab=tab_1">according to the World Health Organization.</a> Even before COVID-19, less than 24% of children 6 to 17 years of age did 60 minutes of physical activity daily, as per <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/healthyschools/physicalactivity/facts.htm">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)</a>.</p>
<p>Working from home and staying at home during the pandemic exacerbated being physical inactivity. Most people opt for sedentary entertainment that involves minimal movement like watching movies or streaming live concerts, playing video games and throwing virtual parties.</p>
<p>To solve the global problem of inactivity by creating new ways to encourage active play for everyone, <a href="https://www.nex.inc/">NEX</a>, a San Jose and Hong Kong-based motion entertainment startup, is building motion entertainment &#8211; content that encourages physical movement. It is now announcing a $25 million Series B round to coincide with launch of <a href="https://www.nex.inc/products/active-arcade">Active Arcade</a>, its new mobile AI interactive motion-tracking game.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The new funding was led by Blue Pool Capital, with participation from Samsung Ventures, SparkLabs and Susquehanna. This round also attracted influencers in sports, entertainment industries and business executives including Simu Liu (Shang-Chi), Albert Pujols (LA Dodgers), Thierry Henry (Arsenal Legend), Sabrina Ionescu (WNBA), tech CEOs and founders from YouTube, Dapper Labs, Alchemy, OpenDoor, WordPress and executives from Zendesk, Uber, MasterClass and Facebook.</span></p>
<p>This latest round comes after NEX raised an $8.5 million Series A in 2019 from the NBA, Will Smith&#8217;s Dreamers Fund, and the Alibaba Entrepreneurship Fund. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/17/an-app-that-uses-ai-to-help-you-improve-your-basketball-shot-just-raised-4-million/">It also previously raised a $4 million seed round</a> from Charmides Capital, Harris <span class="il">Blitzer</span> <span class="il">Sports</span> &amp; <span class="il">Entertainment</span> <span class="il">Ventures</span> and Mandra Capital, Steve Nash, Jeremy Lin and Mark Cuban in 2018. Many other leaders in sports, media and technology have also baked NEX.</p>
<p>The Series B round brings NEX’s total raised so far to $40 million.</p>
<p>NEX was founded in 2018 by David Lee, Philip Lam and Reggie Chan, with a mission to transform passive activity into active play through apps like Active Arcade. Its first app, HomeCourt, has been played in more than 200 countries.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“A pandemic drew even more attention to the already huge and growing problem of more sedentary lifestyles across the world,” said Dave Lee, CEO and co-founder of NEX. “Having fun while moving is one of the purest definitions of play. But unlike the old days, the standard of engagement for active play must be on par with the best video games. It was apparent to us that accessible motion-based entertainment was the answer to a global need for more physical activity.”</p>
<p>Some people say that they don’t have enough time for physical activity, but the real problem is the idea that leisure time is supposed to be spent doing things that are fun and easy while getting active is perceived as expensive, time consuming and hard.</p>
<p>NEX’s newly launched Active Arcade, with a collection of motion games, helps both kids and adults move more by playing games. It is accessible to everyone, everywhere by any computing device with a camera, like smartphone, tablets, laptops and desktops.</p>
<p>Unlike other motion-based entertainment companies’ products that require expensive gear like a VR headset, connected hardware or game consoles, NEX develops motion-based entertainment apps without requiring special equipment, monitors, or a subscription.</p>
<p>Anyone can play Active Arcade using their body movement. Each game has different game play, style and depth, so there’s something for players of any age or level of activity.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7AR4BahK1So?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>“There are many high-tech exercise programs global companies developed in the motion-based entertainment industry, but most of them require expensive new equipment or a steep learning curve,” said Alex Wu, vice president of Strategy, MarComm and Partnerships at NEX.</p>
<p>With a proprietary combination of AI using mobile and vision technology, NEX merges the digital and physical worlds into a phone application that can create games like Active Arcade.</p>
<p>This summer, the company launched its limited test version of Active Arcade, Lee said.</p>
<p>NEX launched its first AI-based basketball training app HomeCourt in 2018, which was demoed on stage alongside Steve Nash at an Apple iPhone special event.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am constantly looking to invest in companies and products that I can stand behind and that are in line with my values. Nex&#8217;s approach to get kids and adults moving more and transforming activity into a play, is a mission I am wholeheartedly behind,&#8221; Steve Nash, Brooklyn Nets Coach and 2x league MVP said.</p>
<p>“We continue to be proud of the team at <span class="il">NEX</span> as they take this significant next step in transforming activity into play for people around the world,” said Chip Austin, General Partner of Harris Blitzer Sports &amp; Entertainment Ventures. “We embrace their important vision and are impressed by their leadership and technology.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nDD3IZCbDw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/01/oculus-shows-off-the-50-launch-titles-for-its-touch-motion-controllers/">Oculus shows off the 50+ launch titles for its Touch motion controllers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Oculus shows off the 50+ launch titles for its Touch motion controllers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/01/oculus-shows-off-the-50-launch-titles-for-its-touch-motion-controllers/embed/#?secret=nDD3IZCbDw" data-secret="nDD3IZCbDw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/nex-a-motion-based-entertainment-company-announces-25b-series-b-round-and-its-motion-game-app-active-arcade-launch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205010</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Salesforce reaches Net Zero energy usage, announces updates to Sustainability Cloud</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/salesforce-reaches-net-zero-energy-usage-announces-updates-to-sustainability-cloud/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/salesforce-reaches-net-zero-energy-usage-announces-updates-to-sustainability-cloud/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 13:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bret Taylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dreamforce 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Salesforce has often preached about responsible capitalism, and today at Dreamforce, the company&#8217;s annual customer extravaganza, it announced a notable achievement in the battle against global climate change. The company said that it has achieved effective Net Zero energy usage across its entire value chain with 100% renewable energy, while purchasing carbon offsets when that&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://salesforce.com">Salesforce</a> has often preached about responsible capitalism, and today at Dreamforce, the company&#8217;s annual customer extravaganza, it announced a notable achievement in the battle against global climate change. The company said that it has achieved effective Net Zero energy usage across its entire value chain with 100% renewable energy, while purchasing carbon offsets when that&#8217;s not possible.</p>
<p class="p1">At the same time, it announced updates to the Sustainability Cloud, a product that the company sells to other organizations to manage their climate initiatives, proving you can be responsible, and still be capitalists. Suzanne DiBianca, chief impact officer &amp; EVP for corporate relations at Salesforce, speaking at yesterday&#8217;s Dreamforce press event says the company is proud to be an example of a large organization taking positive climate action.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m very excited about our commitment to climate action around being a Net Zero company today. And this is not in 2030, not in 2040, not in some other future moment. We know we have to accelerate, and we have gotten to Net Zero today including our entire value chain, which is Scope 1, 2 and 3. Very few companies have gotten here,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>There is a lot of sustainability jargon there, so we spoke to Ari Alexander, GM of Sustainability Cloud to break it down for us. Alexander explained that the sustainability community measures a company&#8217;s carbon footprint in three main areas known as Scope 1, Scope 2 and Scope 3. &#8220;Scope 1 and 2 are what you own, what you operate, what you control and then what energy is procured in order to power your operation,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Scope 3 is everything else your company touches, which is referred to as &#8216;up and down the value chain&#8217; in industry parlance. &#8220;The vast majority of the emissions that a company is responsible for are actually not in their direct operational control, but relate to their upstream suppliers that they procure goods and services from, or in the case of other industries the downstream use of the product or the life of a product,&#8221; he said. A downstream example might be what happens to your phone after you trade it in for a new one.</p>
<p>So when Salesforce says that it&#8217;s Net Zero up and down the value chain, it involves everything it controls and every company it interacts with in the act of doing business. Because there are so many variables here outside of Salesforce&#8217;s control, Alexander says when the company can&#8217;t ensure that a partner or vendor is in compliance with the standard set by the company, it buys what he calls &#8220;high quality carbon offsets.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Also for where we can&#8217;t do that immediately, we are purchasing high quality carbon offsets to make up the difference to be able to be fully Net Zero now, while we continue on that really important journey of reducing to absolute zero across the supply chain [over time],&#8221; he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RZYeEDtLUj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/tech-leaders-can-be-the-secret-weapon-for-supercharging-esg-goals/">Tech leaders can be the secret weapon for supercharging ESG goals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tech leaders can be the secret weapon for supercharging ESG goals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/tech-leaders-can-be-the-secret-weapon-for-supercharging-esg-goals/embed/#?secret=RZYeEDtLUj" data-secret="RZYeEDtLUj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In addition, the company announced updates to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/18/salesforce-is-developing-an-app-to-help-build-a-sustainable-company/">the Sustainability Cloud</a>, the commercial tool it has developed to sell to other companies, using the same tools and technology that Salesforce is using in-house.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sustainability is undergoing a transformation in that it&#8217;s going from something that&#8217;s a nice to have to something that&#8217;s actually at the heart of business transformation itself. That it&#8217;s one of the mega trends of our time and growing exponentially every year, and part of what that means is that companies are moving significant resources in order to respond to the climate crisis and moving sustainability to the core of how they do business,&#8221; Alexander said.</p>
<p>At the same time, the company published a blueprint based on its own plans to be a more sustainable organization called the <a href="https://www.salesforce.com/content/dam/web/en_us/www/assets/pdf/reports/salesforce-climate-action-plan-2021.pdf">Salesforce Climate Action Plan</a> (link to pdf) that it is making available for free online.</p>
<p>The company also announced plans to accelerate its tree planting goals to grow 30 million trees this year. This involves working with other organizations to plant, grow and restore 100 million trees in a 10 year period, a goal that they have been pushing to make happen much sooner.</p>
<p>Company president and COO Bret Taylor speaking at the Dreamforce press event said that the climate crisis has had an impact on everyone, and he believes Salesforce can have a meaningful impact based on its behavior while acting as an example for other organizations.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re showing up at Dreamforce, [&#8230;] really to recognize that we think business is the greatest platform for change and to paint a picture of this vision for inspiring every organization to become a trusted enterprise and address these crises [like climate],&#8221; Taylor said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/salesforce-reaches-net-zero-energy-usage-announces-updates-to-sustainability-cloud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205718</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ben Rubin, who founded Houseparty, Meerkat and Slashtalk, will peer into the future of social at Disrupt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/ben-rubin-disrupt-2021-slashtalk/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/ben-rubin-disrupt-2021-slashtalk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 13:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ben rubin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House Party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HouseParty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS App Store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meerkat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Periscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slashtalk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ben Rubin understands where social is going. In fact, he understands it so well, he&#8217;s always there early. Rubin is the current CEO and co-founder of Slashtalk and an angel investor who scouts for Sequoia Capital. He previously founded Houseparty and Meerkat — apps that pioneered group video chat and mobile livestreaming, respectively — shaping [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ben Rubin understands where social is going. In fact, he understands it so well, he&#8217;s always there early.</p>
<p>Rubin is the current CEO and co-founder of <a href="https://slashtalk.com/">Slashtalk</a> and an angel investor who scouts for Sequoia Capital. He previously founded Houseparty and Meerkat — apps that pioneered group video chat and mobile livestreaming, respectively — shaping massive social trends in their earliest stages.</p>
<p>In 2015, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/03/01/meerkat/">Meerkat took SXSW by storm</a>. The app seemed to have captured lightning in a bottle, and entrenched players in social noticed. Twitter was early to the trend too, having <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/03/13/how-periscope-works/">bought Periscope earlier that year</a>, and leveraged Meerkat&#8217;s momentum to attract people to its own product. Half a year later, Facebook vaulted into the space with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/08/05/facescope/">Facebook Live</a>.</p>
<p>Meerkat didn&#8217;t keep up, but it did transform. In 2016, the same team launched Houseparty, a group video chat app geared toward connecting established friends in casual virtual hangouts rather than streaming to the masses. Three years later, in a world not yet ravaged by the pandemic, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/12/fortnite-maker-epic-acquires-social-video-app-houseparty/">it sold to Fortnite maker Epic Games</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ioYXI7spwn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/12/fortnite-maker-epic-acquires-social-video-app-houseparty/">Fortnite maker Epic acquires social video app Houseparty</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fortnite maker Epic acquires social video app Houseparty&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/12/fortnite-maker-epic-acquires-social-video-app-houseparty/embed/#?secret=ioYXI7spwn" data-secret="ioYXI7spwn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>With people driven indoors and away from IRL social interactions, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/houseparty-reports-50m-sign-ups-in-past-month-amid-covid-19-lockdowns/">Houseparty boomed</a>. In a single month during the pandemic&#8217;s early phase, the app saw 50 million new signups and hit the top of the charts across the iOS App Store and Google Play. But Houseparty struggled to retain users, and by fall of 2021 Epic announced that it would unceremoniously wind down the project and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/epic-games-to-shut-down-houseparty-in-october-including-the-video-chat-fortnite-mode-feature/">pull Houseparty from app stores.</a></p>
<p>Only time will tell if Houseparty&#8217;s technology will play a role in Epic&#8217;s vision for the metaverse — an interconnected series of seamless virtual worlds for people to explore and socialize in. But regardless of the app&#8217;s eventual fate, Houseparty&#8217;s take on social spontaneity and casual group video was ahead of its time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If anyone is well positioned to know where social networks are going in the near future, it&#8217;s probably Rubin. He&#8217;s now working on Slashtalk, &#8220;an anti-meeting tool for fast, decentralized conversations.&#8221; Slashtalk&#8217;s ethos echoes both Meerkat and Houseparty&#8217;s belief in social serendipity, but this time Rubin is focused on the workplace rather than consumer social.</p>
<p>Rubin will join us onstage at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> to talk about his new company and the trends powering current upheavals in social networking, from decentralization and ownership to the future of a connected post-pandemic world.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/ben-rubin-disrupt-2021-slashtalk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205193</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Business Canvas, a Korea-based document management SaaS company, closes $2.5M seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/business-canvas-a-korea-based-document-management-saas-company-closes-2-5m-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/business-canvas-a-korea-based-document-management-saas-company-closes-2-5m-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business canvas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[typed]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Business Canvas, the South Korean document management SaaS company behind Typed, announced today it has raised a $2.5 million seed round led by Mirae Asset Venture Investment, with participation from Kakao Ventures and Nextrans Inc. The seed round will be used for accelerating product development and the global launch of an open beta for its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.typed.biz/">Business Canvas</a>, the South Korean document management SaaS company behind Typed, announced today it has raised a $2.5 million seed round led by <a href="http://venture.miraeasset.co.kr/en/">Mirae Asset Venture Investment</a>, with participation from <a href="https://www.kakao.vc/">Kakao Ventures</a> and <a href="https://www.nextrans.vn/">Nextrans Inc</a>.</p>
<p>The seed round will be used for accelerating product development and the global launch of an open beta for its AI-powered document management platform. The company opened an office in Santa Clara, California this year to spur its global expansion.</p>
<p>The problem that Business Canvas has identified and is building solutions to target is the challenge faced by people who are tasked with ingesting information and producing writing or decisions based on that: lawyers, entrepreneurs, researchers, students and communications workers like journalists among them. People are bombarded with information these days, thanks to technology. That might be good in some cases, but in the world of work, and specifically written work, there is such a thing as too much information, which can take a lot of time to process, and thus eat into the time we need to produce work based on that information.</p>
<p>Business Canvas, founded in 2020 by CEO Woojin Kim, Brian Shin, Seungmin Lee, Dongjoon Shin and Clint Yoo, is hoping to solve the challenge that every knowledge worker and writer faces: spending more time on research and file organization than the actual content output they need to create.</p>
<p>“In fact, people commit over 30% of their working hours trying to search for that file we once saved in a folder that we just cannot find anymore,” Kim said.</p>
<p>Through a network that intelligently tracks and organizes files based on the user’s interactions, Typed brings together knowledge from different websites and applications into one simple-to-use and quick-to-learn digital workspace.</p>
<p>Strictly keeping its users&#8217; information and their confidential files uninterrupted, Typed does not access the content of users’ documents but utilizes them as machine learning data, Kim told TechCrunch. It collects users&#8217; actions as data points, merging this with publicly available metadata from documents and resources under users&#8217; permission, Kim added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Modern document writing has not changed since the 1980s,” Yoo said. “While we have more knowledge at our fingertips than ever before, we use the same rudimentary methods to organize and make sense of it. We want any writer &#8212; from lawyers and entrepreneurs to researchers and students &#8212; to focus on creating great content instead of wasting time organizing their source material. We achieved this by making knowledge management more like the way our brain operates.”</p>
<p>Since the launch of the closed beta test in February 2021, Typed has seen significant user growth, with 25,000 files uploaded and 350% month-over-month active user growth. It does not disclose active user numbers but said that it currently has more than 10,000 users on the waitlist.</p>
<p>Typed will be available through a freemium model and is currently accepting beta registrations on its website.</p>
<p>“When we tested our closed beta, our metrics showed top traction among students as well as journalists, writers and lawyers, who require heavy research and document work on a frequent basis. We opened up access earlier this month for the waitlists in over 50 countries. These are primarily B2C users,” Kim told TechCrunch. “As for B2B, we are currently in the process of proof-of-concept for one of the largest conglomerates in South Korea. Smaller teams like startups, boutique law, consulting firms, venture capitals and government institutions also have been adopting Typed as well.”</p>
<p>“While the company is still in its nascent stage in its development, Typed has the potential to fundamentally change how we work individually or as a team. If there is a business to take on our outdated way of writing content, it’s them [Typed],” Shina Chung, Kakao Ventures CEO said.</p>
<p>The global market size for social software and collaboration SaaS is <a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/social-software-and-collaboration-market-forecast-to-net-4-5-billion-in-2021/">estimated at $4.5 billion in 2021</a>, increasing over 17% year on year, Kim said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mKHqDQTWWH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/27/mozilla-pockets-pocket-in-first-acquisition/">Mozilla pockets Pocket in first acquisition</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mozilla pockets Pocket in first acquisition&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/27/mozilla-pockets-pocket-in-first-acquisition/embed/#?secret=mKHqDQTWWH" data-secret="mKHqDQTWWH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/business-canvas-a-korea-based-document-management-saas-company-closes-2-5m-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205584</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Battery Resourcers raises $70M to grow closed-loop battery supply chain</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/battery-resourcers-raises-70m-to-grow-closed-loop-battery-supply-chain/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/battery-resourcers-raises-70m-to-grow-closed-loop-battery-supply-chain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 13:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery recycling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battery Resourcers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle batteries]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Battery Resourcers, a startup that’s developing a closed-loop approach to lithium-ion battery materials, has closed $70 million in mid-round funding to scale its commercial operations across two continents. The company, which is based in Worcester, Massachusetts, doesn’t just recycle batteries. It’s also engineered a process to turn that recycled material back into critical battery materials [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.batteryresourcers.com/">Battery Resourcers</a>, a startup that’s developing a closed-loop approach to lithium-ion battery materials, has closed $70 million in mid-round funding to scale its commercial operations across two continents.</p>
<p>The company, which is based in Worcester, Massachusetts, doesn’t just recycle batteries. It’s also engineered a process to turn that recycled material back into critical battery materials – specifically, nickel-manganese-cobalt cathodes and purified graphite, a material used in anodes. It intends to sell those materials right back to the battery manufacturer.</p>
<p>This latest round saw participation from new investor Hitachi Ventures, as well as existing investors Orbia Ventures, Jaguar Land Rover’s InMotion Ventures, Doral Energy, At One Ventures, TDK Ventures and Trumpf Ventures.</p>
<p>Battery Resources secured a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/battery-resourcers-raises-20m-to-commercialize-its-recycling-plus-manufacturing-operations/">$20 million Series B</a> a little over five months ago. That funding was to accelerate the launch of the startup’s first commercial-scale facility, which will be able to process 10,000 tons of batteries per year. CEO Michael O’Kronley told TechCrunch in a recent interview that that plant will open in the first quarter of 2022, though the company has not yet announced where it will be located in the U.S.</p>
<p>With this new funding, the company will be opening two additional commercial-scale sites in Europe, which will be operational by the end of 2022. In all, Battery Resourcers aims to have 30,000 tons of recycling capacity by the end of next year across its three commercial-scale locations. Cathode material production will be added to these sites in the following year.</p>
<p>There are a number of reasons to look abroad, O’Kronley said, not least because Battery Resourcers anticipates Europe being an even larger market than the U.S.</p>
<p>“Europe has the same concerns the U.S. does about retaining critical battery materials in the supply chain,” he said, adding that European lawmakers currently mandate battery recycling on the part of OEMs, and will likely mandate the use of recycled materials in batteries. “Couple that with the amount and the number of gigafactories that have been announced in Europe, relative to the US, most people believe, including Battery Resourcers, we believe the European market will be larger than the North American market.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2205479" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2205479" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2205479" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-20-at-2.39.21-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="1177" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-20-at-2.39.21-PM.png 1152w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-20-at-2.39.21-PM.png?resize=131,150 131w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-20-at-2.39.21-PM.png?resize=261,300 261w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-20-at-2.39.21-PM.png?resize=768,883 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-20-at-2.39.21-PM.png?resize=592,680 592w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-20-at-2.39.21-PM.png?resize=44,50 44w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2205479" class="wp-caption-text">CEO Michael O’Kronley <strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.batteryresourcers.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Battery Resourcers <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The lion’s share of critical battery materials are currently produced in Asia, but O’Kronley said the industry is shifting from being highly concentrated in specific locations to a more global operation.</p>
<p>“Whether it&#8217;s the Asian company that is moving to Europe or North America, or new entrants that are coming in and supplying Europe and North America – we&#8217;re a new entrant coming in supplying these regions – the battery material supply chain will absolutely have to be localized,” he said. “We’re part of that.”</p>
<p>O’Kronley added that the company has been in talks with a number of OEMs and consumer electronics companies, but declined to specify any details. However, he did say that vehicle OEMs and battery manufacturers have already taken the company’s cathode material and built it into batteries for testing and to compare it to “virgin” cathodes.</p>
<p>“It&#8217;s Battery Resourcers’ belief that long term, you need a vertically integrated supply chain, and to be able to extract the highest amount of value out of these spent batteries,” O’Kronley said. “We&#8217;re moving upstream in making these engineering materials that go right back into a new battery.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/battery-resourcers-raises-70m-to-grow-closed-loop-battery-supply-chain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205440</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bilt Rewards banks $60M growth on a $350M valuation to advance credit card benefits for renters</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/bilt-rewards-banks-60m-growth-on-a-350m-valuation-to-advance-credit-card-benefits-for-renters/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/bilt-rewards-banks-60m-growth-on-a-350m-valuation-to-advance-credit-card-benefits-for-renters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 13:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ankur Jain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AvalonBay Communities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bilt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GID-Windsor Communities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greg Bates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landlord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loyalty program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ownership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Blackstone Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wells Fargo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The latest round comes just 90 days from Bilt's launch.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.biltrewards.com/">Bilt Rewards</a>, a loyalty program for property renters to earn points on rent with no fees and build a path toward homeownership, announced Tuesday a round of $60 million in growth funding that values the company at $350 million.</p>
<p>The investment comes from Wells Fargo and Mastercard and a group of the nation’s largest real estate owners, including The Blackstone Group, AvalonBay Communities, Douglas Elliman, Equity Residential, GID-Windsor Communities, LENx, The Moinian Group, Morgan Properties, Starwood Capital Group and Related.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/a-rewards-program-for-your-rent-payments-meet-bilt/">Bilt launched back in June</a> out of Kairos, the startup studio led by Ankur Jain, focused on enabling over 109 million renters in the U.S. to earn points from paying their rent every month — typically someone’s largest monthly expense. Since then, the program was rolled out across over 2 million rental units, Jain told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>“We are the first and only alliance of the major property owners to create this kind of program and already have 15 of the top 20 owners involved,” he added. “We are also the only co-branded card to offer points on rent.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TxW97VFDFS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/a-rewards-program-for-your-rent-payments-meet-bilt/">A rewards program for your rent payments? Meet Bilt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A rewards program for your rent payments? Meet Bilt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/a-rewards-program-for-your-rent-payments-meet-bilt/embed/#?secret=TxW97VFDFS" data-secret="TxW97VFDFS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Greg Bates, GID president and CEO, said his company has 130 assets spread across the top 20 markets and manages 40,000 apartment units. He learned about Bilt from a colleague who attended a proptech conference where Jain demoed the Bilt card.</p>
<p>For as long as Bates has been in the real estate industry, about 20 years or so, renters have wanted to pay rent with a credit card for convenience and to earn loyalty points. However, that was cost-prohibitive in terms of the surcharges needed to be added to the rental rate &#8212; until Bilt, he said. The card “is incredibly easy to use” and integrates into property owners’ online payment systems.</p>
<p>“Bilt has transformed the value proposition for residents that want to use a credit card and for landlords that want to accept them,” Bates added. “There will always be barriers to entry for products like this, but Bilt spent time with Mastercard and Wells Fargo to develop this unique product which will be a competition differentiator for a few years to come.”</p>
<p>In addition to the new funding, Bilt is also announcing new benefits for its loyalty members and upgraded offerings for the Bilt Mastercard, including the ability to earn up to 50,000 points on rent per year and unlimited points using the credit card.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For members, Bilt will pay interest in the form of points for a member’s account each month based on their average daily points balance over the 30-day period, and offer a concierge service for members choosing to redeem their Bilt points toward a home down payment. In addition, members can earn bonus points on top of points used by landlords on new leases and renewals.</p>
<p>Bilt worked with regulators, as well as Fannie Mae and the Department of Housing and Urban Development, to gain approval for using rewards points toward a mortgage. Members can also report their rent payments to the credit bureaus at no cost, which can help build credit history for millions of young renters.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the company’s new “0-1-2-3” point earning structure for Bilt Mastercard holders provides no annual fee, 1x points on rent payments, 2x points on travel, 3x points on dining and 1x points on all other purchases.</p>
<p>This is the company’s first major external financing round and will be used to expand its real estate and loyalty partner network, grow its distribution channels and make its platform credit card more widely available to the public. Jain estimates Bilt is seeing 20% enrollment across residents.</p>
<p>As more renters move to homeownership over time, Bilt has plans to leverage this potential larger business to eventually become a mortgage provider for them.</p>
<p>“Renting is something people do for a while, and the core business has a massive scale opportunity, especially in the demographic under 35 years old, who tend to be up-and-coming professionals,” Jain added. “This is a unique target market, and Bilt will grow with them as they build their path to homeownership.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="w06jh7fXdi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/all-the-reasons-why-you-should-launch-a-credit-or-debit-card/">All the reasons why you should launch a credit or debit card</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;All the reasons why you should launch a credit or debit card&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/all-the-reasons-why-you-should-launch-a-credit-or-debit-card/embed/#?secret=w06jh7fXdi" data-secret="w06jh7fXdi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/bilt-rewards-banks-60m-growth-on-a-350m-valuation-to-advance-credit-card-benefits-for-renters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205181</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ellen DeGeneres, Portia de Rossi, Shaun White, Shawn Mendes get behind Shelf Engine</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/ellen-degeneres-portia-de-rossi-shaun-white-shawn-mendes-get-behind-shelf-engine/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/ellen-degeneres-portia-de-rossi-shaun-white-shawn-mendes-get-behind-shelf-engine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b2b software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compass Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ellen DeGeneres]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joe montana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kroger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PLUS Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portia de Rossi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shaun White]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shawn Mendes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shelf Engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stefan Kalb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole foods]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shelf Engine’s grocery order automation technology applies AI to food order volume so that grocery customers can reduce their food waste by as much as 32%.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://shelfengine.com/">Shelf Engine</a>’s mission to eliminate food waste in grocery retailers now has some additional celebrity backers. The company brought in a $2 million extension to its $41 million Series B announced in March.</p>
<p>Ellen DeGeneres, Portia de Rossi, Shaun White and Shawn Mendes are the new backers, who came in through a strategic round of funding alongside PLUS Capital to bring the Seattle-based company’s total funding to $60 million since the company’s inception in 2016. This includes a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/shelf-engine-has-a-plan-to-reduce-food-waste-at-grocery-stores-and-12-million-in-new-cash-to-see-i/">$12 million Series A</a> from 2020.</p>
<p>Shelf Engine’s grocery order automation technology applies advanced statistical models and artificial intelligence to deliver accurate food order volume so that customers can reduce their food waste by as much as 32% while increasing gross margins and sales of more than 50%. The company has already helped retailers divert 1 million pounds of food waste from landfills, Stefan Kalb, co-founder and CEO of Shelf Engine, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>“We’ve had phenomenal growth last year, some of it from our mid-market customers, but mostly from customers like Target and Kroger,” Kalb said. “Our other big news is that we hired a president (<a href="https://www.shelfengine.com/news/kane-mccord-shelf-engine-president-chief-revenue-officer/">Kane McCord</a>) in the past six weeks, which is cool to have the reinforcement on the leadership side.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N5tEUqQ5r2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/shelf-engine-has-a-plan-to-reduce-food-waste-at-grocery-stores-and-12-million-in-new-cash-to-see-i/">Shelf Engine has a plan to reduce food waste at grocery stores, and $12 million in new cash to do it</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Shelf Engine has a plan to reduce food waste at grocery stores, and $12 million in new cash to do it&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/shelf-engine-has-a-plan-to-reduce-food-waste-at-grocery-stores-and-12-million-in-new-cash-to-see-i/embed/#?secret=N5tEUqQ5r2" data-secret="N5tEUqQ5r2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Over the past 12 months, the company, which works with retailers like Kroger, Whole Foods and Compass Group, saw over 540% revenue growth. At the same time, it grew its employees to 200 from 23, Kalb said. He expects to more than double Shelf Engine’s headcount over the next 12 months.</p>
<p>As a result, the new funding will be used to scale with current customers and accelerate further investment in R&amp;D of its AI systems and automation capabilities.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Amanda Groves, partner at PLUS Capital, said her firm works with about 65 individuals who are in film, television, sports and culture, including the four new investors in Shelf Engine.</p>
<p>She says many of her clients are looking to participate in business as an investor or with sweat equity. Her firm works with them to determine interests and will then source opportunities and invest alongside them.</p>
<p>Shelf Engine fits into one of PLUS Capital’s core investment areas of sustainability. The firm looks across different sectors like food, energy, apparel, packaging and recycling. Shelf Engine’s approach of leveraging technology to aid in sustainability efforts was attractive to all of the investors, as was their method of scaling within grocery clients without affecting consumer behavior.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“When Shelf Engine is installed in the grocery store, they can reduce spoilage by 10% right off the bat — that immediacy of the impact was what got our clients excited,” Groves added.</p>
<p>One of Shelf Engine’s first celebrity investors was Joe Montana, and Kalb said partnering with celebrities enables the company’s mission to eliminate food waste and address the climate crisis to be made more aware.</p>
<p>“B2B software is not as glamorous, but the climate has become a big issue and something many celebrities care about,” he added. “Shawn Mendes has over 60 million followers, so for him to share about this issue is extremely meaningful. Where he invests will lead to his followers knocking on the doors of stores and saying ‘this matters to me.’ That is the strategy shift from B2B to a movement for our community.”</p>
<p>The company is not alone in tackling food waste, which globally each year amounts to $1.3 trillion. For example, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apeel-bites-into-another-250m-funding-round-at-a-2b-valuation-to-accelerate-fresh-food-supply-chains/">Apeel</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/05/food-sharing-app-olio-raises-43m-series-b-as-the-world-switches-on-to-the-food-waste-crisis/">OLIO</a>, <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/imperfect-foods-secures-95mm-series-d-investment-commitment-301212899.html">Imperfect Foods</a>, <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20200717005006/en/Cambridge-Crops-Rebrands-as-Mori-and-Raises-12-Million-in-Series-A-Funding-to-Combat-Food-Waste">Mori</a> and <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/exclusive-phood-heats-up-2m-seed-to-reduce-food-waste/">Phood Solutions</a> are all working to improve the food supply chain and have attracted venture dollars in the past year to go after that mission.</p>
<p>Shelf Engine is already in over 3,000 stores nationwide in the areas of grocery, food service and convenience stores, which “is a large lift from 18 months ago,” Kalb said. Next up, the company is progressing to open new categories and managing more projects. He is specifically looking at what the company can manage in the store and manage for the customer.</p>
<p>“We are getting to the point where we can manage more of the store in complex categories like meat, seafood and deli that are mainly custom,” he added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="I4RWlRA7UU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/iot-and-data-science-will-boost-foodtech-in-the-post-pandemic-era/">IoT and data science will boost foodtech in the post-pandemic era</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;IoT and data science will boost foodtech in the post-pandemic era&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/iot-and-data-science-will-boost-foodtech-in-the-post-pandemic-era/embed/#?secret=I4RWlRA7UU" data-secret="I4RWlRA7UU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/ellen-degeneres-portia-de-rossi-shaun-white-shawn-mendes-get-behind-shelf-engine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205299</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stairwell secures $20M Series A to help organizations outsmart attackers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/stairwell-secures-20m-series-a-to-help-organizations-outsmart-attackers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/stairwell-secures-20m-series-a-to-help-organizations-outsmart-attackers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anomali]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inception]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[McAfee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palo alto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarWinds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stairwell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[system administration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2204273</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Back when Stairwell emerged from stealth in 2020, the startup was shrouded in secrecy. Now with $20 million in Series A funding, its founder and CEO Mike Wiacek — who previously served as chief security officer at Chronicle, Google’s moonshot cybersecurity company — is ready to talk. As well as raising $20M, an investment round [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Back when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/chronicle-cso-stairwell-cybersecurity-startup/">Stairwell emerged from stealth in 2020</a>, the startup was shrouded in secrecy. Now with $20 million in Series A funding, its founder and CEO Mike Wiacek — who previously served as chief security officer at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/chronicle/">Chronicle</a>, Google’s moonshot cybersecurity company — is ready to talk.</p>
<p>As well as raising $20M, an investment round co-led by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/sequoia-capital/">Sequoia Capital</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/accel/">Accel</a>, Stairwell is launching Inception, a threat hunting platform that aims to help organizations determine if they were compromised now or in the past. Unlike other threat detection platforms, Inception takes an &#8220;inside out&#8221; approach to cybersecurity, which starts by looking inwards at a company’s data.</p>
<p>“This helps you study what&#8217;s in your environment first before you start thinking about what&#8217;s happening in the outside world,” Wiacek tells TechCrunch. “The beautiful thing about that approach is that&#8217;s not information that outside parties, a.k.a. the bad guys, are privy to.”</p>
<p>This data, all of which is treated as suspicious, is continuously evaluated in light of new indicators and new threat intelligence. Stairwell claims this enables organizations to detect anomalies within just days, <a href="https://www.capita.com/sites/g/files/nginej291/files/2020-08/Ponemon-Global-Cost-of-Data-Breach-Study-2020.pdf">rather than the industry average of 280 days</a>, as well as to “bootstrap” future detections.</p>
<p>“If you go and buy a threat intelligence feed from Vendor X, do you really think that someone who&#8217;s spending hundreds of thousands, or even millions of dollars to conduct an offensive campaign isn&#8217;t going to make sure that whatever they&#8217;re using isn&#8217;t in that field?,” said Wiacek. “They know what McAfee knows and they know other antivirus engines know, but they don&#8217;t know what you know and that&#8217;s a very powerful advantage that you have there.”</p>
<p>Stairwell’s $20 million in Series A funding, which comes less than 12 months after it secured $4.5 million in seed funding, will be used to further advance the Inception platform and to increase the startup’s headcount; the Palo Alto-based firm currently has a modest headcount of 21.</p>
<p>The Inception platform, which the startup claims finally enables enterprises to “outsmart the bad guys”, is launching in early release for a limited number of customers, with full general availability scheduled for 2022.</p>
<p>“I just wish we had a product to market when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/solarwinds/">SolarWinds</a> happened,” Wiacek added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="52CV59FZUE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/chronicle-cso-stairwell-cybersecurity-startup/">Chronicle&#8217;s ex-CSO is starting a new company he doesn&#8217;t want you to know much about</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chronicle&#8217;s ex-CSO is starting a new company he doesn&#8217;t want you to know much about&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/chronicle-cso-stairwell-cybersecurity-startup/embed/#?secret=52CV59FZUE" data-secret="52CV59FZUE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/stairwell-secures-20m-series-a-to-help-organizations-outsmart-attackers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2204273</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon’s Kindle Paperwhite returns with a bigger screen, USB-C and wireless charging</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/amazons-kindle-paperwhite-returns-with-a-bigger-screen-usb-c-and-wireless-charging/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/amazons-kindle-paperwhite-returns-with-a-bigger-screen-usb-c-and-wireless-charging/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-reader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kindle paperwhite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paperwhite]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’ve entered the throes of hardware season, with big events from all of the industry’s big names. Amazon has already announced a number of new Fire TVs, with plans for a big (likely Echo-focused) event a week from today. In the meantime, the retail giant just dropped a sizable surprise on our heads in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We’ve entered the throes of hardware season, with big events from all of the industry’s big names. Amazon has already <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/amazon-is-releasing-its-own-tvs-with-alexa-built-in/">announced</a> a number of new Fire TVs, with plans for a big (likely Echo-focused) event a week from today. In the meantime, the retail giant just dropped a sizable surprise on our heads in the form of a brand new Kindle Paperwhite.</p>
<p>I say “surprise” primarily because the whole of the Kindle hardware division has been quiet for a while now. When the Paperwhite got its last major upgrade in 2018, we noted, “The Voyage may be dead, but the Kindle line still has some life left in it.” Because, let’s face it, the whole of the devoted e-reader market isn’t exactly bustling. Sure Kobo is still hanging around the edges, but Amazon more or less sits alone as a monolith these days.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2205337" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2205337" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2205337" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Covers.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="894" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Covers.jpg 1217w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Covers.jpg?resize=150,131 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Covers.jpg?resize=300,262 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Covers.jpg?resize=768,671 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Covers.jpg?resize=680,594 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Covers.jpg?resize=50,44 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2205337" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p>
<p>There were some rumblings, however, including a UI update for the line and a smattering of leaks, precipitating today’s news. And sure enough, here’s a new Paperwhite, representing the biggest update to the mid-tier Kindle in recent memory.</p>
<p>The star of the show is a long-awaited increase to the display &#8212; up from six to 6.8 inches, while maintaining the 300 PPI pixel density. That’s edging into the seven-inch 300 PPI Kindle Oasis territory. Like the Oasis, the bezels are flush with the device and they’ve been shaved down 12% from the previous generation (to 10.2mm) to help maintain the device’s footprint.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2205340" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2205340" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2205340 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Lifestyle-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="545" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Lifestyle-1.jpg 3008w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=300,160 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=768,409 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=680,362 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=1536,818 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=2048,1091 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2205340" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p>
<p>Honestly, though, the most exciting addition here is USB-C charging. I realize that sounds a bit silly, but the Kindle line has been the last vestige of microUSB &#8212; it’s one of the few reasons I keep those cables around anymore. I fully expected the pricier Oasis to be the first device to adopt the new (well, newer) connector, but, then, that would require Amazon to release a new Oasis.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Charging is faster, requiring 2.5 hours to go from zero to full. The battery itself has also been improved, up to 10 weeks on a charge from six &#8212; but what’s a month between friends, right? The other surprise on the battery side of things is the arrival of wireless charging. That’s available with the new Paperwhite Signature Edition, which also bumps the base-level 8GB of storage up to 32GB. Amazon is also introducing a $30 charging dock, which is available separately &#8212; it should work with any standard Qi charging pad.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2205345" style="width: 985px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2205345" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2205345" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Kids-2.jpg" alt="" width="975" height="779" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Kids-2.jpg 975w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Kids-2.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Kids-2.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Kids-2.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Kids-2.jpg?resize=680,543 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Kindle-Paperwhite-Kids-2.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 975px) 100vw, 975px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2205345" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p>
<p>Max brightness on the screen has been bumped up 10%, coupled with an auto-adjusting light based on ambient light. Like the Oasis, the light will adjust to a warmer color to save your eyes closer to bedtime. The processor has been improved since the last gen (no specifics there at the moment), promising 20% faster page turning. The device is made from with 60% post-consumer recycled plastics and 70% recycled magnesium.</p>
<p>The new Paperwhite runs $140 for standard and $190 for the Signature Edition. They come with four free months of Kindle Unlimited and are up for preorder today. Also up for preorder is the first-ever Kids edition of the device. The Kindle Paperwhite for Kids features a kid-friendly cover, a year of Amazon Kids+ and a two-year warranty. That runs $160.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/amazons-kindle-paperwhite-returns-with-a-bigger-screen-usb-c-and-wireless-charging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205336</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instacart shopper activist group asks customers to delete the app until demands for better conditions are met</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/instacart-shopper-activist-group-asks-customers-to-delete-the-app-until-demands-for-better-conditions-are-met/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/instacart-shopper-activist-group-asks-customers-to-delete-the-app-until-demands-for-better-conditions-are-met/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 12:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apoorva Mehta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fidji Simo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gig]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig workers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instacart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telemedicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, the Gig Workers Collective &#8212; representing a body of about 13,000 Instacart shoppers &#8212; launched a #DeleteInstacart campaign, urging customers to delete the Instacart app as a show of solidarity with workers advocating for better treatment. The collective of shoppers asked that customers refrain from reinstalling the app until five demands are met. They [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Yesterday, the <a href="https://www.gigworkerscollective.org/home">Gig Workers Collective</a> &#8212; representing a body of about 13,000 Instacart shoppers &#8212; launched a <a href="https://gigworkerscollective.medium.com/?p=b1e138ed88f3">#DeleteInstacart campaign</a>, urging customers to delete the Instacart app as a show of solidarity with workers advocating for better treatment. The collective of shoppers asked that customers refrain from reinstalling the app until five demands are met. They are asking to be paid by individual order, not by a batch of orders; to re-introduce item-based commissions; to ensure the rating system doesn&#8217;t punish shoppers for issues beyond their control; to provide occupational death benefits; and to make the default tip at least 10%, up from the current 5% default.</p>
<p>“We’re deeply committed to creating the best possible experience for our shopper community. Over the past several years, this unwavering commitment has led us to introduce new features, policies, offerings, and support for shoppers &#8212; significantly improving the shopper experience and resulting in the highest shopper sentiment in company history. During the COVID-19 pandemic, we&#8217;ve invested in countless new measures to support the health and safety of the shopper community. We take shopper feedback very seriously and remain committed to listening to and using that feedback to improve their experience,&#8221; Instacart said in a statement provided to TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Instacart employs 500,000 shoppers, the company said, up from 200,000 before <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/23/instacart-will-bring-on-300000-new-full-time-shoppers-due-to-coronavirus/">a pandemic-driven hiring spree</a>. The company told TechCrunch that its payment structure has not changed since February 2019. That month, the company faced a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/05/instacart-faces-class-action-lawsuit-regarding-wages-and-tips/">class-action lawsuit</a> over its practice of subsidizing wages with tips &#8212; Instacart had previously instituted a $10 earning minimum per order, but on small orders that totaled less than $10, customer tips would subsidize the rest of the cost (so, if a customer bought $8 of food and tipped $3, the customer would receive $10 plus $1 in tips, rather than the $10 minimum plus a $3 tip). Former CEO Apoorva Mehta wrote <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/06/instacart-ceo-apologizes-for-tipping-debacle/?utm_campaign=fullarticle&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=inshorts">an apology</a> to shoppers and affirmed that tips should always be separate from employee compensation, and Instacart retroactively compensated shoppers whose tips were included in minimums.</p>
<p>A Gig Workers Collective lead organizer and Instacart shopper, Willy Solis said that he was hopeful workers&#8217; concerns would be met when Fidji Simo took over as Instacart CEO in August. Since then, the company set up an inbox for shoppers to send messages to a VP or CEO. Instacart said that Simo has been regularly conversing with shoppers about their experiences on the job, but Solis said that shoppers don&#8217;t feel like their concerns are being heard.</p>
<p>&#8220;While we had hope, there seems to be a disconnect from what she&#8217;s saying publicly and what she&#8217;s actually doing,&#8221; Solis told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>On her first day as CEO, Simo wrote <a href="https://www.instacart.com/company/shopper-community/excited-to-join-the-instacart-family/">an open letter</a> to Instacart shoppers asking for feedback. In <a href="https://gigworkerscollective.medium.com/?p=b1e138ed88f3">response</a>, the Gig Workers Collective outlined the same five demands that they shared again yesterday, posing them as dire issues that needed to be addressed. But the collective said their letter was ignored, and shoppers&#8217; emails to Simo were met with canned responses.</p>
<p>&#8220;Each time the company gives us one thing, they take something else away,&#8221; the Gig Workers Collective <a href="https://gigworkerscollective.medium.com/open-letter-to-fidgi-simo-instacarts-ceo-e72c0de55e22">wrote</a>. When former CEO Mehta apologized for subsidizing wages with tip money, Instacart changed the minimum order payment from $10 to a range between $7 and $10 per batch, which can contain up to three orders. The issue of batch order payment has become a key part of the Gig Workers Collective&#8217;s demands.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;If we shopped a single order, the base pay would be $7, but if we shopped three orders at once, the base pay would be $7 for the lot. Instead of a shopper fulfilling three orders for a total of $30 base, we now do it for $7 base,&#8221; the collective wrote in <a href="https://gigworkerscollective.medium.com/?p=b1e138ed88f3">their post today</a>. &#8220;This is effectively a 76% cut to base pay, and is unacceptable.&#8221;</p>
<p>Shoppers can see what payment is offered before they accept a batch. But Solis told TechCrunch that there is &#8220;no rhyme or reason&#8221; to the way orders are batched.</p>
<p>&#8220;You would think that they would be in the same geographic location that you&#8217;re delivering to, but they&#8217;re not,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It can be totally different parts of the city, so you have to drive east for one and west for the other.&#8221;</p>
<p>Instacart said that batching orders makes it possible for shoppers to earn three separate tips, and that the $7 base is a minimum that is adjusted based on time, effort, items, mileage, and other factors. But tipping is another hot issue for organizers.</p>
<p>&#8220;We rely on tips heavily,&#8221; Solis said. &#8220;Without tips, a large majority of orders that we take are not beneficial or profitable for us.&#8221;</p>
<p>The default tip on Instacart is set at 5%, which means customers must manually select a higher tip. Organizers want Instacart to make the default tip 10%. Instacart told TechCrunch that tipping is encouraged, but not required. Though the default tip is 5%, the company said, if a user chooses a different tip percentage, then that percentage will become the default for their following order. So, if a customer tips 15% on their first order, for example, then their second order will default to a 15% tip instead of a 5% tip.</p>
<p>The collective is also demanding occupational death benefits due to the risk of shoppers&#8217; work during the coronavirus pandemic; even beyond that, one Instacart shopper <a href="https://www.9news.com/article/news/local/boulder-shooting/lynn-murray-king-soopers-victim/73-c4b3c2a8-0137-46b0-a1ba-0e43bc2af0ea">Lynn Murray</a> was killed in a mass shooting while on the job. But Instacart does offer coronavirus protections to its shoppers, as well as shopper injury protection, which is inclusive of accidental death benefits. For example, if a part-time employee or full-service shopper is diagnosed with COVID-19 or placed in mandatory isolation, they can receive up to 14 days&#8217; pay. Accrued sick pay is also available to in-store shoppers; pay is determined by the shopper&#8217;s average daily earnings. Instacart also provides a vaccine support stipend, enabling workers to take time off to get vaccinated, and offers access to free telemedicine and safety supplies. But in May 2020, the Gig Workers Collective alleged that a shopper who was on a ventilator was <a href="https://gigworkerscollective.medium.com/an-instacart-shopper-with-covid-19-is-now-on-a-ventilator-instacart-refuses-to-help-92d5f2d4c844"><span class="s1">denied payment and healthcare</span></a> under Instacart&#8217;s COVID-19 policy. Instacart reaffirmed to TechCrunch that since March 2020, shoppers have been able to receive up to 14 days&#8217; pay if they have COVID-19 or are in mandatory isolation.</p>
<p>But some of shoppers&#8217; health benefits were only extended after the Gig Workers Collective staged <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/30/business/economy/coronavirus-instacart-amazon.html">an emergency walkout</a> on March 30, 2020. At the time, the collective said Instacart <a href="https://gigworkerscollective.medium.com/instacart-emergency-walk-off-ebdf11b6995a">didn&#8217;t provide PPE</a> or sick pay to people who had a doctor&#8217;s note urging them not to be on the job (for example, people who were quarantined due to an exposure).</p>
<p>Instacart didn&#8217;t indicate to TechCrunch that it has any plans to address the Gig Workers Collective&#8217;s demands. As Instacart <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-instacart-directlisting-exclusive/exclusive-instacart-mulls-direct-listing-in-snub-to-ipos-sources-idUSKBN2AX13F">considers going public</a>, Solis thinks now is a good time to take shoppers&#8217; demands to the next level by asking customers to boycott the service.</p>
<p>&#8220;People that speak out against us taking action will say things like, &#8216;You know, if you don&#8217;t want to do this, get another job,'&#8221; Solis said. &#8220;But the problem is that this work is so exploitative that if somebody doesn&#8217;t take a stand, then the next person in line is going to be exploited. Together, we gain so much power and traction by collectively speaking out.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/instacart-shopper-activist-group-asks-customers-to-delete-the-app-until-demands-for-better-conditions-are-met/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205279</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Slack releases Clips video tool, announces 16 Salesforce integrations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/slack-releases-clips-video-tool-announces-16-salesforce-integrations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/slack-releases-clips-video-tool-announces-16-salesforce-integrations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 12:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bret Taylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collaboration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dreamforce 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stewart Buttefield]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205298</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Slack has been talking about expanding beyond text-based messaging for some time. Today at Dreamforce, the Salesforce customer conference taking place this week, it announced Clips, a way to leave short video messages that people can watch at their leisure. Slack CEO Stewart Butterfield sees Clips as a way to communicate with colleagues when a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://slack.com">Slack</a> has been talking about expanding beyond text-based messaging <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/slack-introduces-new-features-to-ease-messaging-between-business-partners/">for some time</a>. Today at Dreamforce, the Salesforce customer conference taking place this week, it announced Clips, a way to leave short video messages that people can watch at their leisure.</p>
<p>Slack CEO Stewart Butterfield sees Clips as a way to communicate with colleagues when a full 30 minutes meeting isn&#8217;t really required. Instead, you can let people know what&#8217;s going on through a brief video. &#8220;Clips are a way to record yourself on your screen. And the idea is that a lot of the meetings shouldn&#8217;t require us to be together in real time,&#8221; Butterfield said at a Dreamforce press event yesterday.</p>
<p>He added that these video clips provide more value because you can still get the point that would have been delivered in a full meeting without having to actually attend to get access to that information. What&#8217;s more, he says the videos create an audit trail of activity for archival purposes.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s easily shareable with people who weren&#8217;t in attendance, but [still] get the update. It&#8217;s available in the archive, so you can go back and find the answers to questions you have or trace back the roots of a decision,&#8221; he said. It&#8217;s worth noting that Slack first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/slack-introduces-new-features-to-ease-messaging-between-business-partners/">introduced this idea</a> last October, and announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/slack-wants-to-be-more-than-a-text-based-messaging-platform/">an early customer beta</a> last March, at which point they hadn&#8217;t even named it yet.</p>
<p>He admitted that this may require people to rethink how they work, and depending on the organization that may be harder in some places than others, but he believes that value proposition of freeing up employees to meet less and work more will eventually drive people and organizations to try it and then incorporate into the way that they work.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cy7uwLhFrq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/why-slack-and-salesforce-execs-think-theyre-better-together/">Why Slack and Salesforce execs think they&#8217;re better together</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Slack and Salesforce execs think they&#8217;re better together&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/why-slack-and-salesforce-execs-think-theyre-better-together/embed/#?secret=cy7uwLhFrq" data-secret="cy7uwLhFrq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Clips builds on the Huddles tool <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/slack-wants-to-be-more-than-a-text-based-messaging-platform/">released earlier this year</a>, which is a way via audio to have serendipitous water cooler kinds of conversations, again as a way to reduce the need for a full-fledged meeting when people can get together for a few minutes, resolve an issue and get back to work. Butterfield says that Huddles has had the fastest adoption of any new capability since he first launched Slack.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In March, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/slacks-new-video-and-voice-tools-are-nod-to-changing-face-of-work/">in a Clubhouse interview</a> with SignalFire investor Josh Constine (who is also a former TechCrunch reporter), Butterfield said that the company was also working on a Clubhouse tool for business. The company did not announce any similar tool this week though.</p>
<p>The company also announced 16 integrations with Salesforce that span the entire Salesforce platform. These include the sales-focussed deal room and the customer support incident response called swarms <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/slack-wants-to-be-more-than-a-text-based-messaging-platform/">announced earlier this month</a>, as well as new connections to other tools in the Salesforce family of product including Mulesoft and Tableau and industry-specific integrations for banking, life sciences and philanthropy.</p>
<p>In case you had forgotten, Salesforce bought Slack at the end of last year in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">a mega deal worth almost $28 billion</a>. Today, as part of the CRM giant, the company continues to build on the platform and product roadmap it had in place prior to the acquisition, while building in integrations all across the Salesforce platform.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/slack-releases-clips-video-tool-announces-16-salesforce-integrations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205298</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PayPal launches its &#8216;super app&#8217; combining payments, savings, bill pay, crypto, shopping and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/paypal-launches-its-super-app-combining-payments-savings-bill-pay-crypto-shopping-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/paypal-launches-its-super-app-combining-payments-savings-bill-pay-crypto-shopping-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 11:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PayPal has been talking about its &#8220;super app&#8221; plans for some time, having recently told investors its upcoming digital wallet and payments app had been given a go for launch. Today, the first version of that app is officially being introduced, offering a combination of financial tools including direct deposit, bill pay, a digital wallet, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">PayPal has been talking about its &#8220;super app&#8221; plans for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/paypal-details-its-digital-wallet-plans-for-2021-including-crypto-honey-integration-and-more/">some time</a>, having <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/paypals-new-super-app-is-ready-to-launch-will-also-include-messaging/">recently told investors</a> its upcoming digital wallet and payments app had been given a go for launch. Today, the first version of that app is officially being introduced, offering a combination of financial tools including direct deposit, bill pay, a digital wallet, peer-to-peer payments, shopping tools, crypto capabilities and more. The company is also announcing its partnership with Synchrony Bank for its new high-yield savings account, PayPal Savings.</p>
<p>These changes shift PayPal from being largely a payments utility that&#8217;s tacked on other offerings here and there, to being a more fully fleshed out finance app. Though PayPal itself doesn&#8217;t aim to be a &#8220;bank,&#8221; the new app offers a range of competitive features for those considering shifting their finances to neobanks, like Chime or Varo, as it will now also include support for paycheck Direct Deposits through PayPal&#8217;s bank partners, bill pay and more.</p>
<p>By enabling direct deposit, PayPal users can get paid up to two days earlier, which is one of the bigger draws among those considering digital banking apps over traditional banks.</p>
<p>In addition to shifting their paychecks to Payal, customers&#8217; PayPal funds can then be used for things that are a part of daily life, like paying their bills, saving or shopping, for example.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2eyOFZ6SSJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/paypals-new-super-app-is-ready-to-launch-will-also-include-messaging/">PayPal&#8217;s new &#8216;super app,&#8217; to include messaging, is ready to launch</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;PayPal&#8217;s new &#8216;super app,&#8217; to include messaging, is ready to launch&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/paypals-new-super-app-is-ready-to-launch-will-also-include-messaging/embed/#?secret=2eyOFZ6SSJ" data-secret="2eyOFZ6SSJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The enhanced bill pay feature lets customers track, view and pay bills from thousands of companies, including utilities, TV and internet, insurance, credit cards, phone and more, PayPal says. When bill pay first arrived earlier this year, it offered access to (single-digit) thousands of billers. Now, it will support around 17,000 billers. Customers can also discover billers through an improved, intelligent search feature, set reminders to be notified of upcoming bills and schedule automatic payments for bills they have to pay on a regular basis. The bills don&#8217;t have to only be paid from funds currently in the PayPal account, but can be paid through any eligible funding source that&#8217;s already linked to their PayPal account.</p>
<p>Via a Synchrony Bank partnership, PayPal Savings will offer a high-yield savings account with a 0.40% Annual Percentage Yield (APY), which is more than six times the national average of 0.06%, the company says. However, that&#8217;s lower than top rivals in the digital banking market offer, like Chime (<a href="https://www.chime.com/applyggv4-hys2/">0.50%</a>), Varo (starts at 0.20%, but users <a href="https://www.varomoney.com/savings-account/">can qualify</a> to get 3.00% APY), Marcus (<a href="https://www.marcus.com/us/en/savings/high-yield-savings">0.50%</a>), Ally (<a href="https://www.ally.com/bank/online-savings-account">0.50%</a>), ONE (<a href="https://www.onefinance.com/">1.00% or 3.00%</a> on Auto-Save transactions), and others. However, the rate may appeal to those who are switching from a traditional bank, where rates tend to be lower.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>PayPal believes its high-yield offering will be able to compete not based on the APY alone, but on the strength of its combined offerings.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2205131" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2205131" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2205131" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Savings-2.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Savings-2.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Savings-2.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Savings-2.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Savings-2.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Savings-2.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Savings-2.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2205131" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> PayPal</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We know that about half of customers in the United States don&#8217;t even have a savings account, much less one with a very competitive rate,&#8221; notes PayPal SVP of Consumer, Julian King. &#8220;So all in all, we think that by bringing together the full set of solutions on the platform, it&#8217;s a really competitive offering for an individual.&#8221;</p>
<p>The app has also been reorganized to accommodate the new features and those yet to come.</p>
<p>It now features a personalized dashboard offering an overview of the customer&#8217;s account. The wallet tab lets users manage Direct Deposits and connect funding sources like bank accounts and debit and credit cards alongside the ability to enroll in PayPal&#8217;s own debit, credit and cash cards. And a finance tab provides access to the high-yield savings and the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/paypal-says-all-users-in-u-s-can-now-buy-hold-and-sell-cryptocurrencies/">previously available crypto capabilities</a>, which allows users to buy, hold and sell Bitcoin, Ethereum, Bitcoin Cash and Litecoin.</p>
<p>The payments tab, meanwhile, will hold much of PayPal&#8217;s traditional feature set, including peer-to-peer payments, international remittances, charitable and nonprofit giving, plus now bill pay <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/paypals-new-super-app-is-ready-to-launch-will-also-include-messaging/">and a two-way messaging feature</a> that allows users to request payments or say thank you after receiving a payment &#8212; whether that&#8217;s between friends and family or between merchants and customers. This addition could bring PayPal more in line with PayPal-owned Venmo, which already offers the ability to add notes to payments and make comments.</p>
<p>Messaging also ties into PayPal&#8217;s new Shopping hub, which is where the company is finally putting to good use its 2019 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/20/paypal-to-acquire-shopping-and-rewards-platform-honey-for-4-billion/">$4 billion Honey acquisition</a>. Honey&#8217;s core features are now becoming a part of the PayPal mobile experience, including personalized deals and exclusive rewards.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2205130" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2205130" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2205130" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Shopping-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Shopping-1.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Shopping-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Shopping-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Shopping-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Shopping-1.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/New-PayPal-App-Shopping-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2205130" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> PayPal</p></div></p>
<p>PayPal users will be able to browse the discounts and offers inside the app, then shop and transact through the in-app browser. The deals can be saved to the wallet for future use, so they can be applied if shopping later in the app or online. Customers will also be able to join a loyalty program, where they can earn cashback and PayPal shopping credit on their purchases. The company says these personalized deals will improve over time.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ll use AI and [machine learning] capabilities to understand what kind of shopping deals are most interesting to customers and continue to develop that over time. They&#8217;ll just get smarter and smarter as the product gets more usage,&#8221; notes King. This will include using the data about the deals a customer likes, then bringing similar deals to them in the future.</p>
<p>Also new in the updated mobile app is the addition of PayPal&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/paypal-launches-a-new-crowdsourced-fundraising-platform-the-generosity-network/">crowdsourced fundraising platform, the Generosity Network</a>, first launched late last year. The network is PayPal&#8217;s answer to GoFundMe or Facebook Fundraisers, by offering tools that allow individuals to raise money for themselves, others in need, or organizations like small businesses or charities. The network is also now expanding to international markets with Germany and the U.K. to start, with more countries to come.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5KH5vL4OEw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/all-the-reasons-why-you-should-launch-a-credit-or-debit-card/">All the reasons why you should launch a credit or debit card</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;All the reasons why you should launch a credit or debit card&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/all-the-reasons-why-you-should-launch-a-credit-or-debit-card/embed/#?secret=5KH5vL4OEw" data-secret="5KH5vL4OEw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As PayPal has said, the new app is laying the groundwork for other new products in the quarters to come. The biggest initiative on its roadmap is a plan to enter the investment space, to rival other mobile investing apps, like Robinhood. When this arrives, it will support the ability to buy stocks, fractional stocks and ETFs, PayPal says.</p>
<p>It will also later add support for paying with QR codes, like Venmo, and tools for using PayPal to save while in stores.</p>
<p>The updated app is rolling out starting today in the U.S. as a staggered release that will complete in the weeks ahead. However, PayPal Savings won&#8217;t be available immediately &#8212; it will arrive in the U.S. in the &#8220;coming months,&#8221; as will some of the shopping and rewards tools.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/paypal-launches-its-super-app-combining-payments-savings-bill-pay-crypto-shopping-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205001</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EarthOptics helps farmers look deep into the soil for big data insights</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/earthoptics-helps-farmers-look-deep-into-the-soil-for-big-data-insights/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/earthoptics-helps-farmers-look-deep-into-the-soil-for-big-data-insights/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 11:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Farming sustainably and efficiently has gone from a big tractor problem to a big data problem over the last few decades, and startup EarthOptics believes the next frontier of precision agriculture lies deep in the soil. Using high-tech imaging techniques, the company claims to map the physical and chemical composition of fields faster, better, and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Farming sustainably and efficiently has gone from a big tractor problem to a big data problem over the last few decades, and startup <a href="https://earthoptics.com/">EarthOptics</a> believes the next frontier of precision agriculture lies deep in the soil. Using high-tech imaging techniques, the company claims to map the physical and chemical composition of fields faster, better, and more cheaply than traditional techniques, and has raised $10M to scale its solution.</p>
<p>&#8220;Most of the ways we monitor soil haven&#8217;t changed in 50 years,&#8221; EarthOptics founder and CEO Lars Dyrud told TechCrunch. &#8220;There&#8217;s been a tremendous amount of progress around precision data and using modern data methods in agriculture &#8211; but a lot of that has focused on the plants and in-season activity — there&#8217;s been comparatively little investment in soil.&#8221;</p>
<p>While you might think it&#8217;s obvious to look deeper into the stuff the plants are growing from, the simple fact is it&#8217;s difficult to do. Aerial and satellite imagery and IoT-infused sensors for things like moisture and nitrogen have made surface-level data for fields far richer, but past the first foot or so things get tricky.</p>
<p>Different parts of a field may have very different levels of physical characteristics like soil compaction, which can greatly affect crop outcomes, and chemical characteristics like dissolved nutrients and the microbiome. The best way to check these things, however, involves &#8220;putting a really expensive stick in the ground,&#8221; said Dyrud. The lab results from these samples affects the decision of which parts of a field need to be tilled and fertilized.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TechFieldDemo.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2205380" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TechFieldDemo.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TechFieldDemo.jpg 2016w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TechFieldDemo.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TechFieldDemo.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TechFieldDemo.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TechFieldDemo.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TechFieldDemo.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TechFieldDemo.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s still important, so farms get it done, but having soil sampled every few acres once or twice a year adds up fast when you have 10,000 acres to keep track of. So many just till and fertilize everything for lack of data, sinking a lot of money (Dyrud estimated the U.S. does about $1B in unnecessary tilling) into processes that might have no benefit and in fact might be harmful — it can release tons of carbon that was safely sequestered underground.</p>
<p>EarthOptics aims to make the data collection process better essentially by minimizing the &#8220;expensive stick&#8221; part. It has built an imaging suite that relies on ground penetrating radar and electromagnetic induction to produce a deep map of the soil that&#8217;s easier, cheaper, and more precise than extrapolating acres of data from a single sample.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/earthoptics-soilmap.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2205378" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/earthoptics-soilmap.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="549" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/earthoptics-soilmap.jpg 1626w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/earthoptics-soilmap.jpg?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/earthoptics-soilmap.jpg?resize=300,161 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/earthoptics-soilmap.jpg?resize=768,412 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/earthoptics-soilmap.jpg?resize=680,365 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/earthoptics-soilmap.jpg?resize=1536,824 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/earthoptics-soilmap.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>Machine learning is at the heart of the company&#8217;s pair of tools, GroundOwl and C-Mapper (C as in carbon). The team trained a model that reconciles the no-contact data with traditional samples taken at a much lower rate, learning to predict soil characteristics accurately at level of precision far beyond what has traditionally been possible. The imaging hardware can be mounted on ordinary tractors or trucks, and pulls in readings every few feet. Physical sampling still happens, but dozens rather than hundreds of times.</p>
<p>With today&#8217;s methods, you might divide your thousands of acres into 50-acre chunks: this one needs more nitrogen, this one needs tilling, this one needs this or that treatment. EarthOptics brings that down to the scale of meters, and the data can be fed directly into roboticized field machinery like a variable depth smart tiller.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TillMapperMap.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2205376" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TillMapperMap.png" alt="" width="1024" height="627" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TillMapperMap.png 2857w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TillMapperMap.png?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TillMapperMap.png?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TillMapperMap.png?resize=768,470 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TillMapperMap.png?resize=680,416 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TillMapperMap.png?resize=1536,940 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TillMapperMap.png?resize=2048,1254 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EarthOptics_TillMapperMap.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>Drive it along the fields and it goes only as deep as it needs to. Of course not everyone has a state of the art equipment, so the data can also be put out as a more ordinary map telling the driver in a more general sense when to till or perform other tasks.</p>
<p>If this approach takes off, it could mean major savings for farmers looking to tighten belts, or improved productivity per acre and dollar for those looking to scale up. And ultimately the goal is to enable automated and robotic farming as well. That transition is in an early stage as equipment and practices get hammered out, but one thing they will all need is good data.</p>
<p>Dyrud said he hopes to see the EarthOptics sensor suite on robotic tractors, tillers, and other farm equipment, but that their product is very much the data and the machine learning model they&#8217;ve trained up with tens of thousands of ground truth measurements.</p>
<p>The $10.3M A round was led by Leaps by Bayer (the conglomerate&#8217;s impact arm), with participation from S2G Ventures, FHB Ventures, Middleland Capital’s VTC Ventures and Route 66 Ventures. The plan for the money is to scale up the two existing products and get to work on the next one: moisture mapping, obviously a major consideration for any farm.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/earthoptics-helps-farmers-look-deep-into-the-soil-for-big-data-insights/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205185</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google’s updated iOS 15 apps support Focus Mode and iPad widgets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/googles-updated-ios-15-apps-support-focus-mode-and-ipad-widgets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/googles-updated-ios-15-apps-support-focus-mode-and-ipad-widgets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 11:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS 15]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With iOS 15 now available to download, developers both big and small have started updating their apps to take advantage of the operating system’s marquee features. Google went big on iOS 15 features.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Igor Bonifacic</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Igor Bonifacic is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/rivian-announces-membership-plan-with-complimentary-charging-and-lte-connectivity/">Rivian announces membership plan with complementary charging and LTE connectivity</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/microsoft-office-2021-will-be-available-on-october-5th/">Microsoft Office 2021 will be available on October 5th</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">With <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ios-15-ipados-15-watchos-8-iphone-ipad-watch-release-170601389.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="16" data-v9y="1"><ins>iOS 15 now available to download</ins></a>, developers both big and small have started updating their apps to take advantage of the operating system’s marquee features. One of those is Google, which <a href="https://blog.google/products/google-on-ios/google-apps-meet-ios-15/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1"><ins>detailed today</ins></a> the iOS 15-related enhancements you can expect from its apps.</p>
<p>The biggest change involves how Gmail, Meet, Tasks, Maps, Home and many of Google&#8217;s other applications will handle notifications. Should you have iOS 15’s new Focus Mode enabled, Google says prompts that don’t require your immediate attention will go to the Notifications Center where you can deal with them later. More timely reminders, such as those Google Maps sends you when you’re trying to navigate somewhere, won’t be silenced, and you’ll see them as they’re sent to you. Google says its goal was to make notifications “as relevant and timely as possible.” You&#8217;ll see these roll out to the company&#8217;s apps in the &#8220;coming weeks.&#8221;</p>
<div id="max-player<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>-injector" class="vmmi-si" data-maxi="0">
<div class="vdb_player">
<div><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Meanwhile, if you own an iPad you can look forward to new Google Photos and YouTube Music widgets that take advantage of the extra screen space Apple’s tablets offer. The company says it will roll these out in the coming weeks as well. Lastly, Google Drive and YouTube Music feature new Spotlight integrations. You can use the tool to search for specific files and to play a song directly in Google’s music streaming service. Those enhancements are available today — though you&#8217;ll probably wish more apps worked with Spotlight in this way.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-ios-15-enhacenments-224214541.html">Engadget</a>.</em></span></div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/googles-updated-ios-15-apps-support-focus-mode-and-ipad-widgets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205684</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blue Bear Capital raises $150M to fund climate, energy and infrastructure tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/blue-bear-capital-raises-150m-to-fund-climate-energy-and-infrastructure-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/blue-bear-capital-raises-150m-to-fund-climate-energy-and-infrastructure-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 11:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blue bear capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blue Bear Capital has raised a new $150 million fund that will be used to find and invest in startups developing technology aimed at speeding up the adoption and industrialization of renewable energy. This is the venture firm&#8217;s second fund, which it says is oversubscribed. Blue Bear has already backed nine new companies since 2020. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Blue Bear Capital has raised a new $150 million fund that will be used to find and invest in startups developing technology aimed at speeding up the adoption and industrialization of renewable energy.</p>
<p>This is the venture firm&#8217;s second fund, which it says is oversubscribed. Blue Bear has already backed nine new companies since 2020. The firm said the fresh cash will be used to fund <span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">digital technologies &#8220;making an outsized impact&#8221; in markets including wind, solar, the electric grid, EV infrastructure, transportation and energy-intensive industries.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">“Trillions of dollars will be spent to scale renewable energy, modernize infrastructure and secure sustainable supply chains,” Blue Bear partner Ernst Sack said in a statement. “Meanwhile, artificial intelligence is redefining how data is captured, decisions are mad and relationships are built all around us. Where these two forces converge — applying the power of AI-enabled technologies to the immense challenges of the energy transition — is where Blue Bear sees the greatest investment and impact opportunity of our lifetimes.”</span></p>
<p dir="ltr">Blue Bear has a two-fold investment strategy. The firm&#8217;s investors look for those that &#8220;nail a vertical,&#8221; which is code for startups that have developed Software as a Service solutions that help industries address <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">operational bottlenecks and handle niche use cases. Blue Bear also looks for startups that have developed software that can scale horizontally across many markets.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr">The portfolio companies in Blue Bear&#8217;s &#8220;nail a vertical&#8221; bucket include FreeWire Technologies, which developed a suite of mobile EV charging products and <span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Omnidian, a distributed solar asset management company. Horizontal scale companies that BlueBear has backed include </span>Urbint, which is focused on infrastructure safety and Demex, a climate and weather risk management company.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As with Blue Bear&#8217;s first fund, this one is aimed at helping early-stage companies scale — and not just by investing capital. The VC touts the expertise of its partners, who have decades of experience in sustainable investments and hands-on work in climate, policy, corporate venture, cloud computing and other related technologies.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">“As specialists we believe in a high conviction and relatively concentrated approach to portfolio construction,” said Blue Bear partner Vaughn Blake in a statement, adding that the firm select companies with long-term partnership in mind. Blake also said the firm avoids the high-volume approach to venture, where a handful of companies are expected to make up a fund&#8217;s returns while the bulk are left to fall away.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Investors in Blue Bear&#8217;s fund include AIMS Imprint of </span><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Goldman Sachs Asset Management, Rockefeller Brothers Fund and the McKnight Foundation, as well as leadership from other private equity firms and energy companies. Advisory Board members include First Reserve President Alex Krueger, former NASA astronaut Tim Kopra, and former BP Chairman and CEO Lord John Browne.  </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/blue-bear-capital-raises-150m-to-fund-climate-energy-and-infrastructure-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205577</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alan acquires Jour and launches mental health service Alan Mind</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/alan-acquires-jour-and-launches-mental-health-service-alan-mind/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/alan-acquires-jour-and-launches-mental-health-service-alan-mind/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 10:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alan Mind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205662</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Alan is better known for its health insurance products — they now insure 200,000 people. But it has been slowly building a superapp for your health and expanding with new services. Today, the company announced its first acquisition ever with the acquisition of Jour for $20 million. This is going to be the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://alan.com">Alan</a> is better known for its health insurance products — they now insure 200,000 people. But it has been slowly building a superapp for your health and expanding with new services. Today, the company announced its first acquisition ever with the acquisition of <a href="https://jour.com">Jour</a> for $20 million. This is going to be the foundation for a new service called <a href="https://mind.alan.com">Alan Mind</a>.</p>
<p>“More than 13 million people in France are facing a mental health issue. If you look at people under 35, it’s 3 out of 4 people — so it’s basically everybody,” co-founder an CEO Jean-Charles Samuelian-Werve said in a press conference earlier today.</p>
<p>And if you look at the past 18 months, the COVID-19 pandemic has had a tremendous impact on mental health. Depressive moods and anxiety issues have basically doubled. 66% of people are dealing with sleep disorders.</p>
<p>“The question we asked ourselves is: How did we get there?” Samuelian-Werve said. “We see two important topics. First, there has been a chronic lack of prevention that is quite obvious. Mental health has been neglected by public health policies.”</p>
<p>“The second pillar that led us where we are is poor care. There are disparities between regions that are very high. In Paris, it can take up to 8 months in some hospitals if you want to see a therapist. In the Rhône-Alpes area, it takes 67 days on average to book an appointment,” he added.</p>
<p>And even if you can find the right person, you’ll often end up spending a lot of money. France’s national healthcare system doesn’t cover mental health that well.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With Alan Mind, the startup wants to work on these two areas of improvement. It’s a B2B service, so the company is selling access to Alan Mind to its B2B clients, who can then recommend Alan Mind to their employees.</p>
<p>“Do companies have a role to play in mental health? We believe that they do. Companies are responsible for protecting their employees’ health,” Samuelian-Werve said. In particular, they reached that conclusion when they realized that lockdowns have affected work-life balance. It&#8217;s hard to say when your work day ends and your personal time starts.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2205665" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2205665" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alan-Mind.png" alt="" width="1024" height="495" class="size-full wp-image-2205665" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alan-Mind.png 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alan-Mind.png?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alan-Mind.png?resize=300,145 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alan-Mind.png?resize=768,371 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alan-Mind.png?resize=680,329 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alan-Mind.png?resize=1536,743 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alan-Mind.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2205665" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Alan</p></div></p>
<p>By acquiring Jour, Alan is betting on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_behavioral_therapy">cognitive behavioral therapy</a>. Employees can install an app and start answering questions to evaluate their current state of mind. They can find content in the app, put words on their feelings and work on themselves. There are videos, a dashboard feature, breathing exercises, etc.</p>
<p>If employees feel like that’s not enough, they can start an individual therapy with a health professional. Alan Mind lets you book a telehealth appointment. The company has hired a handful of psychologists so that you can get an appointment in just a few days.</p>
<p>Of course, companies never know that someone in the team has used Alan Mind. But HR teams receive an anonymized report every month. It’s not about spying on employees, but more about identifying common issues and providing ideas for prevention workshops.</p>
<p>Alan Mind is just getting started as the company only has five clients for this service — BioSerenity, Brut, Joone, Opal and Talk. Companies pay €5 per month per employee if they’re already Alan customers, or a bit more if they just want Alan Mind.</p>
<p>As for Jour, the B2C app will remain available in the App Store. The startup has attracted 2 million downloads before its acquisition. It has a slightly different positioning and it’s going to be useful to identify areas of improvement for Alan Mind.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2205663" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2205663" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jour.png" alt="" width="1024" height="656" class="size-full wp-image-2205663" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jour.png 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jour.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jour.png?resize=300,192 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jour.png?resize=768,492 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jour.png?resize=680,435 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jour.png?resize=1536,983 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Jour.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2205663" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshots of Jour. Image Credits: Alan</p></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KjzhCBBGBG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/alan-raises-220-million-for-its-health-insurance-and-healthcare-super-app/">Alan raises $220 million for its health insurance and healthcare superapp</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Alan raises $220 million for its health insurance and healthcare superapp&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/alan-raises-220-million-for-its-health-insurance-and-healthcare-super-app/embed/#?secret=KjzhCBBGBG" data-secret="KjzhCBBGBG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/alan-acquires-jour-and-launches-mental-health-service-alan-mind/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205662</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Post-pandemic shifts means Patch will take co-working to UK small towns and suburbs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/post-pandemic-shifts-means-patch-will-take-co-working-to-uk-small-towns-and-suburbs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/post-pandemic-shifts-means-patch-will-take-co-working-to-uk-small-towns-and-suburbs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 10:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cofounder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commuting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coworking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eka Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grabyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kingston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Localglobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matt clifford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robin klein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Simon Murdoch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeWork]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It would be fair to say the pandemic has had enormous effects on the world of work, but it has come at a time when other factors were already ongoing. The decline of main-street shopping due to e-commerce has only been hastened. The shift to remote working has sky-rocketed. And people no longer want to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It would be fair to say the pandemic has had enormous effects on the world of work,  but it has come at a time when other factors were already ongoing. The decline of main-street shopping due to e-commerce has only been hastened. The shift to remote working has sky-rocketed. And people no longer want to commute 8am-6pm anymore. But we’ve also found that working from home isn’t all its cracked up to be. Plus, they don&#8217;t see the point of commuting into a big city, only to have to co-work in something like a WeWork, when they could just as easily have gone to something local. The problem is, there is rarely a local co-working space, especially in the suburbs or smaller towns.</p>
<p>If, instead, you could bring work nearer to home (rather than working <em>from</em> home) then, the theory goes, you’d get a more balanced lifestyle, but also get that separation between work and home so many people, especially families, still desire.</p>
<p>Now, a new UK startup has come top with a ‘decentralized workspace’ idea which it plans to roll out across the UK.</p>
<p><a href="http://patch.work">Patch</a> will take empty local high street shops and turn them into “collaborative cultural spaces” with its ‘Work Near Home’ proposition aimed at traditional commuters. There are an estimated 6 million knowledge work commuters in the UK, and Patch will run on monthly subscriptions from these kinds of members.</p>
<p>It’s now raised a $1.1M Seed funding round from a number of leading UK angel investors including Robin Klein (cofounder of LocalGlobe), Matt Clifford (Cofounder of Entrepreneur First), alongside Charlie Songhurst, Simon Murdoch (Episode 1), Wendy Becker (former CEO Jack Wills and NED at Great Portland Estates), Camilla Dolan (founding partner of sustainable investor Eka Ventures), Zoe Jervier (talent Director for US investment firm Sequoia), and Will Neale (founder of Grabyo and early-stage investor).</p>
<p>Patch says its ‘Work Near Home’ idea is geared to the Post-Covid ‘hybrid working’ movement and it plans to create public venues, “with a focus of entrepreneurship, technology, and cultural programming.”</p>
<p>Each Patch location will offer a range of private offices, co-working studios, “accessible low-cost options” and free scholarship places.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Patch’s first site will open in Chelmsford, Essex in early November, and the startup says several more sites are planned for 2022. It says it has received requests from people in Chester, St Albans, Wycombe, Shrewsbury, Yeovil, Bury, and Kingston upon Thames.</p>
<p>Patch’s founder <a href="https://twitter.com/FreddieFforde">Freddie Fforde</a> said: “Where we work and where we live have traditionally be seen as distinct environments. This has led to the hollowing out of many high streets during the working week, and equally redundant office districts. We think that technology fundamentally changes this, allowing people to work near home and creating a new mixed environment of professional, civic, and cultural exchange.”</p>
<p>Fforde is a former Entrepreneur First founder and employee who has held various roles in early-stage tech companies in London and San Francisco. The head of product will be <a href="https://twitter.com/palomastrelitz?lang=en">Paloma Strelitz</a>, formerly cofounder of Assemble, a design studio that won the 2015 Turner Prize.</p>
<p>Commenting, Matt Clifford, Entrepreneur First and Code First Girls, said: “Technology has always changed the way we organize and work together. Patch will unlock opportunities for talented people based on who they are, unconstrained by where they live. We want to be a country where high-skilled jobs are available everywhere and Patch is a key part of that puzzle.”</p>
<p>Targeting towns and smaller cities, in residential areas, not the major city centres, Patch says it will look for under-utilised landmark buildings in the center of towns. In Chelmsford, their first space will be a Victorian brewery, for instance.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2205666" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2205666" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Grays-Yard.jpg" alt="Grays Yard" width="1024" height="730" class="size-full wp-image-2205666" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Grays-Yard.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Grays-Yard.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Grays-Yard.jpg?resize=300,214 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Grays-Yard.jpg?resize=768,548 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Grays-Yard.jpg?resize=680,485 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Grays-Yard.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2205666" class="wp-caption-text">Grays Yard</p></div></p>
<p>Chelmsford Councillor Simon Goldman, Deputy Cabinet Member for Economic Development and Small Business and representative for the BID board, said: “The introduction of a new co-working space in Gray’s Yard is a really positive scheme for the city. Providing local options for residents to work from will help them to have less of a commute which will hopefully allow a better work/life balance. Working closer to home brings many benefits for both individuals and their families, but also for the environment and the local economy.”</p>
<p>Patch says it will also operate a model of ‘giving back’, with 20% of peak event space hours donated to local and national providers of community services “that support the common good”. Early national partners include tech skills providers Code First Girls, and with Coder Dojo, a Raspberry Pi Foundation initiative.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/post-pandemic-shifts-means-patch-will-take-co-working-to-uk-small-towns-and-suburbs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205658</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK&#8217;s MarketFinance scores $383M to fuel its online loans platform for SMBs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/uks-marketfinance-secures-383m-to-fuel-its-online-loans-platform-for-smbs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/uks-marketfinance-secures-383m-to-fuel-its-online-loans-platform-for-smbs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 09:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barclays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coursera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital ocean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[embedded finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invoice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MarketInvoice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marqeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short-term loans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205649</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Small and medium businesses regularly face cashflow problems. But if that&#8217;s an already-inconvenient predicament, it has been exacerbated to the breaking point for too many during the Covid-19 pandemic. Now, a UK startup called MarketFinance &#8212; which has built a loans platform to help SMBs stay afloat through those leaner times &#8212; is announcing a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Small and medium businesses regularly face cashflow problems. But if that&#8217;s an already-inconvenient predicament, it has been exacerbated to the breaking point for too many during the Covid-19 pandemic. Now, a UK startup called <a href="https://marketfinance.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MarketFinance</a> &#8212; which has built a loans platform to help SMBs stay afloat through those leaner times &#8212; is announcing a big funding infusion of £280 million ($383 million) as it gears up for a new wave of lending requests.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s a good time to lend, at the start of the economic cycle,&#8221; CEO and founder Anil Stocker said in an interview.</p>
<p>The funding is coming mostly in the form of debt &#8212; money loaned to MarketFinance to in turn loan out to its customers as an approved partner of the UK government&#8217;s <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/recovery-loan-scheme" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Recovery Loan Scheme</a>; and £10 million ($14 million) of it is equity that MarketInvoice will be using to continue enhancing its platform.</p>
<p>Italian bank Intesa Sanpaolo S.p.A. and an unnamed &#8220;global investment firm&#8221; are providing the debt, while the equity portion is being led by Black River Ventures (which has also backed Marqeta, Upgrade, Coursera and Digital Ocean) with participation from existing backer, Barclays Bank PLC. Barclays is a strategic investor: MarketFinance powers the bank&#8217;s online SMB loans service. Other investors in the startup include Northzone.</p>
<p>We understand that the company&#8217;s valuation is somewhere in the region of under $500 million, but more than $250 million, although officially it is not disclosing any numbers.</p>
<p>Stocker said that MarketFinance has been profitable since 2018, one reason why it&#8217;s didn&#8217;t give up much equity in this current tranche of funding.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are building a sustainable business, and the equity we did raise was to unlock better debt at better prices,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It can help to post more equity on the balance sheet.&#8221; He said the money will be &#8220;going into our reserves&#8221; and used for new product development, marketing and to continue building out its API connectivity.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That last development is important: it taps into the big wave of &#8220;embedded finance&#8221; plays we are seeing today, where third parties offer, on their own platforms, loans to customers &#8212; with the loan product powered by MarketFinance, similar to what Barclays does currently. The range of companies tapping into this is potentially as vast as the internet itself. The promise of embedded finance is that any online brand that already does business with SMEs could potentially offer those SMEs loans to&#8230; do more business together.</p>
<p>MarketFinance began life several years ago as MarketInvoice, with its basic business model focused on providing short-term loans to a given SMB against the value of its unpaid invoices &#8212; a practice typically described as <a href="https://www.british-business-bank.co.uk/finance-hub/invoice-finance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">invoice finance</a>. The idea at the time was to solve the most immediate cashflow issue faced by SMBs by leveraging the thing (unpaid invoices, which typically would eventually get paid, just not immediately) that caused the cashflow issue in the first place.</p>
<p>A lot of the financing that SMBs get against invoices, though, is mainly in the realm of working capital, helping companies make payroll and pay their own monthly bills. But Stocker said that over time, the startup could see a larger opportunity in providing financing that was of bigger sums and covered more ambitious business expansion goals. That was two years ago, so after its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/20/invoice-finance-platform-marketinvoice-raises-33-5m-from-barclays-santander/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last equity round</a> MarketInvoice rebranded accordingly to MarketFinance. (It still very much offers the invoice-based product.)</p>
<p>The timing turned out to be fortuitous, even if the reason definitely has not been lucky: Covid-19 came along and completely overturned how much of the world works. SMEs have been at the thin edge of that wedge not least because of those cashflow issues and the fact that they simply are less geared to diversification and pivoting due to shifting market forces because of their size.</p>
<p>This presented a big opportunity for MarketInvoice, it turned out.</p>
<p>Stocker said that the early part of the Covid-19 pandemic saw the bulk of loans being taken out to manage business interruptions due to Covid-19. Interruptions could mean business closures, or they could mean simply customers no longer coming as they did before, and so on. &#8220;The big theme was frictionless access to funding,&#8221; he said, using technology to better and more quickly assess applications digitally with &#8220;no meetings with bank managers&#8221; and reducing the response time to days from the typical 4-6 weeks that SMBs would have traditionally expected.</p>
<p class="p2">If last year was more about &#8220;panicking, shoring up or pivoting,&#8221; in Stocker&#8217;s words, &#8220;now what we’re seeing are a bunch of them struggling with supply chain issues, Brexit exacerbations and labor shortages. It’s really hard for them to manage all that.&#8221;</p>
<p>He said that the number of loan applications has been through the roof, so no shortage of demand. He estimates that monthly loan requests have been as high as $500 million, a huge sum for one small startup in the UK. It&#8217;s selective in what it lends: &#8220;We choose to support those we thought will return the money,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/uks-marketfinance-secures-383m-to-fuel-its-online-loans-platform-for-smbs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205649</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
