<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 18:41:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>With funding from top investors, Gameto is aiming to delay &#8212; even eradicate &#8212; menopause</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/with-funding-from-top-investors-gameto-is-aiming-to-delay-even-eradicate-menopause/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/with-funding-from-top-investors-gameto-is-aiming-to-delay-even-eradicate-menopause/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 18:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brian armstrong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Future Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack abraham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lux capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maryanna Saenko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menopause]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With every year, more scientists and academics are very specifically trying to lengthen the lifespan of humans and to ensure that those extra years are worth living. Some of these teams are focused on detecting cancer earlier as a means of extending longevity; some are working to improve people&#8217;s metabolism. A small but growing group [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With every year, more scientists and academics are very specifically trying to lengthen the lifespan of humans and to ensure that those extra years are worth living. Some of these teams are focused on detecting cancer earlier as a means of extending longevity; some are working to improve people&#8217;s metabolism.</p>
<p>A small but growing group is also beginning to focus on menopause, which impacts half the population as whose onset is associated with a long list of health conditions, from higher blood pressure, “bad&#8221; cholesterol, and triglycerides, which a form of fat in the blood, to, even more frighteningly, a greater risk of breast cancer, heart disease and osteoporosis.</p>
<p>The newest outfit focused on the cause is <a href="https://gametogen.com/">Gameto</a>, which says it wants to solve the problem of &#8220;accelerated&#8221; ovarian aging to change the trajectory of women&#8217;s health and equality.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255421" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>As explained by the company&#8217;s cofounder and CEO, Dina Radenkovic, who studied medicine at University College London and has spent most of her career in computational medicine, ovaries age up to five times faster than any organ in the sense that they stop working far earlier than, say, the liver, or brain, or even skin. While women are born with a certain number of ovocytes &#8212; an immature female sex cell that later gives rise to fully mature ovum or egg cell &#8212; they eventually run out of these, at which point their ovaries stop functioning as an organ and stop producing the hormones that control women&#8217;s physiology.</p>
<p>Gameto wants to help delay that process, or even push it off forever if a woman chooses, by developing a platform for ovarian therapeutics that will initially be used to improve the process of assisted fertility but hopefully, eventually, be used, too, to identify cell therapies that can prevent what Radenkovic describes as the &#8220;medical burden&#8221; of menopause. Asked for more details, Radenkovic is loath to dive into specifics but she says that the young company has already begun testing whether ovarian supporting cells could help mature eggs and reduce the number of IVF cycles that many women who are hoping to become pregnant currently endure.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have strong preclinical evidence to to believe in our platform,&#8221; she adds of the company, which is chaired by serial entrepreneur Martin Varsavsky, whose last company, <a href="https://www.preludefertility.com/">Prelude Fertility</a>, has  create a nationwide network of fertility centers across the U.S.</p>
<p>Some notable investors are willing to bet on the company, too. Gameto just raised $20 million in funding led by Future Ventures, whose cofounder, Maryanna Saenko, says the firm is &#8220;deeply excited about the prospect of a better standard of care for women undergoing menopause. The suffering caused by menopause is not a biological imperative, and the many complications that come along with menopause, particularly early-onset menopause, can be entirely avoided&#8221; along with today&#8217;s hormone replacement therapies, which she describes as &#8220;blunt hammers, lacking personalization.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Other participants include Bold Capital Partners, Lux Capital, Plum Alley, TA Ventures, Overwater Ventures, Arch Venture Partners cofounder Robert Nelsen and 23andMe CEO Anne Wojcicki.</p>
<p>Gameto had previously raised $3 million in seed funding last year, including from Atomic founder Jack Abraham, SALT Fund, FJ Labs, Coatue Management founder Dan Rose and Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong.</p>
<p>Certainly, the market opportunity is huge and the thesis &#8212; given that people are living longer &#8212; makes a lot of sense. Indeed, look for other startups to begin focusing more squarely on delaying menopause.</p>
<p>Already, Gameto has some competition, including from Celmatix, a 12-year-old company that&#8217;s <a href="https://fortune.com/2021/04/19/celmatix-delay-menopause-womens-ovarian-health">creating a drug program</a> to slow the depletion of a woman’s ovarian reserve and that similarly hopes to separate a woman’s endocrine function from reproduction. In the past, <a href="https://fortune.com/2021/04/19/celmatix-delay-menopause-womens-ovarian-health">according to Fortune</a>, the company has received a grant Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation to work on nonhormonal contraceptives and early last year, it announced a separate a partnership with pharmaceutical giant Bayer and the drug development company Evotec.</p>
<p>Researchers have meanwhile been looking into the issue of treating menopause as a treatable disease for at least several years. You can check an earlier paper from 2019 <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6366956/">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/with-funding-from-top-investors-gameto-is-aiming-to-delay-even-eradicate-menopause/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255421</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Y Combinator will now invest $500,000 in accelerator companies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/y-combinator-will-now-invest-500000-in-accelerator-companies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/y-combinator-will-now-invest-500000-in-accelerator-companies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 18:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Startup accelerator Y Combinator announced this morning that it has updated its terms, providing participating companies with more total cash. The group will now invest $500,000 in batch startups. The money comes in two different forms. The first is the well-known Y Combinator equity deal, worth $125,000 for 7% of accelerated startups. The group will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Startup accelerator Y Combinator <a href="https://blog.ycombinator.com/ycs-standard-deal/">announced</a> this morning that it has updated its terms, providing participating companies with more total cash. The group will now invest $500,000 in batch startups.</p>
<p>The money comes in two different forms. The first is the well-known Y Combinator equity deal, worth $125,000 for 7% of accelerated startups. The group will now also offer $375,000 in the form of an uncapped SAFE note &#8212; a simple agreement for future equity &#8212; with a &#8220;most favored nation&#8221; clause.</p>
<p>Uncapped means that there is no defined maximum price at which the $375,000 SAFE will convert to shares, while the &#8220;most favored nation&#8221; language ensures that Y Combinator gets as good a deal as anyone else in a later conversion.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255659" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>That Y Combinator is now offering more capital to startups is not surprising; indeed, that it took this long for the group to update its terms is the bigger surprise. Still, a half-million dollars is much more in keeping with where the pre-seed and seed-stage investing markets have headed in recent years, namely to larger dollar amounts at higher prices.</p>
<p>The updated terms do not mean that the accelerator itself will have any less preserved upside in portfolio companies. In fact, you could argue that Y Combinator&#8217;s updated terms are defensive in that it is offering more capital in addition, but not in place of, its traditional equity stake in companies that pass through its doors. So the accelerator may be better able to attract the best early-stage startups with larger checks, even as it puts its initial equity investment to work at a price point that has proven historically lucrative.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BqvjmAzRn6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/our-favorite-startups-from-ycs-summer-21-demo-day-part-1/">Our favorite startups from YC’s Summer 21 Demo Day, Part 1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Our favorite startups from YC’s Summer 21 Demo Day, Part 1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/our-favorite-startups-from-ycs-summer-21-demo-day-part-1/embed/#?secret=BqvjmAzRn6" data-secret="BqvjmAzRn6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As an institution, Y Combinator has been updating itself as the startup market has evolved. From a focus on in-person work, YC <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/20/y-combinator-officially-shifts-its-next-accelerator-class-to-fully-remote-format/">went remote during the pandemic</a>. The result of that switch was more participating startups from other countries and markets, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/this-yc-summer-batch-features-the-largest-group-of-african-startups-yet/">by TechCrunch reckoning</a>. The group has also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/06/citing-concern-over-covid-19-y-combinator-moves-demo-day-online/">moved to remote demo days</a>, something that we&#8217;ve appreciated here at TechCrunch as we no longer have to drive down from San Francisco to a large room with too few chairs.</p>
<p>It will be interesting to see how rival accelerators react, if at all, to Y Combinator&#8217;s updated terms set.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/y-combinator-will-now-invest-500000-in-accelerator-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255659</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Career Karma lands $40M to evolve into an edtech employee benefit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/career-karma-lands-40-million-to-evolve-into-a-edtech-employee-benefit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/career-karma-lands-40-million-to-evolve-into-a-edtech-employee-benefit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 18:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Karma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Tier Capital Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Career Karma raised its first millions off of a pitch that resonates with anyone who has ever googled coding bootcamps: a navigation tool for aspiring students and working professionals. Instead of creating its own curriculum, Career Karma helps students find the best programs for their price point and career goals. The startup, founded in 2018 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Career Karma <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/career-karma-series-a/">raised its first millions off of a pitch</a> that resonates with anyone who has ever googled coding bootcamps: a navigation tool for aspiring students and working professionals. Instead of creating its own curriculum, Career Karma helps students find the best programs for their price point and career goals.</p>
<p>The startup, founded in 2018 by Ruben Harris, Artur Meyster and Timur Meyster, is now growing its ambition to serve more than the bogged down bootcamp student: over the past few months, Career Karma has seeded partnerships with employers, making it the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/employers-are-consumer-edtechs-next-beta-test">latest consumer-focused edtech startup</a> to go the employer benefit route as it scales. Now, Harris describes, his vision is that Career Karma will match employees and contractors to job training programs in the marketplace it has built over the past few years.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="18K3Pi9Lv4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/employers-are-consumer-edtechs-next-beta-test/">Employers are consumer edtech&#8217;s next beta test</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255653" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Employers are consumer edtech&#8217;s next beta test&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/employers-are-consumer-edtechs-next-beta-test/embed/#?secret=18K3Pi9Lv4" data-secret="18K3Pi9Lv4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>To execute on this stage of the business, Career Karma announced today that it has raised a $40 million Series B at an undisclosed valuation. The round was led by Top Tier Capital Partners, alongside GV (Google Ventures), Bronze Venture Fund, Stardust, and Trousdale Ventures, and Alumni Ventures Group. Existing investors also participated in the round, including Softbank, Emerson Collective, Kapor Capital, Backstage, 4S Bay Partners, Y Combinator.</p>
<p>“Stage one was become the number one career advice service for the internet, stage two was become the world’s largest community of career transitioners, and now phase three is to become the world’s largest staffing firm,” said Harris in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Similar to Handshake and Guild Education, both valued as multi-billion dollar businesses, Career Karma is playing the middleman. As an employee benefit, Career Karma will be able to get students employer-paid tuition, and then re-skill and up-skill them into ideally more advanced job skills.</p>
<p>Employers will serve as a zero-cost acquisition channel that helps Career Karma work with lots of employees at scale &#8211; a business its been in since launch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“On the user side, we&#8217;re able to identify the job training programs that they&#8217;re interested in, the current skills that they have, and the job that they want,” Harris said. “Eventually we’re going to have a really powerful database internally.”</p>
<p>Career Karma’s strategy shift means its business model will need a refresh as well. Previously, Career Karma charged a fee to bootcamps when it successfully placed a student in one of their programs. The fee was usually 10% of a placed-student’s tuition, which could range from $10,000 to $50,000, Harris says. While this strategy could appear to align incentives &#8211; Career Karma only makes money when it successfully places a student inside a boot camp- it could also pressure the platform to focus more on pace of placement than personalization of placement. The enterprise business won&#8217;t necessarily bring the same sorts of pressures, since it will be built to serve career services, not just program matching.</p>
<p>Now, with an enterprise side, Harris said the company is hiring folks to help figure out the best new pricing strategy. Beyond the aforementioned companies, there’s precedent in this sort of pivot: last year, Codecademy <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/codecademy-series-d/)">raised the same sum in a Series D round to sell its services to the enterprise</a>. A few weeks ago, the same company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/23/codecademy-sends-it-with-skillsoft-in-a-525m-deal/">sold to Skillsoft in a $525 million deal.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/career-karma-lands-40-million-to-evolve-into-a-edtech-employee-benefit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255653</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Panasonic says hackers accessed personal data of job candidates</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/panasonic-breach-data-stolen/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/panasonic-breach-data-stolen/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 17:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panasonic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Japanese tech giant Panasonic has confirmed that hackers accessed personal information belonging to job candidates and interns during a November cyberattack. At the time of the data breach, which the company first confirmed on November 26, the company was unable to say whether hackers had accessed any sensitive information. However, in an update published on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Japanese tech giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/panasonic/">Panasonic</a> has confirmed that hackers accessed personal information belonging to job candidates and interns during a November cyberattack.</p>
<p>At the time of the data breach, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/29/panasonic-data-breach/">which the company first confirmed on November 26</a>, the company was unable to say whether hackers had accessed any sensitive information. However, in <a href="https://news.panasonic.com/global/press/data/2022/01/en220107-3/en220107-3-1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an update published on January 7</a>, Panasonic said some personal information relating to candidates who applied for employment or participated in internships at certain divisions of the company was accessed during the incident. Panasonic said it was notifying those affected.</p>
<p>When reached, Panasonic spokesperson Dannea DeLisser declined to say how many people were impacted and the nature of the information accessed.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255618" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Panasonic’s update also confirmed that the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/data-breach/">data breach</a> — which began June 22 and ended on November 3, before being detected on November 11 — saw the as-yet-unnamed hackers obtain files containing unspecified “business-related information” provided by business partners, as well as information about business partner personnel.</p>
<p>The findings of the company&#8217;s internal investigation, which was carried out with the help of an external security advisor, confirmed that a third party illegally accessed a file server in Japan via the server of an overseas subsidiary. Panasonic says that after detecting the unauthorized access, it “immediately implemented additional security countermeasures,” including strengthening access controls from overseas locations, resetting relevant passwords and strengthening server access monitoring.</p>
<p>Panasonic said it was strengthening its security measures to prevent a repeat attack.</p>
<p>The November data breach that hit Panasonic came just months after the company&#8217;s Indian subsidiary fell victim to a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ransomware/">ransomware</a> attack that saw hackers leak 4 gigabytes of data, including financial information and email addresses.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Up3Wtdx7is"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/29/panasonic-data-breach/">Panasonic confirms data breach after hackers access internal network</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Panasonic confirms data breach after hackers access internal network&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/29/panasonic-data-breach/embed/#?secret=Up3Wtdx7is" data-secret="Up3Wtdx7is" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/panasonic-breach-data-stolen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255618</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is cell-cultured meat ready for prime time?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/is-cell-cultured-meat-ready-for-prime-time/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/is-cell-cultured-meat-ready-for-prime-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barclays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bioinformatics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cellular agriculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cultured meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Just]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Food Climate and Sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finistere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food production]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Future Meat Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hanwha Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[josh tetrick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leonardo DiCaprio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[McKinsey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memphis meats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qatar Investment Authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Siddhi Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sofinnova Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sound ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stem cells]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechU Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temasek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Threshold Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[True Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tyson Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Upside Foods]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2253102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cell-cultured meat is a hot topic, yet the process for producing meat in this manner remains slow and costly.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Meat has been part of the human diet since before we found fire, but it&#8217;s becoming increasingly apparent that the production of meat at scale is more of a detriment to the environment and the world than a benefit.</p>
<p>Across cultures and geographies, animals have been such a vital part of the food chain that it&#8217;s hard to imagine a world where animals are not put to the knife to produce protein.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no stopping innovation, however, and alternative sources of protein are increasingly becoming a choice people would rather make.</p>
<p>Cell-cultured meat is one such source. Also known as cultivated or lab-grown meat, this process uses cells from animals to make meat without slaughter. While the nascent sector is a hot topic for the benefits it promises, the process remains slow and costly.</p>
<p>Investments in this sector are heating up, though. If 2021 was anything to go by, there is an abundance of both companies and investors hungry for ways to scale and speed up the process &#8212; and do it profitably.</p>
<p>However, it&#8217;s not yet clear when meat grown in labs will reach the kind of scale required to see it at your local grocery store.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			This is not a revolution, it is a transformation, and it is going to take time.							<cite>Friederike Grosse-Holz</cite>
					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<h2>High steaks</h2>
<p>Cell-cultured meat owes its growing popularity, at least in part, to some of the macro challenges the world faces with food production. Overcultivation, human-made climate change and diminishing sources of water are all contributing to a future where food insecurity will be a gigantic problem.</p>
<p>The outlook is bleak: The United Nations estimates <a href="https://www.un.org/press/en/2009/gaef3242.doc.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">food production will need to double</a> to feed the <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2019/6/18/un-world-population-expected-to-rise-to-9-7-billion-in-2050" target="_blank" rel="noopener">nearly 10 billion people expected to populate the planet by 2050</a>. As for protein, people around the world <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/274522/global-per-capita-consumption-of-meat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">consumed about 324 million metric tons of meat</a> in 2020, and that number is set to <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/04/26/1023636/sustainable-meat-livestock-production-climate-change/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rise even further</a>.</p>
<p>Changing how we cultivate and produce food is key to solving this problem, and we already have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1-origin/">systems like vertical farming to address the problem of overcultivation</a>, as well as protein sources other than meat. Currently, alternative protein <a href="https://web-assets.bcg.com/a0/28/4295860343c6a2a5b9f4e3436114/bcg-food-for-thought-the-protein-transformation-mar-2021.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">makes up just about 2%</a> of the animal protein market, but it is expected to increase more than 7x by 2025.</p>
<p>“We are trying to meet the <a href="https://unfccc.int/process-and-meetings/the-paris-agreement/the-paris-agreement" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paris Agreement</a>, but we can’t meet that without addressing the food system and the way we produce meat, eggs and dairy,” said Sharyn Murray, senior investor engagement specialist at Good Food Institute, a nonprofit advocating for reimagined meat production. “The conversion ratio for calories in versus calories out is seven to eight calories for a chicken for one calorie out, while plant-based is one calorie in and one out.”</p>
<p>Cultivated meat is just one of the approaches to meeting future demand for protein alongside plant-based and fermentation techniques. Murray and others I spoke to referred to the movement as “a massive transformation of the food system that will take time.” Meaning the shift will not happen overnight, Murray said.</p>
<p>There is also only one company with cell-cultured meat products available in the market currently: Eat Just, whose subsidiary GOOD Meat has received regulatory approval to produce and sell its cell-cultured meat in Singapore. Eat Just also recently received approval to sell chicken breasts made with cell cultures.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2255518" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255518" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2255518" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1230258332.jpg" alt="A nugget made from lab-grown chicken meat is seen during a media presentation in Singapore, the first country to allow the sale of meat created without slaughtering any animals, on December 22, 2020. (Photo by Nicholas YEO / AFP) (Photo by NICHOLAS YEO/AFP via Getty Images)" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1230258332.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1230258332.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1230258332.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1230258332.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1230258332.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1230258332.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255518" class="wp-caption-text">A nugget made from lab-grown chicken meat is seen during a December media presentation in Singapore, the first country to allow the sale of meat created without slaughtering any animals. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nicholas YEO / AFP / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Josh Tetrick, co-founder and CEO of Eat Just, said the movement is here even if people are not buying a lot of lab-grown meat yet.</p>
<p>“It is still small-scale, and the most important thing we are doing that other companies should do is focus on the design, engineering and full-scale installations of vessels and the supporting systems to make a lot of it.”</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/is-cell-cultured-meat-ready-for-prime-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2253102</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Netflix gets its first Golden Globe for best motion picture (drama) in a bizarre, live-tweeted event</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/netflix-gets-its-first-golden-globe-for-best-motion-picture-drama-in-a-bizarre-live-tweeted-event/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/netflix-gets-its-first-golden-globe-for-best-motion-picture-drama-in-a-bizarre-live-tweeted-event/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[actress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Director]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dune]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emmy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Golden Globes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nicole kidman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squid game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[succession]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warner Bros]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Smith]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You didn&#8217;t miss last night&#8217;s Golden Globes &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t on. But you may have seen the tweets. NBC announced in May 2021 it wouldn&#8217;t broadcast the awards show this year after an investigation by The L.A. Times revealed the lack of diversity within the Hollywood Foreign Press Association (HFPA), the organization that hosts the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You didn&#8217;t miss last night&#8217;s Golden Globes &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t on. But you may have seen the tweets. NBC announced in May 2021 it wouldn&#8217;t broadcast the awards show this year after an investigation by The L.A. Times <a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/business/story/2021-02-21/hfpa-golden-globes-2021-who-are-the-members" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed the lack of diversity</a> within the Hollywood Foreign Press Association (HFPA), the organization that hosts the annual event, as well as evidence of some members receiving gifts that amounted to bribes. As the HFPA undergoes reforms, it hosted last night&#8217;s pared-down event privately &#8212; it was not aired on television, nor even livestreamed.</p>
<p>Instead, the event&#8217;s winners were live-tweeted in an often bizarre fashion.</p>
<p>It seems the HFPA could have benefitted from Twitter&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/twitter-blue-launches-in-the-u-s-and-new-zealand-with-expanded-feature-set/">paid subscription</a> offering, which lets you undo tweets with mistakes. Last night, the HFPA&#8217;s Golden Globes Twitter account regularly <a href="https://twitter.com/kylebuchanan/status/1480370936469544964" target="_blank" rel="noopener">forgot to note</a> which TV or movie projects Globe recipients were winning for &#8212; like how <a href="https://time.com/6138082/golden-globes-2022-twitter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andrew Garfield&#8217;s win</a> was for &#8220;tick, tick&#8230;BOOM!&#8221;, for example &#8212; when it was announcing the night&#8217;s winners on social media. The organization also oddly referred to &#8220;West Side Story&#8217;s&#8221; laughter (?) as being &#8220;the best medicine,&#8221; in a tweet it later deleted, only to be posted again to say that <em>music</em> was the best medicine &#8212; which is not how that saying goes.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255562" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Nowhere in these deeply chaotic Golden Globe tweets do they even mention the projects people are winning for <a href="https://t.co/4Tt5CHaojE">pic.twitter.com/4Tt5CHaojE</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Kyle Buchanan (@kylebuchanan) <a href="https://twitter.com/kylebuchanan/status/1480370936469544964?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 10, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Nevertheless, the event went on.</p>
<p>In addition to being an overall quieter year as the HFPA tries to reform its organization following the controversies, the winning networks also aren&#8217;t touting their victories as they would normally, despite some seeing some notable firsts and upsets.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In prior years, HBO would be happily promoting its sweep over rivals. The network led the night with six wins, including four for HBO and two for HBO Max. Several of these were for its TV series &#8220;Succession,&#8221; which won for best TV drama, TV drama actor (Jeremy Strong) and supporting actress (Sarah Snook.) HBO Max&#8217;s comedy &#8220;Hacks&#8221; also notably beat out Emmy winner &#8220;Ted Lasso&#8221; (Apple TV+) as best comedy, and saw its lead, Jean Smart, win for best actress in a comedy. And Kate Winslet won best TV actress in a limited series for HBO&#8217;s &#8220;Mare of Easttown&#8221;.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, though Netflix <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-13/golden-globe-awards-attempt-a-comeback-after-year-of-scandals" target="_blank" rel="noopener">led the year by nominations</a> &#8212; including for best dramatic film &#8220;The Power of the Dog&#8221; and drama series &#8220;Squid Game&#8221; &#8212; it had said it wouldn&#8217;t participate in the event until the HFPA institutes changes. That decision means it&#8217;s also now not bragging about a couple of notable firsts that resulted from last night&#8217;s awards.</p>
<p>Netflix&#8217;s big win of the night was for its original film, &#8220;The Power of the Dog,&#8221; which became the streamer&#8217;s first-ever movie to take home a Golden Globe for best motion picture (drama). The movie also won for best director (Jane Campion) and best supporting actor (Kodi Smit-McPhee).</p>
<p>In addition, Netflix&#8217;s runaway hit TV series &#8220;Squid Game&#8221; received three nominations this year, leading to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/lifestyle/hippy-granddad-o-yeong-su-wins-skoreas-first-golden-globe-squid-game-role-2022-01-10/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the first-ever win for South Korea</a>, as South Korean actor O Yeong-su won for his role in the series, beating out &#8220;Succession&#8217;s&#8221; Kieran Culkin (HBO) and &#8220;The Morning Show&#8217;s&#8221; Billy Crudup (Apple TV+).</p>
<p>Netflix also won for &#8220;tick, tick&#8230;BOOM!&#8221; when Andrew Garfield took the trophy for best actor in a motion picture (musical or comedy), though the tweet had forgotten to credit the project by name.</p>
<p>Apple TV+ took home one win last night, as &#8220;Ted Lasso&#8217;s&#8221; Jason Sudeikis won best actor in a TV series (comedy). Hulu also got one Globe, as &#8220;Dopesick&#8217;s&#8221; Michael Keaton won best actor in a TV limited series or motion picture made for television, while Amazon Prime Video&#8217;s &#8220;The Underground Railroad&#8221; won the category. Amazon Prime Video&#8217;s &#8220;Being the Ricardos&#8221; was highlighted with Nicole Kidman&#8217;s win as best actress in a motion picture.</p>
<p>In another milestone, the first trans actress to win a Golden Globe, FX&#8217;s &#8220;Pose&#8221; star Michaela Jaé Rodriguez, took home the trophy for best actress in a drama.</p>
<p>20th Century Studio/Disney&#8217;s &#8220;West Side Story&#8221; won best picture (musical or comedy) and its stars, Rachel Zegler and Ariana DeBose, won best actress and supporting actress, respectively. Disney&#8217;s &#8220;Encanto,&#8221; which streamed on Disney+ just a month after hitting theaters, won best animated picture.</p>
<p>Warner Bros.&#8217; &#8220;Dune&#8221; got the trophy for best score (Hans Zimmer), and Will Smith was named best actor in a motion picture (drama) for &#8220;King Richard.&#8221; The best non-English language picture award went to the Japanese film “Drive My Car.&#8221;</p>
<p>The full list of winners <a href="https://www.goldenglobes.com/winners-nominees" target="_blank" rel="noopener">is here.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/netflix-gets-its-first-golden-globe-for-best-motion-picture-drama-in-a-bizarre-live-tweeted-event/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255562</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How one founder is putting the power of home ownership back in the hands of actual homeowners</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/how-one-founder-is-putting-the-power-of-home-ownership-back-in-the-hands-of-actual-homeowners/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/how-one-founder-is-putting-the-power-of-home-ownership-back-in-the-hands-of-actual-homeowners/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 15:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liz Young]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proptech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Liz Young remembers when her family became homeowners, even at six years old she understood it was a big deal. That sparked a fascination with real estate and the home-owning experience. While working at Bloomberg, she discovered the importance of data-driven decisions in the housing market. She wanted to give the power of data to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Liz Young remembers when her family became homeowners, even at six years old she understood it was a big deal. That sparked a fascination with real estate and the home-owning experience. While working at Bloomberg, she discovered the importance of data-driven decisions in the housing market. She wanted to give the power of data to the average homeowner, so she founded Realm, which helps homeowners prioritize renovation projects to increase the value of the home and use their time and money wisely. Darrell, Jordan and Liz talk about the tricky housing market, how powerful localized data is for homeowners and how Darrell can renovate his basement dungeon gym for the greeted ROI.</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwCotybrbEFX8yli-thpevQ4E4rLOtITXUQl6htZpoTguSiA/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Take our listener survey</a> and let us know a bit about yourself and what you think of FOUND.</p>
<p>Links from the episode:</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255582" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/ggv-capitals-gave-this-real-estate-startup-founder-a-term-sheet-48-hours-after-meeting/">Mary Ann Azevedo’s TechCrunch article</a></li>
<li><a href="https://realmhome.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Realm</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Connect with us:</p>
<ul>
<li>On<a href="https://twitter.com/found" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Twitter</a></li>
<li>On<a href="https://www.instagram.com/foundpod/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Instagram</a></li>
<li>Via email: <a href="mailto:found@techcrunch.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found@techcrunch.com</a></li>
<li>Call us and leave a voicemail at (510) 936-1618</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/c0d6bf82-910d-4212-b61f-27abe823470b?dark=false&amp;show=true" width="100%" height="480px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/how-one-founder-is-putting-the-power-of-home-ownership-back-in-the-hands-of-actual-homeowners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255582</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin slips under the $40,000 mark</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/bitcoin-slips-under-the-40000-mark/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/bitcoin-slips-under-the-40000-mark/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 14:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The value of bitcoin fell under the $40,000 mark in early morning trading today.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The value of bitcoin fell under the $40,000 mark in early morning trading today.</p>
<p>The popular cryptocurrency sold off sharply this morning, while rival tokens like ether also lost value. Currently worth $39,831 per coin, bitcoin is off 4.3% and ether 5.1%, <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/price">according to Coinbase data</a>.</p>
<p>While it is always risky to cover price changes in the crypto world, the fall in the value of bitcoin has crossed the threshold from notable to material. <a href="http://finance.yahoo.com">Yahoo Finance</a> indicates that bitcoin&#8217;s recent all-time high saw the cryptocurrency trade as high as $68,789.62 per coin. Today&#8217;s price puts bitcoin&#8217;s current drawdown at just over 42%.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255560" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>That&#8217;s twice the swing required for bitcoin to have entered a technical bear market, and four times what it would need to meet the requirements of a correction.</p>
<p>But price declines in the value of certain cryptocurrencies are not slowing the decentralized world. Crypto-focused publication <a href="https://www.theblockcrypto.com/linked/129693/nft-marketplace-opensea-kicks-off-the-new-year-with-strong-volumes">The Block noted this morning</a> that NFT trading volumes at the popular OpenSea marketplace are strong to start the year. So, web3 activity appears strong by some measures, despite recent price declines; whether today&#8217;s selloff will have an impact on NFT trading activity, to stick with that particular example, is not yet clear.</p>
<p>For other crypto market participants, the selloff could harm near-term results. There is a historical, positive connection between rising crypto prices and trading volumes. Companies like Coinbase and others make their daily bread off trading fees, meaning that falling crypto prices are generally bearish for their financial performance. Of course, the past is not a perfect predictor of the future, but today&#8217;s selloff is not precisely bullish.</p>
<p>Cryptos are not the only volatile asset that is trading lower this morning: Tech stocks as a whole are off 1.81% (Nasdaq Composite), while software stocks are off an even more painful 2.62% (WisdomTree Cloud Computing Fund).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/bitcoin-slips-under-the-40000-mark/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255560</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Startup fundraising again sets records as public markets slash tech valuations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/startup-fundraising-again-sets-records-as-public-markets-slash-tech-valuations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/startup-fundraising-again-sets-records-as-public-markets-slash-tech-valuations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 14:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The public and private markets have traded the Most Bullish baton back and forth in recent years, but today's situation feels riskier than ever.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/vcs-and-founders-are-max-bullish-as-public-markets-flash-warning-signs/">TechCrunch noted</a> a week ago that private markets appeared strongly bullish on future startup value creation, while public markets were drifting lower, repricing possible exit values for today&#8217;s upstart companies. The was, it seemed, a rising gap between the level of bullishness in the private and public markets.</p>
<p>That dissonance has only increased in volume in the intervening days. New data from China&#8217;s private market, sharper central banking forecasts, sliding tech shares and rampantly bullish funding rounds make today&#8217;s startup cocktail even more confusing than what we saw a week ago.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>In broad terms, the era of cheap money is coming to a close as startups continue to raise record sums, creating a possible collision course between private-market enthusiasm and a tightening stock market. And the discrepancy is only getting bigger.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2220367 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Let&#8217;s talk about it.</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s changed?</h2>
<p>This morning, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-10/goldman-now-expects-four-fed-hikes-sees-faster-runoff-in-2022">Goldman Sachs updated its expectation</a> regarding how quickly the U.S. Federal Reserve will tighten monetary policy. Three hikes to the key overnight rate were anticipated this year; that figure has risen to four. The financial giant also expects the Fed to start to shrink its balance sheet in July. This is a full-on reversion of today&#8217;s policy that has kept rates at effectively zero and bond-buying afoot.</p>
<p>The macro environment is going to change mightily this year, meaning that we&#8217;ll close 2022 in a very different state than we began it. You might not know that, looking at the market today.</p>
<p>A few data points for flavor concerning startup fundraising:</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/startup-fundraising-again-sets-records-as-public-markets-slash-tech-valuations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255514</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Station: A special CES galaxy brain edition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/the-station-a-special-ces-galaxy-brain-edition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/the-station-a-special-ces-galaxy-brain-edition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 14:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobileye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nvidia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stellantis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox. Hello readers and Happy New Year (I was gone last week): Welcome to The Station, your central hub for all past, present and future means of moving people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox</a>.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Hello readers and Happy New Year (I was gone last week): Welcome to The Station, your central hub for all past, present and future means of moving people and packages from Point A to Point B.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Welp, CES 2022 came and went. And while other news did happen this week, we&#8217;re gonna give you the ultimate CES breakdown. Hang on for this galaxy brain adventure.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255570" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2255359" style="width: 506px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/giphy.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255359" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2255359 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/giphy.gif" alt="galaxy brain ces information" width="496" height="419" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2255359" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>Giphy</p></div></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And nope, I did not attend. This was the second year in a row — after years and years of walking the packed convention center and the rows of startups jammed in at Eureka Park — that I didn&#8217;t go in person. It was sad, as I do love to meet up with founders and test out new tech, but then again &#8230;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Perhaps, next year.</p>
<p>Before you jump in this CES 2022 wonderland. <strong>Sec. Pete Buttigieg</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/steering-innovation-toward-the-public-good/">wrote an op-ed</a> that TechCrunch ran last week — the same day he made prepared remarks (virtually) at CES 2022.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>What did he overlook? What did he get right? And what did he get wrong? Let me know!</p>
<p>Oh and one final note, <strong>Jim Motavalli</strong>, an author and EV expert, wrote a weekend feature for us that ties in perfectly with all of the tech shown off at CES. It&#8217;s all about what he describes as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/09/feature-bloat-cars-chip-shortage/">&#8220;feature bloat.&#8221;</a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As always, you can email me at <a href="mailto:kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com</a> to share thoughts, criticisms, opinions or tips. You also can send a direct message to me at Twitter — <a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@kirstenkorosec</a></p>
<h2>Micromobbin&#8217;</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1999054 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png" alt="" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s micro CES time. Whoop.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a snippet from a lengthy roundup that Rebecca Bellan and I put together. The upshot? Smarter, connected, more powerful e-bikes and scooters were the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/07/smarter-powerful-electric-scooters-bikes-ces-2022/">top micromobility trends of CES 2022</a>.</p>
<p>We also noticed that a lot of the products that were shown weren&#8217;t actually new. But even most of those EV products included more powerful onboard computers that are synced up to apps that can help riders do things like find their vehicle, track fitness goals and control bike functions like locks and lights.</p>
<p><strong>Some of the highlights</strong>:</p>
<p><b>Bosch </b>showed up with its connected smart e-bike system, which isn’t exactly new, but it was awarded honoree status at the CES Innovation Awards.</p>
<p><strong>Cake</strong> announced new updates to its Ridecake connectivity app, including features to allow professional fleet managers to monitor and manage their vehicles.</p>
<p><b>Delfast</b>, the American-Ukrainian startup, rolled out an upgraded model of its electric Top 3.0 bike, which the company claims can go up to 200 miles on a single charge.</p>
<p><strong>Moonbikes </strong>showed off its electric snow vehicle. And while it is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/18/the-station-a-tesla-nhtsa-fight-brews-catching-up-with-kodiak-and-how-la-is-prepping-for-air-taxis/">not exactly new</a>, this was the first time people really got to check it out in person. It’s a single-track snowmobile that has a 3 kW (4hp) electric motor and reaches a 26 mile-per-hour top speed.</p>
<p><b>Niu</b> showed up this year with its new <a href="https://www.niu.com/en/ces2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BQi-C1 e-bike</a>, a vehicle the Chinese e-scooter company has already teased but finally shared pricing and tech specs at CES. The step-through bike is powered by a 500W continuous and 750W Bafang hub motor in the rear and can reach top speeds of 28 miles per hour in the U.S. The BQi, priced at $1,499, will also be app-connected and feature many smart security features.</p>
<p><b>Okai</b>, another Chinese manufacturer that supplies vehicles to many big-name shared operators, came to CES with five products, including a smart helmet and a smart backpack.</p>
<p><b>Segway</b>, the electric micromobility manufacturer that not only sells personal vehicles but also supplies a number of the world’s shared operators with vehicles, came to CES with a new kick scooter line, the P-Series, and a new moped-type e-scooter, the E11a.</p>
<h2>Vehicle tech at CES</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2254887" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Snapdragon-Digital-Chassis-Render-04.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2254887" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2254887 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Snapdragon-Digital-Chassis-Render-04.png" alt="Qualcomm Snapdragon Digital Chassis Render" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Snapdragon-Digital-Chassis-Render-04.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Snapdragon-Digital-Chassis-Render-04.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Snapdragon-Digital-Chassis-Render-04.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Snapdragon-Digital-Chassis-Render-04.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Snapdragon-Digital-Chassis-Render-04.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Snapdragon-Digital-Chassis-Render-04.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Snapdragon-Digital-Chassis-Render-04.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2254887" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Qualcomm Technologies</p></div></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">There was a lot of &#8220;vehicle tech&#8221; this year. I will provide a roundup below, but first some themes.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">CES 2022 was not a showcase of autonomous vehicle technology — at least not compared to years past. I base this &#8220;observation&#8221; on feedback from industry experts who were on the ground as well as examining which companies attended and their announcements.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">It wasn&#8217;t absent, mind you. But it was overshadowed by a lot of advanced driver assistance system technology, services and experiences that drivers and passengers can have inside vehicles and the compute power needed to deliver it all. When automated driving did pop up, it often came in the form of future promises, narrowly defined autonomous features like parking — or both.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">We have a nice long <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/07/ces-2022-best-weirdest-car-tech/">3,000 word article</a> on all the weird and cool vehicle tech we took note of at CES 2022. Here are a few of those items.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">The automotive chip game was on</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Intel</strong>, <strong>Nvidia</strong> and <strong>Qualcomm</strong> all showed up in force. There were two areas where &#8220;compute&#8221; was talked about the most. The first was to provide the power to deliver <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/qualcomm-ces-auto-snapdragon-digital-chassis/">digital services and content</a> like Qualcomm&#8217;s Spandragon Digital Chassis. The other area that compute showed up was in support of automated driving features and advanced driver assistance systems. Intel, Nvidia and Qualcomm also made announcements, including Intel subsidiary Mobileye announcing plans to bring a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/intels-mobileye-autonomous-driving-chip-for-consumer-vehicles/">new supercomputer</a> to market designed to give passenger cars, trucks and SUVs autonomous driving powers.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">Connected everything</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">Another big theme was connectivity. Sure, sure, that&#8217;s old news, right? This year it wasn&#8217;t just talking about what <em>might</em> come from an internet connected vehicle with the right underlying operating system and processing power; companies also showcased the products and services that will be in cars imminently.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Amazon</strong>, <strong>Blackberry</strong>, <strong>Cerence</strong>, <strong>Google</strong>, <strong>Stellantis</strong> and <strong>Volvo</strong> were some of the companies that introduced new connected features or systems. Amazon kicked off its effort in the fourth quarter last year when it announced Stellantis would became the first automaker to integrate Fire TV for in-car entertainment with its new Wagoneer and Grand Wagoneer. At CES, Amazon said it will bring the entertainment experiences to Jeep Grand Cherokee and Chrysler Pacifica, as well. In addition, Fire TV will come built-in on Ford Explorer and Lincoln Navigator&#8217;s 2022 models.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Google and Volvo talked about how car owners would be able to download YouTube into the vehicle&#8217;s infotainment system via the Google Play Store and Cerence and Blackberry made announcements about their &#8220;digital co-pilots.&#8221;</p>
<h3>ADAS and AD</h3>
<p>I won&#8217;t get too deep into the weeds because you&#8217;d be here all day, but companies like <strong>GM</strong>, <strong>Volvo</strong>, <strong>TuSimple</strong> and <strong>Gentex</strong> made announcements about autonomous driving and ADAS.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Oh, and how can I forget, <strong>Mobileye</strong> is partnering with Chinese automaker <strong>Zeekr</strong> to develop an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/mobileye-and-zeekr-plan-to-build-an-autonomous-ev-for-chinese-consumers/">all-electric autonomous vehicle</a> for consumers. The vehicle will be sold in China starting in 2024 and eventually roll out to other markets.</p>
<h3>Other wacky stuff</h3>
<p>You probably saw <strong>BMW</strong> showed off a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/bmw-shows-off-a-color-changing-car/">color-changing car.</a> But did you hear that Vietnamese automaker VinFast will issue the first customers to preorder a vehicle a “VinFirst” certificate on the blockchain platform in NFT form, which the company says is a completely transparent way to prove ownership of an order number?</p>
<p>NFTs and the term digital twins popped up a few times in the automotive sector at CES 2022, including an announcement from <strong>Cerence</strong> and VinFast.</p>
<p>The gist is this: Cerence has cloud-based software that allows VinFast (or any other company intrigued by the product) to create a virtual representation of its entire car, including software, mechanics, electrics and physical behavior, along with driver data and environmental data.</p>
<h2>CES: It&#8217;s electric</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">CES has been used as a platform for automakers to launch new electric vehicles since at least the middle of the last decade. And this year was no different, although maybe even more than in the past. Even Sony came back with its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/sony-mobility/">Vision S concept electric car</a>, and announced that the Sony Group is starting a new division &#8212; the Sony Mobility Inc. &#8212; which will start commercializing its electric vehicles.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>General Motors CEO and Chair Mary Barra</strong>, who introduced the  Chevy Bolt EV on the CES stage back in 2016, came back virtually again with a bevy of announcements related to its electric vehicle plans.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">First up was the reveal of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/the-chevy-silverado-finally-goes-electric/">Chevy Silverado EV</a>. GM introduced two trims, a basic work truck called at WT that has a range of 400 miles, up to 664 horsepower and a starting price of $39,900. Then there is the RST First Edition, a fully loaded, four-wheel-steering truck that will start at $105,000.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The Silverado EV is the third electric truck announced by GM, following the Hummer EV and the Sierra Denali. Little is known about the Denali &#8212; GM teased it just last month &#8212; but it appears the Silverado shares the majority of its parts with the impressive Hummer EV. Don&#8217;t mistake the Silverado EV as an afterthought, editor Matt Burns noted in his report. The Silverado EV is the most important of the bunch.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The Chevy Silverado has long been the main competitor with the top-selling Ford F-150 pickup. Side note: Last week Ford said it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/ford-double-production-lightning-pickup/">doubling production capacity</a> of the new all-electric F-150 Lightning.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Barra also confirmed — and showed pictures of — an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/electric-chevrolet-equinox-chevrolet-blazer-suvs-are-coming-in-2023/">electric Chevy Equinox</a>, as well as a Chevy Blazer, which will both come in 2023.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">What might have been missed during the splashy event (there were a number of announcements) was an image of a pontoon boat that flashed behind Barra as she spoke.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2255417" style="width: 1810px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GM-CES-PureWatercraft-02.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255417" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2255417 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GM-CES-PureWatercraft-02.jpg" alt="GM pure watercraft electric boat pontoon CES" width="1800" height="1200" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GM-CES-PureWatercraft-02.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GM-CES-PureWatercraft-02.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GM-CES-PureWatercraft-02.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GM-CES-PureWatercraft-02.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GM-CES-PureWatercraft-02.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GM-CES-PureWatercraft-02.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GM-CES-PureWatercraft-02.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1800px) 100vw, 1800px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2255417" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> GM</p></div></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I got confirmation from GM that this is the newest boat from Pure Watercraft, which separately revealed the <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/pure-watercraft-unveils-new-electric-pontoon-boat-301454425.html">new product at CES 2022</a> and opened up preorders. If you recall, the automaker <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/gm-acquires-25-stake-in-electric-boat-company-pure-watercraft/">took a 25% stake</a> in the Seattle-based electric boat company last November.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">This is the first product to come from GM&#8217;s investment in Pure Watercraft. The boat uses GM EV components. What makes this so interesting, beyond the EV boat, is that this illustrates GM&#8217;s broader push into EV component strategy, which the company thinks has an addressable market of $20 billion by 2030. This includes marine applications, along with EV crate motors for historic vehicles and converting equipment like airport ground support vehicles to electric propulsion.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I chatted with <strong>Travis Hester</strong>, GM&#8217;s VP of EV growth operations, so stay tuned this coming week for insights on this strategy.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Other major automakers that showed off electric vehicle concepts included <strong>Stellantis</strong> with its Airflow concept and <strong>Mercedes-Benz</strong> with the EQXX.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Stellantis actually had a bunch of news, including that it will turn <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/stellantis-airflow-chrysler-all-electric-brand-by-2028/">Chrysler into an all-electric brand</a>. The big overall announcement was the tip-to-tail agreement Stellantis now has with Amazon that covers a cloud computing contract, software development and supplying the e-commerce company with its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/amazon-delivery-fleet-electric-ram-promaster-vans/">upcoming all-electric Ram Promaster vans</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I interviewed <strong>Stellantis CEO Carlos Tavares</strong> and am saving the good stuff for this coming week.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And then there is Mercedes-Benz and its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/03/mercedes-benzs-vision-for-the-future-is-an-ultra-efficient-luxury-620-mile-range-ev/">EQXX concept</a>. This isn&#8217;t meant to be your typical we&#8217;ll-never-see-this-again concept car.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The EQXX is meant to showcase what the automaker&#8217;s electric future will look like and includes a ton of tech and features, which <span class="il">Markus</span> <span class="il">Schäfer, a board member of Daimler AG and CTO of Mercedes-Benz AG, told me will show up in vehicles beginning in 2024. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">There were lots of smaller players as well that I want to briefly mention.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>ElectraMeccanica</strong> showed off a few of its single-occupant EVs, including the SOLO &#8220;O2&#8221; Oxygen, which has a redesigned dashboard, and the SOLO Cargo, a modified version of the flagship vehicle, designed to accommodate a wide range of commercial applications.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Then there was <strong>Triggo</strong>, a fun-looking single-occupant electric vehicle that can actually get slimmer if needed.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2255418" style="width: 1740px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-09-at-8.06.12-AM.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255418" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2255418 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-09-at-8.06.12-AM.png" alt="" width="1730" height="968" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-09-at-8.06.12-AM.png 1730w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-09-at-8.06.12-AM.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-09-at-8.06.12-AM.png?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-09-at-8.06.12-AM.png?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-09-at-8.06.12-AM.png?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-09-at-8.06.12-AM.png?resize=1536,859 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-09-at-8.06.12-AM.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1730px) 100vw, 1730px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2255418" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Triggo/screenshot</p></div></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">OK folks, that&#8217;s it. Thanks for hanging in there for the CES information dump. This coming week I plan to feature interviews with Stellantis&#8217; Tavares, GM&#8217;s Hester and Toyota chief scientist Dr. Gill Pratt.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/the-station-a-special-ces-galaxy-brain-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255570</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kodland, which teaches kids digital skills, grabs $9M to scale its online coding school</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/kodland-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/kodland-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 14:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argentina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[k12]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kodland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learn to code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Redseed Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Series A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STEM skills]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2244802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[London-based Kodland, which started out back in 2018 offering in-person courses for children to learn digital skills like computer programming before switching focus to online learning from early 2020, has closed a $9 million Series A funding round to scale into more markets. The round is led by Redseed Ventures, with participation from Baring Vostok, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">London-based <a href="https://kodlandschool.webflow.io/en/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kodland</a>, which started out back in 2018 offering in-person courses for children to learn digital skills like computer programming before switching focus to online learning from early 2020, has closed a $9 million Series A funding round to scale into more markets.</p>
<p>The round is led by Redseed Ventures, with participation from Baring Vostok, Kismet, Flyer One Ventures and Alexander Nevinsky, a partner at New York-based I2BF.</p>
<p>Kodland&#8217;s remote courses for children aged 6-17 are currently available in the U.K., Ireland, the U.S., Canada, CIS Region, Malaysia, Indonesia and Argentina &#8212; with the startup offering proprietary localized content for each target region (although its users are spread across some 40 countries). So far, it says some 16,000 children have been signed up for its paid courses.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2244802" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The new funding will be used to further expand the reach of its online courses.</p>
<p>The courses focus on group- and project-based learning, teaching kids digital skills including coding, website building, games creation, animation and video editing in a way that&#8217;s structured to be more fun and interactive than traditional classroom-based lessons. Although the online learning offered by Kodland&#8217;s platform is guided by teachers rather than self-serve.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jUmu6KeVmw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/stem-toys-for-kids-and-teens/">Gift Guide: 20+ STEM toy gift ideas for aspiring young builders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gift Guide: 20+ STEM toy gift ideas for aspiring young builders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/stem-toys-for-kids-and-teens/embed/#?secret=jUmu6KeVmw" data-secret="jUmu6KeVmw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Kodland says it has around 1,000 teachers on its platform (some are employed by it, some are gig workers, depending on the market); while the &#8220;typical&#8221; ratio is one teacher per 15 pupils. It notes its platform does also offer one-to-one teaching.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The edtech startup says it&#8217;s focused on extracurricular teaching of digital skills for kids versus selling tools and resources to schools as it&#8217;s easier to scale globally &#8212; meaning it skips the complexities of K12 procurement.</p>
<p>And with a nod towards the creator economy, it&#8217;s established its own &#8220;accelerator&#8221; &#8212; called Out of the Box &#8212; where it offers (extra) support to the most talented students to help them monetize their digital creations by turning them into &#8220;real-life&#8221; products.</p>
<p>Kodland&#8217;s latest tranche of funding &#8212; which brings its total raised to date to $11 million &#8212; will be used for market expansion, with courses in a further eight languages planned over the next two years. It says it will also be spending on product development.</p>
<p>&#8220;During 2022 we will expand further in English-speaking countries, in addition to U.K. and Ireland, enter Spanish-speaking countries and several countries in South-East Asia,&#8221; the startup tells TechCrunch.</p>
<p>A smaller slice of the funding will be ploughed into its accelerator program.</p>
<p>The Series A funding comes off the back of what Kodland bills as &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">considerable traction&#8221; with students and &#8220;robust top-line growth&#8221; &#8212; noting that it grew its revenue 6.5x in the third quarter of 2021 versus the same period last year. </span></p>
<p>Edtech generally has had a booming pandemic, given all the extra screen time caused by lockdowns and restrictions on in-person mixing &#8212; not to mention the demand for support as homeworking parents have sought tools to keep their offspring gainfully employed while they try to work.</p>
<p>That does mean competition is pretty heated, though.</p>
<p>Funding giants like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/class-a-zoom-only-virtual-classroom-nears-unicorn-status-after-softbank-check/">SoftBank have been ploughing millions into the space</a> and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/">clutch of edtech unicorns</a> is also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/softbank-backed-korean-edtech-startup-riiid-acquires-langoo-to-expand-further-to-japan/">driving plenty</a> of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/booming-edtech-ma-activity-brings-consolidation-to-a-fragmented-sector/">M&amp;A activity</a>. A bunch of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/edtech-leans-into-the-creator-economy-with-cohort-based-classes/">cohort-based learning platforms</a> has also been successful in attracting recent investment &#8212; by, similarly, seeking to bridge the gap between edtech and the creator economy.</p>
<p>Where kids are concerned, a giant of the category remains <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/31/roblox-follows-minecraft-into-the-education-market/">Roblox</a> &#8212; which leverages social gaming to get children interested in learning programming and potentially earning money off of their creations.</p>
<p>Still, Kodland&#8217;s structure and focus &#8212; STEM skills for kids delivered via teacher-led classes &#8212; may help it carve a niche in the growing sea of edtech plays.</p>
<p>Billing itself as an &#8220;international online digital skills school for kids and teens&#8221;, its marketing is geared toward pitching parents on the notion of quality educational screen time for their offspring &#8212; selling bundles of four classes (aka a &#8220;module&#8221;) for €110; or a &#8220;complete&#8221; course of 32 classes from €660.</p>
<p>Commenting on the Series A in a statement, Eugene Belov, managing partner at Redseed, said: &#8220;Traditional educational institutions have a hard time keeping up with the rapid pace of technological development in today&#8217;s world. This often leads to a disconnect between the supply (skills and abilities of young graduates) and demand for talent (the requirements of modern workplaces). [Co-founders] Alexander [Nosulich] and Oleg [Kheyfets], are working hard on filling this gap by teaching their students skills which are very often left out of classical school programs, but which are becoming essential in today&#8217;s digital universe. And the unique result-oriented way their programs are structured make them highly appealing to modern kids. We are very excited to support Kodland on their journey.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;There is no monopoly in the educational segment now, which means that more and more players are entering the market to meet the growing demand for educational services,&#8221; added Vital Laptenok, general partner at Flyer One Ventures, in another supporting statement. &#8220;Those who understand the real needs of their customers will be able to become major players and set trends in the market. The Kodland team focuses precisely on the practical knowledge and opportunities for children to learn relevant professions in an interactive manner.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FKfN6WN2Vd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/edtech-leans-into-the-creator-economy-with-cohort-based-classes/">Edtech leans into the creator economy with cohort-based classes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Edtech leans into the creator economy with cohort-based classes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/edtech-leans-into-the-creator-economy-with-cohort-based-classes/embed/#?secret=FKfN6WN2Vd" data-secret="FKfN6WN2Vd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="R53jp6zUnK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/">Outschool is the newest edtech unicorn</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Outschool is the newest edtech unicorn&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/embed/#?secret=R53jp6zUnK" data-secret="R53jp6zUnK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/kodland-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2244802</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: The end of cheap money, and Take-Two buys Zynga</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/equity-monday-the-end-of-cheap-money-and-take-two-buys-zynga/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/equity-monday-the-end-of-cheap-money-and-take-two-buys-zynga/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 14:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assent Compliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paytm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pine labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[take-two]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zynga]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, a podcast about the business of startups, where we unpack the numbers and nuance behind the headlines. This is our Monday show, our short ramp into the week. Yes, it&#8217;s Monday again. No, you can&#8217;t stay in bed. Things are already happening! Take-Two is buying Zynga: In a cash and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/c09656e4-1a89-4d27-8e75-44c625ba978e?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Equity</a>, a podcast about the business of startups, where we unpack the numbers and nuance behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is our Monday show, our short ramp into the week. Yes, it&#8217;s Monday again. No, you can&#8217;t stay in bed. Things are already happening!</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255503" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/take-two-to-acquire-mobile-gaming-giant-zynga-for-12-7b/">Take-Two is buying Zynga</a>: In a cash and stock deal worth around $12.7 billion (enterprise value), the transaction has delighted Zynga shareholders and bummed out Take-Two&#8217;s own.</li>
<li>Paytm is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/paytm-stock-drops-to-record-low/">taking shots</a>, as other 2021 IPOs slim down.</li>
<li>The macro environment that startups exist in is about to change for the first time, from a monetary perspective.</li>
<li>Pine Labs is <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-10/fintech-startup-pine-labs-said-to-seek-500-million-in-u-s-ipo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">looking to go public in the United States</a>, China venture capital data is <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-09/china-venture-funding-hits-record-131-billion-despite-crackdown" target="_blank" rel="noopener">looking pretty strong</a>, Assent Compliance <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/canadas-assent-compliance-lands-350m-from-vista-equity-for-supply-chain-data-management/">raised a huge round</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/arive-raises-20m-for-an-instant-delivery-service-beyond-groceries-and-essentials/">Arive is apparently a thing</a>.</li>
<li>All that and we are just getting ready for earnings season, so stay hype as there is a lot of data coming in short order.</li>
</ul>
<p>Welcome to the week! The Equity team is entirely back from vacation now, and we are ready to freaking rock this year. Let&#8217;s kick some ass!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div>
<div class="article-content">
<div>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>,</i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i> Spotify </i></a><i>and all the casts.</i></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/equity-monday-the-end-of-cheap-money-and-take-two-buys-zynga/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255503</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doctolib is now used by 300,000 doctors and medical workers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/doctolib-is-now-used-by-300000-doctors-and-medical-workers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/doctolib-is-now-used-by-300000-doctors-and-medical-workers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doctolib]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Doctolib held a (virtual) press conference this morning to share some metrics, look back at the company’s recent product launches and give a hint about future investments. Doctolib started as a booking platform for doctors and has expanded to other services for doctors and medical workers in general. With its software-as-a-service strategy, medical [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.doctolib.fr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Doctolib</a> held a (virtual) press conference this morning to share some metrics, look back at the company’s recent product launches and give a hint about future investments. Doctolib started as a booking platform for doctors and has expanded to other services for doctors and medical workers in general.</p>
<p>With its software-as-a-service strategy, medical workers pay a monthly subscription to use Doctolib’s tools and use them with their patients. And it’s been working well, as 300,000 medical workers currently pay Doctolib every month — general practitioners, dentists, pharmacies, psychologists, etc. With a subscription price starting at €129 per month, the startup has a monthly recurring revenue ranging in the tens of millions of euros.</p>
<p>2021 has been a pivotal year for the company as the platform has reached a critical mass in France. For instance, when you want to get vaccinated against COVID-19 in France, many people visit Doctolib’s website to find the nearest vaccination center, pharmacy or doctor with free slots. Vaccination places can use <a href="https://vitemadose.covidtracker.fr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">other platforms</a>, but in reality most of them use Doctolib to handle bookings.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255509" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Doctolib currently operates in France, Germany and Italy. France is still the company’s main market; 60 million people have used Doctolib so far — most of them have interacted with the service to book an appointment. In 2022, the company predicts that it’ll work with an additional 100,000 medical workers.</p>
<h2>Creating a suite of products</h2>
<p>Now that Doctolib has a commercial relationship with a ton of doctors, it can release new products and build its suite of services. In many ways, Doctolib is following Salesforce’s strategy. It has a very sticky main product that acts as a springboard for other products.</p>
<p>A couple of years ago, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/16/doctolib-details-how-telemedicine-appointments-work/">launched</a> remote appointments with a telemedicine add-on. Doctors who choose to pay a bit more can start video calls and use Doctolib’s payment systems for remote appointments.</p>
<p>Last year, Doctolib launched <a href="https://info.doctolib.fr/doctolib-medecin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Doctolib Médecin</a>, a back-office tool for administrative tasks. For instance, it lets you centralize documents for each patient, see a patient’s history, take notes and issue invoices.</p>
<p>“We started working on it three years ago. We thought we would start from scratch compared to what’s available,” Doctolib’s Managing Director of France Arthur Thirion said. “It is being used by a bit more than 2,000 doctors right now.”</p>
<p>Of course, this isn’t the first product that helps you manage your work as a doctor. But it integrates nicely with the rest of the Doctolib ecosystem.</p>
<p>Similarly, Doctolib wants to increase the network effects of its platform with a new service called <a href="https://info.doctolib.fr/doctolib-team/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Doctolib Team</a>. This time, the company doesn’t want to create a new revenue stream, it wants to make Doctolib essential.</p>
<p>Doctolib Team is an instant messaging service that lets you find specialists and chat with them. You can also securely send documents about your patients.</p>
<p>For health professionals already using Doctolib, it’s a nice-to-have feature. For health professionals who aren’t using Doctolib already, they can create a free Doctolib Team account and start using it — and maybe they might subscribe to Doctolib’s other products down the road.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2255512" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255512" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2255512" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Doctolib-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Doctolib-2.jpg 6970w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Doctolib-2.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Doctolib-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Doctolib-2.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Doctolib-2.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Doctolib-2.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Doctolib-2.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Doctolib-2.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255512" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Doctolib</p></div></p>
<h2>Operating with a high level of scrutiny</h2>
<p>Doctolib isn’t your average startup, as the company handles sensitive medical data. There have been <a href="https://www.telerama.fr/medias/sur-doctolib-le-secret-medical-est-soigne-avec-beaucoup-de-legerete-6665635.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a lot</a> <a href="https://www.franceinter.fr/justice/doctolib-le-chiffrement-des-donnees-incomplet" target="_blank" rel="noopener">of reports</a> on the company’s hosting stack and design decisions.</p>
<p>And the company is well aware that it can’t act like other startups. For instance, the startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/19/doctolib-is-now-a-unicorn-with-new-170-million-round/">reached unicorn status</a>, but it has stopped sharing funding details since then. You don’t want to talk too much about money when you’re trying to improve everyone’s health.</p>
<p>“We have stopped communicating on funding rounds for the past several years,” co-founder and CEO Stanislas Niox-Chateau said. “Every quarter, every year, investors invest once again or invest for the first time based on our long-term project.”</p>
<p>Doctolib now wants to become a mission-driven company — it’s a special status that you can get if you comply with certain rules. And Stanislas Niox-Chateau founds multiple arguments to position his company as a company that improves society.</p>
<p>For instance, he said that Doctolib’s business model is quite clear — the company relies exclusively on subscriptions from health professionals. The company doesn&#8217;t monetize patient data.</p>
<p>According to him, the platform is also used widely and doesn’t create a digital divide. Many users don’t live in major cities for instance. And the product is supposedly easy enough that even elderly people can use it.</p>
<p>But that doesn&#8217;t mean that the company plans to stand still. It has ambitious expansion plans for 2022. Doctolib will grow its team from 2,300 employees to 3,000 employees. And starting today, all employees will become Doctolib shareholders. Everyone will get at least €20,000 in stock grants.</p>
<p>In 2022, the company plans to invest €300 million to improve its products and grow its platforms in France, Germany and Italy — it mostly means new hires and new offices. There won’t be any new market launch in 2022, but that might come later down the road.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/doctolib-is-now-used-by-300000-doctors-and-medical-workers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255509</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AskNicely answers how companies can best connect with frontline workers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/asknicely-frontline-workers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/asknicely-frontline-workers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aaron Ward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AskNicely]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackbird]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Five Elms Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontline worker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontline workers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homebase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nexus Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oregon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ryan Mandl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company's tools pull in Net Promoter Score, workflow, recognition and feedback, coaching and insights so that businesses can lead from their frontline workers.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.asknicely.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AskNicely</a> is the latest company attracting capital for its app targeting shift or frontline worker success as more businesses rightly begin to see how valuable these employees are to their bottom line and how technology can ensure these key employees are empowered to help the company grow.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2255199" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255199" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2255199 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?w=300" alt="Aaron Ward, AskNicely" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg 1661w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Aaron-Ward-AskNicely.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255199" class="wp-caption-text">Aaron Ward, CEO, AskNicely. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> AskNicely</p></div></p>
<p>The Portland, Oregon-based company, which has its tech team in New Zealand, began developing its SaaS customer experience management tools in 2014 for businesses that rely on humans, co-founder and CEO Aaron Ward told TechCrunch. The tools pull in Net Promoter Score, workflow, recognition and feedback, coaching and insights so that businesses can lead from their frontline workers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255192" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“Historically, we’ve been taught that businesses are top down, but what we know is that the signal often gets lost,” he added. “The ‘magic’ is to make those signals always on and for the practice of sharing feedback and delivering coaching are daily things, not just those that happen once a quarter or once a month.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Today, the company announced a $32 million Series B round of funding that was led by Five Elms Capital, with participation from existing investors Nexus Venture Partners and Blackbird. Five Elms’ Ryan Mandl is joining AskNicely’s board as part of the funding.</p>
<p>The new capital gives AskNicely a total of $47 million in fundraising. It previously raised its Series A in January 2019, and Ward said the driver for going after additional capital was in part the global pandemic. Many of its service business customers shut their doors as a result, and the company was contemplating if it was time to pivot. Instead, AskNicely doubled down on its mission and took the down time during the pandemic to invest in the product and its marketing, he added.</p>
<p>Those efforts paid off for the company, and Ward was able to take those early results to the capital markets, which recognized this as new technology for a class of workers largely ignored previously by technology, he said.</p>
<p>Ward believes that taking that time to focus on the company gives AskNicely a headstart on the rest of the market.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="r93hWXQnuv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/shiftsmart-a-marketplace-matching-shift-workers-to-employers-grabs-95m/">Shiftsmart, a marketplace matching shift workers to employers, grabs $95M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Shiftsmart, a marketplace matching shift workers to employers, grabs $95M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/shiftsmart-a-marketplace-matching-shift-workers-to-employers-grabs-95m/embed/#?secret=r93hWXQnuv" data-secret="r93hWXQnuv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We were the first to market with this and focusing on the changing technology for this class of workers,” he added. “The new capital will enable us to go deeper on product and invest in business out sales and marketing as we get ready to take our platform to market and announce ourselves.”</p>
<p>With <a href="https://1huddle.co/blog/2021-trends-digital-frontline-workforce/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">80% of the global working population</a> considered frontline workers in industries like retail, food service and healthcare, Ward says the market opportunity is a massive one. Companies also taking in venture capital as they aim to reverse this underserved market include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/blink-a-productivity-app-aimed-at-frontline-workers-raises-20m-at-a-100m-valuation/">Blink</a>, an app for frontline workers to use and engage with the various IT services used by their organizations, as well as with each other. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/shiftsmart-a-marketplace-matching-shift-workers-to-employers-grabs-95m/">Shiftsmart</a>, a marketplace matching shift workers to employers, raised $95 million, while messaging app <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/when-i-work-an-messaging-app-that-lets-shift-based-teams-schedule-work-and-more-raises-200m/">When I Work</a> closed on a huge round — $200 million. Meanwhile, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/as-companies-search-for-hourly-workers-fountain-brings-in-85m-to-assist-them/">Fountain</a> brought in $85 million and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/seasoned-spices-up-restaurant-hiring-after-bagging-18-7m/">Seasoned</a> grabbed $18.7 million for its tool for restaurant workers. Earlier this year, we saw <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/homebase-raises-71m-for-a-team-management-platform-aimed-at-smbs-and-their-hourly-workers/">Homebase</a>, which raised $71 million earlier this year, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/workiz-locks-in-13m-for-productivity-tools-aimed-at-home-services-professionals/">Workiz</a>, which focuses on home services pros, raised $13 million.</p>
<p>AskNicely has over 60 employees, and plans to double that over the next year. Ward wouldn’t get specific about company revenue other than to say the company is a “high-growth SaaS business.” He did reveal that AskNicely is working with 1,300 customers, mainly in North America, Australia and Europe, and that it has gotten to a point with its selling price that “every new customer today is worth 10 times more what we have been doing historically.”</p>
<p>“We are here to fix how frontline workers work, and in the past 24 months, companies have realized a new appreciation for what they have done,” Ward said. “They are underserved by technology and frankly underappreciated, underpaid and underestimated. We are helping them be successful, but we can’t do it alone. We need to build a movement to link arms with coalition partners and build partnerships with other players to make a difference.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iX7eqpVzNt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/as-human-capital-grows-scarce-flexible-compensation-can-help-attract-and-retain-talent/">As human capital grows scarce, flexible compensation can help attract and retain talent</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As human capital grows scarce, flexible compensation can help attract and retain talent&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/as-human-capital-grows-scarce-flexible-compensation-can-help-attract-and-retain-talent/embed/#?secret=iX7eqpVzNt" data-secret="iX7eqpVzNt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/asknicely-frontline-workers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255192</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Take-Two to acquire mobile gaming giant Zynga for $12.7B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/take-two-to-acquire-mobile-gaming-giant-zynga-for-12-7b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/take-two-to-acquire-mobile-gaming-giant-zynga-for-12-7b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[take-two]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[take-two interactive software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zynga]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Huge consolidation is afoot in the world of gaming. Today Take-Two Interactive announced a plan to acquire mobile games giant Zynga, in a deal valued at $9.86 per share &#8212; $3.50 in cash and the remaining $6.36 in shares of Take-Two common stock. Zynga&#8217;s enterprise value in the deal works out to $12.7 billion. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Huge consolidation is afoot in the world of gaming. Today Take-Two Interactive <a href="https://ir.take2games.com/news-releases/news-release-details/take-two-and-zynga-combine-bringing-together-best-class" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> a plan to acquire mobile games giant Zynga, in a deal valued at $9.86 per share &#8212; $3.50 in cash and the remaining $6.36 in shares of Take-Two common stock. Zynga&#8217;s enterprise value in the deal works out to $12.7 billion.</p>
<p>The deal will bring together two gaming powerhouses, Take-Two in consoles and PC games (including such iconic titles as Grand Theft Auto) and Zynga in a massive swathe of mobile games, a genre that was arguably largely defined by the company (it&#8217;s behind FarmVille, Empires &amp; Puzzles, Words with Friends and more).</p>
<p>The deal, Take-Two said, will result in $6.1 billion in 12-month pro-forma net bookings (ending September 30, 2021), making it one of the largest gaming companies overall, regardless of platform.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255494" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The transaction is expected to close in Q1 of fiscal year 2023, subject to shareholder and regulatory approvals.</p>
<p>“We are thrilled to announce our transformative transaction with Zynga, which significantly diversifies our business and establishes our leadership position in mobile, the fastest growing segment of the interactive entertainment industry,” said Strauss Zelnick, chairman and CEO of Take-Two, in a statement. “This strategic combination brings together our best-in-class console and PC franchises, with a market-leading, diversified mobile publishing platform that has a rich history of innovation and creativity. Zynga also has a highly talented and deeply experienced team, and we look forward to welcoming them into the Take-Two family in the coming months. As we combine our complementary businesses and operate at a much larger scale, we believe that we will deliver significant value to both sets of stockholders, including $100 million of annual cost synergies within the first two years post-closing and at least $500 million of annual Net Bookings opportunities over time.”</p>
<p>“Combining Zynga’s expertise in mobile and next-generation platforms with Take-Two’s best-in-class capabilities and intellectual property will enable us to further advance our mission to connect the world through games while achieving significant growth and synergies together,” added Frank Gibeau, CEO of Zynga. “I am proud of our team’s hard work to deliver a strong finish to 2021, with one of the best performances in Zynga’s history. We are incredibly excited to have found a partner in Take-Two that shares our commitment to investing in our players, amplifying our creative culture, and generating more value for stockholders. With this transformative transaction, we begin a new journey which will allow us to create even better games, reach larger audiences and achieve significant growth as a leader in the next era of gaming.”</p>
<p>Strauss Zelnick will lead the larger company, with Gibeau and Zynga&#8217;s president of Publishing, Bernard Kim, overseeing the larger mobile business (including integrating Zynga with Take-Two&#8217;s existing mobile operations).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As with a lot of other consolidation moves, this is about cost savings through synergies. Take-Two said the deal would help the larger business save about $100 million annually after two years (first will come integrations). Take-Two already has a number of mobile games titles and has expanded its franchises into mobile, but this will give the company a significantly larger holding in the space.</p>
<p>This is key, considering how Zynga has fared over the years. Since a huge boom in its share price when it first went public, the company has been on a bit of a roller coaster, and over the last year has seen its <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/ZNGA?p=ZNGA&amp;.tsrc=fin-srch" target="_blank" rel="noopener">share price drop</a>, making it an acquisition target.</p>
<p>The move also puts to an end an era of sorts. As a startup based out of San Francisco&#8217;s SOMA district just as the city was coming into its own as a tech hub separate from Silicon Valley, it was an early mover in spotting and scaling the mobile gaming opportunity.</p>
<p>Initially it found huge traction as a social gaming giant, leaning on growth by way of Facebook&#8217;s social graph, but as that became annoying and spammy, over time Facebook changed the rules and cut off Zynga&#8217;s audience supply. More generally, the mobile gaming market has proven to be a more precarious one when it comes to consumer tastes and usage, and so a lot of Zynga&#8217;s success has been banked around finding (and sometimes acquiring) the next hot new title and franchise to replace those that have waned in popularity. (One of its bigger recent acquisitions was acquiring, in 2020, Turkey&#8217;s Peak Games, which had already established traction with Toon Blast and Toy Blast, for<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/01/zynga-acquires-turkeys-peak-games-for-1-8b-after-buying-its-card-games-studio-for-100m-in-2017/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> $1.8 billion</a>.)</p>
<p>Combining with Take-Two, which also publishes Red Dead Redemption, Midnight Club, NBA 2K, BioShock, Borderlands, Civilization, Mafia and Kerbal Space Program, will give it a large library of franchises and IP from which to build new mobile gaming experiences. Similarly, Zynga&#8217;s IP may now find new traction in different formats and different screens.</p>
<p>What is interesting is whether and how the larger company will use its expanded content IP to think about how it engages with the market at large. These days so much action in gaming happens more on the platforms where people meet to discuss games and be social with each other, whether that is over Twitch, Discord or somewhere else.</p>
<p>The gaming market has seen a huge surge of attention in the last couple of years, as one of the &#8220;winners&#8221; in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic with more people looking for diversions while staying put at home.Take-Two quoted figures that said overall the mobile gaming industry saw $136 billion in gross bookings in 2021 and is growing currently at 8%. Mobile will now account for half of Take-Two&#8217;s bookings, it said.</p>
<p>More to come&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/take-two-to-acquire-mobile-gaming-giant-zynga-for-12-7b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255494</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla &#8216;Full Self-Driving&#8217; beta features an &#8216;Assertive&#8217; mode with rolling stops</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/tesla-full-self-driving-beta-features-an-assertive-mode-with-rolling-stops/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/tesla-full-self-driving-beta-features-an-assertive-mode-with-rolling-stops/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fsd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[full self driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Profiles are back in Tesla's latest "Full Self-Driving" beta 10.3 with an "Assertive Mode" that may perform rolling stops and other borderline maneuvers.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Steve Dent</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Steve Dent is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/24/tiktok-moderator-sues-over-mental-trauma-caused-by-graphic-videos/">TikTok moderator sues over mental trauma caused by graphic videos</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/22/zillow-adds-facetime-shareplay-to-browse-homes-with-friends/">Zillow adds FaceTime SharePlay to browse homes with friends</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><div class="article-text">
<p id="speakable-summary">Profiles are back in Tesla&#8217;s latest &#8220;Full Self-Driving&#8221; beta 10.3 with an &#8220;Assertive Mode&#8221; that may perform rolling stops and other borderline maneuvers, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/9/22875382/tesla-full-self-driving-beta-assertive-profile" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1"><em>The Verge</em></a> has reported. The update was originally released in October 2021 with three profiles (&#8220;Chill,&#8221; &#8220;Average&#8221; and &#8220;Assertive&#8221;), but was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-pulls-latest-self-driving-beta-over-left-turn-and-other-issues-063331006.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">pulled</a> just two days later over issues with traffic light left turns, unexpected stopping and more.</p>
<p>The latest update issued yesterday shows that the Full Self-Driving (Beta) profiles are back. If you choose &#8220;Assertive,&#8221; the notes state that &#8220;in this profile, your Model X will have a smaller follow distance, perform more frequent speed lane changes, will not exit passing lanes and may perform rolling stops.&#8221; As <a href="https://twitter.com/digitalhen/status/1480230704520773632" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1">@Digitalhen</a> notes, the system may also perform rolling stops even in &#8220;Average&#8221; mode.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I guess &quot;Road Rage Mode&quot; didn&#39;t fit on the screen <a href="https://t.co/6pJNFvrJXA">pic.twitter.com/6pJNFvrJXA</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255495" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&mdash; David Zipper (@DavidZipper) <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidZipper/status/1480218411162550273?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 9, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Generally, a rolling stop means a vehicle doesn&#8217;t come to a complete halt at a stop sign (which is illegal and <a href="https://www.automotive-fleet.com/74646/dangerous-risks-of-rolling-stops-highlighted-in-new-video" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1">dangerous</a>) but it&#8217;s not yet clear if that&#8217;s what FSD will do. It&#8217;s also <a href="https://www.mwl-law.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/SLOWER-TRAFFIC-KEEP-RIGHT.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1">illegal in many states</a> to stay in the left or passing lane if you&#8217;re not passing anyone, and of course, it&#8217;s never a great idea to follow the vehicle ahead too closely. All of that said, the mode hasn&#8217;t been tested enough yet to demonstrate exactly how it&#8217;s doing those things.</p>
<p>On the weekend, CEO Elon Musk announced that Tesla would be <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-fsd-price-increase-12000-002847392.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1">raising the price</a> of FSD from $10,000 to $12,000, even though it&#8217;s still in beta. As we&#8217;ve pointed out before, the name &#8220;Full Self-Driving&#8221; is misleading (much like Autopilot), as FSD does not offer true Level 4 self-driving, but simply Level 2 advanced driver assistance.</p>
</div>
<div data-component="TagBoilerplate"><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong><em> This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/teslas-full-self-driving-assertive-mode-reportedly-returns-with-rolling-stops-091938600.html">Engadget</a>.</em></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/tesla-full-self-driving-beta-features-an-assertive-mode-with-rolling-stops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255495</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Parrot, a tool for digitizing Mexico’s restaurants, takes in $9.5M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/parrot-a-tool-for-digitizing-mexicos-restaurants-takes-in-9-5m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/parrot-a-tool-for-digitizing-mexicos-restaurants-takes-in-9-5m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Villarreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[F-prime Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mexico city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parrot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[point-of-sale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roberto Cebrián]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ParrotConnect is a point-of-sale software for restaurants enabling them to digitize and take advantage of the home delivery boom to accelerate growth.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The global pandemic threw a wrench in the plans of restaurants all over the world two years ago when diners stayed home, causing many eateries to shift their business to pickup or delivery.</p>
<p>Roberto Cebrián and David Villarreal both had experience working with restaurants in Mexico and recognized that many restaurants were not prepared to change their operations quickly, so they jumped on the opportunity to help them.</p>
<p>“There are a bunch of food tech solutions in Latin American and U.S., but it ended up turning the operations in both the front and back of the house into a mess,” Cebrián said. “The pandemic was a crazy experience. Not a lot of people knew what would happen, but the downside was that restaurants closed.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255270" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2255279" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255279" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2255279 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Fotos_Prensa_SerieA_-Bob6-e1641593881950.jpg?w=300" alt="Roberto Cebrián, Parrot" width="300" height="273" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255279" class="wp-caption-text">Roberto Cebrián, co-founder of Parrot. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Parrot</p></div></p>
<p>With an eye on reversing that trend, they created Monterrey-based <a href="https://pos.parrotsoftware.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Parrot</a> in April 2020, and in 2021 launched with ParrotConnect, its point-of-sale software for restaurants enabling them to digitize and take advantage of the home delivery boom to accelerate growth.</p>
<p>Cebrián told TechCrunch that many restaurants were balancing an average of three delivery apps and 15 different menus at each location. Often connectivity issues and menu errors caused restaurants to get anywhere from 10% to 15% of the orders wrong or late when they were pushed from the apps to the restaurant’s point-of-sale software so that they could be made.</p>
<p>Instead, ParrotConnect offers a way for restaurants to centralize all of those fragmented operations, including table service and online orders — into one management portal where users can operate functions like menus, kitchen management, payment methods and reports.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company is working with over 60 collaborators on the product and now has more than 500 restaurants across Monterrey, Mexico City and the Riviera Maya using ParrotConnect.</p>
<p>On Monday, the company announced it secured $9.5 million, led by F Prime Capital, to continue developing ParrotConnect and expand its footprint in Mexico. The new capital gives the company a total of $11.7 million in funding.</p>
<p>Parrot is the latest company raising capital as part of a broader trend of companies helping restaurants thrive in this new digital world, including<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/digital-restaurant-startup-zak-orders-up-new-capital-on-mission-to-be-toast-of-latam/"> Zak</a>, also developing point-of-sale technology for restaurants, payment system <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/sunday-raises-24-million-seed-round-to-build-a-fast-restaurant-checkout-flow/">Sunday</a> and restaurant management software company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/marginedge-a-restaurant-management-software-company-raises-18m/">MarginEdge</a>.</p>
<p>Since making a soft launch in January 2021, Parrot is now working with over 500 restaurants — all paying customers, Cebrián said. It has 60 employees currently after starting in 2021 with 10 employees. The company has been focused on helping restaurants grow, and Cebrián said it was too early to disclose revenue figures. Plans for ParrotConnect start at $73 per month for companies with one POS.</p>
<p>“We are heavily investing in product because we want to give the right experience,” he added. “The restaurant industry is an old industry, and it always finds its way out, so we are happy to be helping them do that with technology. We admire the industry and how creative they are to make things work. Delivery has played a huge part in saving a lot of restaurants during this time.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NzFkueHvm2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/tech-in-mexico-a-confluence-of-latin-america-the-us-and-asia/">Tech in Mexico: A confluence of Latin America, the US and Asia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tech in Mexico: A confluence of Latin America, the US and Asia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/tech-in-mexico-a-confluence-of-latin-america-the-us-and-asia/embed/#?secret=NzFkueHvm2" data-secret="NzFkueHvm2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/parrot-a-tool-for-digitizing-mexicos-restaurants-takes-in-9-5m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255270</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arive raises $20M for an instant delivery service beyond groceries and essentials</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/arive-raises-20m-for-an-instant-delivery-service-beyond-groceries-and-essentials/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/arive-raises-20m-for-an-instant-delivery-service-beyond-groceries-and-essentials/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 10:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Prime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Balderton Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colin Hanna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distribution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frankfurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global founders capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hamburg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lululemon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[max]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[munich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prime Now]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samwer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instant purchase and delivery of food and other essentials was one of the big bubbles of opportunity in the world of e-commerce in the last year, with dozens of startups big and small emerging and scooping up funding to build out businesses to bring items like groceries, toilet paper and Tylenol to people&#8217;s doors in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instant purchase and delivery of food and other essentials was one of the big bubbles of opportunity in the world of e-commerce in the last year, with dozens of startups big and small emerging and scooping up funding to build out businesses to bring items like groceries, toilet paper and Tylenol to people&#8217;s doors in 30 minutes or less. Now a startup called <a href="https://www.getarive.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Arive</a> that&#8217;s applying this concept to the wider world of consumer goods in a Prime Now-style service &#8212; partnering with premium stores and brands to sell and deliver items like Apple electronics and Bose headphones, Lululemon active wear, furniture and beauty and bath products and Van Moof electric bikes, and then delivering items via its own courier service &#8212;  is announcing a Series A of $20 million to see if the idea finds traction beyond essentials.</p>
<p>The funding is being led by Balderton Capital, with Global Founders Capital (the firm connected to Rocket Internet&#8217;s Samwer family), Burda Principal Investments, La Famiglia and 468 Capital also participating. (La Famiglia and 468 Capital are repeat backers of Munich-based Arive, both having invested in the seed round for the company, which is not to be confused with the <a href="https://www.arive.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mortgage startup</a> of the same name in the U.S.)</p>
<p>Arive&#8217;s funding, and list of backers, is notable in that it&#8217;s based on a pretty limited run so far. The startup launched only four months ago and is currently active in just four cities in Germany &#8212; Berlin, Hamburg, Munich and Frankfurt &#8212; although now the idea will be to use the investment to expand further across the country and to start considering which other markets to tackle next.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255486" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The reason for the vote of confidence is that so far, the numbers look promising. Arive is not disclosing how many customers it has or what its revenues are looking like, but it notes that the average order size is between €50 and €100 ($56 and $113) across some 1,000 SKUs, with the average basket containing between one and four items. That presents what Arive is doing as a very different proposition to what, say, a Gopuff or Getir is hoping to achieve with its instant delivery model, essentially replacing the weekly grocery shop with multiple baskets delivered to one&#8217;s door.</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s not just about being the next quick commerce vertical but building the next generation of e-commerce,&#8221; said Maximilian Reeker, who co-founded Arive with Linus Fries (the two co-lead the company). He described that next generation like this: &#8220;Very convenient delivery of between 30 and 60 minutes, connecting people to local stores with a bike-based service, in an app optimized for the phone.&#8221; All of its couriers are employed by the company, either full-time or part-time.</p>
<p>Arive has up to now split the model into three parts, providing consignment, wholesale and, in the next 2-3 months, marketplace options for sourcing supply. Fries said that currently the wholesale part accounts for the largest part of its business and sales.</p>
<p>Beyond that, white label services &#8212; where Arive might sell its backend technology and delivery infrastructure to third-party retailers to build their own instant delivery services &#8212; is another area that the company is considering, Fries said. This could be a very interesting opportunity in areas such as fashion: typically online sales of clothes have been challenged by issues of sizing and dealing with returns, which make for a high barrier of entry for a company like Arive without making extensive and focused investments to address them. What it could do, however, is provide its technology to fashion brands and retailers that have, who are considering ways of getting apparel faster to would-be online buyers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Meanwhile, although it&#8217;s taking a different approach in instant delivery by eschewing groceries and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast-moving_consumer_goods" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FMCG</a> essentials and focusing on higher-ticket slower-moving consumer goods, Arive is still operating very much with those grocery delivery startups in mind for another reason.</p>
<p>Reeker told me that Arive actually relishes the oversupply of these startups in certain markets &#8212; indeed, the bubble has definitely started to burst for some of these startups, as they get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/after-acquiring-dija-and-fancy-instant-grocery-startup-gopuff-launches-in-the-uk-en-route-to-european-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">snapped up</a> by much larger and highly capitalized rivals looking to expand to new geographies &#8212; because they become a signal for where Arive should be considering to expand to next.</p>
<p>&#8220;We want to go to more places in Germany and expand internationally, and while we haven’t decided which cities, we are looking at those where existing grocery plays are live,&#8221; said Reeker. &#8220;The U.K., France, they are all interesting. Having those grocery companies there is an advantage for us because it&#8217;s evidence of the consumer shift that has taken place. They are already used to getting their food quickly, which is the first step.&#8221;</p>
<p>Arive is not the first company to have thought of building a service around instant delivery of virtually any kind of item a person might like to have without leaving their homes to buy it. This was basically the premise behind Amazon Prime Now, which the e-commerce giant launched in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/12/18/amazon-brings-one-hour-delivery-to-nyc-with-prime-now/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2014</a>. Pointedly, although Amazon expanded it to several markets, eventually it <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/21/amazon-is-shutting-down-its-prime-now-fast-delivery-app" target="_blank" rel="noopener">discontinued</a> the standalone app and branding it had built for Prime Now, which now exists as a faster-delivery option for some of the items that it sells via Prime.</p>
<p>The message there could be interpreted in two ways. It could point to challenges for scaling something like a fast-delivery service without also providing a wider range of options that offer cheaper options and longer delivery times to customers put off by the premium that comes with instant.</p>
<p>Or, it could point to how there remains an opportunity for a smaller and more focused company to get the model right, understanding that the market has matured in the last eight years and consumers are not only more willing to shop online than ever before due to COVID-19, but have focused their expectations of how that experience should more closely mirror the instant-gratification of shopping in person.</p>
<p>Investors are willing to bet that the two co-founders &#8212; which hatched the idea of Arive while at business school &#8212; have a shot in building something to fit the latter of those.</p>
<p>“Linus, Max, and the entire team at arive are challenging e-commerce conventions with energetic execution and an acute sensitivity to the priorities of modern brands,&#8221; said Colin Hanna, partner at Balderton Capital, in a statement. &#8220;Using light electric vehicles to rapidly fulfill orders leaves a lighter footprint on our planet and ensures that customers are home to receive goods they’ve purchased online, avoiding costly failed deliveries. The team is also committed to building their UX in a way that protects, rather than erodes, the value of the brands they are lucky to work with. Finally, high basket sizes and no wastage means the company has a much stronger path to a sustainable business model over the long run. Balderton is fortunate to be backing arive as it scales rapidly across Europe.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/arive-raises-20m-for-an-instant-delivery-service-beyond-groceries-and-essentials/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255486</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paytm stock drops to record low</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/paytm-stock-drops-to-record-low/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/paytm-stock-drops-to-record-low/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 08:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One97 Communications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paytm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vijay Shekhar Sharma]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shares of Paytm closed Monday at ₹1,157 ($15.6), the lowest since its market debut in November following the nation&#8217;s biggest-ever initial offering, after a key brokerage house further cut its price on the payments stock. The stock, which opened Monday at ₹1,226, dropped 6% at 3:30 p.m. India standard time. Paytm, which has been struggling [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Shares of Paytm closed Monday at ₹1,157 ($15.6), the lowest <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/india-paytm-makes-market-debut/">since its market debut in November</a> following the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/paytm-raises-1-1-billion-from-anchor-investors-in-indias-blockbuster-ipo/">nation&#8217;s biggest-ever initial offering</a>, after a key brokerage house further cut its price on the payments stock.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://bseindia.com/stock-share-price/one-97-communications-ltd/paytm/543396/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stock</a>, which opened Monday at ₹1,226, dropped 6% at 3:30 p.m. India standard time. Paytm, which has been struggling to improve its stock price ever since its debut, has slid by over 46% from its issue price of ₹2,150 ($28.9). The firm’s market cap, at the time of publishing, was $10.13 billion, nearly half of what it had sought during the debut and below the $16 billion valuation at which it raised a financing round in late 2019.</p>
<p>The plunge in price follows brokerage house Macquarie&#8217;s report on Monday in which it retained its lowest rating on One97 Communications, the parent firm of Paytm, and cut its target price to ₹900 ($12.14), down from ₹1,200 that it had assigned ahead of the market debut on November 18. Paytm, which says it has amassed over 300 million users, operates a number of businesses, including mobile wallet, credit top-ups, movie and travel ticketing businesses, and an e-commerce service.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255473" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Macquarie was the only brokerage firm which had such a grim view on Paytm’s outlook at the time of market debut. Analysts at Bernstein, in comparison, had estimated that Paytm&#8217;s valuation will swing between $21 billion to $24 billion. (A Bernstein spokesperson did not respond to a request for comment in November.)</p>
<p>“Post the various business updates and results, we believe our revenue projections, particularly on the distribution side, is at risk and hence we pare down our revenue CAGR from 26% to 23% for FY21- 26E. We are roughly cutting revenue estimates for FY21-26E on an average by 10% every year due to lower distribution and commerce/cloud revenues offset partially by higher payment revenues,” Macquarie analysts wrote Monday.</p>
<p>“We cut our earnings (increase our loss projections) by 16-27% for FY22-25E owing to lower revenues and higher employee and software expenses. We cut our TP (target price) sharply by ~25% owing to lower target multiple of 11.5x (price to sales ratio) (from 13.5x earlier) and lower sales numbers. Maintain UP with a revised TP of ₹900.”</p>
<p>The brokerage firm said RBI&#8217;s proposed digital payments regulations could cap wallet charges, which would hurt Paytm&#8217;s business, where payments side still accounts for 70% of the firm&#8217;s overall gross revenue. Macquarie also cited departure of senior Paytm executives and the shrinking ticket size for loans disbursed by Paytm as other factors that could impact the firm&#8217;s future outlook.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In a report in the second half of December, analysts at Morgan Stanley labeled Paytm&#8217;s stock as &#8220;overweight,&#8221; and assigned a target price of ₹1,875 ($25.2), saying the firm was &#8220;well positioned to capitalize on upcoming acceleration in digital distribution of financial services/commerce in India.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Huge TAM (total addressable market), India&#8217;s distinctive tech architecture and regulatory supportive partnership approach are key enablers, we believe. India is under-penetrated in financial services, and across segments we expect strong growth. More importantly, the penetration of third party digital distribution of financial services is significantly low and we will see strong acceleration over the next five years &#8211; this will be helped by the distinctive rails in India around identity, payments and data sharing,&#8221; they wrote in a report to clients on December 18.</p>
<p>&#8220;Also, we believe that Paytm&#8217;s financial services is synergistic, in line with the regulatory thought process and scalable. Balance sheet risk is low, and Paytm&#8217;s technology capabilities to leverage alternative data sets as well as design customized products are some key value adds against the above backdrop.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>The story was updated at the close of the trading day to reflect price changes. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/paytm-stock-drops-to-record-low/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255473</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigeria&#8217;s ThankUCash secures $5.3M to build infrastructure for cash back, deals and BNPL services</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/nigerias-thankucash-secures-5-3m-to-build-infrastructure-for-cashback-deals-and-bnpl-services/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/nigerias-thankucash-secures-5-3m-to-build-infrastructure-for-cashback-deals-and-bnpl-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 08:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[500 Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cashback]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interswitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loyalty program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pricing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ThankUCash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unicorn Growth Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255422</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Loyalty, deals and rewards services are a rarity in most African markets. The unit economics and other factors such as currency instability make such businesses hard to pull off in the region. Yet ThankUCash, a platform launched in 2018 by Connected Analytics, has managed to thrive, proving that not all is gloomy in the deals, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Loyalty, deals and rewards services are a rarity in most African markets. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The unit economics and other factors such as currency instability make such businesses hard to pull off in the region</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yet <a href="https://thankucash.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ThankUCash</a>, a platform launched in 2018 by <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/company/connectedanalytics" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Connected Analytics</a>, has managed to thrive, proving that not all is gloomy in the deals, coupon and rewards business</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And to that end, the startup, which announced an undisclosed seven-figure seed last year, has finally closed the round at $5.3 million</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VC firms 500 Global and Unicorn Growth Capital co-led the Lagos-based company’s seed round</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It saw participation from U.S.-based accelerator Expert Dojo, Predictive VC, SaaS Growth Ventures, Betatron Venture Group and Accelerex Holdings. Individual investors like Andrew Dell, former CEO of HSBC Africa and Craig Fenton of Google U.K. also took part.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255422" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to use the investment to expand within its home market of Nigeria &#8212; where it operates in Lagos, Port Harcourt and Abuja &#8212; and outside to Ghana and Kenya. It also wants to improve its product offerings and add more staff.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For years, store-like businesses in Nigeria such as supermarkets and restaurants have operated offline, relying on bookkeeping and head knowledge to record their customers’ activities in their shops. This made it difficult to offer cash back and loyalty points to customers</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; -webkit-text-size-adjust: 100%;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Online platforms like ThankUCash present these merchants with an opportunity to delve into rewards and help them retain loyalty and increase revenue.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/simeonononobi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Simeon Ononobi</a> started ThankUCash with <a href="https://in.linkedin.com/in/surajms" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Suraj Supekar</a>, <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/madonnaononobi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Madonna Ononobi</a> and <a href="https://in.linkedin.com/in/harshalgandole" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Harshal Gandole</a>, who act as a chief technical officer, chief operating officer and senior vice president of engineering, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The multi-merchant rewards platform (which means customers can hop on from one merchant to another to earn loyalty points) allows customers to earn rewards anytime they shop with thousands of merchants listed on its app.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The business raised a $320,000 pre-seed after grabbing the <a href="https://techpoint.africa/2020/02/12/thankucash-accepted-into-500-startups/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">attention of accelerators</a> such as 500 Startups, Google Launchpad and other local investors like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/early-stage-african-vc-firm-microtraction-reports-portfolio-boom-despite-the-weight-of-covid-19/">Microtraction</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/ventures-platform-announces-first-close-of-its-40m-pan-african-fund/">Ventures Platform</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Up until this point, ThankUCash said it has recorded over 600,000 users and onboarded more than 1,000 stores on its platform</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Also, it claims to have processed over $80 million in transaction volume.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having matured as a business, Ononobi and his team want to take on a more complicated task: building infrastructure for companies that want to offer akin services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are creating solutions that help SMEs succeed while increasing consumer buying power and opportunities. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We want to build an infrastructure for rewards, loyalty, deals, buy now, pay later, cash back,” he said to TechCrunch on a call</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Cash back was our low-hanging fruit and an entry point. We’re still going to go into deals, couponing, gift cards, buy now, pay later, anything that will help the business grow, but at the same time, allowing the consumer increase in opportunities of buying.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ononobi, a serial entrepreneur who previously built a payments company and also apps for Nigerian banks and the government, reckons that ThankUCash will do to rewards the same thing Flutterwave and Paystack did to payments in Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some companies such as banks have launched cashback programs via debit cards to users in the past</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But most of them have been generally inefficient, from setup down to collections and redeeming of points, and Ononobi argues that their inefficiencies boil down to no technical support. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ThankUCash sees a gold mine to provide plugins banks and fintechs can tap into to offer cashback and rewards</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2255438" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255438" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2255438" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ThankUCash-cofounders-1280x1023-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="543" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ThankUCash-cofounders-1280x1023-1.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ThankUCash-cofounders-1280x1023-1.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ThankUCash-cofounders-1280x1023-1.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ThankUCash-cofounders-1280x1023-1.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ThankUCash-cofounders-1280x1023-1.jpg?resize=680,543 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ThankUCash-cofounders-1280x1023-1.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255438" class="wp-caption-text">ThankUCash co-founders. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> ThankUCash</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The bit about buy now, pay later is fuzzy now since there are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/will-carbon-and-shahry-usher-in-a-wave-of-buy-now-pay-later-services-in-africa/">only a handful of prominent BNPL services</a> in Africa. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the company seems to be positioning itself for the imminent proliferation of such services buoyed by similar happenings globally where buy now, pay later services have seen an uptake as a result of pandemic-induced consumer behaviour.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The technology is such that we have our machines in stores. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So as customers request loans, we generate a code for it, customers input it into the POS machine and the merchant gets credited </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">directly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The code can only </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be used</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the store chosen and only for the loan amount requested, such that at the end of the day the customer is buying straight from the merchants,” explained the founder, who also mentioned that his startup might venture into offering buy now, pay later services itself in the future.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">ThankUCash’s consumer-facing platform will remain operational. But to set the infrastructure play in motion, it has signed a partnership with payments company Interswitch to onboard its merchants.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company, which is also </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in the process of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> making integrations with payments gateways, said a couple of bank partnerships are in its pipeline.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In terms of how ThankUCash makes money, merchants pay the company a fee on every </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">purchase</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> made in their stores. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For instance, ThankUCash gets a 1.5% commission for every customer it brings into the store to redeem a 5% cashback item. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Lagos-based company also takes commissions for deals and plans to charge an onboarding fee for businesses that want to use its APIs for its services, including buy now, pay later. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">ThankUCash has perfected one offering: the cashback product where merchants can get more walk-in customers. It’s improving the deals category, allowing merchants to sell products fast </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">(by hiring <a href="https://techcabal.com/2021/11/22/ex-dealdey-managers-reunite-to-launch-thankucash-deals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ex-managers of DealDey</a>, a Nigerian defunct deals company). </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And while currently building out its buy now, pay later infrastructure (which gives businesses a chance to sell products regardless of whether customers have money or not), ThankUCash plans to add a fourth offering soon: a remittance product where merchants can sell </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">directly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to the diaspora.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The chief executive doesn’t give details about this product. Meanwhile</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, its investors, who have doubled down while privy to information like this, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are enthused</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about “the continued evolution of the company”, a remark made by Amit Bhatti, the principal at co-lead investor 500 Global.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Since going through 500 Global’s accelerator in 2019, we’ve </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been impressed by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Simeon and the ThankUCash team’s progress in implementing a rewards system that works for Nigerian consumers, regardless of cash or credit or online or offline payment,” said the principal. “It’s a win-win for businesses and banks, too, as ThankUCash gives them the tools and data they need to grow.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 45-man team has hired Aaron Tindiseega to lead its expansion into Kenya and the eastern Africa region</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Ugandan professional has experience working for banks and tech companies like Uber, Standard Chartered Bank and Stanbic IBTC</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. For its expansion into Ghana, Kiki Anku, who has worked at Apple and a couple of startups, will spearhead the task.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/nigerias-thankucash-secures-5-3m-to-build-infrastructure-for-cashback-deals-and-bnpl-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255422</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
