<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 12:03:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>PandaDoc, the e-document startup, now valued at $1B as it closes a big Series C</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/pandadoc-the-e-document-startup-now-valued-at-1b-as-it-closes-a-big-series-c/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/pandadoc-the-e-document-startup-now-valued-at-1b-as-it-closes-a-big-series-c/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 12:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altos ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belarus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DocuSign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[G Squared]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mikita Mikado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[official]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OMERS Growth Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one peak partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PandaDoc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rembrandt Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Business tools have gone completely virtual in the last 20 months due to the Covid-19 pandemic, and today a startup whose e-document platform has played a big role in supporting that shift is announcing a big round of funding on the heels of huge growth. PandaDoc, which lets users create, share and sign official documents [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Business tools have gone completely virtual in the last 20 months due to the Covid-19 pandemic, and today a startup whose e-document platform has played a big role in supporting that shift is announcing a big round of funding on the heels of huge growth. <a href="https://www.pandadoc.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PandaDoc</a>, which lets users create, share and sign official documents online, has closed a Series C that the company confirms values it at $1 billion.</p>
<p>To be clear, PandaDoc is not making the full amount of funding in this round public. The company is based out of San Francisco, but it has extensive operations in Belarus, where it has been in hot political water &#8212; several employees were arrested by authorities <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/05/pandadoc-employees-arrested-in-belarus-after-founders-protest-against-lukashenko-regime/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">over a year ago</a> there after publicly protesting the current regime. The lack of disclosure on the size of this round is intentional and related to this. From what we understand, that situation is still ongoing.</p>
<p>OMERS Growth Equity and G Squared are co-leading this Series C, and Altos Ventures, Rembrandt Venture Partners, One Peak Partners, and Microsoft&#8217;s venture arm M12 are also participating.</p>
<p>Today PandaDoc &#8212; which competes with the likes of DocuSign, Eversign, DocSend, GetAccept and others &#8212; already provides a range of services to users across many different verticals. Content ranges from building and collecting e-signatures and payments around contracts, proposals and forms through to invoices; and PandaDoc&#8217;s users are also pretty varied, including construction, education, medical, and professional services businesses &#8212; some 30,000 customers in all. The plan will be to double down on growing more of that current business as well as bring more functionality and use cases into the fold.</p>
<p>&#8220;We plan on getting broader and deeper in the areas where we already play,&#8221; Mikita Mikado, PandaDoc&#8217;s CEO and co-founder, said in an interview with TechCrunch. Its contract management product is one of the most popular already in the market, and PandaDoc claims that its e-signature solution is one of the top three in terms of ubiquity. &#8220;We are going to continue competing in these areas, but at the same time we plan to go global this year and invest in localization and international growth.&#8221;</p>
<p>That comes on the heels of an already-strong business. PandaDoc&#8217;s customers are currently distributed across some 130 countries, and in the last year its user base has grown by 80%, with revenues jumping 63%. (The company&#8217;s business model is based around a freemium model, where basic e-signing is free &#8212; notably, a tweak it made at the start of the pandemic, and perhaps one reason it&#8217;s one of the top-three e-signing solutions today &#8212; and additional features and usage are priced in $19/month, $49/month, and enterprise-scale &#8220;let&#8217;s talk&#8221; tiers.)</p>
<p>The &#8220;let&#8217;s talk&#8221; tier is important in the context of this investment. Small and medium businesses are the company&#8217;s bread and butter but investors see an opportunity in selling up market, too, by way of vastly expanding the features that it provides to customers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“As a leader in the SMB segment, we believe the company is uniquely positioned to challenge current incumbents with a dynamic full-stack product that goes far beyond e-signing,&#8221; said Larry Aschebrook, managing partner at G Squared, said in a statement. &#8220;The management team is one of the best we’ve seen, and we look forward to supporting their creative and efficient approach to this fast-growing space.”</p>
<p>Mikado puts it a different way: &#8220;The more workflows that we can automate and achieve and do over time, the better.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="letter-spacing: -0.1px; font-size: 1rem;">PandaDoc&#8217;s widening window of opportunity is a sign of the times. </span></p>
<p><span style="letter-spacing: -0.1px; font-size: 1rem;">Covid-19 has precipitated a huge amount of so-called &#8220;digital transformation&#8221;: organizations that in the past used to carry out a lot more work in physical environments, were essentially, overnight, asked to shift all of that into digital, virtualized formats. </span></p>
<p><span style="letter-spacing: -0.1px; font-size: 1rem;">While that has definitely seen companies make bigger infrastructure and operational shifts, it&#8217;s also played out on a more immediate services level. Specifically, daily materials like documents that people have long relied on in physical formats still were getting created, shared and made official, but now all of that needed to be done in a digital format: that ushered in a big wave of business to companies like PandaDoc.</span></p>
<p>The company got its start, Mikado said, with B2B sales, &#8220;but we have started getting requests from organizations that have other use cases that aren’t in the same bucket, such as schools, government institutions and healthcare organizations trying to streamline their employee onboarding, for example.&#8221;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s partly because of this trend that investors have been swarming around enterprise tech. The other main reason in this case is that PandaDoc has proven to be one of the solutions that&#8217;s seen a lot of traction.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“We are proud to have led this new investment in PandaDoc – a highly-innovative company that is shaping the future of documents, through its robust, all-in-one document automation platform,&#8221; said Mark Shulgan, managing partner and head of OMERS Growth Equity. &#8220;PandaDoc is a leader in the document automation market, and its solutions allow businesses to increase efficiency, reduce costs, and accelerate their growth. We are thrilled to support Mikita Mikado’s ambitious vision, and look forward to supporting him and his team in this further evolution.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/pandadoc-the-e-document-startup-now-valued-at-1b-as-it-closes-a-big-series-c/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206533</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Insight Partners leads $34M round in Singapore-based fintech Spenmo</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/insight-partners-leads-34m-round-in-singapore-based-fintech-spenmo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/insight-partners-leads-34m-round-in-singapore-based-fintech-spenmo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accounting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accounts payable management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMBs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spenmo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201990</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spenmo originated as an expense management platform before realizing that expenses “are just a tiny sliver” of a company’s payables, founder and CEO Mohandass Kalaichelvan told TechCrunch. Financial teams also need to manage vendor payments, supplier payments, payroll and reconcile bank accounts, often in different countries, resulting in an overwhelming amount of work. Spenmo was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://spenmo.com/">Spenmo</a> originated as an expense management platform before realizing that expenses “are just a tiny sliver” of a company’s payables, founder and CEO Mohandass Kalaichelvan told TechCrunch. Financial teams also need to manage vendor payments, supplier payments, payroll and reconcile bank accounts, often in different countries, resulting in an overwhelming amount of work. Spenmo was created to centralize SMBs&#8217; accounts payable workflows. The Singapore-based company announced today it has raised a $34 million Series A led by Insight Partners, the New York-based investment firm known for its <a href="https://www.insightpartners.com/blog/categories/scale-up/">ScaleUp program</a>.</p>
<p>Spenmo says this is one of the largest Series A rounds ever raised by a Singaporean startup. It included participation from Lee Fixel’s investment firm Addition, Salesforce Ventures, Alpha JWC, Global Founders’ Capital, Broadhaven, Operator Partners and Commerce Ventures, along with angels like Plaid co-founder William Hockey; Grab Financial Group senior managing director Reuben Lai; and head of Stripe Indonesia Ongki Kurniawan.</p>
<p>A Y Combinator alum, Spenmo was launched last year and has now raised a total of $36 million.</p>
<p>“We stopped branding ourselves as expense management and focused on building a payables experience because we want to be at the heart of everything a company pays out,” Mohandass Kalaichelvan told TechCrunch. “Right now companies don’t have that one source of truth. They use a tool for expense management, which is a silo, something else for vendor payments, something else for payroll and all these bank accounts they have to manage. We quickly realized that gave us an opportunity to bring all of these things into one place and reduce the silos that teams have to manage.”</p>
<p>Since one of Spenmo’s products is corporate cards, it is often compared to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/brex/">Brex</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/aspire/">Aspire</a>. But Mohandass Kalaichelvan said the company has no desire to build a neobank. Instead, its aim is to help businesses manage the bank accounts they already have. Spenmo also doesn’t want to replace accounting software and, in fact, it integrates with solutions like Xero and Quickbooks.</p>
<p>About 80% of Spenmo’s customers perform cross-border payments and have multiple bank accounts across Southeast Asia. If a company has 500 invoices and bank accounts in Singapore and Indonesia, Spenmo helps its finance team manage which ones to send payments from.</p>
<p>“One thing we found about Southeast Asia is that cross-border is super important. Your workforce is remote, so very early on you have to send salaries abroad,” said Mohandass Kalaichelvan. “Secondly, your supply chain is international as well, so there’s a lot of cross-border trades and services you want to account for.” Spenmo can integrate with FX wallets in addition to bank accounts, so its clients can find the best rates.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LUWsERUc25"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/aspires-business-accounts-reach-1b-in-annualized-transaction-volume-one-year-after-launching/">Aspire&#8217;s business accounts reach $1B in annualized transaction volume one year after launching</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Aspire&#8217;s business accounts reach $1B in annualized transaction volume one year after launching&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/aspires-business-accounts-reach-1b-in-annualized-transaction-volume-one-year-after-launching/embed/#?secret=LUWsERUc25" data-secret="LUWsERUc25" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Along with Singapore, Spenmo is also currently focused on Vietnam and Indonesia because both of those countries have growing numbers of small- to medium-sized businesses, and a lot of payment gateways, making managing payables even more complicated.</p>
<p>Spenmo’s clients typically process about 500 to 9,000 payables a month. “That space is good for us because we don’t want to be anchored around things like the total dollar amount of payables,” Mohandass Kalaichelvan said. “If it’s just one invoice for a million dollars, someone can do that on their own. But if the million dollars is 1,000 different freelancer payments and they need to manually extract all that data to schedule payments, Spenmo will be immensely useful for them.”</p>
<p>Insight Partners principal Rebecca Liu-Doyle, who is joining Spenmo’s board, said in a statement that the firm is “thrilled to partner with Spenmo as the company builds its category-leading finance workflow software. Corporate spend management and payments remain ripe for disruption, especially in the Southeast Asian market.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kQqu2zmVvf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/investors-are-doubling-down-on-southeast-asias-digital-economy/">Investors are doubling down on Southeast Asia&#8217;s digital economy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Investors are doubling down on Southeast Asia&#8217;s digital economy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/investors-are-doubling-down-on-southeast-asias-digital-economy/embed/#?secret=kQqu2zmVvf" data-secret="kQqu2zmVvf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/insight-partners-leads-34m-round-in-singapore-based-fintech-spenmo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201990</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SoftBank and Demi Lovato back June Homes, a proptech startup emerging from stealth with $50M in funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/softbank-and-demi-lovato-back-june-homes-a-proptech-startup-emerging-from-stealth-with-50m-in-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/softbank-and-demi-lovato-back-june-homes-a-proptech-startup-emerging-from-stealth-with-50m-in-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 12:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apartment rental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[demi lovato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[June Homes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proptech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Ventures Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[June Homes, a proptech startup that aims to make renting less painful and more flexible for both tenants and landlords, is emerging from stealth today with $50 million in total funding. SoftBank Ventures Asia led the startup’s latest round &#8212; a $27 million Series B. Other backers in the company include FJ Labs, Kairos, TQ [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://junehomes.com/">June Homes</a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a proptech startup that aims to make renting less painful and more flexible for both tenants and landlords, is emerging from stealth today with $50 million in total funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SoftBank Ventures Asia led the startup’s latest round &#8212; a $27 million Series B. Other backers in the company include</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> FJ Labs, Kairos, TQ Ventures II LP (Scooter Braun, Schuster Tanger, Andrew Marks), Reshape, Quiet Capital and angel investors including musician Demi Lovato and Behance founder Scott Belsky. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The New York-based company also previously raised (but did not announce) a $13 million Series A &#8212; also led by SoftBank Ventures Asia &#8212;  and $10 million in seed funding.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="n7Q4WQGDWm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/9-proptech-investors-talk-co-living-home-offices-and-other-pandemic-trends/">9 proptech investors talk co-living, home offices and other pandemic trends</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;9 proptech investors talk co-living, home offices and other pandemic trends&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/9-proptech-investors-talk-co-living-home-offices-and-other-pandemic-trends/embed/#?secret=n7Q4WQGDWm" data-secret="n7Q4WQGDWm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founder and CEO Daniel Mishin first became interested in real estate with a missed train and an unplanned stay in a cheap youth hostel in Berlin when he was 11 years old. The experience inspired him to start his first business at an early age, turning his grandmother’s empty apartment into a short-term rental space for backpackers. After starting, and selling, a hospitality business, Mishin founded June Homes in 2017. He was motivated after his one struggle with apartment hunting in New York City.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Prohibitive costs, predatory fees, complicated requirements, long-term lease commitments — it seemed impossibly difficult to secure housing under these terms,” Mishin said. “I started thinking that there was a real opportunity for innovation that could benefit tenants as well as mom and pop landlords, and that’s how June Homes was born.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mishin founded the company on the premise that the current rental system is “broken” for both tenants and small landlords. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even the fact that we use the word “landlord” in itself is very outdated, he said, since the word literally means “lord over land.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re still speaking like we’re in the 16th century,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So how does it work exactly? The company says it has built an algorithm that detects mispriced rental apartments that are often in need of repair. It also has developed a process that it says can inspect, upgrade, renovate and list units for rent in less than 72 hours. Then, according to Mishin, people can discover, apply for and move into a new apartment “in as little as three hours.”</span></p>
<p><span class="s1">&#8220;Our proprietary algorithm automatically performs best use analysis for every building and chooses which June Homes model to apply to it,&#8221; Mishin said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup touts that its units are fully customizable. Tenants can rent furnished or unfurnished, with roommates or alone, and have the option to stay for anywhere from one to 18 months. The company says that unlike some short-term corporate housing companies that significantly upcharge tenants for flexibility, its rental rates are more in line with the price range you’d expect to pay on a traditional lease.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the flip side, June Homes says it helps landlords by working to help them fill properties faster and managing things like tenant defaults, non payments and building performance. The startup also eliminates broker and management fees, and never charges upfront fees to owners, according to Mishin. Instead, June Home</span><span class="s1">s processes all rental payments from tenants through its platform and pays owners either a smaller fixed payment every month, or a portion of revenue collected from tenants. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the last six months, according to Mishin, June Homes has seen a 150% increase in tenant growth and a 137% increase in unit growth. Specifically, it has signed on thousands of tenants across New York City, Washington, D.C., San Francisco, Los Angeles, Philadelphia and Boston. In particular, millennials and Gen Zers seeking convenience and flexibility are some of the biggest users of the platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The new generation deserves more when it comes to housing, and June Homes has created the easiest and fastest way for them to find their footing in a new city,&#8221; said singer Demi Lovato, who invested as part of the company’s Series A last year, in a written statement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because it offers more flexible lease terms, t</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">he company claims to have 25.5x less tenant defaults than the industry average. It also says that it can fill units 10x faster than traditional legacy systems. For example, Mishin said, in July 2021 the average June Homes apartment in New York was rented in 7.5 days while all other rental listings rented on average in 76 days. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, June Homes plans to use the new capital primarily to expand to other markets in the U.S. in the short term, and then globally over the next 12 to 18 months. It also plans to do more hiring. Currently, the company has 144 employees, up 3x compared to this time last year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sherman Li, partner at SoftBank Ventures Asia and June Homes board member, believes that June Homes is providing today’s renters “with exactly what they want in the post-pandemic world — flexibility, access and convenience,” he wrote via email. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He said SoftBank was also impressed with the company’s ability to build such a large housing company “without owning a single property.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While SoftBank Ventures Korea initially focused on the South Korean market, it has since expanded its focus toward early-stage ventures all over the world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We actively look for early- to growth-stage startups that have strong business potential regardless of geographical boundaries, and June Homes is definitely one such case,” Li said.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/softbank-and-demi-lovato-back-june-homes-a-proptech-startup-emerging-from-stealth-with-50m-in-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206240</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As inflation fears spike, 1build raises $14M to help construction firms optimize their cost estimates</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/1build-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/1build-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s an extraordinarily exhausting time to estimate costs in the construction industry. Lumber prices skyrocketed during the post-pandemic construction spree, only to come hurtling back down to Earth in recent weeks. Copper, concrete, and steel have also seen wild price swings as supply chain breakages, workers shortages, border restrictions and more plague price stability. Construction [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s an extraordinarily exhausting time to estimate costs in the construction industry. Lumber prices skyrocketed during the post-pandemic construction spree, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-20/tumbling-lumber-prices-force-canadian-mill-to-curb-production?sref=j5SuHr0s">only to come hurtling back down to Earth in recent weeks</a>. Copper, concrete, and steel have also seen wild price swings as supply chain breakages, workers shortages, border restrictions and more plague price stability.</p>
<p>Construction is among the world’s largest industries, with firms planning and building projects valued at trillions of dollars at pretty much any time. Yet, it’s also one of the most archaic industries, with a heavy reliance on paper even as IT has increasingly filtered into more of the industry’s processes. Paper though can’t match the extreme volatility in materials and labor happening today, and that means construction firms need better and more real-time software tools to handle cost estimates.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.1build.com">1build</a> has a bold vision to own not just cost estimating, but everything that it takes to get a building under construction. “We are going to occupy the whitespace niche of pre-construction — your planing, your estimating, up until you break ground on your building,” CEO and founder Dmitry Alexin said.</p>
<p>Alexin had been scouting around for startup ideas in the real estate sector in 2018 and 2019, having previously worked in finance. He worked briefly at a stealth startup in the space, where he “helped to select real estate with data science.” He discovered a problem when it came to modeling the development of a property though: it wasn’t easy to determine what could be built or how much it would cost. “I just assumed you can just use an API to figure out the cost to build,” he said.</p>
<p>That led him into the rabbit hole that is the math of the construction industry. He discovered “this analog industry … three times as large as ecommerce and still in this offline, non-digitized way to consume,” he said. He wanted to automate more of these processes, but even that ran into challenges. “When I was forming 1build, it was creating a data standard for the construction industry,” he explained. Eventually, he zeroed in on cost estimating.</p>
<p>Alexin is a solo founder, who has since built up a management team around him. He and a few early employees joined the YC Winter 2020 batch, where 1build was identified as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/18/the-20-best-startups-from-y-combinators-w20-demo-day/">one of TechCrunch’s 20 most exciting startups in the batch</a> out of several hundred (the company was my selection).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="y9JgVYf6XP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/18/the-20-best-startups-from-y-combinators-w20-demo-day/">The 20 best startups from Y Combinator&#8217;s W20 Demo Day</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The 20 best startups from Y Combinator&#8217;s W20 Demo Day&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/18/the-20-best-startups-from-y-combinators-w20-demo-day/embed/#?secret=y9JgVYf6XP" data-secret="y9JgVYf6XP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The startup’s timing, though, was horrific. “COVID happened right as we were graduating,” Alexin said. The company suffered a “50% reduction in usage in the first 30 days.” The company was still small and it hunkered down, but then something surprising happened: the construction industry just zoomed forward as millions of people moved to new homes and offices with the rise of remote work.</p>
<p>The company raised a previously undisclosed $5.5 million seed round from Initialized Capital and kept building. It focused on building a single platform (that’s the “1build”) around all aspects of estimating costs and handling the planning phase of construction. It’s “almost an experience that feels like interacting a spreadsheet, but we pull in the latest materials rate, the latest labor rates,” Alexin said. From there, you can “develop your estimate yourself, line item by line item.” He says that integrating all construction planning in one location can massively save time and money, and is particularly valuable for smaller contractors and construction firms who don’t have the scaled-up planning teams of their larger brethren.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2205035" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2205035" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2205035" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/1build-team.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/1build-team.jpeg 6000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/1build-team.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/1build-team.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/1build-team.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/1build-team.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/1build-team.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/1build-team.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/1build-team.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2205035" class="wp-caption-text">1build&#8217;s team, with CEO and founder Dmitry Alexin sitting in center of first row. Image Credits: 1build</p></div></p>
<p>Alexin said that subscription revenues have risen 7x in the past 10 months, and 10x since April when we talked a few weeks ago. That excitement led it to a quick, $14.5 million Series A led by Brent Baltimore at Greycroft. Alexin said that Baltimore has been engaged in construction tech for a long time, and said that “we felt that they were the one firm that understood what we are doing.”</p>
<p>The team, as is typical these days, is spread out, with the majority in the U.S. and others in Canada and Europe.</p>
<p>1build wants to be the one stop for the construction industry, and hopes that the industry standardizes on a universal set of data formats. “The more and more builders that adapt that, the more we can build into the product,” he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="b6xYtappnb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/construction-tech-startups-are-poised-to-shake-up-a-1-3-trillion-dollar-industry/">Construction tech startups are poised to shake up a $1.3-trillion-dollar industry</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Construction tech startups are poised to shake up a $1.3-trillion-dollar industry&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/construction-tech-startups-are-poised-to-shake-up-a-1-3-trillion-dollar-industry/embed/#?secret=b6xYtappnb" data-secret="b6xYtappnb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/1build-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205032</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Albertsons sets off Firework’s livestream, shoppable video experience on website</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/albertsons-sets-off-fireworks-livestream-shoppable-video-experience-on-website/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/albertsons-sets-off-fireworks-livestream-shoppable-video-experience-on-website/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 11:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[albertsons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firework]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GSR Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IDG Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jewel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Redwood City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safeway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Usman Humayun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Albertsons is the first U.S. grocer to utilize Firework's platform to create, host and curate its own short-form and livestream video to improve customer engagement.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Grocery giant Albertsons Companies, which owns Safeway and Jewel-Osco, is steadily adding to its digital transformation, this time with shoppable, livestream video experiences developed by Redwood City-based <a href="https://firework.tv/us/">Firework</a>.</p>
<p>Firework noted that Albertsons is the first U.S. grocer to utilize its platform to create, host and curate their own short-form and livestream video for the Albertsons brands websites and app to improve customer engagement, Usman Humayun, vice president of digital marketing at Albertsons told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>This is the latest in a pipeline of digital advances Albertsons is making; for example, it is currently piloting <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/albertsons-taps-tortoise-for-remote-controlled-grocery-delivery-robots/">remote-controlled delivery robots</a> developed by Tortoise.</p>
<p>As part of its digital transformation, Albertsons is shifting to be mobile-first as it focuses on customer engagement and retention. Humayun explained that e-commerce and brick-and-mortar stores were believed to be two things a few years ago, but when the global pandemic hit, those lines blurred.</p>
<p>“Now customers are starting in one place and ending in another place,” he added. “There is also an increased value of having a good digital experience that closely mirrors what people experience in the store, where there is selection, fulfillment — you can buy it right then — and you can ask an associate for advice.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2206096" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2206096" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2206096" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Albertsons-mobile-version-2-e1632268416590.gif?w=192" alt="" width="225" height="352" /><p id="caption-attachment-2206096" class="wp-caption-text">Albertsons mobile app with Firework. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Albertsons</p></div></p>
<p>Customers going to an Albertsons site or using its app are there to research, get tips and advice and read reviews, something Humayun said if a retailer doesn’t have that, people will go elsewhere. The more people come to shop and engage with the content, it also provides the company with data and insights for building more content, what he called “the flywheel effect.”</p>
<p>Firework, a short-form video platform, launched in 2017 by co-founders Vincent Yang and Jerry Luk and is now led by Jeff Lucas, former global head of ad sales for Verizon Media. The company works with more than 600 direct-to-consumer brands, retailers and media publishers and has raised over $100 million to date from backers including IDG Capital, Lightspeed Venture Partners and GSR Ventures.</p>
<p>Working with Firework provides Albertsons the ability to create and present content faster, in a lighter-touch manner, and move toward being not just about product and recipes but becoming “the single source for food-related content” as well as health through its pharmacy, Humayun said.</p>
<p>The grocer intends to begin by rolling out video content, like fruits and vegetables that are in season or how to pick the best fruit, and then follow that up with recipes and meal prep videos using those foods. It also wants to go inside areas like the deli to show a video of how popular foods are prepared and the best methods for grocery storage, similar to what customers are already consuming on Instagram and TikTok, he added. The partnership will come out with expanded offerings and experiences in 2022 that will include customer personalization and leveraging local experience.</p>
<p>“This is transformational for us and moves us upwards from the static images and text to a new way of engaging with customers,” Humayun added. “Short-form video is the right format for us because our customers have so much content to consume, and it challenges us to make a high impact in a shorter time frame.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="39ZgMZpxLb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/albertsons-taps-tortoise-for-remote-controlled-grocery-delivery-robots/">Albertsons taps Tortoise for remote-controlled grocery delivery robots</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Albertsons taps Tortoise for remote-controlled grocery delivery robots&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/albertsons-taps-tortoise-for-remote-controlled-grocery-delivery-robots/embed/#?secret=39ZgMZpxLb" data-secret="39ZgMZpxLb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tftRJJrBoi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/whos-building-the-grocery-store-of-the-future/">Who&#8217;s building the grocery store of the future?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Who&#8217;s building the grocery store of the future?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/whos-building-the-grocery-store-of-the-future/embed/#?secret=tftRJJrBoi" data-secret="tftRJJrBoi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/albertsons-sets-off-fireworks-livestream-shoppable-video-experience-on-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206064</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cabinet brings in $2.6M, designs software for executive assistants</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/cabinet-brings-in-2-6m-designs-software-for-executive-assistants/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/cabinet-brings-in-2-6m-designs-software-for-executive-assistants/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 11:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evan Kesten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Good Friends Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harlem Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[henri pierre-jacques]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heroic Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julia Leibowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[office management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parade Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peer to peer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software vendors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2205731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Executive assistants are the ultimate multitaskers. Instead of relying on half a dozen apps for productivity, Cabinet is pulling all of that together into one software package designed just for them.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Executive assistants are the ultimate multitaskers and instead of relying on half a dozen apps to make their jobs easier, startup <a href="https://www.joincabinet.com/">Cabinet</a> is pulling all of that together into one software package designed for the 10 million-person administrative professional market.</p>
<p>The company, with bases in both Denver and New York, is developing software to aid with daily productivity; for example, a scheduling tool that sits on top of existing company calendars like Outlook and GCal and a peer-to-peer community for EAs to share knowledge.</p>
<p>Cabinet was founded by CEO Julia Leibowitz and CTO Evan Kesten in 2018. Leibowitz, herself, started her career as an executive assistant, which she told TechCrunch was “an incredible place to start” because she was able to gain an inside look at how her organization functioned, especially at the top.</p>
<p>However, as her job grew, so did her responsibilities. And it wasn’t just owning the calendar and making travel arrangements for executives, which Leibowitz says most people think of when they think of EAs. Instead, that is a small part of the job that also includes event coordination, office catering, human resources and even marketing.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“You wear a lot of hats, especially if you are capable,” she added.</p>
<p>While in graduate school, she discovered that many tools and software were created for nearly everyone else in the organization to drive productivity, from engineering, sales and marketing to human resources, but she felt EAs were an overlooked market.</p>
<p>In 2018, she met Kesten while attending Cornell Tech. He was in engineering, and Leibowitz was getting her MBA. She brought him to an administrative professional conference, and not only was Kesten one of only two men, there were no software vendors of any kind, Leibowitz recalled. It was that starting point that then became Cabinet.</p>
<p>The company’s software is not just one feature, but brings a lot of capabilities into one package to drive workflow. Some EAs may have to schedule for more than one executive, and could be doing that more than 50 times per day. While some scheduling software is more suitable for individual executives, Cabinet provides ease in offering the option to either send a booking link or handpick from a variety of times that are automatically aggregated based on the executive’s calendar. It can even generate an email that lists the times available in plain text.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HJ1SMwddUv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/04/cortana-wants-to-be-your-personal-executive-assistant-and-read-your-emails-to-you-too/">Cortana wants to be your personal executive assistant and read your emails to you, too</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cortana wants to be your personal executive assistant and read your emails to you, too&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/04/cortana-wants-to-be-your-personal-executive-assistant-and-read-your-emails-to-you-too/embed/#?secret=HJ1SMwddUv" data-secret="HJ1SMwddUv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The software also goes beyond scheduling to improve efficiencies in travel management, office management and inbox management. Cabinet is a subscription-based model that charges users a fee of $29 per month if paying annually, or $36 per month.</p>
<p>“It’s a charge that EAs can easily purchase on their company credit card,” Leibowitz said. “That’s one of the ways that differentiates them — EAs are powerful customers because they typically have access to cards and are used to spending money on behalf of their teams.”</p>
<p>To get the software in front of more executive assistants, Cabinet closed on $2.6 million in funding, led by Harlem Capital with participation from Good Friends Capital and existing investor Parade Ventures. The investment also includes money from a pre-seed round in July 2020 from Parade, Techstars, Heroic Ventures, The Fund and angel investors.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of our former interns and now senior associates, Nicole DeTommaso, sourced Cabinet at a late 2020 Techstars demo day,” Henri Pierre-Jacques, managing partner of Harlem Capital, said via email. “It was a little early for us, but we kept in touch with Julia even through her pregnancy earlier this year. Seeing the product development and customer growth over the past few months was very impressive, especially for a small team and new mother. Julia embodies the type of founder we look for and we are grateful that she and Evan chose to partner with us.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the last six months, Cabinet has grown 30% month over month. It has also amassed over 4,000 administration professionals in its community, where they can exchange insider knowledge on topics like the best non-glitchy conferencing software.</p>
<p>The company also plans to invest the new funding in technology development. Cabinet works closely with its customers who often give feedback on new features, and the investment will enable the company to quickly iterate to drive efficiency in new feature launches.</p>
<p>In addition, the company is looking to hire marketing and engineering positions in its Denver and New York offices. Cabinet has three employees currently, and Leibowitz expects to be at eight in the next six months.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DcS0w65AoI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/3-strategies-to-make-adopting-new-hr-tech-easier-for-hiring-managers/">3 strategies to make adopting new HR tech easier for hiring managers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 strategies to make adopting new HR tech easier for hiring managers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/3-strategies-to-make-adopting-new-hr-tech-easier-for-hiring-managers/embed/#?secret=DcS0w65AoI" data-secret="DcS0w65AoI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/cabinet-brings-in-2-6m-designs-software-for-executive-assistants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2205731</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Netflix is acquiring the rights to Roald Dahl&#8217;s books</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/netflix-is-acquiring-the-rights-to-roald-dahls-books/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/netflix-is-acquiring-the-rights-to-roald-dahls-books/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 10:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[original content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Netflix is acquiring the Roald Dahl Story Company (RDSC) and rights to the author's entire catalog, including classics like Charlie and The Chocolate Factory, Matilda and James and the Giant Peach.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Steve Dent</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Steve Dent is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/20/netflix-and-apple-tv-clean-up-at-the-emmys-with-the-crown-and-ted-lasso/">Netflix and Apple TV+ clean up at the Emmys with &#8216;The Crown&#8217; and &#8216;Ted Lasso&#8217;</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/17/rolls-royces-all-electric-aircraft-completes-15-minute-maiden-voyage/">Rolls-Royce&#8217;s all-electric aircraft completes 15-minute maiden voyage</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Netflix is acquiring the Roald Dahl Story Company (RDSC) and rights to the author&#8217;s entire catalog, including classics like <em>Charlie and The Chocolate Factory</em>, <em>Matilda</em> and <em>James and the Giant Peach</em>, the company <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/netflix-acquires-iconic-roald-dahl-story-company" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">announced</a>. Terms of the deal weren&#8217;t disclosed (and are subject to regulatory approval), but three years ago Netflix <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/netflixs-roald-dahl-deal-could-create-tv-universe-1164419/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">paid</a> &#8220;nine figures&#8221; for the rights to 16 of Dahl&#8217;s works, according to <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/netflix-acquires-roald-dahl-story-company-sale-includes-catalog-1235018402/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1"><em>The Hollywood Reporter</em></a>. In any event, it likely represents one of Netflix&#8217;s largest acquisitions to date.</p>
<p>News of the acquisition started bubbling up yesterday following a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-21/netflix-is-said-to-be-nearing-deal-to-buy-roald-dahl-catalog?sref=W6GJF3MS" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1"><em>Bloomberg</em></a> report. Netflix has big plans for Dahl&#8217;s works, including &#8220;the creation of a unique universe across animated and live actions films and TV, publishing, games, immersive experiences, live theater, consumer products and more,&#8221; wrote Netflix Co-CEO Ted Sarandos and RDSC managing director (and Dahl&#8217;s grandson) Luke Kelly.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Excited to announce that the Roald Dahl Story Company (RDSC) and Netflix are joining forces to bring some of the world&#39;s most loved stories to current and future fans in creative new ways.</p>
<p>“We are now about to visit the most marvellous places and see the most wonderful things.” <a href="https://t.co/NIiBeStJm2">pic.twitter.com/NIiBeStJm2</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Netflix (@netflix) <a href="https://twitter.com/netflix/status/1440571573363089412?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 22, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The companies revealed that director Taika Waititi and screenwriter Phil Johnston are working on a series based on the <em>Charlie and the Chocolate Factory</em>world. Netflix is also working with Sony and Working Title on an adaptation of <em>Matilda The Musical</em>.</p>
<p>The acquisition appears to go well beyond Netflix&#8217;s past content deals, in which it simply licensed content from others. It famously did so with Marvel, then ended up <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-29-daredevil-cancel-netflix.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1">canceling <em>Daredevil</em></a> and other Marvel shows when it couldn&#8217;t come to terms with Disney, which was planning at the time to launch rival service Disney+.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With Roald Dahl&#8217;s catalog, it promises to &#8220;bring these timeless tales to more audiences in new formats&#8230; [while] maintaining their unique spirit and their universal themes of surprise and kindness,&#8221; Sarandos and Dahl wrote. &#8220;These stories and their messages of the power and possibility of young people have never felt more pertinent.&#8221; Last year, the company issued an apology on its <a href="https://www.roalddahl.com/global/rdsc-and-family-notice" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1">website</a> for Dahl&#8217;s history of antisemitic statements, as <em>Bloomberg</em> noted.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong><em> This article originally appeared on<a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-reportedly-purchasing-the-rights-to-roald-dahls-entire-catalog-091947985.html"> Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/netflix-is-acquiring-the-rights-to-roald-dahls-books/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206521</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sony Group unit seeks to acquire India&#8217;s Zee Entertainment, invest an additional $1.57 billion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/sony-zee-india-acquisition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/sony-zee-india-acquisition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 09:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sony Pictures Networks India said on Wednesday it has agreed to acquire Zee Entertainment, which if the deal materializes, will bring together two of the largest broadcasting giants in India that run large cable television networks, streaming services, music labels, and own scores of other digital assets. The subsidiary of the Japanese conglomerate group said [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Sony Pictures Networks India said on Wednesday it has agreed to acquire Zee Entertainment, which if the deal materializes, will bring together two of the largest broadcasting giants in India that run large cable television networks, streaming services, music labels, and own scores of other digital assets.</p>
<p>The subsidiary of the Japanese conglomerate group said it will invest $1.575 billion in Zee Entertainment, a 30-year-old firm that has been grappling with internal governance issues.</p>
<p>Sony said it wants to acquire a controlling 53% stake in the publicly listed Zee Entertainment, but did not disclose how much it plans to spend on buying Zee, which operates over five dozen TV channels in English, Hindi, and many regional languages and has tie-ups with several global studios for broadcasting and streaming their library in India. Sony Pictures Networks India, similarly, operates over two dozen TV channels in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>A merger would help the two firms regain market share in the country, where the television landscape has significantly changed in the past two decades &#8212; thanks to the arrival of new players and dramatically fast internet adoption.</p>
<p>Both Zee and Sony have been important fixtures in the Indian TV industry for the last 25 years. Sony launched Sony Entertainment Television in India in 1995 and has aired some of the most memorable shows including &#8216;Indian Idol,&#8217; and &#8216;Kaun Banega Crorepati,&#8217; an official Hindi adaptation of &#8216;Who Wants to be a Millionaire?&#8217;</p>
<p>The firms also operate on-demand streaming services such as Zee5 and SonyLiv that compete with dozens of other players including Netflix, Amazon Prime Video, and Disney&#8217;s Hotstar. Zee5 and SonyLiv both together amassed over 150 million monthly active users &#8212; though there is likely a considerable overlap between their userbases.</p>
<p>The two firms said that over the next 90 days they will conduct due diligence and finalize a definitive agreement. Analysts say that Zee will need a majority approval from its shareholders for the deal to go through.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In a filing to BSE, the publicly listed Zee Entertainment said the proposed merged entity will be led by current Zee chief executive Punit Goenka (pictured above). Several Zee shareholders have asked for the termination of Goenka and other top officials in recent days.</p>
<p>Zee’s shares surged 35% on the news Wednesday, giving it a market value of $4.5 billion.</p>
<p>“The combined company would be a publicly listed company in India and be better positioned to lead the consumer transition from traditional pay TV into the digital future,” Sony Pictures Networks India said in a statement. “The merger of ZEEL and SPNI would bring together two leading Indian media network businesses, benefitting consumers throughout India across content genres, from film to sports.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/sony-zee-india-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206503</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mojo, a men&#8217;s sexual health startup that&#8217;s pushing therapy not pills, gets $4.4M seed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/mojo-a-mens-sexual-health-startup-thats-pushing-therapy-not-pills-gets-4-4m-seed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/mojo-a-mens-sexual-health-startup-thats-pushing-therapy-not-pills-gets-4-4m-seed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 09:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Erectile Dysfunction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[errol damelin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ian hogarth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindred Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Made.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men's health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mojo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Numan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Octopus Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexual health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[songkick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Blomfield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A number of sexual health startups have spun up in recent years offering men discreet help with the awkward issue of erectile dysfunction. Companies like Numan and Roman. But &#8216;help&#8217; in this context usually means making it easier to get hold of drugs like Viagra. UK-based startup Mojo has been taking a different tack. It&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A number of sexual health startups have spun up in recent years offering men discreet help with the awkward issue of erectile dysfunction. Companies like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/13/numan-is-a-startup-which-aims-to-tackle-your-tackle-problem-erectile-dysfunction/">Numan</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/31/roman-startup/">Roman</a>. But &#8216;help&#8217; in this context usually means making it easier to get hold of drugs like Viagra.</p>
<p>UK-based startup <a href="https://mojo.so">Mojo</a> has been taking a different tack. It&#8217;s built a subscription service to support men&#8217;s sexual wellbeing by providing on-tap access to dedicated therapies &#8212; partnering with professional psychosexual therapists to provide online courses that are billed as offering a longer term solution to male sexual health problems vs just popping some blue pills.</p>
<p>This approach means Mojo sits within a wider digital health trend where the smartphone in the pocket is being appropriated by app makers to deliver targeted, non-pharmaceutical support &#8212; be it for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/07/21/big-health/">insomnia</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/oviva-grabs-80m-for-app-delivered-healthy-diet-programs/">dietary needs</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/kaia-health-grabs-75m-on-surging-interest-in-its-virtual-therapies-for-chronic-pain-and-copd/">musculoskeletal disorders</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/calm-raises-75m-more-at-2b-valuation/">mental health</a> or indeed sexual wellbeing. (The latter category includes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/emjoy-picks-up-3m-to-get-more-women-tuned-into-sexual-self-care/">dedicated apps for women, too</a>.)</p>
<p>The idea driving all of these startups is to offer people a viable alternative to Big Pharma. (And hopefully eat some of the drug companies&#8217; lunch in the process.)</p>
<p>Mojo&#8217;s support platform is geared towards a spectrum of issues that can affect men and have links to their sexual wellbeing &#8212; with digital programs not just geared towards with erectile dysfunction but other sexual problems like porn addition or anxiety more generally.</p>
<p>So it could be an interesting &#8216;way in&#8217; &#8212; to encourage men to explore wider psychological issues by accessing support services. (Men are a notoriously difficult group to get into therapy but erectile dysfunction is likely to be a trigger for a lot of therapy-shy individuals to seek support.)</p>
<p>Mojo&#8217;s quarterly subscription service (costing £49/$68 every three months) provides access to professional resources that Mojo bills as &#8220;unobtainable for most&#8221;. It also describes its app as a &#8220;virtual coach&#8221; &#8212; saying it&#8217;s aiming to &#8220;encourage men to reclaim their erections and have great sex without resulting to a medication first approach&#8221;.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The digital support package includes video courses and exercises, therapy podcasts and meditations, and live events &#8212; including the chance to connect directly with Mojo&#8217;s panel of sexual health experts and the wider community of men using the app. A dedicated community reduces the stigma that men may feel around discussing intimate health issues &#8212; since other users are likely to be experiencing similar problems.</p>
<p>The 2019-founded startup says it&#8217;s signed up &#8220;close to&#8221; 50,000 users across 36 countries so far.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s announcing seed funding today to step on the growth gas.</p>
<p>The £3.25 million ($4.4M) round is co-led by London early stage fund Kindred Capital and Octopus Ventures. Angel investors in the round include some familiar names in the European startup world, including Tom Blomfield (Monzo), Julien Callede (<a href="http://made.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://Made.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1632384309512000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFKzqkCddKf0pr9ch_QDC4WdOxtVw">Made.com</a>), Ian Hogarth (SongKick), Freddy Macnamara (Cuvva), Alex Rose (Let’s Do This) and Errol Damelin (Wonga).</p>
<p>Commenting on the seed funding in a statement, Kamran Adle, health investor at Octopus Ventures, said: “Taboo areas within health continue to be a key area of interest for us, as there is often high latent demand due to decades of underinvestment. Men’s sexual health is a perfect example of this, creating a huge opportunity for Mojo to challenge the stigma and move beyond pills to a much broader, sustainable and scalable solution.”</p>
<p>In another supporting statement, Maria Palma, general partner at Kindred, added: “We deeply believe that the strong founding team at Mojo can redefine the conversation around male sexuality and vulnerability. It is clear from their early evangelical user base that they have created a product which resonates with men all over the world and helps them transform their confidence, relationships, and their everyday lives.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EjzlbxgV9j"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/mens-health-startup-manual-raises-30m-series-a-from-us-and-european-investors/">Men’s health startup Manual raises $30M Series A from US and European investors</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Men’s health startup Manual raises $30M Series A from US and European investors&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/mens-health-startup-manual-raises-30m-series-a-from-us-and-european-investors/embed/#?secret=EjzlbxgV9j" data-secret="EjzlbxgV9j" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oSk5iRjPSn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/12/mens-at-home-health-startup-vault-takes-in-30-million-from-tiger-global/">Men&#8217;s at-home health startup Vault takes in $30 million from Tiger Capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Men&#8217;s at-home health startup Vault takes in $30 million from Tiger Capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/12/mens-at-home-health-startup-vault-takes-in-30-million-from-tiger-global/embed/#?secret=oSk5iRjPSn" data-secret="oSk5iRjPSn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/mojo-a-mens-sexual-health-startup-thats-pushing-therapy-not-pills-gets-4-4m-seed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206480</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hai Robotics picks up $200M for its warehouse robot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/hai-robotics-picks-up-200m-for-its-warehouse-robot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/hai-robotics-picks-up-200m-for-its-warehouse-robot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 08:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hai Robotics, a Shenzhen, China-based warehouse robotics startup that develops autonomous, case-handling robotic (ACR) system, announced it has raised $200 million. The funding comes from two separate equity rounds, a Series C and Series D, which are being disclosed simultaneously. Its Series C funding was led by 5Y Capital, with participation from Sequoia Capital China, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.hairobotics.com/en/home/index?gclid=CjwKCAjwhaaKBhBcEiwA8acsHGkC61ZBdxW8BetrH6wQmsfPYSdcjJy54WZsrIzjV2wL9Xsg_lNAsRoC1QMQAvD_BwE">Hai Robotics</a>, a Shenzhen, China-based warehouse robotics startup that develops autonomous, case-handling robotic (ACR) system, announced it has raised $200 million. The funding comes from two separate equity rounds, a Series C and Series D, which are being disclosed simultaneously.</p>
<p>Its Series C funding was led by 5Y Capital, with participation from Sequoia Capital China, Source Code Capital, VMS, Walden International and Scheme Capital while the Series D round was led by Capital Today along with existing investors including Sequoia Capital China, 5Y Capital, Source Code Capital, Legend Star and 01VC.</p>
<p>The latest fundings, which come after its $15 million Series B+ round in March this year, will be used to bolster its robot fleet with technological upgrades, penetrate further to the global market, hire talent, and support its supply chain management.</p>
<p>Hai Robotics, founded in 2016, has five overseas subsidiaries in Hong Kong SAR, Japan, Singapore, the U.S. and the Netherlands with international customers in more than 30 countries. <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/hai-robotics-enters-australia-market-boosts-largest-online-book-retailer-booktopia-s-efficiency-by-800--825474720.html">The company entered Australia in this year</a> by deploying HAI’s warehouse robots at Australia’s largest online bookstore Booktopia to handle packing and dispatch orders.</p>
<p>“Our major future orientation will center on expanding the overseas market and localize our service,” said Richie Chen, Hai Robotics co-founder and CEO.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HPi57DLgBi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/28/exotec-raises-90-million-for-its-warehouse-robots/">Exotec raises $90 million for its warehouse robots</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Exotec raises $90 million for its warehouse robots&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/28/exotec-raises-90-million-for-its-warehouse-robots/embed/#?secret=HPi57DLgBi" data-secret="HPi57DLgBi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Hai Robotics develops an autonomous case-handling (ACR) system that provides warehouse automation solutions via robotics technology and AI algorithms for the logistics warehouse industry. The company said it has more than 400 global patents in areas like robot control and warehouse management, based on its statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The global warehouse automation market is projected to increase to $30 billion by 2026, at a CAGR of 14%, from $15 billion in 2019, based on <a href="https://www.thelogisticsiq.com/research/warehouse-automation-market/">a report by Logistics IQ</a>.</p>
<p>There are a number of startups and larger technology companies building warehouse robotics these days &#8212; industrial applications more generally being one of the earliest and most successful use cases for robots. Others include Fetch Robotics, NextShift Robotics and Alog Tech.</p>
<p>Chen also said the company differs from other global peers in many aspects including project costs and customization capability. Hai Robotics has been running over more than 200 projects globally with 2,000 ACR robots deployed. Its ACR system can be applied in various industries like apparel, e-commerce, retail, manufacturing, 3PL, electronics, pharmaceutical, energy, and automotive.  It has partnered with global logistics and supply chain firms including <a href="https://www.lgcns.com/EN/Home">LG CNS</a>, <a href="https://mujin-corp.com/">MUJIN</a>, <a href="https://www.bps-group.net/en/">BPS Global</a>, and <a href="https://www.savoye.com/en">Savoye</a>.</p>
<p>In 2015, the company launched its first ACR system (called HAIPICK A42), which can pick and place totes and cartons on storage shelves up to 5-7 meters high and carry up to 9 loads to conveyors.</p>
<p>Hai Robotics has several other models in that line.</p>
<p>“The case-handling robot is riding on the market trend that shifts towards smaller workflows, such as from pallet-picking to totes-picking. We’re very pleased to see the company’s fast growth with good innovation,” Guo Shanshan, a partner of Sequoia Capital China said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QDEXoekKIa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/youibot-funding/">SoftBank leads $15M round for China&#8217;s industrial robot maker Youibot</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SoftBank leads $15M round for China&#8217;s industrial robot maker Youibot&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/youibot-funding/embed/#?secret=QDEXoekKIa" data-secret="QDEXoekKIa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6Z1TvOJleQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/robotics-roundup-11/">The fulfilling world of warehouse robotics</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The fulfilling world of warehouse robotics&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/robotics-roundup-11/embed/#?secret=6Z1TvOJleQ" data-secret="6Z1TvOJleQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zUvuHVmgIG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/02/fetch-robotics-ceo-on-the-companys-acquisition-and-the-future-of-warehouse-robots/">Fetch Robotics’ CEO on the company’s acquisition and the future of warehouse robots</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fetch Robotics’ CEO on the company’s acquisition and the future of warehouse robots&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/02/fetch-robotics-ceo-on-the-companys-acquisition-and-the-future-of-warehouse-robots/embed/#?secret=zUvuHVmgIG" data-secret="zUvuHVmgIG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/hai-robotics-picks-up-200m-for-its-warehouse-robot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206458</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Evolito&#8217;s electric motors look set to take off in aerospace where YASA left off in automotive</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/evolitos-electric-motors-look-set-to-take-off-in-aerospace-where-yasa-left-off-in-automotive/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/evolitos-electric-motors-look-set-to-take-off-in-aerospace-where-yasa-left-off-in-automotive/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 07:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric aircraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jet engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercedes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes-Benz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rolls-royce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YASA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Back in July, British “axial-flux” electric motor startup YASA was acquired by Mercedes-Benz for an undisclosed amount. YASA’s electric motors generated considerable EV industry interest because of their efficiency, high power density, small size and low weight. Indeed, Rolls-Royce, best known in aviation for its jet engines, employed YASA engines in its all-electric airplane “Spirit [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Back in July, British “axial-flux” electric motor startup <a href="https://www.yasa.com/">YASA</a> was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/03/acquired-by-mercedes-benz-yasas-revolutionary-electric-motor-is-set-for-big-things/">acquired</a> by Mercedes-Benz for an undisclosed amount. YASA’s electric motors generated considerable EV industry interest because of their efficiency, high power density, small size and low weight.</p>
<p>Indeed, Rolls-Royce, best known in aviation for its jet engines, employed YASA engines in its all-electric airplane “Spirit of Innovation” which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/17/rolls-royces-all-electric-aircraft-completes-15-minute-maiden-voyage/?cx_testId=6&#038;cx_testVariant=cx_undefined&#038;cx_artPos=0#cxrecs_s">recently completed</a> a 15-minute test flight.</p>
<p><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/821d4e30-17b9-11ec-b3f9-f0dd9fabce24.cf_-1.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>But it’s emerged today that there was, to put it mildly, more to the deal than met the eye.</p>
<p>It turns out that a new company, <a href="http://www.evolito.co.uk/">Evolito</a>, was spun out of YASA <em>before</em> its acquisition by Mercedes Benz, taking with it an electric motor it describes as ultra-high performance, low-weight, and most suitable for the aerospace industry.</p>
<p>The prospect now is that Evolito will pick up in the aerospace world where YASA left off in the automotive world. Evolito’s investors lead are Waypoint Capital and Oxford Science Enterprises (OSE).</p>
<p>The implication is that because YASA’s technology has proven itself in high volume production in the automotive industry, Evolito could have particular advantages in aerospace.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pixLWsnTXg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/03/acquired-by-mercedes-benz-yasas-revolutionary-electric-motor-is-set-for-big-things/">Acquired by Mercedes-Benz, YASA&#8217;s revolutionary electric motor is set for big things</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Acquired by Mercedes-Benz, YASA&#8217;s revolutionary electric motor is set for big things&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/03/acquired-by-mercedes-benz-yasas-revolutionary-electric-motor-is-set-for-big-things/embed/#?secret=pixLWsnTXg" data-secret="pixLWsnTXg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Evolito claims its motors are “ultra high-performance, low-weight axial-flux motors&#8221; and its power electronics are &#8220;smaller, lighter and more robust than any other competing technology” with wide potential applications in Electric Vertical Take-off and Landing (eVTOL), Fixed Wing and distributed electric propulsion applications such as Urban Air Mobility (UAM).</p>
<p>Gareth Morris, Managing Director, Evolito said: “Electrification in aerospace is some ten years behind that of the automotive industry, but the market potential is huge. Electric Vertical Take-off and Landing, Electric Helicopter, Fixed-Wing, and Urban Air Mobility aircraft need high power density, low weight electric powertrains with inherently high safety factors &#8211; a combination of attributes that are unique to our axial-flux electric motor and power electronics. By leveraging YASA’s unique IP in the aerospace market, Evolito will fast-track the commercialization of electric flight and transform mobility as we know it.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2206333" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2206333" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png" alt="Evolito Motor" width="1024" height="1024" class="size-full wp-image-2206333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Evolito-Motor.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2206333" class="wp-caption-text">Evolito Motor</p></div></p>
<p>Many of these claims appear to ring true. After personally visiting the YASA factory and having the advantages of the “topology” of its engine explained in great detail, I would be extremely hard-pressed to argue against the claims made for it. It’s this technology that Evolito is now taking forward into the aerospace industry, and it looks like it will be a very bright future indeed.</p>
<p>Cyrus Jilla, Partner and Board Director, Waypoint Capital said: “At Waypoint, one of our thematic interests is in energy transition and sustainability, including electrification. We look to invest in businesses with unique disruptive technology led by outstanding teams. Evolito is a perfect fit for us and we look forward to backing the team as they develop their game-changing electrification solutions for the aerospace market, making emissions-free flight a reality.”</p>
<p>Alexis Zervoglos, Senior Partner, OSE added: “The electrification of flight is one of the most exciting market opportunities of our time. Realizing this potential will require innovative new technology and an ability to scale to meet the fast-emerging demand. OSE is delighted to be supporting Evolito on its mission to accelerate the adoption of electric flight.”</p>
<p>The market for electric drive solutions for urban applications is forecast to grow to $90 billion and 160,000 vehicles by 2050, according to some industry experts.</p>
<p>(Just no-one tell them about <a href="https://silicon-valley.fandom.com/wiki/Aviato">Aviato</a>, ok?)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/evolitos-electric-motors-look-set-to-take-off-in-aerospace-where-yasa-left-off-in-automotive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206307</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fintech startup Tag valued at $100 million in Pakistan&#8217;s largest seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/fintech-startup-tag-valued-at-100-million-in-pakistans-largest-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/fintech-startup-tag-valued-at-100-million-in-pakistans-largest-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 07:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Addition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airlift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bazaar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BridgeLinx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canaan Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lee Fixel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pakistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tag]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206460</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tag, a one-year-old startup that offers banking and financial services to users in Pakistan, has raised over $12 million in what is now the largest seed financing round in the South Asian market. Liberty City Ventures, Canaan Partners, Addition, Mantis and Banana Capital and others financed the round, which brings YC-backed Tag’s to-date raise to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tag, a one-year-old startup that offers banking and financial services to users in Pakistan, has raised over $12 million in what is now the largest seed financing round in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>Liberty City Ventures, Canaan Partners, Addition, Mantis and Banana Capital and others financed the round, which brings YC-backed Tag’s to-date raise to over $17.5 million. This is the firm time many of these investors, including Lee Fixel’s Addition, have invested in a startup in Pakistan.</p>
<p>The round values Tag at $100 million, two people involved in the deal told TechCrunch. The new funding took just two weeks to close, Tag founder and chief executive Talal Gondal told TechCrunch in an interview. He declined to comment on the valuation.</p>
<p>The investor’s excitement to Tag comes as the startup builds one of the crucial railroads for users in Pakistan. “We are trying to become both Revolut and Paytm in Pakistan,” the 29-year-old founder said.</p>
<p><a href="https://tagme.pk">Tag</a> partners with public and private firms to offer their employees banking services including getting their salaries on the Tag account and Visa-powered virtual and physical cards. Signing up on Tag &#8212; which includes some verification of an individual’s identity &#8212; just takes three minutes, he said.</p>
<p>It also provides a range of B2C offerings such as the ability to pay others online and top up utility bills that are available to any user in Pakistan who signs up to the platform.</p>
<p>“We eventually want to offer the complete set of banking and financial services to users in Pakistan,” he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Before starting Tag, Gondal worked as an investor for seven years in Europe. He said he had long decided to return to Pakistan and start a firm to serve people in his home nation, but was waiting for the right moment.</p>
<p>Pakistan’s startup ecosystem has received a major boost this year with the arrival of high-profile investors including those backing Tag as well as Harry Stebbings’ 20 VC and Josh Buckley’s Buckley Ventures.</p>
<p>A group of very young startups have made splashy funding announcements in recent weeks. Quick-commerce startup Airlift unveiled <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/pakistans-airlift-raises-85-million-for-its-quick-commerce-startup-eyes-international-expansion/">a record $85 million Series B last month</a>, followed by business-to-business Bazaar’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/pakistans-b2b-marketplace-and-digital-ledger-platform-bazaar-raises-30-million/">record $30 million Series A round</a>. Last week, the digital freight marketplace BridgeLinx <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/digital-freight-marketplace-bridgelinx-raises-10-million-in-pakistans-largest-seed-funding/">announced a $10 million seed round</a>, which at the time was the nation’s largest. Wednesday&#8217;s announcement also makes Tag one of the most valued firms from Y Combinator&#8217;s recent batches.</p>
<p>Gondal said startups are finally having a moment in the South Asian market. “Each country’s startup ecosystem goes through various waves. In India, we saw e-commerce firms like Flipkart flourish in the first wave. Firms like Ola, Zomato and Swiggy and fintech firms like PhonePe and Paytm made inroads in the waves after that,” he said, adding that he saw a similar trend in Berlin.</p>
<p>“I had the conviction that a similar thing would play out in Pakistan.”</p>
<p>Gondal said the startup is now working to broaden its product offerings and hire talent to win the trust of the market.</p>
<p>“Liberty City Ventures is proud to support a visionary leader like Talal in his efforts to expand financial inclusion for the underserved and underbanked,” said Murtaza Akbar, Managing Partner at Liberty City Ventures, in a statement. “We expect the world class team he has assembled at TAG to build a regional Fintech powerhouse.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/fintech-startup-tag-valued-at-100-million-in-pakistans-largest-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206460</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mexico&#8217;s Kavak drives away with $700M in new funding, doubling its valuation to $8.7B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/mexicos-kavak-raises-700m-for-its-used-car-marketplace-doubling-its-valuation-to-8-7b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/mexicos-kavak-raises-700m-for-its-used-car-marketplace-doubling-its-valuation-to-8-7b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Valkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial inclusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kavak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LATAM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mexico city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kavak, a Mexico City-based startup that operates a pre-owned car marketplace in Latin America, announced today that it has raised a massive $700 million in a Series E round that more than doubles the company’s valuation to $8.7 billion. This news is notable for a few reasons. For one, it’s a staggering sum for any [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.kavak.com/">Kavak</a>, a Mexico City-based startup that operates a pre-owned car marketplace in Latin America, announced today that it has raised a massive $700 million in a Series E round that more than doubles the company’s valuation to $8.7 billion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This news is notable for a few reasons. For one, it’s a staggering sum for any startup, much less one based in Latin America. Also, news of this raise comes just five months after Kavak <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/mexican-unicorn-kavak-raises-a-485m-series-d-at-a-4b-valuation/">raised $485 million in a Series D at a $4 billion valuation</a>. The investment also marks the second time this year that Kavak has doubled its valuation. (The company only achieved unicorn status last October.) And lastly, the round makes Kavak the second most valuable startup in all of Latin America &#8212; the first being Brazilian fintech Nubank, which </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/fintech-all-star-nubank-raises-a-750m-mega-round/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">earlier this year</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was valued at $30 billion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cambridge, Massachusetts-based General Catalyst led Kavak’s Series E, which brings the company’s total raised to over $1.5 billion since its 2016 inception. Tiger Global, Spruce House, D1, SEA, Founders Fund, Ribbit Capital, SoftBank and others also participated in the latest financing.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yOqjjWzKBJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/why-global-investors-are-flocking-to-back-latin-american-startups/">Why global investors are flocking to back Latin American startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why global investors are flocking to back Latin American startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/why-global-investors-are-flocking-to-back-latin-american-startups/embed/#?secret=yOqjjWzKBJ" data-secret="yOqjjWzKBJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Put simply, Kavak is an online marketplace that aims to bring transparency, security and access to financing to the used car market. It promises to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ensure “reliable” transactions that mitigate fraud and aims to raise used car standards from a mechanical and safety point of view by using artificial intelligence and data technology. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company also offers its own financing through its fintech arm, Kavak Capital, which it launched about 18 months ago. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I like to describe it as if Spotify, Amazon, Toyota and Citibank had a kid, then something like Kavak would be born,” said Kavak co-founder and CEO Carlos García Ottati in an interview with TechCrunch.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clearly, the company&#8217;s business model seems to be working. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kavak has been doubling its revenue every three to five months, according to García Ottati. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And over the last 14 months, it’s no surprise &#8212; considering the increase in its valuation and all the capital it has raised &#8212; that Kavak has grown exponentially &#8212; from 300 to more than 5,000 employees in Latin America, to meet what </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">García Ottati describes as strong demand.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The startup currently has 40 logistic and reconditioning hubs in Mexico, Brazil and Argentina. That compares to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> more than 2,500 employees and 20 logistics and reconditioning hubs in Mexico and Argentina at the time of its last raise in April.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Over the years, it has served &#8220;hundreds of thousands&#8221; of customers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What excites me about this raise is a reflection of Kavak’s ambition we have and what we want to build, and less so about need,” he said. “Most importantly, it’s going to allow us to think long term and build a true generational company.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Financial inclusion is a big part of Kavak’s mission in addition to wanting to make it easier for people to own cars, and thus improve their professional and personal lives, added García Ottati, who was inspired to start the company after his own challenges selling a car in Colombia and trying to buy one in Mexico.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">If we do our job well, in the next 20 years, the middle class should grow up by 30% in emerging markets just by granting financing products to a huge amount of people that are excluded today, giving them a tool that can definitely enhance their lives,” he said. &#8220;We want to be a s</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">uper app, or an ecosystem of services, that empowers mobility and financial health and do more than just help people buy and sell cars.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, Kavak plans to use its new capital in part to expand across Latin America, with plans to begin operating in several other markets over the next 12 months. Longer term, it is eyeing an expansion into “other emerging markets” globally. It also plans to continue hiring &#8212; particularly engineers and product folks &#8212; as well double down on product development.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">García Ottati is also excited about the impact Kavak&#8217;s raise has on the Latin American startup scene as a whole.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s wonderful bringing in new funds who had not previously invested in the region to see how LatAm looks and works,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They can see that we are addressing deep and big issues.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">General Catalyst Managing Director Adam Valkin believes the startup </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">has established itself as “the clear leader” in Latin America&#8217;s pre-owned car market. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The company has developed a playbook for providing a transformational customer experience with a compelling and efficient economic model,” he said in a written statement. “We are excited for Kavak to expand into other emerging markets where a similar opportunity exists to drive financial inclusion and empower the middle class through access to car ownership.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vnbDw1A9QO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/">Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/embed/#?secret=vnbDw1A9QO" data-secret="vnbDw1A9QO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/mexicos-kavak-raises-700m-for-its-used-car-marketplace-doubling-its-valuation-to-8-7b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206358</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian buy now, pay later startup ZestMoney raises $50 million from Australia&#8217;s Zip</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/indian-buy-now-pay-later-startup-zestmoney-raises-50-million-from-australias-zip/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/indian-buy-now-pay-later-startup-zestmoney-raises-50-million-from-australias-zip/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 05:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zestmoney]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ZestMoney, a Bangalore-based buy now, pay later platform, said on Wednesday it has raised $50 million in a new financing round from Australia’s Zip as the Indian firm looks to double down on a trend that has shown early signs of traction in several global markets. The eight-year-old Australian firm, which has a presence in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">ZestMoney, a Bangalore-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/18/zestmoney-goldman-sachs/">buy now, pay later platform</a>, said on Wednesday it has raised $50 million in a new financing round from Australia’s Zip as the Indian firm looks to double down on a trend that has shown early signs of traction in several global markets.</p>
<p>The eight-year-old Australian firm, which has a presence in 12 markets across five continents, is acquiring a minority stake in ZestMoney as part of the new Series C financing round, the two said.</p>
<p>ZestMoney said in a statement the new financing round hasn’t closed as existing investors will be participating in it as well. The startup, which has raised over $110 million to date, counts Goldman Sachs, Quona Capital, PayU, and Xiaomi among its early backers.</p>
<p>The buy now, pay later market remains at a nascent stage in India, where only a fraction of the population has a credit card. But a handful of startups including ZestMoney, Capital Float, and LazyPay are beginning to show traction in a market largely dominated by traditional giant Bajaj Finance.</p>
<p>The low penetration of credit cards in India has meant that very few people in the nation have a traditional credit score that banks heavily rely on to establish one’s credit worthiness before issuing them a loan. Moreover, small loans don’t generate lucrative returns for banks, giving them less incentive to write such cheques.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2206447" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2206447" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2206447 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/zestmoney.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="255" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/zestmoney.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/zestmoney.jpg?resize=150,37 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/zestmoney.jpg?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/zestmoney.jpg?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/zestmoney.jpg?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/zestmoney.jpg?resize=1536,383 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/zestmoney.jpg?resize=50,12 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2206447" class="wp-caption-text">Image credits: Bernstein Research</p></div></p>
<p>ZestMoney says it assesses other data points and uses AI to help these people build a profile and become credit-worthy.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup, which said it has amassed over 11 million users and has 25 banking and non-banking financial partners, works with large merchants such as Amazon, Flipkart, Google Pay, Apple and Xiaomi to offer its BNPL services to customers. ZestMoney has presence across over 75,000 physical stores and more than 10,000 online sites, it said.</p>
<p>The startup’s offering starts at as low as 50 Indian rupees (68 cents) to $6,777 and the duration of the payback period ranges between a month to two years.</p>
<p>“This is a deep validation of our position as market leader in the Buy Now Pay Later category in India. The shift towards Pay Later solutions is a global phenomenon and represents young digital consumers looking for transparency, honesty and no hidden charges in financial products,” said Lizzie Chapman, co-founder and chief executive of ZestMoney, in a statement.</p>
<p>“We believe India will leapfrog traditional products like credit cards, along with many other emerging markets, going straight to digital payment solutions. Over the last year we have seen applications for BNPL go up by 5X on our platform. We continue to invest in deepening partnerships with our merchant network and hiring the best talent. We strongly believe India will emerge as the largest BNPL market in the world over the next 5 years.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/indian-buy-now-pay-later-startup-zestmoney-raises-50-million-from-australias-zip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206446</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indonesian halal-focused social commerce startup Evermos lands $30M Series B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/indonesian-social-commerce-startup-evermos-lands-30m-series-b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/indonesian-social-commerce-startup-evermos-lands-30m-series-b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia Impact Investment Fund II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evermos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UOB Venture Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2204211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Evermos is an Indonesian social commerce startup with two goals: to let people earn extra income by opening online stores without spending capital and to help small brands grow into household names. The company, which focuses on halal products and other items for Muslim customers, announced today it has raised a $30 million Series B, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2204212" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2204212" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2204212" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Founder-of-Evermos-From-Left-to-Right-President-and-Co-Founder-Arip-Tirta-Co-Founder-Ghufron-Mustaqim-CEO-and-Co-Founder-Iqbal-Muslimin-and-Co-Founder-Ilham-Taufiq-.jpg" alt="Evermos’ founding team (from left to right): Arip Tirta, Ghufron Mustaqim, Iqbal Muslimin and Ilham Taufiq" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Founder-of-Evermos-From-Left-to-Right-President-and-Co-Founder-Arip-Tirta-Co-Founder-Ghufron-Mustaqim-CEO-and-Co-Founder-Iqbal-Muslimin-and-Co-Founder-Ilham-Taufiq-.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Founder-of-Evermos-From-Left-to-Right-President-and-Co-Founder-Arip-Tirta-Co-Founder-Ghufron-Mustaqim-CEO-and-Co-Founder-Iqbal-Muslimin-and-Co-Founder-Ilham-Taufiq-.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Founder-of-Evermos-From-Left-to-Right-President-and-Co-Founder-Arip-Tirta-Co-Founder-Ghufron-Mustaqim-CEO-and-Co-Founder-Iqbal-Muslimin-and-Co-Founder-Ilham-Taufiq-.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Founder-of-Evermos-From-Left-to-Right-President-and-Co-Founder-Arip-Tirta-Co-Founder-Ghufron-Mustaqim-CEO-and-Co-Founder-Iqbal-Muslimin-and-Co-Founder-Ilham-Taufiq-.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Founder-of-Evermos-From-Left-to-Right-President-and-Co-Founder-Arip-Tirta-Co-Founder-Ghufron-Mustaqim-CEO-and-Co-Founder-Iqbal-Muslimin-and-Co-Founder-Ilham-Taufiq-.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Founder-of-Evermos-From-Left-to-Right-President-and-Co-Founder-Arip-Tirta-Co-Founder-Ghufron-Mustaqim-CEO-and-Co-Founder-Iqbal-Muslimin-and-Co-Founder-Ilham-Taufiq-.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2204212" class="wp-caption-text">Evermos’ founding team (l to r): Arip Tirta, Ghufron Mustaqim, Iqbal Muslimin and Ilham Taufiq. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Evermos</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://evermos.com/home/">Evermos</a> is an Indonesian social commerce startup with two goals: to let people earn extra income by opening online stores without spending capital and to help small brands grow into household names. The company, which focuses on halal products and other items for Muslim customers, announced today it has raised a $30 million Series B, led by UOB Venture Management’s Asia Impact Investment Fund II. Other participants included IFC, MDI Ventures, Telkomsel Mitra Innovation (TMI) and Future Shape, along with returning investors Jungle Ventures and Shunwei Capital.</p>
<p>The funding will be used on hiring, enhancing Evermos&#8217; recommendation engine and other AI-based tech, and entering new regions in Indonesia. The company says it currently has 100,000 active resellers in more than 500 Tier 2 and Tier 3 cities, mostly in Java. Its goal is to reach more than one million resellers throughout Indonesia over the next five years.</p>
<p>On the supply side, Evermos works with more than 500 brands, primarily small Indonesian businesses, and sells fashion, halal health and beauty products, and food and beverages. The company says its total transaction volume has increased by more than 60 times over the last two years.</p>
<p>Evermos was founded in November 2018 by Ghufron Mustaqim, Iqbal Muslimin, Ilham Taufiq and Arip Tirta. Mustaqim told TechCrunch that the team was motivated by its dissatisfaction with many retail practices in Indonesia. For example, this includes multiple layers of distribution that hike up prices and the proliferation of fake products online, which makes many people wary of buying from e-commerce marketplaces.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JeUlRN5Zr4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/super-an-indonesian-hyperlocal-social-commerce-startup-raises-28m-led-by-softbank-ventures-asia/">Super, an Indonesian hyperlocal social commerce startup, raises $28M led by SoftBank Ventures Asia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Super, an Indonesian hyperlocal social commerce startup, raises $28M led by SoftBank Ventures Asia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/super-an-indonesian-hyperlocal-social-commerce-startup-raises-28m-led-by-softbank-ventures-asia/embed/#?secret=JeUlRN5Zr4" data-secret="JeUlRN5Zr4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We’re trying to solve these problems by innovating with the social commerce model, so resellers can help customers pick the right products in a more efficient way,” Mustaqim said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Almost 90% of Indonesians are Muslim, so “when you say we target the Muslim market, we are targeting almost all of Indonesia,” he added. “We carefully curate the products onboarded to our platform, and one of the most important aspects is whether it’s relevant to the Muslim market. For example, it has to be halal, if it’s fashion it has be modest fashion.”</p>
<p>Evermos does not require resellers to buy inventory. Instead, resellers market items picked from Evermos’ catalog to their social circles, including family, friends and neighbors, through WhatsApp, Facebook and other apps. Resellers have an online landing page created on Evermos&#8217; app and can send links about products to customers, but Mustaqim says most sales happen through chat.</p>
<p>Evermos handles inventory, logistics and customer support. Like many other social commerce startups in Indonesia, including Super, KitaBeli and ChiliBeli, Evermos focuses on smaller cities, where e-commerce penetration is lower because of factors like higher shipping costs. To keep shipping costs down, Evermos resellers often group their customers’ orders into batches. Products are usually sent to them from the brands’ own warehouses via third-party logistics providers, but Evermos is currently building inventory analytics and a network of warehouses to stock products closer to resellers.</p>
<p>Mustaqim says brands usually pay 30% commission on products sold through Evermos, and the company shares most of that with resellers. Evermos’ top resellers earn about $200 USD a month, or about the monthly minimum wage in most Indonesian provinces.</p>
<p>Since most of Evermos’ resellers are selling online for the first time, it provides in-app training modules (and occasional offline training events, too). This includes advice on curating inventory, how to use Evermos’ platform to make orders and use its promotional programs and product copywriting.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="U7KMzMTbOH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/indonesian-social-commerce-app-kitabeli-gets-10m-led-by-go-ventures/">Indonesian social commerce app KitaBeli gets $10M led by Go Ventures</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Indonesian social commerce app KitaBeli gets $10M led by Go Ventures&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/indonesian-social-commerce-app-kitabeli-gets-10m-led-by-go-ventures/embed/#?secret=U7KMzMTbOH" data-secret="U7KMzMTbOH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>So far, Evermos has focused primarily on Java, but plans to expand into other regions of Indonesia. Its strategies for reaching one million resellers in five years include running ads and a program where resellers get one-time commissions for referring new sellers to the platform. Mustaqim says over-penetration won’t be a problem because resellers usually focus on a handful of product categories, so even people located in the same community won’t necessarily be competing with one another.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/indonesian-social-commerce-startup-evermos-lands-30m-series-b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2204211</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Foxconn says Thailand EV factory will begin producing 50,000 units by 2023</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/foxconn-says-thailand-ev-factory-will-begin-producing-50000-units-by-2023/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/foxconn-says-thailand-ev-factory-will-begin-producing-50000-units-by-2023/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 23:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EVs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fisker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foxconn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PTT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taiwan-based smartphone manufacturing giant Foxconn and national Thailand oil supplier PTT PLC are moving forward with an agreement to start an electric vehicle manufacturing facility in Thailand. The facility is expected to begin rolling out vehicles by 2023. Foxconn had previously reported plans to begin building factories in both Thailand and the U.S. next year. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Taiwan-based smartphone manufacturing giant Foxconn and national Thailand oil supplier PTT PLC are moving forward with an agreement to start an electric vehicle manufacturing facility in Thailand. The facility is expected to begin rolling out vehicles by 2023. Foxconn had previously reported plans to begin building factories in both Thailand and the U.S. next year.</p>
<p>Foxconn and PTT signed a memorandum of understanding to cooperate on EV production in June, with PTT owning 60% of the joint venture and Foxconn owning the remaining 40%. The initial production capacity of the Thailand facility will be around 50,000 units, which Foxconn says will increase three-fold by 2030. The Thailand plant officially marks Foxconn as an automaker in its own right, but the company is also working with EV maker Fisker on a U.S. manufacturing plant, which should also start production in 2023. The two companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/fisker-and-foxconn-sign-deal-to-build-electric-vehicles/">signed a joint agreement, called Project PEAR</a>, in May.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3jtt4mv5jt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/fisker-and-foxconn-sign-deal-to-build-electric-vehicles/">Fisker and Foxconn sign deal to build electric vehicles</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fisker and Foxconn sign deal to build electric vehicles&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/fisker-and-foxconn-sign-deal-to-build-electric-vehicles/embed/#?secret=3jtt4mv5jt" data-secret="3jtt4mv5jt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“Thailand is fairly new in terms of supply and demand with limited manufacturers producing in the country,&#8221; said Bakar Sadik Agwan, senior automotive analyst at GlobalData, a data and analytics consulting company, in a statement. &#8220;With conducive policies and heritage in auto manufacturing, Thailand offers much more value to Foxconn compared to other markets. The company also has a manufacturing partnership in China with Byton, but it is reportedly on hold now. While China may be the largest EV market, it faces overcapacity issues due to the EV market being fragmented, which will affect many automakers’ ability to make enough margin.”</p>
<p>Thailand&#8217;s government has become a major supporter of Foxconn because it hopes to be a future &#8220;EV hub&#8221; and increase its EV share in total capacity to 30% by 2030 by incentivizing local production.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/foxconn-says-thailand-ev-factory-will-begin-producing-50000-units-by-2023/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206288</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Project44 acquires Convey for $255M to provide end-to-end supply chain visibility</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/project44-acquires-convey-for-225m-to-provide-end-to-end-supply-chain-visibility/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/project44-acquires-convey-for-225m-to-provide-end-to-end-supply-chain-visibility/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 23:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Convey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[project44]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206237</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Real-time supply chain visibility company project44 has acquired last-mile tech platform Convey for $255 million. Together, the two companies will combine forces to provide end-to-end supply chain visibility, from the raw materials to the front door. The acquisition will bolster project44&#8217;s &#8220;Real-time Transportation Visibility Platform&#8221; (RTTVP), which provides information on shipments in transit across all [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Real-time supply chain visibility company project44 has acquired last-mile tech platform Convey for $255 million. Together, the two companies will combine forces to provide end-to-end supply chain visibility, from the raw materials to the front door.</p>
<p>The acquisition will bolster project44&#8217;s &#8220;Real-time Transportation Visibility Platform&#8221; (RTTVP), which provides information on shipments in transit across all modes and geographies, as well as precise ETAs for deliveries, with enhanced last-mile, direct-to-consumer delivery experiences. With the acquisition, project44 will have access to Convey&#8217;s global customer base, including over 200 major brands like The Home Depot, Nieman Marcus and Ferguson Enterprises.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“project44 is solving today’s most critical business challenge &#8211; how to deliver on continuously evolving customer expectations while remaining operationally efficient during unprecedented uncertainty and growing complexity,” said Jett McCandless, CEO and founder of project44, in a statement. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The stakes are high for companies to not only fulfill and ship orders but to make the right promises about availability and delivery. However, volatile conditions, overwhelming complexity and blind spots in the supply chain make this difficult to achieve.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Supply chain management is a hot topic the world over, with more customers relying on e-commerce for goods and experiencing unprecedented delays. The global supply chain management market size was valued at $15.85 billion in 2019, and it&#8217;s expected to reach $37.41 billion by 2027, according to an <a href="https://www.alliedmarketresearch.com/supply-chain-management-software-market">Allied Market Research report from 2020</a>. As manufacturers around the world are still reeling from supply chain disruptions due to the pandemic, it&#8217;s not hard to see why. In a <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1182233/impact-covid-19-supply-chain/">2020 survey</a>, 35% of respondents said cross-border transportation delays had an impact on their business.</p>
<p>The Convey acquisition now allows project44 to connect over 880 global shippers and third-party logistics providers with a network of 113,000 carriers, 2.6 million assets and more than 9 billion last-mile shipment events, according to the company. The outcome for clients should be optimized costs, growth in revenue, faster shipping and service and a better delivery experience overall.</p>
<p>Convey also brings the ability to resolve parcel delivery issues through its automated customer communication service, so project44 customers can spend less time dealing with customer service manually and more time focused on core business capabilities.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“With thousands of shipments in-flight at any point in time and the details around those orders living in many disparate systems across our organization, it can be difficult to figure out which ones need our immediate attention,” Devin Van Hout, vice president of digital commerce at Ferguson Enterprises, said in a statement. “Convey’s solution gives our team all the information we need to go from reactive to proactive, while also providing us with the tools to communicate with all relevant parties within the same view. The result is a simple, consistent customer experience in the face of massive B2B complexity.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This is project44&#8217;s third acquisition this year, including Ocean Insights and ClearMetal. With each acquisition, project44 has been able to integrate new tech stacks in order to create a much shorter turnaround time for customers, according to the company. Earlier this month, <a href="https://www.project44.com/blog/why-google-selected-project44-as-its-first-strategic-supply-chain-visibility-partner">Google chose project44</a> as its first strategic visibility partner for its Google Cloud Supply Chain Twin solution, an initiative designed to help organizations solve complex supply chain challenges.</p>
<p>With a $1.2 billion valuation status achieved earlier this year, project44 is quickly becoming one of the largest real-time logistics companies and a leader in the space.</p>
<p><em>Update: A previous version of this article stated the Convey acquisition was worth $225 million. It has been updated to reflect the accurate amount. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/project44-acquires-convey-for-225m-to-provide-end-to-end-supply-chain-visibility/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206237</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: New PayPal &#8216;super app&#8217; offers consumers a suite of personal finance features</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/daily-crunch-65/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/daily-crunch-65/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 22:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello from day one of Disrupt. I just hopped out of watching Battlefield companies pitch &#8212; more on them below! &#8212; to write this for you. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">Disrupt</a> is looking smooth, impressive and <em>very</em> TechCrunch so far.</p>
<p>I know it’s cliche, but I’m incredibly proud of what the TechCrunch crew managed for this year’s Main Event. A big hug to the TechCrunch <strong>events team</strong>, the <strong>sales team</strong>, the <strong>tech crew</strong>, <strong>editors</strong> and <strong>everyone else</strong> that makes this publication work but that you don’t see.</p>
<p>Now, the news! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/the-iphone-13-pro-goes-to-disneyland/"><strong>Matthew takes the new iPhone to Disneyland:</strong></a><strong> </strong>If you were curious what the platonic ideal of a Matthew Panzarino post is, it’s this. <a href="https://twitter.com/panzer">Panz</a> is our editor-in-chief, one of our Apple reviewers, a photog and a Disney fan. So, he brought all of that together to get some real-world testing done on the latest flagship iPhone. Enjoy!</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/instacart-shopper-activist-group-asks-customers-to-delete-the-app-until-demands-for-better-conditions-are-met/">Gig workers protest Instacart:</a> </strong>The history of leading boycotts of gig-work platforms is spotty in terms of impact, but that isn’t stopping thousands of Instacart shoppers from raising their voices as a collective. This time ‘round the Gig Workers Collective is asking “that customers refrain from reinstalling the app until five demands are met.” Those demands include a higher default tip and changes to commissions.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/paypal-launches-its-super-app-combining-payments-savings-bill-pay-crypto-shopping-and-more/"><strong>PayPal rolls out financial “super app:”</strong></a> Super apps are like other apps, but more stuffed with features and capabilities. Perhaps best known as major players in various Asian economies’ digital realms, PayPal wants to bring the model to the United States. It’s new Super Duper Excellent App will include “direct deposit, bill pay, a digital wallet, peer-to-peer payments, shopping tools, crypto capabilities and more” TechCrunch reports.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Let’s start with a host of Battlefield companies, coming straight from pitching at Disrupt earlier today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Built by a refugee, <strong>Enlight’s</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/built-by-a-refugee-enlights-edtech-tool-bets-it-can-help-students-hope-harder/">edtech tool bets it can help students hope harder.</a></li>
<li><strong>Luos</strong> is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/luos-is-building-an-api-to-help-embedded-engineers-connect-easily-to-any-hardware-component/">building an API to help embedded engineers connect easily to any hardware component.</a></li>
<li>Nigerian fintech <strong>Hervest</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/nigerian-fintech-hervest-wants-to-bring-financial-inclusion-to-more-african-women/">wants to bring financial inclusion to more African women.</a></li>
<li><strong>Tatum</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/tatum-lets-you-interact-with-blockchains-using-api-calls/">lets you interact with blockchains using API calls.</a></li>
<li><strong>Happaning</strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/happaning-aims-to-be-a-google-street-view-for-video/"> aims to be a &#8220;Google Street View&#8221; for video.</a></li>
<li><strong>Folio’s</strong> 24-year-old founder is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/folios-24-year-old-founder-is-bootstrapping-a-curated-online-bookstore/">bootstrapping a curated, online bookstore.</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And then there was everything else:</p>
<ul>
<li>French marketplace startup <strong>Mirakl</strong> has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/marketplace-platform-mirakl-raises-555-million-at-3-5-billion-valuation/">landed a $555 million round at a $3.5 billion valuation</a> &#8212; a huge check for its SaaS play. Silver Lake led.</li>
<li>The foundation behind <strong>Raspberry Pi</strong> minicomputers has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/raspberry-pi-gets-45m-to-meet-demand-for-low-cost-pcs-and-iot/">raised a $45 million round at a $500 million valuation</a>. London-based Lansdowne Partners and The Ezrah Charitable Trust led the round.</li>
<li><strong>Just</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/just-insure-raises-8m/">raised $8 million to make better car insurance</a>, a model that takes lots of capital and patience. Thus <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/06/a-lot-of-cash-and-little-love-an-insurtech-story/?tpcc=ECTW2020">we have learned</a> from watching both Root and MetroMile.</li>
<li>Korea-based <strong>Business Canvas</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/business-canvas-a-korea-based-document-management-saas-company-closes-2-5m-seed-round/">raised $2.5 million in a seed round</a> for its document management service called “<strong>Typed</strong>.” Mirae Asset Venture Investment led the deal.</li>
<li>Bilt Rewards, a fintech that helps renters earn points while paying rent, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/bilt-rewards-banks-60m-growth-on-a-350m-valuation-to-advance-credit-card-benefits-for-renters/">snagged a $60 million round at a $350 million valuation</a>. Wells Fargo and Mastercard led, which makes pretty good sense. Points for sharing the new valuation, Bilt.</li>
<li><strong>Pipe</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/pipe-snaps-up-former-stripe-and-hubspot-execs/">snags former Stripe, HubSpot execs, expands to the U.K.</a> Selling recurring revenues for cash is big business, Pipe shows. The company deals with both recurring software incomes and DTC subscriptions.</li>
<li>Finally, <strong>Sorare</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/20/sorare-raises-680-million-for-its-fantasy-sports-nft-game/">raised $680 million at a $4.3 billion valuation.</a> The company has created a fantasy football program based on NFTs. People love fantasy sports. Some folks are also really into NFTs. Perhaps at the union of both there is a big business? SoftBank certainly thinks so, leading this particular Series B.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Seth Rogen explains how Houseplant promotes cannabis without breaking the rules</h2>
<p>Many celebrities have turned their personal interests into thriving commercial concerns: Ryan Reynolds owns Aviation Gin, Jessica Alba founded nontoxic goods startup The Honest Company, and George Clooney will earn as much as $1 billion for selling his tequila company.</p>
<p>This year, actor Seth Rogen co-founded Houseplant, which sells pottery, cannabis and related accessories.</p>
<p>“We’ve sold house goods in all 50 states at this point,” Rogen explained. “That’s us, developing a relationship and trust with customers in places where weed is not legal yet.”</p>
<p>In a conversation with Managing Editor Matt Burns at TechCrunch Disrupt, Rogen, CEO Mike Mohr and chief commercial officer Haneen Davies discussed some of the challenges of brand-building within the confines of a strict regulatory environment.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think the merger of House and Plant is what’s going to help us establish a brand name that goes beyond the limiting restrictions you have to abide by to communicate cannabis,&#8221; said Davies.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UtQESaPBoZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/seth-rogen-explains-how-houseplant-promotes-cannabis-without-breaking-the-rules/">Seth Rogen explains how Houseplant promotes cannabis without breaking the rules</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Seth Rogen explains how Houseplant promotes cannabis without breaking the rules&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/seth-rogen-explains-how-houseplant-promotes-cannabis-without-breaking-the-rules/embed/#?secret=UtQESaPBoZ" data-secret="UtQESaPBoZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/facebook-adds-a-battery-powered-smart-screen-to-the-portal-line/"><strong>Facebook’s product response to its very bad week is a battery-powered Portal:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Sure, the WSJ is breaking news left and right that makes Facebook appear sneaky at best and downright mendacious at worst. But that isn’t stopping Facebook’s hardware team from releasing new gear.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/roblox-to-add-opt-in-age-verification-for-players-and-developers/"><strong>Roblox intros new age check:</strong></a> It’s optional, but the move is probably a little overdue and overall smart. Roblox is a gaming platform that kids love. Kids need protection. Here’s some!</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/tumblrs-subscription-product-post-enters-open-beta-after-much-scrutiny-from-users/"><strong>Former Yahoo company Tumblr moves subscription product to open beta:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Ah, Yahoo. In a different life (iteration?), Yahoo was busy snapping up companies of all sorts. One such company it plunked down a mint for was Tumblr. Now Tumblr is owned by Automattic, after Verizon sold it. And then Verizon sold the rest of its media assets &#8212; TechCrunch included &#8212; to a private equity firm. Anyhoo, Tumblr’s push into the creator economy is now in open beta. Enjoy.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/amazons-kindle-paperwhite-returns-with-a-bigger-screen-usb-c-and-wireless-charging/"><strong>Amazon refreshes the Kindle Paperwhite:</strong></a><strong> </strong>This one took us by surprise, but Amazon’s Kindle lineup just got an updated SKU. The new Paperwhite has a larger screen, thinner bezels and USB-C charging.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Are you all caught up on last week’s coverage of growth marketing? If not, read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/17/tips-for-managing-growth-across-ios-updates/">here</a>.</p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9M9B78Fy8Z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/17/tips-for-managing-growth-across-ios-updates/">Tips for managing growth across iOS updates</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tips for managing growth across iOS updates&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/17/tips-for-managing-growth-across-ios-updates/embed/#?secret=9M9B78Fy8Z" data-secret="9M9B78Fy8Z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/daily-crunch-65/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206082</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Straffr is a smart resistance band that helps you exercise on the go</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/straffr-is-a-smart-resistance-band-that-helps-you-exercise-on-the-go/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/straffr-is-a-smart-resistance-band-that-helps-you-exercise-on-the-go/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 22:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connected hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peloton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Alley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Alley 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strength training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 Hardware]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Smart fitness gear is often limited by being static and non-portable. (And, well, eye-wateringly expensive.) Think Peloton&#8216;s stationary bike for spin classes or wall-mounted strength training rig Tonal. Great if you&#8217;re at home and can afford to shell out thousands on a fancy home gym, but what if you want to take your workout with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Smart fitness gear is often limited by being static and non-portable. (And, well, eye-wateringly expensive.) Think <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/peloton-launches-new-bike-and-tread-smart-home-gym-equipment-both-at-2495/">Peloton</a>&#8216;s stationary bike for spin classes or wall-mounted strength training rig <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/tonal-adds-live-classes-to-its-strength-training-workouts/">Tonal</a>. Great if you&#8217;re at home and can afford to shell out thousands on a fancy home gym, but what if you want to take your workout with you wherever you go?</p>
<p>Meet <a href="https://en.straffr.com">Straffr</a>, a German startup that&#8217;s exhibiting at the TechCrunch Disrupt <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/startup-alley/">Startup Alley</a> this week. The company sells a smart fitness band that you can just pop in your backpack and take with you when you hit the road.</p>
<p>Originally opting for a crowdfunding route via <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/straffr/meet-straffr-your-gym-and-personal-trainer-to-go">Kickstarter</a> last year, the hardware startup has gone on to sell &#8220;a few thousand&#8221; bands since getting the product to market in March this year. They&#8217;ve also bagged backing from business angels and have just closed a second seed round with an international investor as they gear up to expand their fledgling fitness business.</p>
<p>Straffr&#8217;s smart resistance band, which comes in either medium or strong strength grades, connects to the companion app using Bluetooth and starts tracking soon as you start stretching and flexing &#8212; providing feedback on your training session, not just on reps but on &#8220;quality&#8221; of exercise, per CEO Stefan Weiss.</p>
<p>The whole band is actually a sensor &#8212; made of an expandable rubber that&#8217;s electrically conductive. Straffr&#8217;s team developed the material and has some patents on it.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s really hard to find and develop a material that stretches over 200% or 300% … and not break and not measure anything,&#8221; Weiss tells TechCrunch. &#8220;When you stretch [the Straffr fitness band] the electrical resistance changes and therefore we can say how much you&#8217;ve stretched the band for a specific exercise.&#8221;</p>
<p>Anyone who&#8217;s tried to do strength training using a (non-smart) resistance band knows it can be pretty tricky to keep focused and engaged without professional guidance. Basically it&#8217;s hard to know if you&#8217;re performing the movements in an optimal way or just mindlessly twanging a piece of rubber. So a sensing element looks like it could add a lot of value to this particular bit of fitness kit.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Straffr&#8217;s smart band clocks your reps, power and velocity as you pull, with the app providing real-time feedback through the workout &#8212; offering verbal cues if you&#8217;re pulling &#8220;too fast&#8221; or nudges to keep things &#8220;slow and even.&#8221; It&#8217;ll also show you overall results of the workout if you&#8217;re a fan of fitness stats.</p>
<p>The app features a selection of workout videos which let you follow along to pre-recorded fitness band sessions, such as HIIT-focused workouts, total body strength training or quick home-office exercises.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203676" style="width: 1316px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203676" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2203676 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-16-at-13.04.18-e1632011078926.png" alt="Straffr is a smart resistance band that helps you exercise on the go" width="1306" height="998" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-16-at-13.04.18-e1632011078926.png 1306w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-16-at-13.04.18-e1632011078926.png?resize=150,115 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-16-at-13.04.18-e1632011078926.png?resize=300,229 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-16-at-13.04.18-e1632011078926.png?resize=768,587 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-16-at-13.04.18-e1632011078926.png?resize=680,520 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-16-at-13.04.18-e1632011078926.png?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1306px) 100vw, 1306px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203676" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Straffr</p></div></p>
<p>Weiss says the startup is building a premium on-demand offer, too &#8212; and has recently onboarded five personal trainers so it can offer one-to-one training sessions. That will be for a future Pro feature. The basic app is free, as the startup is charging for the hardware.</p>
<p>Straffr&#8217;s band costs just over $100 (€99.99), which is very pricey if you&#8217;re comparing it to a non-smart alternative (a basic resistance band can cost just a few dollars). But that&#8217;s a fairly poor comparison, because here you&#8217;re getting a whole fitness package versus just a piece of elastic. So those extra dollars are for relevant exercise content and in-app personalization along with workout quantification and the added motivation of live feedback.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also worth noting that Straffr&#8217;s smart band is considerably cheaper than shelling out for a Peloton or other high-end connected home-gym kit, which is now aiming to lighten people&#8217;s wallets by targeting their workouts.</p>
<p>So, seen from that perspective, Straffr&#8217;s spin on smart fitness kinda looks like a bargain.</p>
<p>Typical buyers so far tend to be either fitness-focused men who are very into the &#8220;quantified self&#8221; trend, per Weiss, or middle-aged women wanting an alternative to fitness classes at the gym. But a humble (but smart) fitness band really could offer something for everyone.</p>
<p>&#8220;Where really we see a future of training with resistance bands is with personal trainers directly,&#8221; Weiss adds. &#8220;One-on-one digital training, on-demand, with personal trainers, with pro athletes, with Olympians that talk you through the whole workout routine, what it does, they&#8217;re training with you, it&#8217;s sweaty training, it&#8217;s motivating for people.&#8221;</p>
<p>Still, if resistance band workouts really aren&#8217;t your jam, Straffr does have plans to develop additional bits of a smart fitness kit. Although Weiss won&#8217;t be drawn on exactly what other connected hardware they&#8217;re cooking up.</p>
<p>&#8220;We do have a product in the pipeline now that we&#8217;re developing internally right now &#8212; and we&#8217;re really excited about it,&#8221; he says, adding: &#8220;I can say it&#8217;s not going to be just a jumping rope which counts.</p>
<p>&#8220;For us it&#8217;s always the combination of functional, really portable training with the component of tracking quality &#8212; the quality of your training. Like how good are you? Are you actually effective? Because if you&#8217;re just counting reps and steps and stuff there&#8217;s obviously a good motivational aspect to it … but we want to also see are these reps really good, are they good quality, are you doing the best you can for the condition you&#8217;re in right now?&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-disrupt-2021-hardware/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/techcrunch-disrupt-2021-hardware-footer.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/straffr-is-a-smart-resistance-band-that-helps-you-exercise-on-the-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203326</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple Wallet is getting verifiable COVID-19 vaccination cards</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/apple-wallet-is-getting-verifiable-covid-19-vaccination-cards/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/apple-wallet-is-getting-verifiable-covid-19-vaccination-cards/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 21:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine passports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2206187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There's a real chance you'll need proof of a COVID-19 vaccination to enter certain venues, and Apple is hoping it can save you some of the hassle of proving you've gotten your shots.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jon Fingas</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jon Fingas is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/defense-department-seeks-nuclear-propulsion-for-small-spacecraft/">Defense Department seeks nuclear propulsion for small spacecraft</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/a-chinese-ev-startup-wants-to-build-a-ridable-robot-unicorn-for-kids/">A Chinese EV startup wants to build a ridable robot unicorn for kids</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">There&#8217;s a real chance you&#8217;ll need proof of a COVID-19 vaccination to enter certain venues, and Apple is hoping it can save you the hassle of digging up an email or carrying a physical card in your pocket. The company is bringing verifiable COVID-19 vaccination cards to Wallet as part of a future <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-13-and-13-mini-review-130035113.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">iPhone</a> software update. The feature will take advantage of the international SMART Health Cards standard (already in use in several states) to produce proof of vaccination, sign it with a private key and create a public key to verify your info.</p>
<p>The just-released iOS 15 already lets you store verifiable vaccination and test results in the Health app using the same standard. You&#8217;ll receive your records through QR codes, downloadable files or healthcare providers who use Health Records on iPhone.</p>
<p>Apple is promising strict privacy for all your data. The company won&#8217;t have access to your imported or shared records, and all info must be encrypted and securely stored when transferred elsewhere. The tech giant also can&#8217;t see your vaccination card or how you&#8217;ve used it. You can share information with &#8220;approved&#8221; third-party apps, but only on a one-time basis.</p>
<p>Apple didn&#8217;t say when it might release the card update. This won&#8217;t thrill you if you&#8217;re anxious about the very concept of sharing your vaccination status with a concert venue or restaurant. However, it should at least streamline the process — important when you&#8217;re already running late for a show.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-wallet-vaccination-card-193036015.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/apple-wallet-is-getting-verifiable-covid-19-vaccination-cards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2206187</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
