<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 05:45:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Vietnamese on-demand e-commerce platform Loship raises $12M at a valuation of $100M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/vietnamese-on-demand-e-commerce-platform-loship-raises-12m-at-a-valuation-of-100m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/vietnamese-on-demand-e-commerce-platform-loship-raises-12m-at-a-valuation-of-100m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 05:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on-demand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185426</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Loship, the Vietnamese on-demand e-commerce platform that started as a reviews app, announced today it has raised $12 million in pre-Series C funding, bringing its valuation to $100 million. The round was co-led by BAce Capital, an Ant Group-backed venture firm, and the direct investment unit of Sun Hung Kai &#38; Co Limited.  Founded in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><a href="https://loship.vn/">Loship</a>, the Vietnamese on-demand e-commerce platform that started as a reviews app, announced today it has raised $12 million in pre-Series C funding, bringing its valuation to $100 million. The round was co-led by BAce Capital, an Ant Group-backed venture firm, and the direct investment unit of Sun Hung Kai &amp; Co Limited.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Founded in 2017, Loship offered one-hour deliveries for a large range of products and services, including food, ride-hailing, medicine and B2B supplies. The company says it has more than 70,000 drivers and 200,000 merchants, and serves about 2 million customers in Hanoi, Ho Chi Minh City, Da Nang, Can Tho and Bien Hoa.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The new round brings Loship’s total raised to $20 million. Its previous funding was a bridge round from MetaPlanet Holdings, <a href="https://www.techinasia.com/skype-cofounder-invests-vietnams-delivery-ecommerce-startup-loship">announced in February 2021</a>. Loship is in the process of raising a Series C, expected to close by the end of this year, and is in advanced talks with investors.</p>
<p class="p1">Co-founder and chief executive officer Trung Hoang Nguyen told TechCrunch that Loship raised a pre-Series C round because “there are so many investors participating in our Series C round that we find it would take a long time to completely close.” As a result, Loship decided to split the round into a pre-Series C and Series C.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">MetaPlanet Holdings returned for the pre-Series C round, which also saw participation from Wealth Well, Prism Ventures and SQ Capital Group (SCCG Ventures Asia). Individual investors included former Starbucks Vice President Mojtaba Ahkbari; FNZ Group APAC chief executive officer Tim Neville; BNP Paribas global macro sales director Ben Fitzpatrick; DASS-Inc founder and CEO Wayne Cowden; EC1 managing partners Simon Eglise; Ilwella Pty Ltd director Quentin Flannery; Prenzler Group director Jonathan Feil; and iVS CEO Milan Reinartz</p>
<p class="p1">Loship’s new funding will be used to expand into new cities and grow verticals like B2B deliveries for small food and beverage businesses and retail stores. As part of the round, BAce Capital founder Benny Chen, the former managing director of Ant Group India, where he invested in Paytm and Zomato, will join Loship’s board of directors.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DD8buWDk2V"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/mio-a-social-commerce-startup-focused-on-smaller-cities-and-rural-areas-in-vietnam-raises-1m-seed/">Mio, a social commerce startup focused on smaller cities and rural areas in Vietnam, raises $1M seed</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mio, a social commerce startup focused on smaller cities and rural areas in Vietnam, raises $1M seed&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/mio-a-social-commerce-startup-focused-on-smaller-cities-and-rural-areas-in-vietnam-raises-1m-seed/embed/#?secret=DD8buWDk2V" data-secret="DD8buWDk2V" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p class="p1">Co-founder and CEO Trung Hoang Nguyen said Loship has a “very clear path to profitability.” The company started out as an online review platform, before people began using it to buy and sell items through chats.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">“Back then, people used our Lozi app the same way as eBay, where they could list their products, buy from and sell to others. However, we couldn’t really know whether the transaction via Lozi was completed, especially when it was purely online chat,” Nguyen told TechCrunch. “The best way to know the exact status of the transaction was to control the delivery.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">As a result, the company launched Loship in late 2017, starting with food deliveries and then expanding into other verticals. Nguyen explained that its platform includes “basically anything that can fit on or be transported legally by motorcycle.” This means verticals dedicated to ride-hailing, groceries, medicine, laundry, packages, flowers, beauty products and B2B supplies like ingredients and food packaging.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The number of its verticals helps Loship differentiate from large players like Grab and Gojek, Nguyen said. He added that being a homegrown startup also gives it an advantage.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">“As the only local player, we understand our local customers on a deeper level compared to other regional ones. We are locals and we have our winning playbook. We strategically enter into new and relatively untouched markets like lower-tier cities, grow the customer base and then take things forward from there.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Loship’s plan until the end of 2021 is to expand into five more major cities, bringing the total number of cities it operates in to 10. Then it plans to launch in Tier 2 and 3 cities in Vietnam, before expanding regionally in Southeast Asia (Nguyen describes Laos and Cambodia as “must-win markets.”)</p>
<p class="p1">In a statement about the funding, Chen said, “Loship creates a strong ecosystem which adds value to small business, customers as well as riders. Under Trung’s entrepreneurship and leadership, we saw the company get much stronger during the pandemic by constantly bringing product and service innovation to its merchants and users.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a7hnTzoll0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/18/kamereo-gets-4-6m-to-connect-farmers-and-fb-businesses-in-vietnam/">Kamereo gets $4.6M to connect farmers and F&#038;B businesses in Vietnam</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kamereo gets $4.6M to connect farmers and F&#038;B businesses in Vietnam&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/18/kamereo-gets-4-6m-to-connect-farmers-and-fb-businesses-in-vietnam/embed/#?secret=a7hnTzoll0" data-secret="a7hnTzoll0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gZEkNTEBZw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/10-investors-predict-maas-on-demand-delivery-and-evs-will-dominate-the-post-covid-future-of-mobility/">10 investors predict MaaS, on-demand delivery and EVs will dominate mobility&#8217;s post-pandemic future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 investors predict MaaS, on-demand delivery and EVs will dominate mobility&#8217;s post-pandemic future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/10-investors-predict-maas-on-demand-delivery-and-evs-will-dominate-the-post-covid-future-of-mobility/embed/#?secret=gZEkNTEBZw" data-secret="gZEkNTEBZw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/vietnamese-on-demand-e-commerce-platform-loship-raises-12m-at-a-valuation-of-100m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185426</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazilian digital auto marketplace InstaCarro revs up with $23M in funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/brazilian-digital-auto-marketplace-instacarro-revs-up-with-23m-in-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/brazilian-digital-auto-marketplace-instacarro-revs-up-with-23m-in-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 03:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big sur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car dealership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FJ Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instacarro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[J Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rise capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sao paulo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184837</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[InstaCarro, a digital marketplace that connects used car sellers to dealers in Brazil, has raised $23 million in a Series B round of funding. Notably, U.S.-based firms co-led the investment, including J Ventures, FJ Labs and Rise Capital. Spain’s All Iron Ventures and Big Sur also participated in the financing, among others. With the latest [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.instacarro.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">InstaCarro</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a digital marketplace that connects used car sellers to dealers in Brazil, has raised $23 million in a Series B round of funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Notably, U.S.-based firms co-led the investment, including J Ventures, FJ Labs and Rise Capital. Spain’s All Iron Ventures and Big Sur also participated in the financing, among others. With the latest round, São Paulo-based InstaCarro has now raised more than $56 million since its 2015 inception.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we all know, the COVID-19 pandemic led to an increase in people all over the world buying and selling things online, with cars being no exception. InstaCarro plans to use its new capital in part to capitalize on the shift and “aggressively” expand its reach within Brazil.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Until this year, the startup operated only in São Paulo. In the first half of this year, it launched operations in eight new cities, and is now also live in Campinas, Curitiba, Joinville, Santos, Brasília, Goiânia, Rio de Janeiro and Belo Horizonte.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For context, the startup compares itself to Carvana in the U.S., Chehaoduo in India and Carro in Indonesia. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO Luca Cafici started InstaCarro after having co-founded a car classified startup in Asia with Rocket Internet. That experience, according to Cafici, taught him that “car classifieds were not solving the problems people had when selling their own cars.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inspired by the early success of Auto1 in Europe, he decided to return to Latin America to build a similar model, with an exclusive initial focus on Brazil because it is the third largest car market in the world.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, InstaCarro is one of the largest used car buyers in Brazil, according to Cafici. Since its inception, the company has transacted more than R$1 billion, or US$193.2 million, working with over 35,000 people seeking to sell their cars to dealers. The startup has been growing 21% month over month since the start of COVID, and has been profitable since 2019. Profitability is up by nearly 10x compared to pre-pandemic levels, Cafici said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bGvLEAdv8k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/28/instacarro-raises-22-million-to-tackle-brazils-50-billion-used-car-market/">InstaCarro raises $22 million to tackle Brazil&#8217;s $50 billion used-car market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;InstaCarro raises $22 million to tackle Brazil&#8217;s $50 billion used-car market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/28/instacarro-raises-22-million-to-tackle-brazils-50-billion-used-car-market/embed/#?secret=bGvLEAdv8k" data-secret="bGvLEAdv8k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, InstaCarro aims to become a “full-service” car trading platform after hearing from customers that they would be interested in buying a car directly through its platform as well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under its current model, the process seems straightforward. When a customer sells their car through InstaCarro, the company comes out to their home to inspect the car, taking more than 150 pictures, and then auctions the car through its network of over 4,000 dealers across Brazil. Customers receive a bid for their car in 24 hours, and InstaCarro pays out the customer the same day and handles all of the paperwork, according to Cafici.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The auction is a key component to achieve a great price, as there is no agreement on what the true value of a used car is,” he added. “The more dealers you talk with, the higher price you get.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup also plans to use its new capital to “improve the coverage” of its home inspection model and improve the efficiency of its digital auction process, Cafici said. It, naturally, intends to also do some hiring. InstaCarro has 120 employees, and it plans to double that number by 2022.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prior to the pandemic, the company had partnered with major supermarket chains to create inspection points. But with the onset of the pandemic, it began inspecting cars at the sellers’ homes, which has proven to help the company move and grow faster, Cafici said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The pandemic forced us to reinvent our business model. Before the lockdowns, most of our operations depended on central inspection sites, which we had to shut down overnight in March 2020,” he told TechCrunch. “For our customers, our dealers, and our team, last year was challenging and scary. Our team worked hard to reinvent our business model around home inspections, so that we could continue doing business in a safe way. We started going to our client&#8217;s driveway instead of having them come to an inspection site.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, over 90% of the company’s customers choose to do everything online.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">John Nordin of J Ventures said his firm was impressed by the way the company shifted its business model after COVID hit and is “now growing faster than ever.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We see digital car dealerships finding success in markets across the world, from the U.S. to the U.K., Indonesia and Mexico,” Nordin said. “The team or teams that build a digital car dealership in Brazil have a lot of work cut out for them, not only to figure out how to fit the model to Brazilian consumers, but also to handle the operational challenges of buying and selling a huge volume of cars every day. InstaCarro has the right team to tackle the challenges ahead.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4DxIYzcZd6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/mexican-unicorn-kavak-raises-a-485m-series-d-at-a-4b-valuation/">Mexican unicorn Kavak raises a $485M Series D at a $4B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mexican unicorn Kavak raises a $485M Series D at a $4B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/mexican-unicorn-kavak-raises-a-485m-series-d-at-a-4b-valuation/embed/#?secret=4DxIYzcZd6" data-secret="4DxIYzcZd6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/brazilian-digital-auto-marketplace-instacarro-revs-up-with-23m-in-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184837</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Square’s acquisition of Afterpay means for startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/what-squares-acquisition-of-afterpay-means-for-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/what-squares-acquisition-of-afterpay-means-for-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Lawler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 23:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bain capital ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Better Tomorrow Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fika Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jake gibson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scalapay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TX Zhuo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zilch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185305</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The main takeaways? "Buy now, pay later" may be effective at driving retail conversion, but scale matters and long-term margins look slim for BNPL startups.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On Sunday Square announced it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/">gobbling up Afterpay</a> in a deal worth $29 billion at the time of announcement. Alex followed up yesterday with more details on why the deal made sense for Square and Afterpay <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/?tpcc=ECTW2020">over here</a>, but we wanted to ask some notable VCs what it means for the startup market.</p>
<p>For context, the Square deal follows a ton of money and interest flowing into the BNPL market. Just this year, VCs have invested in companies like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/alma-raises-59-4-million-for-its-klarna-like-payment-option/">Alma</a> ($59.4 million, January 2021), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/scalapay-raises-48m-to-scale-its-buy-now-pay-later-service-in-europe/">Scalapay</a> ($48 million, January 2021), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/wisetack-raises-19m-as-its-buy-now-pay-later-service-for-irl-services-scales/">Wisetack</a> ($19 million, February 2021), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/uks-zilch-raises-80m-at-a-500m-valuation-for-its-direct-to-consumer-buy-now-pay-later-service/">Zilch</a> ($80 million, April 2021) and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/divido-bags-30m-to-take-its-buy-now-pay-later-platform-to-more-markets/">Dividio</a> ($30 million, June 2021).</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Most of the investors we reached out to were generally bullish on the Square and Afterpay integration, but they were less excited about opportunities for other consumer BNPL businesses to emerge.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Then there’s Klarna, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/fintech-giant-klarna-raises-639m-at-a-45-6b-valuation/">raised $639 million</a> at a post-money valuation of $45.6 billion in June, after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/invest-now-sell-later/">raising $1 billion in March</a> at a post-money valuation of $31 billion.</p>
<p>There’s also interest from some major public companies. After a slow start, PayPal is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/in-the-buy-now-pay-later-wars-paypal-is-primed-for-dominance/">aggressively pushing BNPL services</a> with merchants that offer it as a payment option. And there are reports that Apple is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/what-impact-will-apples-buy-now-pay-later-push-have-on-startups/">building its own BNPL offering</a> through Apple Pay.</p>
<p>We reached out to <a href="https://commerce.vc/">Commerce Ventures</a> founder and GP <a href="https://twitter.com/venturedan?lang=en">Dan Rosen</a>,  <a href="http://btv.vc/">Better Tomorrow Ventures</a> founding partner <a href="https://twitter.com/iamjakestream">Jake Gibson</a>, <a href="https://fika.vc/">Fika Ventures</a> partner <a href="https://twitter.com/txzhuo">TX Zhuo</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mattcharris/">Matthew Harris</a> of <a href="https://www.baincapital.com/">Bain Capital Ventures</a> to see what they thought of the deal, as well as what it might mean for the opportunity for other BNPL companies and startups.</p>
<p>The main takeaways? &#8220;Buy now, pay later&#8221; may be effective at driving retail conversion, but scale matters and long-term margins look slim for BNPL startups.</p>
<p>Now, let’s hear from the venture community.</p>
<h2>The venture view</h2>
<p>Why is the BNPL market so hot?<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/what-squares-acquisition-of-afterpay-means-for-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185305</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gig companies take worker classification fight to Massachusetts through ballot initiative</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/gig-companies-take-worker-classification-fight-to-massachusetts-through-ballot-initiative/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/gig-companies-take-worker-classification-fight-to-massachusetts-through-ballot-initiative/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 23:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A coalition of app-based ride-hailing and on-demand delivery companies including Lyft, Uber, Doordash and Instacart have filed a petition for a ballot initiative in Massachusetts that would keep gig economy workers classified as independent contractors as the industry takes a fight it won in California on the road. The ballot measure proposed by the Massachusetts [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A coalition of app-based ride-hailing and on-demand delivery companies including Lyft, Uber, Doordash and Instacart have filed a petition for a ballot initiative in Massachusetts that would keep gig economy workers classified as independent contractors as the industry takes a fight it won in California on the road.</p>
<p>The ballot measure proposed by the Massachusetts Coalition for Independent Work comes nearly a year after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/04/shares-of-uber-lyft-soar-on-expected-passage-of-california-gig-labor-ballot-measure/">California voters approved</a> a similar measure known as Proposition 22 that pitted labor rights advocates against gig economy companies in a costly multimillion battle.</p>
<p>Lyft, Uber and other members of the coalition, which also includes several local chambers of commerce in the state, said Tuesday they want the ballot question included in the November 2022 election. The question has to pass a legal review and receive enough signatures from voters for it to be included on the ballot.</p>
<p>&#8220;While our priority is to find a legislative solution in Massachusetts, this part of our continued efforts to advocate what the vast majority of drivers want — a flexible earning opportunity that our platform provides plus new benefits,&#8221; Lyft co-founder John Zimmer said during Lyft&#8217;s earnings call Tuesday. &#8221; While we&#8217;re pursuing the ballot option, we&#8217;re also closely engaged with the Massachusetts State Legislature and are continuing to work with them on a potential legislative solution.&#8221;</p>
<p>The coalition said the proposed ballot question would grant app-based ride-hail and delivery workers new benefits such as healthcare stipends while keeping them classified as independent contractors.</p>
<p>Among the provisions that the coalition touted would be an earnings floor equal to 120% of the Massachusetts minimum wage ($18 per hour in 2023 from app-based platforms, before customer tips) and healthcare stipends for drivers who work at least 15 hours per week. Drivers would still keep all of their tips and be guaranteed at least $0.26 per mile to cover vehicle upkeep and gas, according to the coalition.</p>
<p>Labor activists are already pushing back. The Coalition to Protect Workers&#8217; Rights, a group composed of a variety of organizations including the NAACP New England Area Conference, the Union of Minority Neighborhoods and the Massachusetts Immigrant and Refugee Coalition, said Tuesday the ballot measure contains <a href="https://noprop22ma.com/402-2/">problematic language that will hurt workers</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The group argued there are extensive loopholes that create a subminimum wage for app-based workers and that few qualify for healthcare. It also noted that the measure would remove anti-discrimination protections, eliminates workers&#8217; compensation rules and allows companies to cheat the state unemployment system of hundreds of millions.</p>
<p>While Uber, Lyft and the broader coalition lobbies for either a ballot measure or legislation, it also <a href="https://www.mass.gov/doc/ride-sharing-complaint">faces a lawsuit</a> filed last year by the Massachusetts Attorney General Maura Healey who has asked the court to rule that Uber and Lyft drivers are employees under Massachusetts Wage and Hour Laws.</p>
<p>The AG&#8217;s Office alleges in its complaint that Uber and Lyft are unable to meet a three-part test under state law that would allow them to classify drivers as independent contractors. To qualify as an independent contractor the worker must be free from a company&#8217;s direction and control, perform services outside the usual course of the business and does similar work on their own.</p>
<p>Uber has been signaling since last year that it planned to push for laws similar to the Proposition 22 measure. Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi said in November 2020 during an earnings call with analysts that the company will &#8220;more loudly advocate for laws like Prop 22.&#8221; He later added that it will be a priority of the company &#8220;to work with governments across the U.S. and the world to make this a reality.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WgFOB2bOSC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/">An even bigger battle for gig worker rights is on the horizon</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;An even bigger battle for gig worker rights is on the horizon&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/embed/#?secret=WgFOB2bOSC" data-secret="WgFOB2bOSC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/gig-companies-take-worker-classification-fight-to-massachusetts-through-ballot-initiative/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185291</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WhatsApp photos and videos can now disappear after a single viewing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/whatsapp-view-once-disappearing-photos-video/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/whatsapp-view-once-disappearing-photos-video/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 22:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private message]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WhatsApp said that it would soon let users send disappearing photos and videos and this week the feature will be rolling out to everybody. Anyone using the Facebook-owned messaging app can share a photo or video in &#8220;view once&#8221; mode, allowing a single viewing before the media in question goes poof. Media shared with &#8220;view [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">WhatsApp said that it would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/zuckerberg-says-whatsapp-will-add-multi-device-support-introduce-view-once-disappearing-feature/">soon let users send disappearing photos and videos</a> and this week the feature will be rolling out to everybody. Anyone using the Facebook-owned messaging app can share a photo or video in &#8220;view once&#8221; mode, allowing a single viewing before the media in question goes <em>poof</em>. Media shared with &#8220;view once&#8221; selected will show up as opened after the intended audience takes a peek.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">New feature alert!</p>
<p>You can now send photos and videos that disappear after they’ve been opened via View Once on WhatsApp, giving you more control over your chats privacy! <a href="https://t.co/Ig5BWbX1Ow">pic.twitter.com/Ig5BWbX1Ow</a></p>
<p>&mdash; WhatsApp (@WhatsApp) <a href="https://twitter.com/WhatsApp/status/1422678722398748676?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 3, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The company notes that the new feature could be helpful for an array of needs that definitely aren&#8217;t sending nudes, like sharing a photo of some clothes you tried on or giving someone your wifi password. In the fine print, the company would like to remind you that just because the photos or video will vanish, that doesn&#8217;t prevent someone from taking a screenshot (and you won&#8217;t know if they do).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ub8UaE3uL8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/whatsapp-now-lets-you-post-disappearing-messages-which-go-away-after-7-days/">WhatsApp now lets you post ephemeral messages that disappear after 7 days</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;WhatsApp now lets you post ephemeral messages that disappear after 7 days&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/whatsapp-now-lets-you-post-disappearing-messages-which-go-away-after-7-days/embed/#?secret=Ub8UaE3uL8" data-secret="Ub8UaE3uL8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Facebook says the new feature is a step to give users &#8220;even more control over their privacy,&#8221; a song it&#8217;s been singing since Mark Zuckerberg <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/06/mark-zuckerberg-discovers-privacy/">first declared a new &#8220;privacy-focused vision&#8221;</a> for the company back in 2019. Facebook has made a few gestures toward letting people wrest control of their online privacy since then, streamlining audience controls on its core app and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/whatsapp-now-lets-you-post-disappearing-messages-which-go-away-after-7-days/">enabling disappearing messages in WhatsApp</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company has also been talking a big game about bringing end-to-end encryption to its full stable of messaging services, which it plans to make interoperable in the future. WhatsApp enabled end-to-end encryption by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/04/05/whatsapp-completes-end-to-end-encryption-rollout/">default back in 2016</a>, but for Messenger and Instagram, the hallmark privacy measure could still be <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-messenger-end-to-end-encryption-default/">years out</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ub8UaE3uL8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/whatsapp-now-lets-you-post-disappearing-messages-which-go-away-after-7-days/">WhatsApp now lets you post ephemeral messages that disappear after 7 days</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;WhatsApp now lets you post ephemeral messages that disappear after 7 days&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/whatsapp-now-lets-you-post-disappearing-messages-which-go-away-after-7-days/embed/#?secret=Ub8UaE3uL8" data-secret="Ub8UaE3uL8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bmoOUi3XMO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/04/05/whatsapp-completes-end-to-end-encryption-rollout/">WhatsApp completes end-to-end encryption rollout</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;WhatsApp completes end-to-end encryption rollout&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/04/05/whatsapp-completes-end-to-end-encryption-rollout/embed/#?secret=bmoOUi3XMO" data-secret="bmoOUi3XMO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/whatsapp-view-once-disappearing-photos-video/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185342</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Extra Crunch roundup: Square buys Afterpay, paid search basics, career advice for devs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/extra-crunch-roundup-square-buys-afterpay-paid-search-basics-career-advice-for-devs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/extra-crunch-roundup-square-buys-afterpay-paid-search-basics-career-advice-for-devs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 22:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don Burnette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Draper Esprit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duolingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason Warnick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kodiak Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scott tong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stuart Chapman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unbabel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Square paid around a quarter of its present-day value for Afterpay. That seems like a lot. But was it too much?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Square paid around a quarter of its present-day value for Afterpay, Alex Wilhelm notes in The Exchange. That seems like a lot. But was it too much?</p>
<p>“Afterpay brings global revenues, global users and a more diverse merchant network to Square,” Alex notes. “It would have had to spend to derive those assets over time. Square is willing to pay up to snag them now.”</p>
<p>Dana Stalder, a partner at Matrix Partners and Afterpay&#8217;s only institutional investor,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/the-next-generation-of-global-payments-afterpay-square/"> describes the deal as part of a recurring &#8220;critical innovation cycle&#8221; in fintech</a> that &#8220;determines the winners and losers&#8221; for decades to come.</p>
<p>&#8220;I’ve never seen a combination that has such potential to deliver extraordinary value to consumers and merchants,&#8221; says Stalder. &#8220;Even more so than eBay + PayPal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading Extra Crunch this week!</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mzLxs65vMe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/the-next-generation-of-global-payments-afterpay-square/">The next generation of global payments: Afterpay + Square</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The next generation of global payments: Afterpay + Square&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/the-next-generation-of-global-payments-afterpay-square/embed/#?secret=mzLxs65vMe" data-secret="mzLxs65vMe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TbYsCpm3E7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/">Why Square is shelling out $29B to snag BNPL player Afterpay</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Square is shelling out $29B to snag BNPL player Afterpay&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/embed/#?secret=TbYsCpm3E7" data-secret="TbYsCpm3E7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The best way to grow your career? Treat it like an app</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2184081" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184081" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184081" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1210091154.jpg" alt="Decision making: Wooden figurine thinking about the path to take to reach the target" width="1024" height="735" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1210091154.jpg 2044w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1210091154.jpg?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1210091154.jpg?resize=300,215 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1210091154.jpg?resize=768,551 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1210091154.jpg?resize=680,488 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1210091154.jpg?resize=1536,1102 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1210091154.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184081" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=jayk7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jayk7 <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Developers may delight in solving complex technical problems, but the problem of a career path is one many don’t think much about, Juniper Networks CTO Raj Yavatkar writes in a guest column.</p>
<p>He offers a solution that should appeal to developers and engineers: “​​Treat career advancement as you would a software project.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EPJGxmQPm4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/the-best-way-to-grow-your-tech-career-treat-it-like-an-app/">The best way to grow your tech career? Treat it like an app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The best way to grow your tech career? Treat it like an app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/the-best-way-to-grow-your-tech-career-treat-it-like-an-app/embed/#?secret=EPJGxmQPm4" data-secret="EPJGxmQPm4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Design expert Scott Tong outlines 4 concepts founders should consider when designing products</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2138701" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138701" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2138701" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg" alt="Scott Tong" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Scott-Tong.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2138701" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Scott Tong</p></div></p>
<p>At Early Stage 2021, design expert Scott Tong shared some ways founders should think about design and branding.</p>
<blockquote><p>If you can link your brand with your company’s reputation, I think it’s a really great place to start when you’re having conversations about brands. What is the first impression? What are the consistent behaviors that your brand hopes to repeat over and over? What are the memorable moments that stand out and make your brand, your reputation memorable?</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oEYkX2XdGg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/design-expert-scott-tong-outlines-4-concepts-founders-should-consider-when-designing-products/">Design expert Scott Tong outlines 4 concepts founders should consider when designing products</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Design expert Scott Tong outlines 4 concepts founders should consider when designing products&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/design-expert-scott-tong-outlines-4-concepts-founders-should-consider-when-designing-products/embed/#?secret=oEYkX2XdGg" data-secret="oEYkX2XdGg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>You can’t afford to make poor decisions about incentive stock options</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2184607" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184607" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184607" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1206008511.jpg" alt="Image of a piggy bank, clock, and calculator on blue and yellow background to represent financial advice." width="1024" height="684" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1206008511.jpg 6016w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1206008511.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1206008511.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1206008511.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1206008511.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1206008511.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1206008511.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1206008511.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184607" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Nora+Carol+Photography" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nora Carol Photography <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>If you’re fortunate enough to be considering cashing in on vested stock options, this guest column is worth a read.</p>
<p>“Most companies admit they need to be better at explaining how ISOs work in general, but they can’t legally work one-on-one with employees to help them exercise and sell shares the right way,” Wealthramp’s Pam Krueger and John Chapman write.</p>
<p>“That’s why, when the time is right, many employees actively look for help from a qualified fiduciary financial adviser who can walk these could-be ‘options millionaires’ through various cash-in scenarios.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cSm9pWGTBL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/you-cant-afford-to-make-poor-decisions-about-incentive-stock-options/">You can’t afford to make poor decisions about incentive stock options</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;You can’t afford to make poor decisions about incentive stock options&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/you-cant-afford-to-make-poor-decisions-about-incentive-stock-options/embed/#?secret=cSm9pWGTBL" data-secret="cSm9pWGTBL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Demand Curve: Questions you need to answer in your paid search ads</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2184706" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184706" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184706" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1277731041.jpg" alt="Retail and technology. Retail as a Service." width="1024" height="575" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1277731041.jpg 2311w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1277731041.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1277731041.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1277731041.jpg?resize=768,431 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1277731041.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1277731041.jpg?resize=1536,862 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1277731041.jpg?resize=2048,1149 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1277731041.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184706" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=metamorworks" target="_blank" rel="noopener">metamorworks <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>At some point, almost every early-stage startup will use paid search ads to connect with customers and throw down the gauntlet with their competitors.</p>
<p>Most of these initial attempts at paid search are unsuccessful. There&#8217;s a steep learning curve when it comes to transforming passive searchers into paying customers, and almost no one gets it right the first time.</p>
<p>In a comprehensive guest post, growth marketing expert Stewart Hillhouse identified &#8220;14 questions your paid search should answer to ensure you&#8217;re only paying for the highest-intent shoppers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Question 1? “What’s in it for <strong>me</strong>?”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0myWrySdgx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/demand-curve-questions-you-need-to-answer-in-your-paid-search-ads/">Demand Curve: Questions you need to answer in your paid search ads</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Demand Curve: Questions you need to answer in your paid search ads&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/demand-curve-questions-you-need-to-answer-in-your-paid-search-ads/embed/#?secret=0myWrySdgx" data-secret="0myWrySdgx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>5 lessons from Duolingo’s bellwether edtech IPO of the year</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2088955" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2088955" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2088955" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/duolingo-backpack.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="544" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/duolingo-backpack.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/duolingo-backpack.jpg?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/duolingo-backpack.jpg?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/duolingo-backpack.jpg?resize=768,408 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/duolingo-backpack.jpg?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/duolingo-backpack.jpg?resize=1536,816 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/duolingo-backpack.jpg?resize=2048,1088 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/duolingo-backpack.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2088955" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Duolingo</p></div></p>
<p>Duolingo’s debut last week was a bright spot, Alex Wilhelm and Natasha Mascarenhas write, with the language learning app’s stock price landing above a raised IPO range.</p>
<p>Alex and Natasha detail five lessons to take from Duolingo’s flotation:</p>
<ol>
<li>The IPO event will bring &#8220;more sophistication&#8221; to Duolingo’s core service.</li>
<li>Roadshow investors didn’t view Duolingo as an edtech company.</li>
<li>China’s edtech crackdown will have a &#8220;neutral&#8221; impact on Duolingo.</li>
<li>In certain cases, post-COVID growth declines aren’t lethal.</li>
<li>Growth can still absolve rising losses.</li>
</ol>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Dl4JTG7J1i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/5-lessons-from-duolingos-bellwether-edtech-ipo-of-the-year/">5 lessons from Duolingo&#8217;s bellwether edtech IPO of the year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 lessons from Duolingo&#8217;s bellwether edtech IPO of the year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/5-lessons-from-duolingos-bellwether-edtech-ipo-of-the-year/embed/#?secret=Dl4JTG7J1i" data-secret="Dl4JTG7J1i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Can your startup support a research-based workflow?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2184627" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184627" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184627" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1242828551.jpg" alt="Artificial Intelligence Brain" width="1024" height="717" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1242828551.jpg 2070w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1242828551.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1242828551.jpg?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1242828551.jpg?resize=768,538 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1242828551.jpg?resize=680,476 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1242828551.jpg?resize=1536,1075 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1242828551.jpg?resize=2048,1434 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1242828551.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184627" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Andriy+Onufriyenko" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andriy Onufriyenko <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>In the U.S. alone, yearly spending on AI R&amp;D is expected to reach $100 billion by 2025.</p>
<p>But can your humble startup attract and retain users while it conducts research and product development?</p>
<p>“For obvious reasons, companies want to make things that matter to their customers, investors and stakeholders. Ideally, there’s a way to do both,” says João Graça, CTO and co-founder of Unbabel, an AI-powered language operations platform.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="COsc0AUSO1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/can-your-startup-support-a-research-based-workflow/">Can your startup support a research-based workflow?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can your startup support a research-based workflow?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/can-your-startup-support-a-research-based-workflow/embed/#?secret=COsc0AUSO1" data-secret="COsc0AUSO1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Kodiak Robotics’ founder says tight focus on autonomous trucks is working</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2184073" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184073" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184073" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/don-burnette-founder.jpg" alt="don-burnette-founder-kodiak" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/don-burnette-founder.jpg 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/don-burnette-founder.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/don-burnette-founder.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/don-burnette-founder.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/don-burnette-founder.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/don-burnette-founder.jpg?resize=1536,863 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/don-burnette-founder.jpg?resize=2048,1151 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/don-burnette-founder.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184073" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin</p></div></p>
<p>As part of an ongoing series with transportation startup founders, Rebecca Bellan interviews Kodiak Robotics CEO and co-founder Don Burnette about why the autonomous trucking company remains private when so many of its rivals have gone public.</p>
<p>“I think there’s also lots of opportunity within the VCs and the private markets,” said Burnette.</p>
<p>“Kodiak is one of the only remaining serious AV trucking companies still in the private sector, and so I think that gives us some advantages in a lot of ways.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4ZfgAfS1e0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/">Kodiak Robotics&#8217; founder says tight focus on autonomous trucks is working</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kodiak Robotics&#8217; founder says tight focus on autonomous trucks is working&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/embed/#?secret=4ZfgAfS1e0" data-secret="4ZfgAfS1e0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>How public markets can help address venture capital’s limitations</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996008" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996008" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996008" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996008" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>After<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/why-draper-esprit-doubled-down-on-its-status-as-a-publicly-listed-vc/"> interviewing</a> Draper Esprit co-founder Stuart Chapman, Alex Wilhelm and Anna Heim took a look at the trend of European VCs floating themselves.</p>
<p>Traditional VC models “can foist artificial time constraints on investors and force them to focus their deal flow into particular stages for fund-construction reasons,” Alex and Anna write for The Exchange.</p>
<p>“As we found out researching this piece, the public venture model highlights some of these limitations — and may be able to alleviate them in part.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RvwbcKiiWq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/how-public-markets-can-help-address-venture-capitals-limitations/">How public markets can help address venture capital&#8217;s limitations</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How public markets can help address venture capital&#8217;s limitations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/how-public-markets-can-help-address-venture-capitals-limitations/embed/#?secret=RvwbcKiiWq" data-secret="RvwbcKiiWq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Robinhood’s CFO says it was ready to go public</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996010" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996010" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996010" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996010" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>After Robinhood failed to burn up the stock charts, Alex Wilhelm wondered why, exactly, the investing and trading app’s IPO didn’t live up to expectations.</p>
<p>He spoke to Robinhood CFO Jason Warnick, who shared a few reasons why it was time for the company to float:</p>
<blockquote><p>… Warnick indicated that there were a few factors at play, including that Robinhood had built out its leadership team and its internal processes, and that it had worked on user-safety-related tasks and expanded the site’s use cases. All of that is true.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lnTIIoIweU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/robinhoods-cfo-says-it-was-ready-to-go-public/">Robinhood&#8217;s CFO says it was ready to go public</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Robinhood&#8217;s CFO says it was ready to go public&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/robinhoods-cfo-says-it-was-ready-to-go-public/embed/#?secret=lnTIIoIweU" data-secret="lnTIIoIweU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/extra-crunch-roundup-square-buys-afterpay-paid-search-basics-career-advice-for-devs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185138</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: For $20/month, crime alert app Citizen will connect users with live &#8216;safety agents&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/daily-crunch-for-20-month-crime-alert-app-citizen-will-connect-users-with-live-safety-agents/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/daily-crunch-for-20-month-crime-alert-app-citizen-will-connect-users-with-live-safety-agents/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 22:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for August 3, 2021. Today we have a delightful mix of news for you, from Twitter product changes to VCs in trouble to megadeals and even some super-early-stage rounds. Let’s have some fun! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/atv-venture-capital-ransomware/">Even VCs get hit by ransomware:</a> </strong>Sure, less technically savvy folks get hit by malware and ransomware all the time. You don’t really expect better from legacy telcos or underfunded utilities. But when the victim is Advanced Technology Ventures, which has around $1.8 billion in assets under management, the scourge of aggressive cybercrime starts to take on a more sinister flavor. Who is safe? No one?</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/twitter-fleets-rip/"><strong>Unfavored Fleets Flee:</strong></a> Twitter’s plan to kill off its Fleets product hit the ground today. It’s gone from our iOS apps. Fleets were fleeting, as everyone has noted, with the lifecycle of the product coming and going in rapid succession. Bad news for Twitter? Not really. Its Stories-like feature wasn’t too popular, and the company has a million other things in the wings, like its subscription service, its live audio product and its newsletter effort.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/substack-doubles-down-on-uncensored-free-speech-with-acquisition-of-letter/">Substack buys Letter:</a> </strong>TechCrunch covered this deal today, causing your humble scribe to sit back and think. Why would Substack buy Letter, a platform for written debate? Well, the newsletter-focused startup is big on the written word, and the value thereof. And many well-known Substack authors are controversial in one way or another. You know, the sort of folks you might want to see have a, say, debate? The two products should line up well.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>We’re breaking our startup and venture capital news today into three sections. The first deals with VCs themselves. Then we’ll talk through some mega-rounds and close with some small venture deals worth our time.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/moderne-ventures-closes-second-fund-with-200m-targets-industry-digital-transformation/"><strong>Moderne Ventures raises $200M:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Every first-time venture capital fund wants to get to its second fund. And if they do, to raise a larger fund. From that perspective, things seem to be going well at Moderne, a firm whose second fund is a multiple of the size of its first. And it was oversubscribed. What does the group invest in? Per our own reporting, startups working in the “real estate, finance, insurance and home services industries.”</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/how-public-markets-can-help-address-venture-capitals-limitations/"><strong>VCs going public is a thing?</strong></a><strong> </strong>Yes, it turns out, it is a thing. Several European venture capital funds have gone public in recent quarters, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/why-draper-esprit-doubled-down-on-its-status-as-a-publicly-listed-vc/">including Draper Esprit moving</a> from the smaller AIM to the main board in London. It turns out that being a public VC can remove certain time constraints that more traditional venture capital firms have to deal with. And regular folks can invest.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, some huge rounds:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/india-fintech-bharatpe-valued-at-2-85-billion-in-tiger-global-led-370-million-funding/"><strong>India’s BharatPe raises $370M:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Confirming TechCrunch’s previous scoop, fintech unicorn BharatPe is now worth $2.85 billion after Tiger led its most recent round. The company, TechCrunch reports, “operates an eponymous service to help offline merchants accept digital payments and secure working capital.” Given the number of SMBs in India, BharatPe’s TAM is huge. And now it has nigh-infinite capital to use to power its own growth.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/rapyd-raises-300m-on-8-75b-valuation-as-fintech-as-a-service-continues-to-boom/"><strong>Rapyd raises $300M for fintech APIs:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The fintech world saw not just one huge round today, but two. Rapyd’s $300 million infusion led by Target Global values the firm at around $8.75 billion, per TechCrunch sources. What does Rapyd do? It offers APIs that power wallets, money transfers and card issuing, among other services, helping other companies offer fintech services around the world.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/india-infra-market-valued-at-2-5b-in-tiger-global-led-125m-funding/"><strong>Sure, why not, here’s another huge Tiger round from India:</strong></a><strong> </strong>More evidence that Tiger is building an index fund of growth-focused private companies the world &#8217;round, and that the Indian startup market is red-hot, Infra.Market announced its third round in nine months today. The $125 million Series D values the Mumbai-based company at $2.5 billion, post-money. Infra.Market builds software to help construction companies get the raw materials they need and handle project logistics.</li>
</ul>
<p>And then there’s startup news from the earlier side of the market:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/edtech-startup-bina-raises-1-4m-to-teach-4-to-12-year-olds-launch-school-as-a-service/"><strong>bina raises $1.4M for kid-focused edtech:</strong></a><strong> </strong>bina &#8212; the small b is part of its branding &#8212; wants to build an online school with small class sizes aimed at 4- through 12-year-olds. Given the huge changes to the global education market in light of COVID-19, it’s a big task.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/south-africas-khula-closes-1-3m-seed-to-scale-its-software-for-agriculture-platform/"><strong>$1.3M for African-focused agtech startup Khula:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Providing farmers large and small with software and a marketplace, Khula wants to meet chronic issues in the African farming market with technology.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/wireless-charging-firm-aria-raises-12m/"><strong>Finally, Aira’s wireless charging tech just raised $12 million:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Sure, Apple gave up on AirPower, but Aira is still hard at work on the wireless charging problem set. Which gives us hope, because our phones are always out of batteries, along with our headphones, keyboards and pretty much everything else. It’s not just us, right?</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/controversial-crime-app-citizen-launches-20-month-protect-service/"><strong>Citizen launches its $20/month Protect service:</strong></a> Controversial consumer security startup Citizen’s Protect service is now something that you can buy. Reach that line of communication and the company’s staff will help you handle your emergency. That doesn’t sound too spicy, but as TechCrunch reports “the app made news earlier this year for launching a private ‘personal rapid response service’ fleet of vehicles and a reward for a person wrongly accused of starting a Los Angeles wildfire.”</li>
</ul>
<h2>Embodied AI, superintelligence and the master algorithm</h2>
<p>Over the next 18 months, one technologist says the increased adoption of embodied artificial intelligence will open a path to superintelligence — incredibly powerful software that dwarfs anything the human mind could produce.</p>
<p>&#8220;All the crazy Boston Dynamics videos of robots jumping, dancing, balancing and running are examples of embodied AI,&#8221; says Chris Nicholson, founder and CEO of Pathmind, which uses deep reinforcement learning to optimize industrial operations and supply chains.</p>
<p>“The field is moving fast and, in this revolution, you can dance.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yGaZNZqnQI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/embodied-ai-superintelligence-and-the-master-algorithm/">Embodied AI, superintelligence and the master algorithm</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Embodied AI, superintelligence and the master algorithm&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/embodied-ai-superintelligence-and-the-master-algorithm/embed/#?secret=yGaZNZqnQI" data-secret="yGaZNZqnQI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/youtubes-100-million-shorts-fund-to-challenge-tiktok-goes-live/"><strong>YouTube’s big short push goes live:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Alphabet’s Google division has a video product called YouTube that you may have heard of. And the subsidiary’s subsidiary has a $100 million fund that it hopes will drive interest in creating short-form videos for its viewers. TikTok changed the video game, and YouTube’s huge financial response is now live.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/google-maps-on-ios-adds-live-location-sharing-in-imessage-home-screen-widget-and-dark-mode/">Google updates its Maps product on iOS:</a></strong> If you use Maps on iOS, which we reckon is around half of you reading this note, good news. Now you can share location more easily in iMessages, use dark mode and get traffic data on your home screen. You are welcome.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/nikola-cuts-delivery-outlook-for-its-electric-semi-trucks/"><strong>Nikola warns on EV deliveries:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The chip shortage has a new victim. This time it’s Nikola, the troubled EV company that saw its CEO under fire for fraud in recent days. The company was an early SPAC success and now stands as a cautionary tale for the financial mechanism.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/marvell-nabs-innovium-for-1-1b-as-it-delves-deeper-into-cloud-ethernet-switches/"><strong>Marvell buys Innovium for $1.1B:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Here’s a neat acquisition story that is also something of a letdown. Innovium, a maker of “networking ethernet switches optimized for the cloud,” per our own reporting, was worth a bit more in its final private round. Still, it’s a big deal and a billion-dollar-plus exit, making it worth our time.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants to help startups find the right expert for their needs. To do this, we’re building a shortlist of the top growth marketers. We’ve received great recommendations for growth marketers in the startup industry since we launched our survey.</p>
<p>We’re excited to read more responses as they come in! <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>Our editorial coverage about growth marketing includes articles from the TechCrunch team, guest columns and posts like “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/demand-curve-questions-you-need-to-answer-in-your-paid-search-ads/">Demand Curve: Questions you need to answer in your paid search ads</a>” by <a href="https://twitter.com/stew_hillhouse">Stewart Hillhouse</a> on Extra Crunch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="O2N4UFgwb8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/demand-curve-questions-you-need-to-answer-in-your-paid-search-ads/">Demand Curve: Questions you need to answer in your paid search ads</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Demand Curve: Questions you need to answer in your paid search ads&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/demand-curve-questions-you-need-to-answer-in-your-paid-search-ads/embed/#?secret=O2N4UFgwb8" data-secret="O2N4UFgwb8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/daily-crunch-for-20-month-crime-alert-app-citizen-will-connect-users-with-live-safety-agents/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185265</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Discord now lets you customize your user profile on its apps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/discord-custom-profiles-about-me/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/discord-custom-profiles-about-me/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 21:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chat apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185125</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For mobile users, Discord is adding one new feature that you&#8217;d find on a more traditional social app. The company rolled out an option for users to customize their profiles across its iOS and Android apps Tuesday, following the feature&#8217;s release on the desktop version of Discord in late June. The new option lives in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For mobile users, Discord is adding one new feature that you&#8217;d find on a more traditional social app. The company rolled out an option for users to customize their profiles across its iOS and Android apps Tuesday, following the feature&#8217;s release on the desktop version of Discord in late June.</p>
<p>The new option lives in Discord&#8217;s user settings menu under &#8220;user profile.&#8221; There, you can describe what you&#8217;re all about in 190 characters or less, including links and emojis. You can also select a custom profile color if the new default profile color that Discord assigned you isn&#8217;t vibing with <em>your whole thing</em>. If you don&#8217;t see the option yet, check back as the feature rolls out widely.</p>
<p>With the addition of custom profiles, the company also offered premium Nitro subscribers the option to choose an image or an animated GIF as a profile banner. The options have been out in the wild for desktop for a bit now, but the additional customization features will now give anyone who mostly uses Discord on iOS or Android a way to spice things up a bit.</p>
<p>The feature addition is small, but it&#8217;s a step toward the chat app becoming a touch more like more profile-centric social networks. Discord&#8217;s chat rooms, known as servers, have long been the platform&#8217;s sole focus, but the company has introduced a flurry of quality of life features in recent months.</p>
<p>Discord rolled out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/discord-threads/">threaded, auto-archiving conversations</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/discord-stage-discovery/">Clubhouse-like audio event spaces</a> earlier this year, and also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/discord-buys-sentropy/">picked up a company called Sentropy</a> that makes AI-powered platform moderation software. The app is already a killer service for community-driven voice and text chat, and the recent additions should help the app attract more users well beyond its humble gaming roots.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dCnawkZuD3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/07/twitch-ux-teardown-the-anchor-effect-and-de-risking-decisions/">Twitch UX teardown: The Anchor Effect and de-risking decisions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitch UX teardown: The Anchor Effect and de-risking decisions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/07/twitch-ux-teardown-the-anchor-effect-and-de-risking-decisions/embed/#?secret=dCnawkZuD3" data-secret="dCnawkZuD3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7N58k2tKwq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/discord-threads/">Discord rolls out threads, side conversations that auto-archive</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Discord rolls out threads, side conversations that auto-archive&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/discord-threads/embed/#?secret=7N58k2tKwq" data-secret="7N58k2tKwq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/discord-custom-profiles-about-me/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185125</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lyft reaches adjusted profitability milestone despite continuing net losses</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/lyft-reaches-adjusted-profitability-milestone-despite-continuing-net-losses/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/lyft-reaches-adjusted-profitability-milestone-despite-continuing-net-losses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 20:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ride hailing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today after the bell, U.S. ride-hailing company Lyft reported its second quarter financial performance. In aggregate the company&#8217;s performance was a rebound from the year-ago second quarter, which was heavily impacted by the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic and resulting lockdowns in the United States. Lyft also managed to produce positive adjusted EBITDA in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today after the bell, U.S. ride-hailing company Lyft <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210803005968/en/Lyft-Announces-Second-Quarter-Results">reported its second quarter</a> financial performance. In aggregate the company&#8217;s performance was a rebound from the year-ago second quarter, which was heavily impacted by the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic and resulting lockdowns in the United States.</p>
<p>Lyft also managed to produce positive adjusted EBITDA in the quarter, a profit metric favored by technology upstarts that have yet to generate net income, a stricter method of calculating profitability. Adjusted EBITDA for the second quarter was $23.8 million.</p>
<p>Company executives relished in hitting the milestone during the earnings call Tuesday. &#8220;<span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">This</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">quarter</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">we</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">crossed</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">a</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">milestone</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">that</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">we&#8217;ve</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">had</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">our</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">sights</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">on</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">for</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">quite</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">some</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">time,&#8221; said co-founder and CEO Logan Green, who noted that last year at this time the company was facing a &#8220;once-in-a-century global pandemic hit that literally halted travel, and at the same time Proposition 22 was playing out in California.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The company&#8217;s adjusted EBITDA reached a nadir in Q2 2020, when it totaled -$280 million. Since then Lyft has posted successive gains to adjusted EBITDA in every quarter. The company&#8217;s adjusted EBITDA margin came to 3% in its most recent quarter. After promising investors that adjusted profits would come, Lyft delivered.</p>
<p>Shares of Lyft are up nearly 7% in after-hours trading following the company&#8217;s financial report.</p>
<p>Lyft reported revenue of $765 million in the second quarter, more than double the $339.3 million million it brought in during the same period last year. While that is remarkable, remember last year at this time the economy and ride-hailing were getting pummeled by the COVID-19 pandemic. In other words, we expected this.</p>
<p>Importantly, Lyft&#8217;s Q2 revenue grew 25.6% over last quarter&#8217;s $609 million. That means that despite rising case counts in the United States thanks to the delta COVID-19 variant, Lyft still managed to grow.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company said it had 17.1 million active riders in the second quarter, up 97% from the 8.68 million riders it had on its network in the same period last year. In the first quarter Lyft said it had 13.49 million active riders in the first quarter. The company also saw more revenue per active user in the second quarter ($44.63) than it did in the year-ago Q2 ($39.06). The company&#8217;s revenue per active rider metric slipped slightly from its Q1 2021 result of $45.13.</p>
<p>Lyft&#8217;s growth bested street expectations, which anticipated revenues of $696.2 million, per Yahoo Finance data. Despite this growth, Lyft is still losing money when all costs are counted. Lyft reported a net loss of $251.9 million in the second quarter, a 42% improvement from the $437.1 million it lost in the same period last year, but still a steeply negative figure.</p>
<p>The company said that net loss for the second quarter includes $207.8 million of stock-based compensation and related payroll tax expenses, and the $20.4 million expense related to the previously disclosed agreement to reinsure certain legacy auto insurance liabilities.</p>
<p>In the second quarter, Lyft&#8217;s aggregate spend on cost of revenue related expenses rose, though that was to be expected given how sharply its revenues themselves expanded compared to the year-ago period. The company also managed to curtail G&amp;A costs, and its &#8220;operations and support&#8221; line item. However, R&amp;D costs and S&amp;M expenses both expanded compared to the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>Finally on numbers, what about cash? Despite managing to generate positive adjusted EBITDA in the last three months, Lyft operations consumed $37.5 million in cash during the quarter. Lyft&#8217;s operations have not generated positive cash flow since Q3 2019. But don&#8217;t worry that Lyft is about to run out of funds &#8212; it has more than $2 billion in cash to support its growth.</p>
<p>There are signs that Lyft&#8217;s business is maturing into something more profitable than it once was. The company&#8217;s contribution margin, a non-GAAP figure that is used to indicate profitability of its ride-hailing model sans corporate costs, rose to 59.1% in the second quarter, an all-time record result. In the year-ago period the metric fell to 34.6%, its worst result since Q1 2017.</p>
<p>Lest we all forget, Lyft is now free of its costly autonomous vehicle technology program called Level 5. Lyft sold Level 5 to Toyota&#8217;s Woven Planet Holdings. That deal closed July 13. The company said during the call it <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">expects</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">to</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">remove</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">roughly</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">$20</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">million</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">of</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">related</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">costs</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">in</span> the third quarter<span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">,</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">relative</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">to</span> the second quarter.</p>
<p>That doesn&#8217;t mean the company isn&#8217;t interested in getting into the robotaxi game.</p>
<p>Last month, Lyft <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/argo-ford-to-launch-self-driving-vehicles-on-lyfts-ride-hailing-app/">announced a partnership</a> with Argo AI and Ford to launch at least 1,000 self-driving vehicles on Lyft&#8217;s ride-hailing network in a number of cities over the next five years, starting with Miami and Austin. The first Ford self-driving vehicles, which are equipped with Argo&#8217;s autonomous vehicle technology, will become available on Lyft&#8217;s app in Miami later this year.</p>
<p><em>TechCrunch has tuned into the Lyft call and will update this story as needed.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/lyft-reaches-adjusted-profitability-milestone-despite-continuing-net-losses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185255</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Demand Curve: Tested tactics for growing newsletters</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/demand-curve-tested-tactics-for-growing-newsletters/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/demand-curve-tested-tactics-for-growing-newsletters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 20:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[converting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are very few marketing channels as well rounded as email newsletters. They provide a direct line of communication; nearly 40x ROI, are infinitely scalable and virtually free.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Stewart Hillhouse</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/stew_hillhouse">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Stewart Hillhouse writes actionable growth marketing insights as senior content lead at<a href="http://demandcurve.com/"> Demand Curve</a>. By night, he interviews marketers and creatives on his podcast,<a href="https://stewarthillhouse.com/tag/podcast/"> Top Of Mind</a>. Before getting into marketing, Stewart was a semi-professional lumberjack. He also writes at<a href="http://stewarthillhouse.com/"> stewarthillhouse.com</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/demand-curve-tested-tactics-for-growing-newsletters/">Demand Curve: Tested tactics for growing newsletters</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/demand-curve-7-ad-types-that-increase-click-through-rates/">Demand Curve: 7 ad types that increase click-through rates</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">There are very few marketing channels as well rounded as email newsletters. They provide a direct, owned line of communication with your audience; nearly 40x return on investment (~$40 generated per every dollar spent), are infinitely scalable and virtually free.</p>
<p>But to unlock these benefits, you&#8217;re going to need to be strategic. In this article, I&#8217;m going to share tactics we&#8217;ve used at<a href="https://www.demandcurve.com/"> Demand Curve</a> to grow our newsletter list to over 50,000 highly-qualified subscribers and maintain an open rate of over 50%.</p>
<h2>Increase popup conversion using the 60% rule</h2>
<p>While they&#8217;re often thought of as intrusive, pop-ups work. On average, they convert 3% of site visitors, and strategic, high-performing pop-ups can reach conversion of about 10%.</p>
<p>To make higher-converting, less intrusive pop-ups, try the 60% rule.</p>
<ol>
<li>Choose a page you&#8217;d like to put a pop-up on. We recommend pages that aren&#8217;t conversion-focused (like product pages, checkout and sign-ups). We&#8217;ve found content pages work the best and they can act as a signal for visitors who are looking for something specific.</li>
<li>Open your website&#8217;s analytics and see what the average time spent on that page is.</li>
<li>Set your pop-up to appear after 60% of the average time of that page has elapsed.</li>
</ol>
<p>So if the average time spent on a page is 50 seconds, set your pop-up to appear 30 seconds (60% of total time) after visitors land on that page.</p>
<p>Why 60%? Readers have shown interest in your content, but are nearing the end of their session. Prompting them to join your newsletter to see more relevant content in exchange for their email will feel fair.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			To encourage new subscribers to open your welcome email, try breaking the welcome email pattern using delayed gratification and a recognizable sender.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<h2>Give samples of your newsletter to prove quality</h2>
<p>If a visitor is new to your content, asking them to sign up for your newsletter can be a big step, and most new visitors won&#8217;t convert. To narrow the gap between a new reader and subscriber, provide a sample on the sign-up page. Use your most engaging newsletter as a sample to prove that your content is high quality.</p>
<p>To source your most engaging content, filter by open rate and replies. In your email service provider, sort your previous editions by open rate. This will help you identify which subject lines are most popular with existing readers. Modify your most popular subject line to turn it into a header on your newsletter sign-up page.</p>
<p>Next, go into your inbox and sort by replies to your newsletter. Identify which newsletter got the most replies from your readers. This is a positive signal that the content from that edition resonated the most and would be a solid choice for your free sample.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184926" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184926" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184926" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/1.png" alt="Give samples of your newsletter to prove your quality" width="1024" height="736" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/1.png 1324w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/1.png?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/1.png?resize=300,216 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/1.png?resize=768,552 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/1.png?resize=680,489 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/1.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184926" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<h2>Emails from real people are opened more often</h2>
<p>People reflexively ignore welcome emails after they sign up. But, those who do open your welcome email are more likely to consistently open your newsletters.</p>
<p>To encourage new subscribers to open your welcome email, try breaking the welcome email pattern using delayed gratification and a recognizable sender.</p>
<p>Delay your welcome email by 45 minutes. This will bypass the reflex that new subscribers have to ignore an email that pings them seconds after signing up. We&#8217;ve found 45 minutes to be ideal, because the delay is long enough that it breaks the pattern, but not so long that your email gets buried in their inbox.</p>
<p>Send your welcome from a person, not from a business account. We&#8217;ve found this tactic to be especially effective when the sender is the founder of the business or someone with an established audience. Use a photo of that person and not your company logo to help the email stand out.</p>
<p>To avoid overflowing the sender&#8217;s real inbox, create a subdomain for your website that will be used exclusively for sending emails. Create an account for your sender and begin using it for your newsletter. This avoids overwhelming their inbox and maintains the health of your sending domain.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184927" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184927" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184927" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2.png" alt="Emails from real people get opened more frequently" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2.png 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184927" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<h2>Send a superissue to new subscribers</h2>
<p>A new subscriber will be keen to receive their first issue. To ensure they&#8217;re satisfied, piece together your best content from past issues into a superissue. But be careful not to use the same content you included as samples on your sign-up page.</p>
<p>Send this first superissue with the welcome email so that your new subscribers are immediately receiving value from your newsletter. Starting with your best content first will get your subscribers excited to open future emails.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve found that shorter welcome emails perform better than long-winded ones. Keep your welcome message short and your opening issue tight. Once they&#8217;ve received the welcome email and the first superissue, add them to the regular email cadence.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184928" style="width: 540px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184928" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184928" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/3.png" alt="Send a super-issue to new subscribers" width="530" height="485" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/3.png 530w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/3.png?resize=150,137 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/3.png?resize=300,275 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/3.png?resize=50,46 50w" sizes="(max-width: 530px) 100vw, 530px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184928" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<h2>Consider sending fewer emails</h2>
<p>We polled <a href="https://twitter.com/growthtactics">over 24,000 marketers on Twitter</a> asking whether people suffer from &#8220;newsletter fatigue,&#8221; causing them to unsubscribe.</p>
<p>The results: 80% of respondents unsubscribe when they get too many emails.</p>
<p>To avoid overwhelming your subscribers:</p>
<p><strong>Give your subscribers control over how often they are emailed:</strong> Some subscribers want them weekly, while others want monthly. In the footer of your email, create opt-out links that allow subscribers to customize the cadence they&#8217;ll receive emails. Giving them the opportunity to opt out of frequent emails while still remaining subscribed keeps them as valid contacts on your email list. You want to avoid losing them completely as a subscriber.</p>
<p><strong>Send fewer emails:</strong> Putting a constraint on how many emails you&#8217;re allowed to send every quarter will force you to be more thoughtful about the contents of those emails. A high volume of emails just for the sake of being in your subscribers&#8217; inbox can burn you and your readers out. We&#8217;ve seen very little correlation between volume of emails and the resulting conversion rate.</p>
<h2>Make your emails fun — not just educational</h2>
<p>Most emails in your inbox are serious. To stand out, consider injecting some lighthearted memes, jokes or interesting links from around the web.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve found this tactic works extremely well, because it gives your readers a dopamine hit in every email. Not every piece of newsletter content you write will resonate with every subscriber. Humor, on the other hand, can have broad appeal. Including interesting and fun content will ensure that every reader is left feeling satisfied.</p>
<p>It also helps build a habit. If every edition is slightly different, your reader will never be sure what they&#8217;re opening when a new edition hits their inbox. We&#8217;ve found that including something fun at the bottom of the newsletter gives readers a reward: Read the serious stuff, then get rewarded with the fun stuff.</p>
<p>We add a meme to each issue. People reply to tell us how much they appreciate it.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184929" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184929" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184929" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/4.png" alt="Add a funny meme or interesting content to engage your readers" width="1024" height="649" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/4.png 1492w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/4.png?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/4.png?resize=300,190 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/4.png?resize=768,487 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/4.png?resize=680,431 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/4.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184929" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<h2>Make referrals seamless</h2>
<p>Referrals are a free way to grow your newsletter. To increase the chances of subscribers referring you to others, make sure the process takes no longer than 25 seconds.</p>
<p>Remind readers at the end of each issue that they can refer others. A simple way is to ask them to forward the email to a friend who would find it interesting. Include a short sentence in the intro to your newsletter telling people being referred where they can subscribe. Include a link.</p>
<p>An advanced tactic is to include a subscriber&#8217;s unique link to a referral program so they can track how many people they&#8217;ve invited. Give them the option to share through email or social media.</p>
<p>You should also have a web version of every issue so that your content can be easily shared outside of email. Most email service providers will automatically generate a web link that you can promote through social media or elsewhere. You can also copy the content and post it to your website as a blog post to generate traffic from search engines.</p>
<p>Consider providing rewards to those who refer your newsletter. Merchandise will likely only work as an incentive if your brand is well known or very unique. We suggest incentivizing referrals using exclusive content. Send a monthly bonus issue to subscribers who have referred five or more friends. This will keep your costs down and give your subscribers more of what they already want.</p>
<p>Note that you will need a critical mass of subscribers before referrals will prove to be effective. We&#8217;ve found the threshold is about 10,000 subscribers. But if your audience is extremely engaged or the community you serve is active, implementing a free referral program has virtually no downside.</p>
<h2>How to turn followers into subscribers</h2>
<p>Your subscribers will likely become aware of your content through a social media channel, but social media audiences are rented from the platform — you do not own a direct channel to communicate with them. Converting followers into newsletter subscribers is one way to control a direct line of communication and deepen your relationship with your audience.</p>
<p>When pitching your followers to subscribe to your newsletter, include a link in your bio. This may sound obvious, but many people don&#8217;t do it. When someone comes across your social media profile, make signing up for your newsletter the call to action. Otherwise, they&#8217;ll have no idea that you even have a newsletter.</p>
<p>You could also cut a Twitter thread or LinkedIn post short and tell people to subscribe for the rest of the insights. You probably don&#8217;t want to overuse this tactic.</p>
<p>Create an offer or unique piece of content that can only be accessed through the newsletter. This will motivate your followers to join your email list to get access to exclusive content or unique offers.</p>
<h2>Recap</h2>
<p><strong>Getting new subscribers:</strong> Use pop-ups that are relevant and only to high-intent readers on your site. Provide proof of why they should subscribe to your newsletter with sample content. Make your welcome email stand out and front-load the first issue with your best content.</p>
<p><strong>Keeping subscribers:</strong> To keep your subscribers wanting more, send fewer emails. Sprinkle in humor and interesting links to turn your newsletter into a habit.</p>
<p><strong>Promoting your newsletter:</strong> Use exclusivity and offers to hook your social media followers into subscribing to your newsletter. Ask your subscribers to refer your newsletter to others to grow your subscriber base.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hPcJD6wSGG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/demand-curve-7-ad-types-that-increase-click-through-rates/">Demand Curve: 7 ad types that increase click-through rates</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Demand Curve: 7 ad types that increase click-through rates&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/demand-curve-7-ad-types-that-increase-click-through-rates/embed/#?secret=hPcJD6wSGG" data-secret="hPcJD6wSGG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/demand-curve-tested-tactics-for-growing-newsletters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184902</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Embodied AI, superintelligence and the master algorithm</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/embodied-ai-superintelligence-and-the-master-algorithm/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/embodied-ai-superintelligence-and-the-master-algorithm/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 19:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybernetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep-reinforcement learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeepMind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nvidia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the next year and a half, we’re going to see increasing adoption of technologies, which will trigger a broader industry shift, much as Tesla triggered the transition to EVs.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Chris Nicholson</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/chrisvnicholson">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		
Chris Nicholson is the founder and CEO of <a href="https://pathmind.com/">Pathmind</a>, a company applying deep reinforcement learning to <a href="https://pathmind.com/use-cases/">industrial operations</a> and supply chains. 
	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/deep-reinforcement-learning-will-transform-manufacturing-as-we-know-it/">Deep reinforcement learning will transform manufacturing as we know it</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/26/machine-learning-can-fix-twitter-facebook-and-maybe-even-america/">UPDATED: Machine learning can fix Twitter, Facebook, and maybe even America</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Superintelligence, roughly defined as an AI algorithm that can solve all problems better than people, will be a watershed for humanity and tech.</p>
<p>Even the best human experts have trouble making predictions about highly probabilistic, wicked problems. And yet those wicked problems surround us. We are all living through immense change in complex systems that impact the climate, public health, geopolitics and basic needs served by the supply chain.</p>
<p>Just determining the best way to distribute COVID-19 vaccines without the help of an algorithm is practically impossible. We need to get smarter in how we solve these problems &#8212; fast.</p>
<p>Superintelligence, if achieved, would help us make better predictions about challenges like natural disasters, building resilient supply chains or geopolitical conflict, and come up with better strategies to solve them. The last decade has shown how much AI can improve the accuracy of our predictions. That’s why there is an international race among corporations and governments around superintelligence.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			In the next year and a half, we’re going to see increasing adoption of technologies, which will trigger a broader industry shift, much as Tesla triggered the transition to EVs.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Highly credible think tanks like Deepmind and OpenAI say that the path to superintelligence is visible. Last month, Deepmind said <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0004370221000862">reinforcement learning (RL) could get us there</a>, and RL is at the heart of embodied AI.</p>
<h2>What is embodied AI?</h2>
<p>Embodied AI is AI that controls a physical “thing,” like a robot arm or an autonomous vehicle. It is able to move through the world and affect a physical environment with its actions, similar to the way a person does. In contrast, most predictive models live in the cloud doing things such as classifying text or images, steering flows of bits without ever moving a body through three-dimensional space.</p>
<p>For those who work in software, including AI researchers, it is too easy to forget the body. But any superintelligent algorithm needs to control a body because so many of the problems we confront as humans are physical. Firestorms, coronaviruses and supply chain breakdowns need solutions that aren’t just digital.</p>
<p>All the crazy Boston Dynamics <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fn3KWM1kuAw">videos</a> of robots jumping, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555535/bts-k-pop-boston-dynamics-spot-robot-dancing-hyundai">dancing</a>, balancing and running are examples of embodied AI. They show how far we’ve come from early breakthroughs in <a href="https://www.techdigest.tv/2007/02/dexter_and_mont.html">dynamic robot balancing</a> made by Trevor Blackwell and Anybots more than a decade ago. The field is moving fast and, in this revolution, you can dance.</p>
<h2>What’s blocked embodied AI up until now?</h2>
<p><strong>Challenge 1: </strong>One of the challenges when controlling machines with AI is the high dimensionality of the world &#8212; the sheer range of things that can come at you.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/embodied-ai-superintelligence-and-the-master-algorithm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185183</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s BharatPe valued at $2.85 billion in Tiger Global-led $370 million funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/india-fintech-bharatpe-valued-at-2-85-billion-in-tiger-global-led-370-million-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/india-fintech-bharatpe-valued-at-2-85-billion-in-tiger-global-led-370-million-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 19:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BharatPe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian fintech startup BharatPe has raised $370 million in a new round of financing as it looks to aggressively scale its business in the next two years. It&#8217;s the nineteenth Indian startup to become a unicorn this year (up from 11 last year) as several high-profile global investors double down in the South Asian market. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Indian fintech startup BharatPe has raised $370 million in a new round of financing as it looks to aggressively scale its business in the next two years. It&#8217;s the nineteenth Indian startup to become a unicorn this year (up from 11 last year) as several high-profile global investors double down in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>The new round &#8212; a Series E &#8212; was led by Tiger Global and valued the New Delhi-based startup at $2.85 billion (post-money), it said in a statement Tuesday evening. Dragoneer Investor Group and Steadfast Capital also participated in the new round, which brings the startup’s to-date raise to over $580 million against equity.</p>
<p>Tuesday’s news <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/tiger-global-in-talks-to-back-bharatpe-at-2-5-billion-valuation/">confirms a TechCrunch scoop from June</a> in which we reported that the four-year-old startup was looking to raise about $250 million at a pre-money valuation of $2.5 billion. BharatPe was valued at about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/india-fintech-bharatpe-valued-at-900-million-in-new-108-million-fundraise/">$900 million in its Series D</a> round in February this year, and $425 million last year.</p>
<p>BharatPe co-founder Ashneer Grover confirmed that the startup was indeed looking to raise $250 million until inbound requests from investors prompted an oversubscription. The new investment also includes some secondary transactions ($20 million).</p>
<p>The startup, <a href="https://themorningcontext.com/internet/what-goes-on-behind-the-scenes-at-bharatpe">mired in some sketchy behavior</a> and which has seen some of its high-profile executives depart in recent quarters, also appointed Suhail Sameer as its new chief executive.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am happy to appoint Suhail Sameer as the CEO in recognition of stupendous business growth he has delivered during the last 1 year and his ability to lead from the front,&#8221; said Grover in a statement.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="htnecUu4vS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/tiger-global-in-talks-to-back-bharatpe-at-2-5-billion-valuation/">Tiger Global in talks to back BharatPe at $2.5 billion valuation</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tiger Global in talks to back BharatPe at $2.5 billion valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/tiger-global-in-talks-to-back-bharatpe-at-2-5-billion-valuation/embed/#?secret=htnecUu4vS" data-secret="htnecUu4vS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>BharatPe, which counts Coatue, Ribbit Capital and Sequoia Capital India among its existing investors, operates an eponymous service to help offline merchants accept digital payments and secure working capital.</p>
<p>Even as India has already emerged as the second-largest internet market, with more than 650 million users, much of the country remains offline.</p>
<p>Among those outside of the reach of the internet are merchants running small businesses, such as roadside tea stalls and neighborhood stores. To make these merchants comfortable with accepting digital payments, BharatPe relies on QR codes and point of sale machines that support government-backed UPI payments infrastructure.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2111978" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2111978" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2111978 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/bharatpe-neighborhood-store-india.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="527" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/bharatpe-neighborhood-store-india.jpg 1722w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/bharatpe-neighborhood-store-india.jpg?resize=150,77 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/bharatpe-neighborhood-store-india.jpg?resize=300,154 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/bharatpe-neighborhood-store-india.jpg?resize=768,395 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/bharatpe-neighborhood-store-india.jpg?resize=680,350 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/bharatpe-neighborhood-store-india.jpg?resize=1536,790 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/bharatpe-neighborhood-store-india.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2111978" class="wp-caption-text">Scores of giants and startups are attempting to serve neighborhood stores in India. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bank of America Research</p></div></p>
<p>The startup, which serves more than 7 million merchants in over 130 Indian cities, said it has disbursed close to $300 million to merchant partners. It does not charge merchants for universal QR code access, but is looking to make money by lending.</p>
<p>BharatPe plans to expand its product offerings as well as work with Centrum Financial Services, with which it was recently granted the license by India’s central bank (Reserve Bank of India) to set up a small finance bank. (Centrum Financial Services has collaborated with BharatPe for the license, and the Indian startup says the two are “equal” partners.)</p>
<p>&#8220;We now have US$ 0.5B cash on books and are extremely well capitalized to deliver on our mandate to build India’s first truly Digital Bank. Rarely does one witness the original thesis play out without any pivot,&#8221; said Grover.</p>
<p>Tuesday&#8217;s development further illustrates the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/11/tiger-global-goes-super-aggressive-in-india/">growing interest of Tiger Global in India</a>. The New York-headquartered firm has backed dozens of Indian startups, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/indian-social-commerce-dealshare-raises-144-million-eyes-international-expansion/">social commerce startup DealShare</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/tiger-global-in-talks-to-invest-in-classplus-at-over-250-million-valuation/">edtech Classplus</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/india-jobs-app-apna-raises-70-million/">Apna</a> (an app that helps blue-collar workers connect with recruiters) and home services platform <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/01/home-services-platform-urban-company-raises-255-million-at-2-1-billion-valuation/">Urban Company</a> in recent months.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Infra.Market, an Indian startup that helps construction and real estate companies procure materials and handle logistics for their projects, said it had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/india-infra-market-valued-at-2-5b-in-tiger-global-led-125m-funding/">raised $125 million in a round led also by Tiger Global</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aOFvoQObfG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/16/india-poised-for-record-vc-year-as-unicorns-head-for-decisive-ipos/">India poised for record VC year as unicorns head for decisive IPOs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India poised for record VC year as unicorns head for decisive IPOs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/16/india-poised-for-record-vc-year-as-unicorns-head-for-decisive-ipos/embed/#?secret=aOFvoQObfG" data-secret="aOFvoQObfG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/india-fintech-bharatpe-valued-at-2-85-billion-in-tiger-global-led-370-million-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185186</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Security flaws found in popular EV chargers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/security-flaws-found-in-popular-ev-chargers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/security-flaws-found-in-popular-ev-chargers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 18:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle charging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pen test partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology policy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.K. cybersecurity company Pen Test Partners has identified several vulnerabilities in the APIs of six home electric vehicle charging brands and a large public EV charging network. While the charger manufacturers resolved most of the issues, the findings are the latest example of the poorly regulated world of Internet of Things devices, which are poised [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">U.K. cybersecurity company Pen Test Partners has identified several vulnerabilities in the APIs of six home electric vehicle charging brands and a large public EV charging network. While the charger manufacturers resolved most of the issues, the findings are the latest example of the poorly regulated world of Internet of Things devices, which are poised to become all but ubiquitous in our homes and vehicles.</p>
<p>Vulnerabilities were identified in the API of six different EV charging brands — Project EV, Wallbox, EVBox, EO Charging’s EO Hub and EO mini pro 2, Rolec and Hypervolt — and public charging network Chargepoint. Security researcher Vangelis Stykas identified several security flaws among the various brands that could have allowed a malicious hacker to hijack user accounts, impede charging and even turn one of the chargers into a &#8220;backdoor&#8221; into the owner’s home network.</p>
<p>The consequences of a hack to a public charging station network could include theft of electricity at the expense of driver accounts and turning chargers on or off.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185146" style="width: 381px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185146" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2185146 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/wallbox.png" alt="" width="371" height="415" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/wallbox.png 371w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/wallbox.png?resize=134,150 134w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/wallbox.png?resize=268,300 268w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/wallbox.png?resize=45,50 45w" sizes="(max-width: 371px) 100vw, 371px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185146" class="wp-caption-text">A Raspberry Pi in a Wallbox charger. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.pentestpartners.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pen Test Partners <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Some EV chargers used a Raspberry Pi compute module, a low-cost computer that&#8217;s often used by hobbyists and programmers.</p>
<p>“The Pi is a great hobbyist and educational computing platform, but in our opinion it’s not suitable for commercial applications as it doesn’t have what’s known as a &#8216;secure bootloader,&#8217;” Pen Test Partners founder Ken Munro told TechCrunch. “This means anyone with physical access to the outside of your home (hence to your charger) could open it up and steal your Wi-Fi credentials. Yes, the risk is low, but I don’t think charger vendors should be exposing us to additional risk.”</p>
<p>The hacks are &#8220;really fairly simple,&#8221; Munro said. “I can teach you to do this in five minutes,” he added.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s report, <a href="https://www.pentestpartners.com/security-blog/smart-car-chargers-plug-n-play-for-hackers/">published this past weekend</a>, touched on vulnerabilities associated with emerging protocols like the Open Charge Point Interface, maintained and managed by the EVRoaming Foundation. The protocol was designed to make charging seamless between different charging networks and operators.</p>
<p>Munro likened it to roaming on a cell phone, allowing drivers to use networks outside of their usual charging network. OCPI isn’t widely used at the moment, so these vulnerabilities could be designed out of the protocol. But if left unaddressed, it could mean &#8220;that a vulnerability in one platform potentially creates a vulnerability in another,&#8221; Stykas explained.</p>
<p>Hacks to charging stations have become a particularly nefarious threat as a greater share of transportation becomes electrified and more power flows through the electric grid. Electric grids are not designed for large swings in power consumption — but that’s exactly what could happen, should there be a large hack that turned on or off a sufficient number of DC fast chargers.</p>
<p>“It doesn’t take that much to trip the power grid to overload,” Munro said. “We’ve inadvertently made a cyberweapon that others could use against us.”</p>
<h2>The &#8220;Wild West&#8221; of cybersecurity</h2>
<p>While the effects on the electric grid are unique to EV chargers, cybersecurity issues aren’t. The routine hacks reveal more endemic issues in IoT devices, where being first to market often takes precedence over sound security — and where regulators are barely able to catch up to the pace of innovation.</p>
<p>“There’s really not a lot of enforcement,” Justin Brookman, the director of consumer privacy and technology policy for Consumer Reports, told TechCrunch in a recent interview. Data security enforcement in the United States falls within the purview of the Federal Trade Commission. But while there is a general-purpose consumer protection statute on the books, &#8220;it may well be illegal to build a system that has poor security, it’s just whether you&#8217;re going to get enforced against or not,” said Brookman.</p>
<p>A separate federal bill, the Internet of Things Cybersecurity Improvement Act, passed last September but only broadly applies to the federal government.</p>
<p>There’s only slightly more movement on the state level. In 2018, California passed a bill <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/05/california-passes-law-that-bans-default-passwords-in-connected-devices/">banning default passwords</a> in new consumer electronics starting in 2020 — useful progress to be sure, but which largely puts the burden of data security in the hands of consumers. California, as well as states like Colorado and Virginia, also have passed laws requiring reasonable security measures for IoT devices.</p>
<p>Such laws are a good start. But (for better or worse) the FTC isn’t like the U.S. Food and Drug Administration, which audits consumer products before they hit the market. As of now, there’s no security check on technology devices prior to them reaching consumers. Over in the United Kingdom, “it’s the Wild West over here as well, right now,” Munro said.</p>
<p>Some startups have emerged that are trying to tackle this issue. One is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/thistle-technology-seed-security-iot/">Thistle Technologies</a>, which is trying to help IoT device manufacturers integrate mechanisms into their software to receive security updates. But it’s unlikely this problem will be fully solved on the back of private industry alone.</p>
<p>Because EV chargers could pose a unique threat to the electric grid, there’s a possibility that EV chargers could fall under the scope of a critical infrastructure bill. Last week, President Joe Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/national-security-memorandum-on-improving-cybersecurity-for-critical-infrastructure-control-systems/">released a memorandum</a> calling for greater cybersecurity for systems related to critical infrastructure. “The degradation, destruction or malfunction of systems that control this infrastructure could cause significant harm to the national and economic security of the United States,” Biden said. Whether this will trickle down to consumer products is another question.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oFWkHMaBIs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/enterprise-security-attackers-are-one-password-away-from-your-worst-day/">Enterprise security attackers are one password away from your worst day</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Enterprise security attackers are one password away from your worst day&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/enterprise-security-attackers-are-one-password-away-from-your-worst-day/embed/#?secret=oFWkHMaBIs" data-secret="oFWkHMaBIs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dUKWiPpwzH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/05/california-passes-law-that-bans-default-passwords-in-connected-devices/">California passes law that bans default passwords in connected devices</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;California passes law that bans default passwords in connected devices&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/05/california-passes-law-that-bans-default-passwords-in-connected-devices/embed/#?secret=dUKWiPpwzH" data-secret="dUKWiPpwzH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/security-flaws-found-in-popular-ev-chargers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185141</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fleet your last Fleet — the Twitter feature vanishes today</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/twitter-fleets-rip/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/twitter-fleets-rip/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 18:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fleets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You don&#8217;t know what you&#8217;ve got &#8217;til it&#8217;s gone. After a fittingly fleeting time in the wild, Twitter is banishing its ephemeral stories feature known as Fleets, which debuted in November 2020. Twitter began testing Fleets back in March of last year. The company thought that it might be able to lure people who were [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You don&#8217;t know what you&#8217;ve got &#8217;til it&#8217;s gone.</p>
<p>After a fittingly fleeting time in the wild, Twitter is banishing its ephemeral stories feature known as Fleets, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/twitter-rolls-out-stories-aka-fleets-to-all-users-will-also-test-a-clubhouse-rival/">which debuted in November 2020</a>.</p>
<p>Twitter began testing Fleets back in March of last year. The company thought that it might be able to lure people who were hesitant about collecting their stray thoughts into the platform&#8217;s semi-permanent format with a &#8220;lower-pressure&#8221; kind of a tweet. Many major social platforms have some form of disappearing content, so it made sense that Twitter would give things a try too — but after eight months live, Twitter is killing the feature.</p>
<p>Like Instagram Stories, Fleets lived on top of the timeline, highlighted in their own dedicated space. As fleets phase out, Spaces, Twitter&#8217;s Clubhouse-like audio rooms, will occupy the same slot in the app.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">if you see a Fleet no you didn&#39;t <a href="https://t.co/4rKI7f45PL">https://t.co/4rKI7f45PL</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Twitter (@Twitter) <a href="https://twitter.com/Twitter/status/1422609438557491205?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 3, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The company hoped that Fleets would bring new users under its wing, but the only people who really adopted the new feature were apparently already Twitter diehards. Twitter said it would go back to the drawing board to figure out how to get more people participating on Twitter and Fleets were an unfortunate casualty of that realization. Some members of the product team that built Fleets shared their thoughts on Twitter in the feature&#8217;s waning hours.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">it&#39;s easy to think fleets was just a stories clone. we never aimed to compete on the best creation tools/filters/etc. we wanted to be raw and authentic. non-performative. feel lighter than tweeting. with the unique twitter network as a differentiator.</p>
<p>&mdash; Paul Stamatiou (@Stammy) <a href="https://twitter.com/Stammy/status/1422283686762983424?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 2, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&#8220;If we&#8217;re not evolving our approach and winding down features every once in a while – we&#8217;re not taking big enough chances,&#8221; Twitter Consumer Product VP Ilya Brown said in a <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/product/2021/goodbye-fleets">blog post</a>.</p>
<p>We can only hope that Twitter&#8217;s future products continue the <a href="https://www.sfweekly.com/culture/sex/butt-stuff-part-two/">gay sex naming scheme</a> that the company accidentally introduced when it named Fleets &#8220;fleets.&#8221; (Congrats, <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterComms/status/1422389683296690177">gay former intern</a>!)</p>
<p>To the company&#8217;s chagrin, the feature&#8217;s swift demise apparently <a href="https://twitter.com/NickPacilio/status/1422293917714849796">inspired more enthusiasm for the product</a> than Fleets had enjoyed previously. Twitter&#8217;s tweet announcing the death of Fleets also somehow turned into an iconic enough moment that the company made it into a collectible hoodie that reads &#8220;We&#8217;re sorry or you&#8217;re welcome,&#8221; ensuring that Fleets will live on in our hearts until we inevitably forget they ever existed — perhaps the most fitting tribute of all.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">this hoodie we made for you is also chef&#39;s kiss. check your DMs <a href="https://t.co/JnFaapW0rO">pic.twitter.com/JnFaapW0rO</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Twitter (@Twitter) <a href="https://twitter.com/Twitter/status/1422595776124006402?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 3, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E2sONp0Qud"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/twitter-is-shutting-down-fleets-on-august-3-citing-low-usage/">Twitter is shutting down Fleets on August 3, citing low usage</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter is shutting down Fleets on August 3, citing low usage&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/twitter-is-shutting-down-fleets-on-august-3-citing-low-usage/embed/#?secret=E2sONp0Qud" data-secret="E2sONp0Qud" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KIdDQMSqZV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/twitter-rolls-out-stories-aka-fleets-to-all-users-will-also-test-a-clubhouse-rival/">Twitter rolls out Stories, aka &#8216;Fleets,&#8217; to all users; will also test a Clubhouse rival</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter rolls out Stories, aka &#8216;Fleets,&#8217; to all users; will also test a Clubhouse rival&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/twitter-rolls-out-stories-aka-fleets-to-all-users-will-also-test-a-clubhouse-rival/embed/#?secret=KIdDQMSqZV" data-secret="KIdDQMSqZV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/twitter-fleets-rip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185130</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Silicon Valley VC firm with $1.8B in assets was hit by ransomware</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/atv-venture-capital-ransomware/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 17:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attorney general]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cedexis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fandango]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Bureau of Investigation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[securedrop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Advanced Technology Ventures, a Silicon Valley venture capital firm with more than $1.8 billion in assets under its management, was hit by a ransomware attack in July that saw cybercriminals steal personal information on the company&#8217;s private investors, or limited partners (LPs). In a letter to the Maine attorney general&#8217;s office, ATV said it became [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Advanced Technology Ventures, a Silicon Valley venture capital firm with more than $1.8 billion in assets under its management, was hit by a ransomware attack in July that saw cybercriminals steal personal information on the company&#8217;s private investors, or limited partners (LPs).</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21033785-advanced-technology-ventures">a letter</a> to the Maine attorney general&#8217;s office, ATV said it became aware of the attack on July 9 after its servers storing financial information had been encrypted by ransomware. By July 26, the ATV learned that data had been stolen from the servers before the files were encrypted, a common <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/as-ransomware-gets-craftier-companies-must-start-thinking-creatively/">&#8220;double extortion&#8221; tactic</a> used by ransomware groups, which then threaten to publish the files online if the ransom to decrypt the files is not paid.</p>
<p>The letter said ATV believes the names, email addresses, phone numbers and Social Security numbers of the individual investors in ATV&#8217;s funds were stolen in the attack. Some<span style="letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> 300 individuals were affected by the incident, including one person in Maine, according to a listing on the Maine attorney general&#8217;s <a style="background-color: #ffffff; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://apps.web.maine.gov/online/aeviewer/ME/40/7e015fa7-e338-450c-a8fb-f0056d59e467.shtml?=2a8bf27469bf669a2753cacd93ca6a51ca952e56">data breach notification portal</a>.</span></p>
<p>Venture capital firms often do not disclose all of their LPs — the investors who have thrown millions into an investment vehicle — to the public. A number of pre-approved names may be included in an announcement, but overall, a company&#8217;s private investors try to stay that way: private. The reasons vary, but it comes down to secrecy and a degree of competitive advantage: The firm may not want competitors to know who is backing them, and an investor may not want others to know where their money is going. This particular attack likely stole key information on a hush-hush part of how venture money works.</p>
<p>ATV said it notified the FBI about the attack. A spokesperson for the FBI did not immediately comment when reached by TechCrunch.<span style="letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> ATV&#8217;s managing director Mike Carusi did not respond to questions sent by TechCrunch on Monday.</span></p>
<p>The venture capital firm, based in Menlo Park, California with offices in Boston, was founded in 1979 and invests largely in technology, communications, software and services, and healthcare technology. The company was an early investor in many of the startups from the last decade, like software library Fandango, Host Analytics (now Planfun) and Apptegic (now Evergage). Its more recent investments include Tripwire, which was later sold to cybersecurity company Belden for $710 million; Cedexis, a network traffic monitoring startup acquired by Cisco in 2018; and Actifo, which was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-acquires-actifio-to-step-into-the-area-of-data-management-and-business-continuity/">sold to Google</a> in 2020.</p>
<hr />
<p><em>Natasha Mascarenhas contributed reporting. Send tips securely over Signal and WhatsApp to +1 646-755-8849. You can also send TechCrunch files or documents using our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/securedrop">SecureDrop</a>.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OIevL5lHm4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/">To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/embed/#?secret=OIevL5lHm4" data-secret="OIevL5lHm4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185063</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anonymous Snapchat-connected app Sendit surges with 3.5M installs after Snap suspends YOLO and LMK</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/anonymous-snapchat-app-sendit-surges-with-3-5m-installs-after-snap-bans-yolo-and-lmk/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/anonymous-snapchat-app-sendit-surges-with-3-5m-installs-after-snap-bans-yolo-and-lmk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 17:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anonymous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apptopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LMK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapkit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yolo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184502</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In May of this year, Snap suspended two Snapchat-integrated apps that allowed users to send anonymous messages, Yolo and LMK, following a lawsuit filed on behalf of a mother whose son died by suicide after being bullied through messages on the apps for many months. In the wake of the suspensions, another anonymous messaging app [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In May of this year, <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/technology/story/2021-05-11/snapchat-suspends-yolo-lmk">Snap suspended two Snapchat-integrated apps</a> that allowed users to send anonymous messages, Yolo and LMK, following <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/05/snap-cuts-off-yolo-lmk-anonymous-messaging-apps-after-lawsuit-over-teens-death/">a lawsuit</a> filed on behalf of a mother whose son died by suicide after being bullied through messages on the apps for many months. In the wake of the suspensions, another anonymous messaging app called <a href="https://getsendit.com/">Sendit</a> has been rising in the app stores&#8217; charts, as Snapchat&#8217;s younger users sought a replacement for the apps the company blocked.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Since the news of the suspensions was first <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/technology/story/2021-05-11/snapchat-suspends-yolo-lmk">reported</a> over 80 days ago, Sendit&#8217;s app has seen more than 3.5 million installs across iOS and Android, according to app intelligence firm Apptopia. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">This is a rapid pace of installs compared with how quickly it grew while Yolo and LMK were active on the market. </span>In the same period before the news was announced, Sendit had only seen seen 180,000 installs across <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/sendit-get-anonymous-love/id1439623630">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fullsenders.sendit&amp;hl=en_US&amp;gl=US">Android</a>, Apptopia says.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184608" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184608" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2184608 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png 1736w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?resize=768,767 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?resize=1536,1534 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-02-at-11.56.44-AM.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184608" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apptopia</p></div></p>
<p>Sendit also received few user reviews before May 11, 2021. But in the days that followed the suspension, &#8220;yolo&#8221; has become the second-most-used keyword in Sendit&#8217;s user reviews, Apptopia told TechCrunch. Most of these reviews are positive, saying the app is like &#8220;Yolo but better,&#8221; for instance. In other words, Snap&#8217;s suspension hasn&#8217;t stamped out demand for anonymous Snapchat Q&amp;A apps, it only crowned a new app as the market leader.</p>
<p>Sendit today is currently ranking No. 3 among Lifestyle apps on Apple&#8217;s U.S. App Store and has climbed to No. 57 on the App Store&#8217;s list of top free apps. It jumped three ranks overnight from Monday to Tuesday, in fact.</p>
<p>Like Yolo and LMK, Sendit also features a popular teen activity on Snapchat, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/28/anonymous-snapchat-group-chat-yolo">anonymous Q&amp;As.</a> The app also includes other Lens games, like &#8220;Never Have I Ever,&#8221; &#8220;This or That,&#8221; &#8220;Kiss, Marry, Block&#8221; and others.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To be clear, none of these are official Snapchat applications. Instead, they integrate with a toolkit for third-party developers called <a href="https://kit.snapchat.com/">Snap Kit,</a> which allows them to create new product experiences that work with Snapchat&#8217;s best features, like Stories, Bitmoji, the Snapchat Camera and <a href="https://kit.snapchat.com/">more</a>.</p>
<p>Snap says its Snap Kit developers have to agree to its Terms of Service, which requires apps to prioritize user safety and take action on any reports of abuse. Those guidelines are meant to encompass any reports of bullying, harassment, hate speech or threats taking place on the third-party services. In addition, apps that offer friend finding, user-generated content and anonymous features are supposed to inform Snap of their moderation practices and customer support response times.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185118" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185118" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2185118" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="615" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS-1.jpg 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS-1.jpg?resize=150,136 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS-1.jpg?resize=300,271 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS-1.jpg?resize=768,695 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS-1.jpg?resize=680,615 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS-1.jpg?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185118" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Screenshot of public App Store review of sendit; username redacted</p></div></p>
<p>In practice, however &#8212; as the lawsuit highlighted &#8212; there appears to be an issue with how well those terms are enforced on Snap&#8217;s end. The company tells us that it&#8217;s continuing to review developers to ensure their compliance. It has yet to announce any policy changes as result of that investigation, but <a href="https://www.nydailynews.com/opinion/ny-oped-apps-that-are-dangerous-to-kids-health-20210607-z6got3ejcvd4jaj3wenkjqzxje-story.html">some</a> <a href="https://www.commonsensemedia.org/blog/apps-to-watch-out-for">child</a> <a href="https://www.tullahomanews.com/news/local/child-advocates-certain-apps-pose-risks/article_4ccf03dc-3a07-11e9-86f6-b3b70d5e02df.html">advocates</a> would argue that anonymous apps should have no place in a teenager&#8217;s life at all.</p>
<p>Even before the Snap lawsuit, apps like Yolo and LMK had raised concerns among child advocates and parents alike. For example, nonprofit Common Sense Media, an independent source for media recommendations and advice for families, <a href="https://www.commonsensemedia.org/app-reviews/lmk-anonymous-polls">pointed out that</a> &#8220;anonymity on social media can easily lead teens down a slippery slope of poor choices.&#8221; The organization said that while teens will be drawn to the excitement of responding anonymously &#8212; perhaps learning that someone might have a crush on them &#8212; &#8220;hiding behind anonymity can also bring out hatefulness and sexually explicit risk taking.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sendit&#8217;s App Store reviews (see photos) indicate that is, indeed, taking place. (Sendit didn&#8217;t respond to a request for more information about its app&#8217;s operations.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185119" style="width: 466px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185119" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2185119" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS.jpg?w=456" alt="" width="456" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS.jpg 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS.jpg?resize=101,150 101w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS.jpg?resize=201,300 201w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS.jpg?resize=768,1145 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS.jpg?resize=456,680 456w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS.jpg?resize=1030,1536 1030w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Image-from-iOS.jpg?resize=34,50 34w" sizes="(max-width: 456px) 100vw, 456px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185119" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Screenshot of public App Store review of sendit; username redacted</p></div></p>
<p>The tech industry is littered with anonymous social apps that failed due to issues with cyberbullying. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/08/12/in-wake-of-teen-suicides-ask-fm-faces-a-myspace-problem/">After numerous</a> teen suicides related to Ask.fm&#8217;s anonymous platform, its owner IAC <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-36702766">sold off</a> the toxic property to an asset management firm. Other high-profile anonymous app failures include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/29/psst/">Secret</a>, which became a home to cyberbullying; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/31/after-bans-from-apple-and-google-sarahah-debuts-enoff-for-anonymous-feedback-at-work/">Sarahah,</a> which was banned by the app stores and later pivoted; Yik Yak, whose <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/28/yik-yak-shuts-down-after-square-paid-1-million-for-its-engineers/">founders left for Square</a> after the app became plagued by cyberbullying; and After School, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/12/03/after-school-is-the-latest-anonymous-app-resulting-in-student-cyberbullying-and-school-threats/">which also got kicked out</a> of the App Store. To date, only anonymous platforms like Glassdoor and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/blind-raises-37m-to-double-down-on-workplace-gossip-and-career-advice/">Blind</a>, which focus on workplace chatter and career advice, have seemed to thrive.</p>
<p>The question for Snap to decide now is not just how it will enforce its terms on anonymous apps, but whether it&#8217;s worth allowing anonymous apps to operate given their documented dangers &#8212; and their potential tragic, as well as legal, consequences.</p>
<p><em>If you or someone you know is struggling with depression or has had thoughts of harming themselves or taking their own life, The National Suicide Prevention Lifeline (1-800-273-8255) provides 24/7, free, confidential support for people in distress, as well as best practices for professionals and resources to aid in prevention and crisis situations.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/anonymous-snapchat-app-sendit-surges-with-3-5m-installs-after-snap-bans-yolo-and-lmk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184502</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Maps on iOS adds live location sharing in iMessage, home screen widget, dark mode</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/google-maps-on-ios-adds-live-location-sharing-in-imessage-home-screen-widget-and-dark-mode/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/google-maps-on-ios-adds-live-location-sharing-in-imessage-home-screen-widget-and-dark-mode/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 17:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gas station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imessage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS 15]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waze]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google Maps announced today three feature updates to its iOS app. With live location sharing in the iMessage app, a traffic widget for the home screen and dark mode, Google Maps is positioning itself as a stronger competitor against iOS&#8217; native Apple Maps. Live location sharing was already possible in Google Maps &#8212; by tapping [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google Maps <a href="https://blog.google/products/maps/widgets-dark-mode-3-updates-google-maps-ios/">announced today</a> three feature updates to its iOS app. With live location sharing in the iMessage app, a traffic widget for the home screen and dark mode, Google Maps is positioning itself as a stronger competitor against iOS&#8217; native Apple Maps.</p>
<p>Live location sharing was already possible in Google Maps &#8212; by tapping on the blue dot that shows where you are, you can share with select friends your ETA to your destination, and even how much battery life your phone has. But the Google Maps iMessage widget makes it easier to share your location without navigating away from your conversation. By default, Google Maps will share your location for one hour, but it&#8217;s possible to extend to up to three days &#8212; if you want to stop sharing, tap the &#8220;stop&#8221; button on the thumbnail.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185094" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185094" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2185094" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Untitled.gif?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185094" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google Maps</p></div></p>
<p>Google Maps&#8217; existing iMessage widget allows users to send GPS coordinates of their location in iMessage &#8212; but if you&#8217;re trying to meet up with friends, this wouldn&#8217;t be as useful as sharing a live location. Apple Maps already has a similar feature built into iMessage, so Google is taking a leaf out of Apple&#8217;s book to try to beat them on their own app. For a long time, Google Maps was widely considered to be the superior navigation app, but in 2018, Apple completely <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/29/apple-is-rebuilding-maps-from-the-ground-up/">rebuilt Maps from the ground up</a>, making it more competitive. Plus, as iOS 15 rolls out, Apple Maps <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-maps-upgrade-brings-more-detailed-maps-transit-features-ar-view-and-more/">will add</a> AR functionality, better public transit features, more detailed maps and other improvements.</p>
<p>Google Maps added <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/17/google-maps-adds-more-waze-like-features-including-driving-incident-reports/">Waze-like traffic and incident report features</a> to its app in 2019, which made it more appealing for driving commuters &#8212; the app says that one of its &#8220;most powerful features is the ability to see live traffic conditions in an area.&#8221; Now, users with the latest Google Maps app will be able to add a traffic widget to their home screen, which can quickly share what traffic is like in their area. The widget also allows users to set frequent destinations, like home, work or the gas station, and navigate to those places with just a tap. Though the app already has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/07/android-q-scores-a-system-wide-dark-theme/">dark mode</a> on Android, this feature will also roll out to iOS users in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>As Google Maps and Apple Maps compete to become the best navigation app, an unlikely competitor comes in Snapchat, which has created a more social experience on its Snap Map. Last week, Snapchat added the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/snapchat-adds-my-places-feature-to-snap-map-connecting-users-to-businesses/">My Places</a> feature to the Snap Map, which helps users find new spots to visit based on the activity of other users in their area. The ephemeral messaging app also announced at the end of July that during Q2 of 2021, the platform grew both revenue and daily active users at the highest rates it has achieved in the last four years. Still, as of last year, Google Maps had <a href="https://blog.google/products/maps/maps-15th-birthday/">over 1 billion worldwide</a> users.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OsTySh5e7V"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-maps-upgrade-brings-more-detailed-maps-transit-features-ar-view-and-more/">Apple Maps upgrade brings more detailed maps, transit features, AR view and more</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple Maps upgrade brings more detailed maps, transit features, AR view and more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-maps-upgrade-brings-more-detailed-maps-transit-features-ar-view-and-more/embed/#?secret=OsTySh5e7V" data-secret="OsTySh5e7V" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/google-maps-on-ios-adds-live-location-sharing-in-imessage-home-screen-widget-and-dark-mode/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185054</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FandangoNOW and Vudu merge into a new streaming service with titles to rent, buy or stream free</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/fandangonow-and-vudu-merge-into-a-new-streaming-service-with-titles-to-rent-buy-or-stream-free/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/fandangonow-and-vudu-merge-into-a-new-streaming-service-with-titles-to-rent-buy-or-stream-free/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 17:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fandango]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nbcuniversal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vudu]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year, movie ticketing and discovery business Fandango, a division of NBCUniversal, bought the on-demand video streaming service Vudu from Walmart, after the retailer had failed to capitalize on the service it had first acquired in 2010 for $100 million. Today, Fandango is taking the next steps with Vudu by merging the service with its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last year, movie ticketing and discovery business Fandango, a <a href="https://together.nbcuni.com/n/fandango/">division</a> of NBCUniversal, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/20/walmart-is-selling-its-on-demand-video-service-vudu-to-fandango/">bought the on-demand video streaming service Vudu</a> from Walmart, after the retailer had failed to capitalize on the service it had first acquired in 2010 for $100 million. Today, Fandango is taking the next steps with Vudu by merging the service with its existing streaming platform, FandangoNOW. The newly combined service will continue to use the name Vudu and will feature over 200,000 new release and catalog movies and TV shows to rent or buy without a subscription, as well as &#8220;thousands&#8221; of free-to-stream titles.</p>
<p>The company tells us it chose to stick with &#8220;Vudu&#8221; as its name because it&#8217;s already a popular brand with a loyal following and is significantly larger than the FandangoNOW service.</p>
<p>Despite the changes coming to the service, existing FandangoNOW customers won&#8217;t lose access to any of the content they already purchased. Both their movies and TV series will be automatically transferred over to the new Vudu service starting today.</p>
<p>Currently, Vudu&#8217;s on-demand library competes with Apple iTunes, Amazon Prime Video and Google Play/YouTube, as well as similar services from various telecos. In particular, these types of services appeal to those who want to watch new releases and have the option to own favorite movies and shows &#8212; rather than subscribe to services where such content comes and goes as licensing deals expire.</p>
<p>At launch, the newly merged Vudu will include new releases like “F9: The Fast Saga,” Pixar’s “Luca,” “The Conjuring: The Devil Made Me Do It,” “Peter Rabbit 2,” “The Hitman’s Wife’s Bodyguard,” “A Quiet Place Part II,” Disney’s “Cruella,” “Godzilla vs. Kong,” “In the Heights” and others. Next Tuesday, it will also gain access to Marvel Studios’ “Black Widow&#8221; &#8212; the title that&#8217;s now the subject of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/scarlett-johansson-files-suit-over-disney-black-widow-release/">a breach of contract lawsuit</a> filed on behalf of actress Scarlett Johansson, who&#8217;s suing Disney for sending what was supposed to be a theatrical release directly to its streaming service Disney+ on opening day.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185033" style="width: 388px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185033" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2185033" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/vudu.jpg?w=378" alt="" width="378" height="254" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/vudu.jpg 378w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/vudu.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/vudu.jpg?resize=300,202 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/vudu.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 378px) 100vw, 378px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185033" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fandango</p></div></p>
<p>Many titles are available in 4K Ultra HD and support formats such as Dolby Atmos and Dolby Vision, the company notes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Vudu already has a large, built-in audience for its movie and TV marketplace. Fandango claims the service has over 60 million registered users and reaches &#8220;millions&#8221; on a daily basis.</p>
<p>By way of its expansive platform support, it&#8217;s capable of reaching over 75 million U.S. TV-connected device households, per NPD Group data. This includes Vudu&#8217;s support for Samsung, LG and Vizio smart TVs; the Roku platform, Amazon Fire TV, Apple TV, Xfinity X1 and Xfinity Flex, PlayStation, Xbox, Tivo and others.</p>
<p>Following the merger and rebranding, the new Vudu service will also take FandangoNOW&#8217;s place as the <a href="https://support.roku.com/article/208756538">official movie store</a> on the Roku platform, where consumers can rent or purchase using Roku Pay.</p>
<p>Vudu joins Fandango&#8217;s existing digital network, which will continue to include Fandango&#8217;s movie ticketing business, MovieTickets.com, Flixster, Movieclips and Rotten Tomatoes. While the merger of the two services at least clears up some overlap within the Fandango division, NBCU parent company Comcast continues to have its own overlap issues when it comes to streaming. Comcast <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/25/comcast-acquires-xumo/">acquired ad-supported streaming service Xumo</a> in February 2020 and, via NBCU, runs the year-old <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/nbcuniversals-streaming-service-peacock-officially-launches-tomorrow/">streaming service Peacock.</a> As of yet, it hasn&#8217;t made any moves to centralize those efforts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="asCsQlFrpr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/streaming-services-face-their-real-test-in-2021/">Streaming services face their real test in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Streaming services face their real test in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/streaming-services-face-their-real-test-in-2021/embed/#?secret=asCsQlFrpr" data-secret="asCsQlFrpr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/fandangonow-and-vudu-merge-into-a-new-streaming-service-with-titles-to-rent-buy-or-stream-free/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edtech startup bina raises $1.4M to teach 4- to 12-year-olds, launch School-as-a-Service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/edtech-startup-bina-raises-1-4m-to-teach-4-to-12-year-olds-launch-school-as-a-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/edtech-startup-bina-raises-1-4m-to-teach-4-to-12-year-olds-launch-school-as-a-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 16:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advisors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jutta steiner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OECD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outschool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parity Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pearson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taizo Son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teacher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Bank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the pandemic wreaking havoc amongst early years education amid school lockdowns, it’s no wonder edtech startups have piled into the space. But it has also served to highlight the abysmal nature of early years teaching: Some 40 million teachers across the globe are leaving the sector, according to the World Bank. Of the 1.5 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With the pandemic wreaking havoc amongst early years education amid school lockdowns, it’s no wonder edtech startups have piled into the space. But it has also served to highlight the abysmal nature of early years teaching: Some 40 million teachers across the globe are <a href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/topic/teachers#:~:text=There%20are%20close%20to%2085,and%2012.5%20in%20tertiary%20education.">leaving</a> the sector, according to the World Bank. Of the 1.5 billion primary-age children, only a few can access high-quality education, and approximately 58 million primary-age children are out of education, <a href="http://www.unesco.org/new/en/media-services/in-focus-articles/unesco-no-progress-in-reducing-global-number-of-children-out-of-school/#:~:text=A%20new%20UNESCO%20policy%20paper,little%20overall%20improvement%20since%202007.&amp;text=Most%20of%20these%20children%20will,at%20risk%20of%20dropping%20out.">most of whom are girls</a>.</p>
<p>So the opportunity to make a difference, using online teaching, in these very young years, is great, because classes sizes can be reduced online, and the quality of teaching improved.</p>
<p>This is the idea behind <a href="https://www.thebinaschool.com/">bina</a>, which bills itself as a “digital primary education ecosystem”. It has now raised $1.4 million to aim at the education of 4- to 12-year-olds.</p>
<p>The funding round was led by <a href="https://www.forbes.com/profile/taizo-son/?sh=2fe2f5961c9b">Taizo Son</a>, one of Japan’s billionaires. Other investors and advisors include Jutta Steiner, founder at Parity Technologies, the company behind Polkadot decentralized protocol, and Lord Jim Knight, ex-Minister of Education (U.K.).</p>
<p>Bina’s &#8220;schtick&#8221; is that it has very small online class sizes of six students (3x smaller than the <a href="https://stats.oecd.org/Index.aspx?DataSetCode=EDU_CLASS#">OECD average</a>).</p>
<p>It also boasts of “adaptive learning paths” that cover international standards; teachers with a minimum of eight years of digital teaching experience; and data-driven decision making for its pedagogical approach.</p>
<p>Noam Gerstein, bina&#8217;s CEO and founder said: “I’ve interviewed students, teachers and parents globally for years, and it is clear a new systemic design is needed. With our founding families, we are building a world in which every child has access to quality education, educators&#8217; skills are valued and continuously developed, and parents don&#8217;t need to choose between their work and family life.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He says it also grants pupils company shares (RSUs) as they grow with the school. Currently available to English-speaking students in the CET time zone, the bina School is planning a SaaS product for governments, NGOs and school systems.</p>
<p>“We right now compete against companies like Outschool, Pearson&#8217;s online Academy, Primer and Prisma,” he told me over a call. “So these are the big names of the last year for the first phase. But the strategy is that we&#8217;re building it in two phases. The first phase is actually building a school that we operate as a &#8216;lab&#8217; school. And the second phase is what we call &#8216;bina as a service&#8217;. So it&#8217;s a SaaS &#8216;school as a service&#8217;. The idea is that we offer collaboration with NGOs and governments, doing accreditation and training and licencing of the product. So for that second part we&#8217;re actually competing against the big accreditation system.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PrMifuD6HB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/the-2021-edtech-avalanche-has-just-begun/">The 2021 edtech avalanche has just begun</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The 2021 edtech avalanche has just begun&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/the-2021-edtech-avalanche-has-just-begun/embed/#?secret=PrMifuD6HB" data-secret="PrMifuD6HB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/edtech-startup-bina-raises-1-4m-to-teach-4-to-12-year-olds-launch-school-as-a-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185082</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CELA Innovation holds a master class on Lean Startup Methodology for the Startup Alley+ cohort</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/cela-innovation-holds-a-masterclass-on-lean-startup-methodology-for-the-startup-alley-cohort/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/cela-innovation-holds-a-masterclass-on-lean-startup-methodology-for-the-startup-alley-cohort/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marquise Foster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 16:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Alley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Startup Alley is the place to be at TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 on September 21-23. The sold-out expo area is the virtual home to hundreds of innovative startups ready to demo their tech and talent. While exhibiting offers plenty of opportunity for all, a VIP experience kicked off in July for 50 startup exhibitors the TechCrunch [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Startup Alley is the place to be at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> on September 21-23. The sold-out expo area is the virtual home to hundreds of innovative startups ready to demo their tech and talent. While exhibiting offers plenty of opportunity for all, a VIP experience kicked off in July for 50 startup exhibitors the TechCrunch staff chose to form the first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/startup-alley/">Startup Alley+ cohort</a>.</p>
<p>Part of that experience includes a series of master classes in the run-up to Disrupt. Case in point, on August 24,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/dan-olsen-leads-a-product-market-fit-masterclass-for-the-startup-alley-cohort/"> Dan Olsen</a> will lead a master class called “How to Create Product-Market Fit.” Now, we’re ready to share the next presentation, and it’s another great one, folks.</p>
<p>On August 17th, John Lynn, co-founder of <a href="https://celainnovation.com/">CELA Innovation</a>, and Jade Kearney, <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Lean Startup expert and co-founder and CEO of She Matters, </span>will present a master class called, “The Key Principles of the Lean Startup Methodology.”</p>
<p><strong>A quick tangent:</strong> If you’re not already familiar with <a href="https://celainnovation.com/">CELA</a> or what it does, the NYC-based company matches early-stage startups to world-class accelerators and incubators that align with a startup’s vertical and business goals. Last year, at Disrupt 2020, CELA connected the winners of our Pitchers and Pitches mini pitch-off competitions with an accelerator to boost their business.</p>
<p><strong>Meanwhile, back at the master class:</strong> Change — positive or negative — is inevitable, and this master class will focus on what founders can do when change arrives on their doorstep. Examples of change can include receiving funding, running out of funding, losing a co-founder or a key customer or anything else that&#8217;s shaking up their situation.</p>
<p>John and Jade will help each cohort founder produce a Lean Startup transformation for one current business situation. Founders can then use it as a template for optimizing anything in their business the next time change comes calling.</p>
<p>The session begins by examining why you should use the Lean Startup methodology at inflection points — when there is a sudden change to your company, good or bad.</p>
<p>You&#8217;ll learn how you can use the Lean Startup methodology to create resources when you are overwhelmed by opportunity or just feel like you have gone as far as you can go with what you have.</p>
<p>Next, John and Jade will show how this methodology makes the difference between knowing what you want to build and learning what you need know about your customers, industry or product.</p>
<p>Lastly, Team CELA will isolate some of your key business activities as they exist right now. Then they will walk you through a process to turn that activity into a Lean Startup experiment that produces insights, new value and new opportunities.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> takes place September 21-23. Don’t miss your opportunity to meet the Startup Alley+ cohort and hundreds of other innovative startups in our expo area. Opportunity is knocking — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=startupalley&amp;utm_source=cela&amp;promo=celadisrupts2021&amp;display=TRUE">buy your TC Disrupt 2021 pass</a> and go kick down the door.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at Disrupt 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/cela-innovation-holds-a-masterclass-on-lean-startup-methodology-for-the-startup-alley-cohort/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183625</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
