<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 15:36:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Jeff Bezos’ Blue Origin launches 4-person crew, including William Shatner, to space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-launches-4-person-crew-including-william-shatner-to-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-launches-4-person-crew-including-william-shatner-to-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 15:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new shepard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[That’s two out of two successful crewed launches for Blue Origin, as the company today sent a crew of four people, including actor William Shatner, to space and back from its facility in West Texas. The mission, dubbed NS-18, is the fifth rocket launch for the company this year and the eighteenth for the rocket [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">That’s two out of two successful crewed launches for Blue Origin, as the company today sent a crew of four people, including actor William Shatner, to space and back from its facility in West Texas.</p>
<p>The mission, dubbed NS-18, is the fifth rocket launch for the company this year and the eighteenth for the rocket overall.</p>
<p>The crew included Shatner, who is arguably best-known for having played Captain James T. Kirk on “Star Trek”; Audrey Powers, a Blue employee who serves as the company’s vice president of New Shepard Mission &amp; Flight Operations; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/dcvc-partner-and-planet-labs-co-founder-chris-boshuizen-bound-for-space-on-blue-origins-second-human-flight/">Chris Boshuizen</a>, co-founder of Planet Labs and current partner at venture capital firm DCVC; and Glen de Vries, co-founder of the clinical trial software company Medidata Solutions.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217525" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Shatner, who is 90, is now the oldest person to reach space, an honor that was previously held by 82-year old Wally Funk (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/blue-origins-new-shepard-carries-jeff-bezos-and-three-crew-members-to-space-and-back/">who flew on Blue’s previous launch in July</a>).</p>
<p>The launch started at around 10:50 AM ET, where the rocket pushed past the Kármán Line – an internationally recognized boundary of space. Around this time, the crew experienced a few minutes of weightlessness. The capsule landed autonomously using a parachute back to the launch facility around 11 minutes later. The booster also landed autonomously near the launch pad.</p>
<p>The successful launch is great news for Blue Origin, which wants to establish itself as a leading player in the burgeoning space tourism industry. But the past few weeks haven’t been completely smooth for the company, which was founded by billionaire Jeff Bezos in 2000. Late last month, <a href="https://www.lioness.co/post/bezos-wants-to-create-a-better-future-in-space-his-company-blue-origin-is-stuck-in-a-toxic-past">21 current and former employees</a> jointly composed an essay alleging that the company’s workplace was one marred by sexual harassment and a lack of proper regard for safety.</p>
<p>The document seemed to have caught the attention of the Federal Aviation Administration, who told TechCrunch, “The FAA takes every safety allegation seriously, and the agency is reviewing the information.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Blue Origin faces competition in the space tourism market from competitors like Richard Branson’s Virgin Galactic, which conducted its own <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/virgin-galactic-and-richard-branson-celebrate-launch-of-first-passengers-into-space/">successful crewed launch this summer</a>, and SpaceX, which carried the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/watch-spacex-launch-the-first-all-civilian-inspiration4-mission-to-space-live/">Inspiration4 crew</a> to space on a three-day journey in September.</p>
<p>Rewatch the launch here:</p>
<p><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FAcufhwjR2I" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-launches-4-person-crew-including-william-shatner-to-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217525</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK startup blasts gov&#8217;t plan to downgrade data protection</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/so-much-for-levelling-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/so-much-for-levelling-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 15:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brexit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cronofy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ed Vaizey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uk plc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UK government&#8217;s post-Brexit appetite to &#8216;reform&#8217; domestic privacy rules by proposing to reduce the level of protections wrapping people&#8217;s data is already having wider ramifications for the country&#8217;s tech ecosystem. Last month the Department of Digital, Culture, Media and Sport (DCMS) announced a consultation on reducing privacy standards &#8212; claiming &#8216;simplified&#8217; rules would be [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The UK government&#8217;s post-Brexit appetite to &#8216;reform&#8217; domestic privacy rules by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/uk-dials-up-the-spin-on-data-reform-claiming-simplified-rules-will-drive-responsible-data-sharing/">proposing to reduce the level of protections wrapping people&#8217;s data</a> is already having wider ramifications for the country&#8217;s tech ecosystem.</p>
<p>Last month the Department of Digital, Culture, Media and Sport (DCMS) announced a consultation on reducing privacy standards &#8212; claiming &#8216;simplified&#8217; rules would be a boon for business innovation.</p>
<p>Now a homegrown scale-up has blasted the consultation in an <a href="https://adambird.com/posts/back-to-eu/">excoriating blog post</a> &#8212; warning that any reduction in data protection standards will &#8220;certainly&#8221; damage its EU business and could even weaken its US business, given that a number of states (such as California) have already passed similar laws to Europe&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217367" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>US lawmakers on both sides of the aisle are also pressing the case to pass comprehensive federal privacy legislation. So &#8212; outside the UK at least &#8212; the direction of travel on personal data is toward greater protections, not fewer.</p>
<p>In the blog post, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/01/29/cronofy/">Cronofy</a>, a 2014-founded startup which sells a calendar API and scheduling platform for enterprises, writes that it&#8217;s making preparations to prevent a domestic deregulatory bomb cratering its business &#8212; saying it will be opening a new company in the Netherlands and offering customers the ability to contract with Cronofy BV under Dutch law.</p>
<p>&#8220;That will become the new HQ for all of our data processing so we can be under the oversight of the Dutch data regulator and thus the EU,&#8221; writes CEO and co-founder Adam Bird. &#8220;Our new General Counsel overseeing all of this is Dutch.</p>
<p>&#8220;How does Britain fare out of this? Not very well I’m afraid,&#8221; he adds, suggesting the restructuring will also mean Cronofy ends up reducing the level of investment it makes into UK skills and UK jobs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Bird is not alone in blasting the UK proposal to rip up data protection rules, either.</p>
<p>Earlier <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/ex-minister-predicts-huge-battleground-over-uks-plan-to-set-internet-content-rules/">this month</a> Ed Vaizey, the former minister of state in charge of DCMS (now Lord Vaizey), warned the UK must stay aligned with the GDPR &#8212; or face &#8220;disastrous&#8221; consequences for the economy and digital businesses.</p>
<p>“The U.K. was very influential in how data protection legislation was drawn up when we were members of the EU so I think it’s slightly odd that we should shy away from that legislation,” Vaizey told TechCrunch last week.</p>
<p>“You do not want a position where you make yourself vulnerable to attacks by the EU to say that your data protection regime is not adequate and we can’t therefore have cross-border exchanges of data — that would be disastrous. So whether we like it or not we will have to keep to a certain extent in lock-step with the European Union.”</p>
<p>However even the policy noises coming out of DCMS appear to be doing damage to UK Plc.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kY4CUCeoaB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/ex-minister-predicts-huge-battleground-over-uks-plan-to-set-internet-content-rules/">Ex-minister predicts &#8216;huge battleground&#8217; over UK&#8217;s plan to set internet content rules</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ex-minister predicts &#8216;huge battleground&#8217; over UK&#8217;s plan to set internet content rules&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/ex-minister-predicts-huge-battleground-over-uks-plan-to-set-internet-content-rules/embed/#?secret=kY4CUCeoaB" data-secret="kY4CUCeoaB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In his blog post, Bird describes Cronofy as &#8220;a truly global company&#8221; &#8212; one that&#8217;s (currently) headquartered in the UK but with revenue split 55% US, 25% EU, 9% UK. Meaning 91% of the scale-up&#8217;s revenue is from exports.</p>
<p>&#8220;EU GDPR legislation has not harmed our US business and in many cases has been an advantage,&#8221; he goes on. &#8220;Having to confront data privacy requirements from the founding of the business puts us at a distinct advantage as US companies wake up to having to protect people’s information.&#8221;</p>
<p>Before Brexit &#8216;got done&#8217;, Bird says a &#8220;significant&#8221; number of EU customers were already raising concerns about what the UK&#8217;s departure might meant for their (sensitive calendar) data and relationship with his business.</p>
<p>&#8220;We will always do our utmost to protect people’s private data. However we were making these assertions against the backdrop of the UK government grandstanding in the name of ‘strong negotiation’, even to the extent that they voted to break international law,&#8221; he continues, saying that even before the end of the transition period customers weren&#8217;t confident Cronofy would be able to stand by its word or that the UK government would bother to enforce compliance even if it kept the same data standards on paper. &#8220;Even more importantly, they couldn’t give that reassurance to their end users,&#8221; Bird adds.</p>
<p>The government&#8217;s noises now about &#8216;simplifying&#8217; UK data protection standards appear to be the final straw for Cronofy.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QU0jryADip"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/uk-dials-up-the-spin-on-data-reform-claiming-simplified-rules-will-drive-responsible-data-sharing/">UK dials up the spin on data reform, claiming &#8216;simplified&#8217; rules will drive &#8216;responsible&#8217; data sharing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK dials up the spin on data reform, claiming &#8216;simplified&#8217; rules will drive &#8216;responsible&#8217; data sharing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/uk-dials-up-the-spin-on-data-reform-claiming-simplified-rules-will-drive-responsible-data-sharing/embed/#?secret=QU0jryADip" data-secret="QU0jryADip" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In the <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/data-a-new-direction">consultation</a>, DCMS talks about &#8220;reforms to create an ambitious, pro-growth and innovation-friendly data protection regime&#8221; &#8212; and about &#8220;maintain[ing] high data protection standards without creating unnecessary barriers to responsible data use&#8221; &#8212; but there&#8217;s no doubt the proposal is about removing layers of protection.</p>
<p>Ministers are, for example, considering expansive legal permissions for businesses to use data for &#8216;innovation&#8217; purposes, whatever that might mean (hint: anything) &#8212; and consulting on removing the need for individual consent to process certain types of data, among other potential amendments to the UK&#8217;s version of GDPR.</p>
<p>Entirely removing a provision that gives people rights over automated decisions that have a legal/equivalent impact on them is also being eyed by government. (And on that front, the professional body <a href="https://www.bcs.org/articles-opinion-and-research/human-review-of-ai-decisions-needs-legal-protection-says-it-industry-body/?utm_content=183285095&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;hss_channel=tw-29681473"><span class="il">BCS</span></a>, aka The Chartered Institute for IT, also warned against such a drastic step &#8212; suggesting in a blog post today that increased clarity of the existing provision would be the more judicious policy than keeping it as is or dumping it altogether.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">UK gov&#39;t is proposing to &#39;reform&#39; legitimate interest as a basis for processing personal data &#8211; justifying the move as targeting &quot;unnecessary recourse to consent&quot; &#8211; by removing need to perform a balancing test for a set of specific activities &#8211; including &quot;business innovation&quot;&#8230; <a href="https://t.co/agSMn7HqHY">pic.twitter.com/agSMn7HqHY</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Natasha <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f9d7-200d-2640-fe0f.png" alt="🧗‍♀️" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@riptari) <a href="https://twitter.com/riptari/status/1436269901799428097?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&#8220;With the recent announcement by the government of the changes they want to make to the UK’s data privacy legislation, it seems that those fears were well founded,&#8221; writes Bird, sounding the alarm over the direction of UK data policy.</p>
<p>&#8220;It wants to move to a ‘do and ask for permission’ model driven not by benefit to mankind but instead by commercial interests. Whatever we say to our customers about how Cronofy approaches data privacy and controls, corresponding enforcement will not follow.</p>
<p>&#8220;We can make our protestations about ISO certifications, data management controls, segmented data hosting. However, prospective customers won’t necessarily get that far because we’ll be discounted based on our location. I don’t blame them. Data protection is fraught and complicated. Why even entertain the risk of going with a provider from outside the EU.&#8221;</p>
<p>If the UK&#8217;s level of protection gets downgraded, the risk is the country will lose a key data flow agreement with the EU &#8212; which has only just be put in place now the UK is a so-called &#8216;third country&#8217; outside the bloc.</p>
<p>UK companies with customers in Europe rely on this &#8216;data adequacy&#8217; agreement for smooth running as it allows for personal data to flow freely from the bloc to the UK. But if the UK&#8217;s standard is assessed as no longer equivalent to EU law the European Commission has said it will revoke the arrangement it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/uk-gets-data-flows-deal-from-eu-for-now/">signed off on this summer</a>.</p>
<p>The data flows deal already includes a sunset clause &#8212; meaning there will be an automatic review of UK standards in 2025.</p>
<p>But EU lawmakers warned they could revoke it at any moment if there&#8217;s divergence. So blistering attacks on UK privacy policy by homegrown entrepreneurs like Bird are unlikely to go unnoticed in Brussels&#8230;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wmu8qGsvpZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/uk-gets-data-flows-deal-from-eu-for-now/">UK gets data flows deal from EU &#8212; for now</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK gets data flows deal from EU &#8212; for now&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/uk-gets-data-flows-deal-from-eu-for-now/embed/#?secret=wmu8qGsvpZ" data-secret="wmu8qGsvpZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;This national act of self-harm will have ramifications for decades to come,&#8221; Bird warns. &#8220;It turns out that Project Fear [as Brexit supporters dismissively dubbed objections to leaving by those that wanted to remain in the EU], was actually Project Fact.</p>
<p>&#8220;Instead of taking it as a warning of something to avoid, the UK government seem to have taken it as an outcome to exceed. Whilst in isolation, Cronofy being collateral damage is unimportant. What we are facing is a worrying portent for the UK and its relationship with the rest of the world.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I expected and wanted to be building Cronofy into a world-beating, UK company. Membership of the EU gave us an enviable platform to do that and, in turn, invest that success back into the UK,&#8221; he adds, underscoring his point that UK government policy has left Cronofy with little choice but to restructure its business in a way that puts the EU at the center.</p>
<p>DCMS has been contacted for a response to Bird&#8217;s blog post.</p>
<p>For a glimpse of the future that awaits UK startups if government &#8216;reforms&#8217; end up torching the UK&#8217;s data adequacy see the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/eu-puts-out-final-guidance-on-data-transfers-to-third-countries/">EDPB&#8217;s intricate guidance on data transfers to third countries</a>. And prepare to level up your legal expense budget..</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mkq1zjNqev"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/europe-puts-out-advice-on-fixing-international-data-transfers-thats-cold-comfort-for-facebook/">Europe puts out advice on fixing international data transfers that&#8217;s cold comfort for Facebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe puts out advice on fixing international data transfers that&#8217;s cold comfort for Facebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/europe-puts-out-advice-on-fixing-international-data-transfers-thats-cold-comfort-for-facebook/embed/#?secret=mkq1zjNqev" data-secret="mkq1zjNqev" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>Are you a UK startup with views on the government&#8217;s <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/data-a-new-direction">Data: a new direction</a> proposal? Get in touch by contacting natasha@techcrunch.com </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/so-much-for-levelling-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217367</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chime&#8217;s Chris Britt and Menlo Ventures&#8217; Shawn Carolan to talk fintech on TechCrunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/chimes-chris-britt-and-menlo-ventures-shawn-carolan-to-talk-fintech-on-techcrunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/chimes-chris-britt-and-menlo-ventures-shawn-carolan-to-talk-fintech-on-techcrunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 15:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Britt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menlo ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shawn carolan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techcrunch live announcement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a world where fintech is so hot right now, and investors are being swept up by their excitement for the space, Chime has managed to ride the wave to near perfection. The company has raised upwards of $2.6 billion, including a fresh $750 million just this year. The startup, playing in the fee-free banking [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a world where fintech is so hot right now, and investors are being swept up by their excitement for the space, Chime has managed to ride the wave to near perfection. The company has raised upwards of <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/chime-2">$2.6 billion</a>, including a fresh $750 million just this year.</p>
<p>The startup, playing in the fee-free banking space, now has a valuation of $25 billion. Sources told The <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/chime-financial-raises-750-million-in-latest-funding-round-11628872069">Wall Street Journal</a> that an IPO is on the horizon for the startup.</p>
<p>So, we&#8217;re more than thrilled to announce that Chime founder and CEO Chris Britt will be joining us on an <a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-live-with-menlo-ventures-and-chime?ref=0b6251e1da9a">upcoming episode of TechCrunch Live (formerly Extra Crunch Live)</a>. Britt will be joined by Shawn Carolan of Menlo Ventures, who led the company&#8217;s Series C funding round back in 2018.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2211956" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>TechCrunch Live is a free, weekly event that lets folks in the audience connect with founders and the investors who finance them to learn how to build better venture-backed businesses. We talk about what drew the investors to the company, how the founder chose to partner with those particular investors and how they work together, and scale the business, moving forward.</p>
<p>In the latter half of each episode, founders in the audience are encouraged to jump on our virtual stage and pitch their products, receiving live feedback from our esteemed duos.</p>
<p>TechCrunch Live is free for anyone who would like to attend live, but only TechCrunch+ members have access to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">full library of TechCrunch Live content on demand</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-live-with-menlo-ventures-and-chime?ref=0b6251e1da9a">This episode of TCL goes down on October 13 at noon PDT/3 p.m. EDT</a>. See you there!</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/chimes-chris-britt-and-menlo-ventures-shawn-carolan-to-talk-fintech-on-techcrunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211956</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reddit adds a new way to post with launch of &#8216;Predictions&#8217; feature</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/reddit-adds-a-new-way-to-post-with-launch-of-predictions-feature/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/reddit-adds-a-new-way-to-post-with-launch-of-predictions-feature/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app maker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collaboration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mammoth Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prediction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Survivor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wikis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wishbone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reddit today is introducing a new way to post to its communities with the launch of the on-platform feature called &#8220;Predictions.&#8221; Spun off of the popular Reddit Polls, Predictions allow users to guess the answers to timely questions like &#8220;who will win the game tomorrow?&#8221; or &#8220;which character will meet their fate in the next [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Reddit today is introducing a new way to post to its communities with the launch of the on-platform feature called &#8220;Predictions.&#8221; Spun off of the popular Reddit Polls, Predictions allow users to guess the answers to timely questions like &#8220;who will win the game tomorrow?&#8221; or &#8220;which character will meet their fate in the next episode?&#8221; or &#8220;how much will the price of Bitcoin move by Monday?,&#8221; among others.</p>
<p>This is the first new posting format Reddit has introduced in nearly two years, and one that the company says is designed to increase engagement on the platform by reducing the barrier to posting. That is, while some users may not feel comfortable posting publicly or engaging in discussions, they may take the time to respond to a poll or, now, make a prediction.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2217443" style="width: 634px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217443" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2217443" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-1.png?w=624" alt="" width="624" height="270" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-1.png 624w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-1.png?resize=150,65 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-1.png?resize=300,130 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-1.png?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 624px) 100vw, 624px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217443" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Reddit</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217400" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>To use the feature in a Reddit community, or subreddit, a moderator will first create a Predictions Tournament. This is a series of questions where Reddit users will predict the answers. The tournament can include as many questions as the moderator wants to have, and they can continue to add new questions even after the tournament starts.</p>
<p>Each Reddit user receives 1,000 tokens when they join the Predictions Tournament. These are free &#8212; Reddit says there&#8217;s no monetization model in place for tokens, nor a plan to roll that out in the future. However, users will not be able to get more tokens during the tournament once those 1,000 are used. That means they have to place their bets wisely across all the predictions, or they could risk losing their ability to respond to later questions if they run out.</p>
<p>Users can place anywhere between 10 and 100 tokens on each question, but no more or less.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2217442" style="width: 399px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217442" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2217442" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-2.png?w=389" alt="" width="389" height="322" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-2.png 389w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-2.png?resize=150,124 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-2.png?resize=300,248 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-2.png?resize=50,41 50w" sizes="(max-width: 389px) 100vw, 389px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217442" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Reddit</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Moderators will choose the correct answers to the predictions, so they control the outcome of the Tournament and decide the winners. Of course, they are motivated to get this right as a community&#8217;s leader &#8212; and because there&#8217;s no financial gain for them either way. In addition, the tokens themselves have no value outside Prediction Tournaments, Reddit says.</p>
<p>Users who were right in their predictions will earn more tokens based on how many they originally put in. That means the better someone&#8217;s prediction skills, the more they&#8217;ll be able to bet in the future. They will also climb higher on the community&#8217;s Prediction Tournament leaderboard.</p>
<p>Reddit has already been testing the feature ahead of today&#8217;s official launch and saw over 1 million participants involve themselves in Prediction Tournaments. Popular tournaments included the Oscar Prediction Tournament on r/movies which saw 100,000 participants; the Azerbaijan Grand Prix Prediction Tournament on r/formula1, which saw 200,000 participants; and the 2020 Eurocup Prediction Tournament on r/soccer, which saw over 300,000 participants.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2217441" style="width: 644px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217441" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2217441" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-3.png?w=634" alt="" width="634" height="411" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-3.png 634w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-3.png?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-3.png?resize=300,194 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/reddit-predictions-3.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 634px) 100vw, 634px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217441" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Reddit</p></div></p>
<p>The company isn&#8217;t the first to see the value in predictions as a tool for user engagement.</p>
<p>Facebook&#8217;s internal R&amp;D lab, the NPE Team, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/facebook-tests-forecast-an-app-for-making-predictions-about-world-events-like-covid-19/">last year introduced an app called Forecast</a> which offered a similar set of capabilities. In Forecast, users could make predictions about world events, like Covid-19, and engage in discussions. Since then, the company went on to announce its entry into the fantasy gaming market, but with a twist. Instead of building up all-star fantasy teams, users make simpler predictions about the games themselves. There are also non-sports games, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/facebook-enters-the-fantasy-gaming-market/">those that allow you to guess</a> what will happen on TV shows like &#8220;Survivor&#8221; or &#8220;The Bachelorette.&#8221;</p>
<p>Elsewhere on the App Store, there are a number of apps for making predictions with friends, also often focused on sports. And across social media, there are Stories filters for personal predictions and other predictions games. For example, the Wishbone app maker Mammoth Media last year <a href="https://medium.com/@bvatere/prediction-master-for-snap-minis-our-latest-collaboration-with-snapchat-f8049c46d34">launched</a> a Snap Mini game called Prediction Master for Snapchat users.</p>
<p>Reddit says the new feature will roll out to all communities with at least 10,000 members which are rated as safe-for-work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/reddit-adds-a-new-way-to-post-with-launch-of-predictions-feature/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217400</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Matik raises $20M to automate the process of creating personalized customer presentations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/matik-raises-20m-to-automate-the-process-of-creating-customized-presentations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/matik-raises-20m-to-automate-the-process-of-creating-customized-presentations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Matik, which has created automated data-driven software for customizing Google Slides or PowerPoint presentations, has raised $20 million in a Series A funding round led by Andreessen Horowitz (a16z). Menlo Ventures, BoxGroup and Oceans Ventures also participated in the financing, which brings the San Francisco-based startup’s total raised to just over $23 million since its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://matik.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Matik</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which has created</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> automated data-driven software for customizing Google Slides or PowerPoint presentations,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has raised $20 million in a Series A funding round led by Andreessen Horowitz (a16z).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Menlo Ventures, BoxGroup and Oceans Ventures also participated in the financing, which brings the San Francisco-based startup’s total raised to just over $23 million since its 2019 inception. The venture firms joined a group of angels &#8212; including </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">GTM Fund</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span> angel investor Keenan Rice (who was part of Looker&#8217;s founding team)<span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Allison Pickens (former COO of Gainsight)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Elena Verna (former SVP of Growth at SurveyMonkey)  and Jon Herstein (current CCO at Box) &#8212; who also put money in the round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Matik’s product targets data-driven organizations, specifically sales and customer success teams, to make it easier</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to create personalized presentations such as quarterly business reviews, pricing proposals and one-pagers.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> It works by automatically importing content from a variety of data sources, according to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nikola Mijic, co-founder and CEO of Matik.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217170" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup says its technology transforms content from static to dynamic &#8212; whether it be text, charts, images or tables. It claims to save teams time from number-crunching, formatting and data pulling from disparate sources such as CRMs like Salesforce, BI/visualization tools like Looker and data warehouses such as Redshift, BigQuery or Snowflake. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because the content is dynamic, presentations are “completely editable” after they’re generated, the company says.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With Matik, “what used to take hours is reduced to minutes,” leaving more time for strategic work, according to Mijic. Enterprise and mid-market companies are its target customers and it claims to be able to help them save money as well as help convert and retain customers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Some people spend four to six hours a week to create data-driven stories, and we get it down to a few minutes, saving them over 200 to 300 hours a year to do more strategic work and speak to customers,” he told TechCrunch.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2217230" style="width: 1694px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217230" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2217230 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Matik.jpg" alt="Matik" width="1684" height="852" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Matik.jpg 1684w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Matik.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Matik.jpg?resize=300,152 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Matik.jpg?resize=768,389 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Matik.jpg?resize=680,344 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Matik.jpg?resize=1536,777 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Matik.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1684px) 100vw, 1684px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217230" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Matik</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company runs on a license-based model, and has seen many companies buy a certain number of licenses and then “expand pretty quickly” to different teams by buying more licenses.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a short amount of time, Matik has built up a customer base that includes some big names, including Glassdoor, KeepTruckin, Handshake and Hover. It says that since Handshake started using Matik, it’s already saved 4,500 hours. While he declined to reveal any hard revenue figures, Mijic said Matik has grown “by 3x” since the beginning of the year and he expects it will have grown “by 4-5x” by year’s end compared to the end of 2020. So far, he added, it has had “zero churn.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mijic first came up with the concept behind Matik while at LinkedIn. He was supporting sales and customer success teams and was constantly asked to help put together presentations at the last minute by, for example, running a bunch of queries that pulled data. There, he </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">worked on an internal solution to facilitate the presentation-building process for the company’s go-to-market teams and led the eventual redesign of the solution. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mijic then teamed up with early Box employee </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/zak-stein" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zak Stein</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to found Matik to solve the problem more broadly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, Matik wants to explore the possibility of applying its technology to e-mail, or “anything that is repetitive in nature that needs to be personalized.” It also wants to expand its product offering to teams beyond sales and go-to-market.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Storytelling is not just in a presentation,” Mijic said. “We can take what’s core to our product and infuse it to other types of narratives.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also, naturally, wants to do some hiring. The company currently has 13 employees and expects to boost its headcount to 20 by the end of the year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A16z general partner Kristina Shen, who will take a seat on Matik’s board as part of the raise, said Matik has built a product that automates “a hugely manual and painful process” for many business functions: the personalization and updating of data in presentations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She described the Matik product experience as “incredibly seamless and intuitive,” giving an end user the ability to create an entire presentation “with just a few inputs and clicks.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Customer feedback for Matik is consistently effusive and really speaks to the fact there are no satisfactory alternatives in the market,” she wrote via email. “Considering the varied use of and ongoing need for data-rich presentations as a key storytelling tool, we believe the long-term potential of Matik is massive.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Naomi Ionita, partner at Menlo Ventures, led Matik’s $3 million seed round in October of 2019. She said she was drawn to the team&#8217;s authenticity as well as the product market fit.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;You can imagine people laboring over these desks, pulling data from all these disparate sources with the goal of really crafting a story and personalizing it and then having to tweak the story based on different data points and making sure that story flows, month after month or quarter after quarter,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Thus, the time savings are an obvious benefit &#8220;out of the gate,&#8221; according to Ionita.</p>
<p>&#8220;The other benefit here is driving revenue, as when companies spend painstaking hours putting presentations together, they tend to only be able to cover a certain percentage of their accounts,&#8221; she told TechCrunch. &#8220;And so by automating this, we&#8217;re seeing customers be able to increase their account coverage. And all of these customer-facing folks will confirm that when you have the personalized touch point with their customers, it does have an impact on expansion and renewal opportunities.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/matik-raises-20m-to-automate-the-process-of-creating-customized-presentations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217170</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lunar Ventures launches technically-oriented, €40M fund, aimed at DeepTech startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/lunar-ventures-launches-technically-oriented-e40m-fund-aimed-at-deeptech-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/lunar-ventures-launches-technically-oriented-e40m-fund-aimed-at-deeptech-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lunar Ventures, is a a new, technically-oriented VC fund aimed at early-stage DeepTech startups, that is now announcing the closing of its €40M first fund. Lunar was founded in Berlin in 2019 by Dr Elad Verbin, a computer science researcher; Mick Halsband, a CTO and software architect; and Luis Shemtov, a former entrepreneur. The launch [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://lunar.vc/">Lunar Ventures</a>, is a a new, technically-oriented VC fund aimed at early-stage DeepTech startups, that is now announcing the closing of its €40M first fund.</p>
<p>Lunar was founded in Berlin in 2019 by Dr Elad Verbin, a computer science researcher; Mick Halsband, a CTO and software architect; and Luis Shemtov, a former entrepreneur.</p>
<p>The launch is timely: DeepTech investments in Europe have almost tripled in the last five years, nearing €10B in 2020. The is roughly a quarter of the total VC investments in the continent.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217494" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Verbin said Lunar Ventures, said, “Technical startup founders in Europe have a big problem. They struggle to find investors who actually understand what they’re building. Most VCs in Europe don’t come from a technical or scientific background, and they struggle to evaluate the underlying technology, failing to invest in promising science-based moonshots.” Personally, I this is also my experience.</p>
<p>Verbin continued: “We are a team of scientists and engineers and we have built Lunar Ventures to solve this problem. We find the best startups building the future, our team conducts rigorous technical due diligence to evaluate their true potential, and then we lead their funding rounds.”</p>
<p>The fund will invest up to €1M into early-stage DeepTech startups that are software-focused, aiming at the thesis frontier computer science, machine learning, cryptography, new cloud infrastructures and next-generation databases.</p>
<p>So far it’s invested in Zama is a Paris-based startup building end-to-end encryption for machine learning models; Berlin-based Deepset enabling computers to understand plain language; and Molecule, a drug discovery platform using the Ethereum blockchain. </p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Lunar is backed by LPS such as Isomer Capital, Multiple Capital, Aldea Ventures, Compagnia di San Paolo and the European Investment Fund.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/lunar-ventures-launches-technically-oriented-e40m-fund-aimed-at-deeptech-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217494</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ViacomCBS gets into NFTs via a partnership with NFT startup Recur</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/viacomcbs-gets-into-nfts-via-a-partnership-with-nft-startup-recur/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/viacomcbs-gets-into-nfts-via-a-partnership-with-nft-startup-recur/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Media company ViacomCBS is getting into NFTs. Amid growing hype around the potential market for NFTs, aka non-fungible tokens &#8212; digital assets linked to ownership that&#8217;s stored on a blockchain, often used for buying and selling digital art and collectibles &#8212; ViacomCBS says it&#8217;s partnering with the NFT company Recur to bring its iconic IP [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Media company ViacomCBS is getting into NFTs. Amid growing hype around the potential market for NFTs, aka non-fungible tokens &#8212; digital assets linked to ownership that&#8217;s stored on a blockchain, often used for buying and selling digital art and collectibles &#8212; ViacomCBS says it&#8217;s <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20211013005667/en/ViacomCBS-Enters-Strategic-NFT-Partnership-with-RECUR">partnering</a> with the NFT company <a href="https://www.recurforever.com/">Recur</a> to bring its iconic IP and franchises to the world of digital collectibles, starting next year. This includes products and collectibles from shows and films across top ViacomCBS brands like CBS, MTV, Showtime, Paramount Pictures, BET, Nickelodeon, and Comedy Central.</p>
<p>The company isn&#8217;t offering many details about the upcoming project just yet, beyond simply saying that it will involve creating a place where its fans can buy, collect and trade NFTs across its portfolio. It also notes this platform will encourage &#8220;peer-to-peer engagement and facilitate innovative ways for users to unlock new experiences,&#8221; which signals there&#8217;s a social element to the new experience that goes beyond just the marketplace aspects.</p>
<p>Recur, which recently closed <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/nft-company-recur-reaches-333m-valuation-following-steve-cohen-backed-fundraiser">on a $50 million Series A</a>, valuing the pre-launch company at $333 million, is currently working on building a NFT platform called NFTU.com. This platform is being created in partnership with digital licensing company Veritone, and will host NFTs created with Pac-12 Networks athletics video content &#8212; like sports highlights, for example.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217457" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>This project can give you an idea of what ViacomCBS likely has in store with its own NFT plans.</p>
<p>While a number of other NFT marketplaces already exist, Recur&#8217;s plan is to develop technology that standardizes recurring royalties minted on any cryptocurrency &#8212; a decision that means NFTs would become &#8220;chain-agnostic,&#8221; bringing more potential fans into the crypto ecosystem. For <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/nisaamoils/2021/04/09/recur-broadens-the-pool-of-customers-for-nfts/?sh=400427b1e570">brand partners and IP holders</a>, that means once the NFT left their own, originating platform to be resold elsewhere, the original rights holder would be able to continue to receive recurring royalties from the sales and resales indefinitely.</p>
<p>That could certainly look appealing to a media company with a deep catalog of IP that could be turned into digital collectibles. Think: <em>Spongebob Squarepants, Southpark</em> or <em>Star Trek</em> collectibles, for instance. (To be clear, ViacomCBS has not announced the specific shows it will include in its initial distributions. And there could be more complicated rights discussions to still be ironed out with creators, actors, and others tied to its IP before those determinations can be made.)</p>
<p>In addition, Recur&#8217;s chain-agnostic approach will allow NFT purchases to be made using U.S. credit and debit cards, instead of just cryptocurriences. That could also appeal to a company looking to reach a wider audience outside of tech early adopters.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The new platform will launch in spring of 2022, ViacomCBS says.</p>
<p>ViacomCBS is not the first media company to embrace NFTs. In addition to adoption by <a href="https://variety.com/vip-video/nft-craze-catching-on-in-media-industry/">top media figures themselves</a>, brands <a href="https://www.axios.com/cnn-moments-nft-b40022f0-dfb8-4ccc-888b-596fb6732406.html">including</a> CNN, The New Yorker, Time, Playboy, <a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/lionsgate-tom-brady-autograph-nft-draftkings-1235024498/">Lionsgate</a>, <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/09/27/2304008/0/en/Media-Central-Corp-Announces-It-Is-Selling-NFTs-of-Nine-Historic-Magazine-Covers-as-Collectibles-Featuring-Grimes-Drake-Seth-Rogan-and-More.html">Media Central</a>, <a href="https://www.pressgazette.co.uk/media-nfts-gannett/">Gannett</a>, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/major-media-wants-in-cnn-and-fox-are-entering-nfts/">Fox</a>, and others have also begun their own investigations and experiments into the medium.</p>
<p>&#8220;Fueled by beloved characters and iconic properties with multi-generational appeal, we are thrilled to accelerate our consumer products presence even further into the growing metaverse,&#8221; said Pam Kaufman, ViacomCBS President of Consumer Products, in a statement. &#8220;In teaming up with Recur to create an NFT platform dedicated to ViacomCBS IP, voracious collectors and first-time NFT buyers alike will find unique opportunities to own a piece of their favorite franchises,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/viacomcbs-gets-into-nfts-via-a-partnership-with-nft-startup-recur/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217457</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GitLab raises IPO range, targeting valuation of as much as $11B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/gitlab-raises-ipo-range-targeting-valuation-of-as-much-as-11b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/gitlab-raises-ipo-range-targeting-valuation-of-as-much-as-11b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Git]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gitlab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initial public offering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nerdwallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rent the Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216683</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At $11.7 billion, GitLab would be worth around 50x its current annualized revenue run rate.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s no longer Hot Summer anything, sadly, as the seasons change. But perhaps we&#8217;re in for Warm IPO Autumn.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/what-rent-the-runways-ipo-filing-says-about-the-business-of-loaner-garments/">Rent the Runway</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/nerdwallets-ipo-filing-reveals-high-margin-content-business-accelerating-marketing-spend/">NerdWallet</a> and other companies are setting us up for a busy second half of October. But this week will see the debut of a company worth a multiple of those other venture-backed former startups <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/17/inside-gitlabs-ipo-filing/">as GitLab goes public</a>. And the developer tooling company recently turned up the valuation heat.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </strong></em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</strong></em></p>
<hr />
<p>This week, GitLab <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001653482/000162828021019932/gitlab-sx1a2.htm">updated its IPO filing</a> to include a higher expected pricing interval. The unicorn now anticipates that it will sell shares in its IPO for between $66 and $69 apiece, up from a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001653482/000162828021019505/gitlab-sx1a1.htm">previous range of $55 to $60</a>.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s quite the jump!</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995210 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Our task this morning is straightforward: We&#8217;re calculating GitLab&#8217;s new simple IPO valuation range and working out what the company could be worth on a fully diluted basis. Then we&#8217;ll execute some revenue multiples work, hoping to suss out if our earlier estimations of the company&#8217;s value are holding up, and what the IPO&#8217;s possible pricing says about the software market more broadly.</p>
<p>This is one of those posts that&#8217;s only good news for startups and their backers. For the other side of this particular coin, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/venture-capital-is-going-to-need-a-record-breaking-run-of-ipos-to-clear-its-own-decks/">head here</a>. Ready? Into the breach.</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s GitLab worth?</h2>
<p>In its first IPO price range, with 143,534,821 shares outstanding after its offering (inclusive of its underwriters&#8217; option), GitLab was set to be worth $7.9 billion to $8.6 billion. IPO-watching Renaissance Capital reported that at the &#8220;midpoint of [its first] proposed range, GitLab would command a fully diluted market value of $9.4 billion.&#8221;</p>
<p>Or more precisely, at $57.5 per share, GitLab would be worth $9.4 billion. At $60 per share, that number would scale to $9.8 billion.</p>
<p>Now at $66 to $69 per share, the company&#8217;s expected 143,534,821 post-IPO share count works out to a simple valuation range of $9.5 billion to $9.9 billion. Translating the company&#8217;s fully-diluted valuation at $57.5 per share to $69 per share, we can estimate that when counting all shares including those that may be exercised, GitLab could be worth as much as $11.3 billion.</p>
<p>I could have showed a little less work there, but I want you to walk along with me as we tinker with the numbers.</p>
<h2>Is that expensive?</h2>
<p>Let&#8217;s find out!</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/gitlab-raises-ipo-range-targeting-valuation-of-as-much-as-11b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216683</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HR platform Hibob raises $150M at a $1.65B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/hr-platform-hibob-raises-150m-at-a-1-65b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/hr-platform-hibob-raises-150m-at-a-1-65b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bessemer Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cazoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eight Roads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entreé Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hibob]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[israel growth partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the heels of Personio raising a big round yesterday, one of its competitors and another big startup in the area of HR has also picked up some fundning. Hibob, a London-based company that targets the mid-market with an all-in-one platform that handles various human resources functions, closed a Series C of $150 million. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">On the heels of Personio <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/personio-an-hr-platform-for-smes-raises-270m-on-a-6-3b-valuation-expands-into-workflow-automation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raising a big round yesterday</a>, one of its competitors and another big startup in the area of HR has also picked up some fundning. <a href="https://www.hibob.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hibob</a>, a London-based company that targets the mid-market with an all-in-one platform that handles various human resources functions, closed a Series C of $150 million. The funding values the company at around $1.65 billion, the company has confirmed to us. This was also the figure that appeared in <a href="https://www.calcalistech.com/ctech/articles/0,7340,L-3919534,00.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">leaked rumors</a> in the market earlier this week, ahead of the company confirming the news today.</p>
<p dir="ltr">General Atlantic led the round, with past investors Bessemer Venture Partners, Battery Ventures, Eight Roads and Entrée Capital among the others investing. Hibob last raised money about 10 months ago, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/hibob-raises-70m-on-a-500m-valuation-for-its-new-take-on-hr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$70 million round</a> in December 2020 (a round led by SEEK and Israel Growth Partners). Its valuation since then has more than tripled, a mark of how hot the market is for HR right now.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;Hot&#8221; and HR are not two terms you might usually hear in the same sentence. The tasks that comprise human resources &#8212; in Hibob&#8217;s case, tracking attendance, time off, compensation, payroll, benefits and running surveys &#8212; are usually seen as some of the more dry, and often overly officious, aspects of working life.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217458" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p dir="ltr">Covid-19 and pandemic working practices &#8212; where the vast majority of knowledge workers were sent home for the better part of a year or more (and some of us are still here in our kitchens) &#8212; have definitely changed how we interface with work, and so HR systems have suddenly come into their own as a way of tracking things, and even helping us all stay connected.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Hibob, which sells its platform as &#8220;Bob&#8221;, says that the last year has seen triple-digit growth in revenues, and its opportunity has been to present its product &#8212; which also offers collaboration and other tools &#8212; as a modern take on what HR can mean to a company.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">“Our mission is to modernize HR technology,” Ronni Zehavi, Hibob’s CEO, who co-founded the company with Israel David, told me last December. “We are a people management platform for how people work today. Whether that’s remotely or physically collaborative, our customers face challenges with work. We believe that the HR platforms of the future will not be clunky systems, annoying, giant platforms. We believe it should be different. We are a system of engagement rather than record.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">While the company&#8217;s roots are in Israel, its modern HQ is in London with another office in New York. It has 1,500 mid-sized customers operating in 134 countries, but right now it says that some 65% those customers &#8212; which include the likes of Ebury Partners Ltd., G.Network, Revolut, and Cazoo &#8212; are in the U.K. and other European markets.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">The funding will be used in part in an effort to tap more growth internationally to complement that existing base.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The last several years have seen a turn in HR tech that mirrors that of all enterprise IT: the explosion of funding available to startups has bred a plethora of point-solution specialists addressing singular aspects of the larger HR process, whether it is payroll, or benefits, or hiring and onboarding, or surveys and employee satisfaction, or training, or recruiting.</p>
<p dir="ltr">However, the bigger gravitational pull of technology seems to always bring us back to the concept of larger platforms, which are in their own way easier to run and potentially less expensive overall. In HR, those targeting smaller and mid-sized customers like Hibob or Personio also have a precedent in the form of Workday (and more historically companies like SAP).</p>
<p dir="ltr">Personio is an interesting company to consider in comparison to Hibob: it is bigger but also has smaller businesses in its mix of customers. When it announced its funding yesterday at a $6.3 billion valuation, it noted that its next steps would be to go into wider workflow automation, bringing more of the data you capture in HR systems (and specifically Personio&#8217;s HR systems) into other applications in a more efficient way.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It will be interesting to see whether Hibob takes a similar route, or if not, how it chooses to evolve its own platform over time. HR, being focused on people management, is in a way is at the heart of how a company runs its whole business, so there are a lot of routes it can take.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“<span class="il">Hibob</span> has created a solution that serves and anticipates the needs of modern, evolving businesses,” said Anton Levy, co-president, MD and global head of tech at General Atlantic, in a statement. “We have tracked the company for years, and positive customer feedback further validates that <span class="il">Hibob</span>’s platform has become a mission-critical component of HR tech stacks. <span class="il">Hibob</span> will mark our sixth investment in an Israel-based company in under two years, signifying our strong conviction in the country’s market. We look forward to supporting the business’ global growth as it redefines employee engagement and HR technology.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/hr-platform-hibob-raises-150m-at-a-1-65b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217458</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weights &#038; Biases raises $135M Series C to keep building MLOps software</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/weights-biases-raises-new-capital-as-developer-tools-remain-a-venture-focus-ml-matures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/weights-biases-raises-new-capital-as-developer-tools-remain-a-venture-focus-ml-matures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aydin Senkut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[felicis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lukas Biewald]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MLops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weights & Biases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Update: The round in question was $135 million, not $100 million as originally noted. I apologize for the mistake! What do you call AI these days? ML in a suit. ML, or machine learning, is a big market today. That is thanks to modern corporations accreting data like hoarders and data science maturing as a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em><strong>Update:</strong> The round in question was $135 million, not $100 million as originally noted. I apologize for the mistake!</em></p>
<p>What do you call AI these days? ML in a suit.</p>
<p>ML, or machine learning, is a big market today. That is thanks to modern corporations accreting data like hoarders and data science maturing as a work category. Evidence of the former can be found in the growth posted by Databricks in recent quarters, and the latter by just how much cash Big Tech companies are willing to drop on ML-focused roles.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217106" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The market that <a href="https://wandb.ai/site">Weights &amp; Biases</a> plays in, then, is active these days. That makes it not a huge surprise that the startup just raised more than $135 million in a supersized Series C. The company is now worth around $1 billion, it said in a release. Felicis, Insight Partners, Bond and Coatue contributed to the deal.</p>
<p>According <a href="https://carta.com/data-desk/#interactive-data">to Carta data</a>, data and analytics-focused Series C rounds since the start of 2020 have median values of $43.75 million, and median resulting valuations (post-money) of around $416 million. That makes this round effectively a double-up on what we might expect the company to raise, given historical data.</p>
<p>In product terms, Weights &amp; Biases plays in the &#8220;MLOps&#8221; space, or the machine learning operations market. MLOps is analogous to DevOps, naturally, despite being a newer category.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2217385" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217385" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2217385 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/5efd7117-1.png?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="174" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/5efd7117-1.png 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/5efd7117-1.png?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/5efd7117-1.png?resize=300,174 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/5efd7117-1.png?resize=768,446 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/5efd7117-1.png?resize=680,394 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/5efd7117-1.png?resize=1536,891 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/5efd7117-1.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217385" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Weights &amp; Biases. The product in question.</p></div></p>
<p>According to Weights &amp; Biases co-founder <a href="https://twitter.com/l2k">Lukas Biewald</a>, the software world has a set of tools built for developers to write and deploy code well. This could include a git-style service (<a href="https://about.gitlab.com/">GitLab</a>, <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a>, etc.), monitoring (<a href="https://www.atlassian.com/devops/devops-tools/devops-monitoring">Atlassian</a>, <a href="https://www.datadoghq.com/solutions/devops/">Datadog</a>, etc.), and the like.</p>
<p>His company&#8217;s goal, he explained, is to build a similar stack of services for the ML world. And today, he explained, many ML teams are working with ad-hoc tooling or simply without software assistance.</p>
<p>The need for such a stack could be stark. A difference between the development and the ML world, according to Biewald, is that while code crashes when it fails, ML work can &#8220;behave badly&#8221; in more subtle ways.</p>
<p>Enter Weights &amp; Biases, naturally. The startup&#8217;s product life started with experiment tracking, which Biewald likened to code versioning in the DevOps stack. Git, he explained, while great for versioning code that humans write, is somewhat poor at handling different versions of computer-generated code, like that which comes from machine learning work. That&#8217;s the sort of issue that Weights &amp; Biases wants to take on.</p>
<p>The effort is certainly attracting investor attention. Felicis investor Aydin Senkut told TechCrunch that he&#8217;d had his eye on Weights &amp; Biases for some time, but that other investors wound up leading its preceding two rounds. This time &#8217;round, Senkut got into the cap table by pre-empting the company. Per Biewald, Weights &amp; Biases would have raised a similar round, albeit later, if Felicis hadn&#8217;t led the charge.</p>
<p>TechCrunch dug into the startup&#8217;s pricing scheme prior to chatting with the company. Its price list looked inexpensive compared to the productivity that Weights &amp; Biases appears intent on delivering as its builds out its service. Note that this is not a compliment per se; underpricing is a way to transfer value from the company &#8212; and investors &#8212; to customers in the near term.</p>
<p>Biewald said that Weights &amp; Biases is pricing its service so that it is easy for anyone to access. Senkut added that amid customer checks executed by Felicis during its diligence for the investment, clients said that the startup was underpricing its service by a factor of three.</p>
<p>The investor added that he was excited by the prospect as other companies like Shopify had pursued similarly long-term greed over near-term incomes.</p>
<p>Frankly, I am intrigued by what Weights &amp; Biases seems to want to build. Let&#8217;s see how far a nine-figure check that came early can get the company. The next time we talk, it will be time to home in on growth metrics more precisely and check in on the margin impacts of its free service (unless, of course, it sticks that particular item in its sales and marketing expense line item).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/weights-biases-raises-new-capital-as-developer-tools-remain-a-venture-focus-ml-matures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217106</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nexla nabs $12M Series A as it builds cash flow positive data operations biz</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/nexla-nabs-12m-series-a-as-it-builds-cash-flow-positive-data-operations-biz/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/nexla-nabs-12m-series-a-as-it-builds-cash-flow-positive-data-operations-biz/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battlefield alums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data operations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nexla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nexla, a company that participated in the TechCrunch Disrupt Battlefield in New York City in 2017, has been building its data operations startup the old fashioned way. After launching in beta and securing a $3.5 million seed at Battlefield, it has proceeded to build a cash flow positive business. Today with a firm financial foundation [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://nexla.com/">Nexla</a>, a company that participated in the TechCrunch Disrupt Battlefield in New York City in 2017, has been building its data operations startup the old fashioned way. After launching in beta and securing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/16/nexla-launches-data-operations-platform-with-3-5-million-investment-at-techcrunch-disrupt/">a $3.5 million seed </a>at Battlefield, it has proceeded to build a cash flow positive business. Today with a firm financial foundation in place, the company announced a $12 million Series A.</p>
<p>Industry Ventures led the round with participation from Liberty Global Ventures, Blumberg Capital, Engineering Capital, Storm Ventures, Correlation Ventures and a number of industry angels.</p>
<p>Company co-founder and CEO Saket Saurabh says that his company has been building a data platform, and bringing together the integration, preparation and monitoring of data in one place. When he started the company in 2017, he was a bit ahead of the market, but since then the data space, particularly as it relates to machine learning, has been heating up and the company has been seeing traction with customers like DoorDash, Instacart, Poshmark and Freshworks, among others.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217415" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Saurabh says that has led to investor interest, and they believed it was the right time to take on additional money. &#8220;The good thing for us is being cash flow positive is that it means that we can control our own destiny as a company, and we thought this was the right time for us to pick up capital and speed things up,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He says that in spite of an initial pandemic slow-down last year, most of the company&#8217;s customers have seen an increase in the need for a platform like Nexla to deal with growing amounts of business data.</p>
<p>&#8220;Data is essential for most businesses we work with, and I think we saw more demand [after the initial stages of the pandemic]. So for example, companies like Instacart and DoorDash certainly saw an increase in demand, and that means that they need more technology and more solutions.That certainly played a factor in our growth,&#8221; Saurabh said.</p>
<p>He adds that his customers are not other startups, but enterprises that need to deal with large amounts of data. &#8220;What benefits us is that enterprise commitment to data and technology has been there and has only grown, the need for acceleration has grown, the need for supporting new business models has grown,&#8221; he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Unlike a lot of startups, that may start in small or medium-sized business, then make the move into the enterprise, Nexla&#8217;s initial customers have been larger companies. The goal with this money is actually to expand the market by offering it to smaller organizations. &#8220;It&#8217;s not just the large companies that need this. More companies are getting there earlier in the cycle. So for us, a large part of the push [moving forward] is bringing this to the masses, bringing it to the companies earlier in the growth cycle,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>With the new money the company plans to hire more people and reach close to 50 employees by the end of the year. Saurabh believes that being a remote company will help build a more diverse group.&#8221;I think that&#8217;s absolutely important and essential, and the fact that it&#8217;s now possible to hire people remotely, we are already building a pretty diverse, somewhat global team.&#8221;</p>
<p>While the company is building a worldwide team, it has an office presence in San Mateo, California and Saurabh hopes to have a hybrid approach when offices reopen.&#8221;We do find that in early stage small companies, it is extremely valuable and useful for people to have face-to-face time to get to get to know each other and to build trust. So we will continue on this hybrid model, where we&#8217;ll facilitate even for remote team members, opportunities to meet in person whenever it becomes safe for them to do so.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/nexla-nabs-12m-series-a-as-it-builds-cash-flow-positive-data-operations-biz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217415</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to sell clothes online and actually make money</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/rent-the-runway-adjusted-ebitda/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/rent-the-runway-adjusted-ebitda/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[queenly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rent the Runway]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is our Wednesday show, the time of the week when we niche down to a single topic. Today? Fashion. Natasha and Danny and Alex got together to dig into the world of fashion resale and rental. It&#8217;s no small [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/f1eb7a49-b2c3-4d0e-9f83-48b512b44027?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is our Wednesday show, the time of the week when we niche down to a single topic. Today? Fashion.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> got together to dig into the world of fashion resale and rental. It&#8217;s no small market, giving birth to both public companies, unicorns, and startups. Most recently, well-known fashion rental player Rent the Runway filed to go public, giving us a window in its own numbers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216939" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Those figures led us to a few questions about how best to go about making money from clothes in a retail context. From our chat:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Selling vs. Renting vs. Reselling: </strong>To start, we wanted to help you group startups into three buckets: those who sell customers to people, those who rent goods to customers, and those who resell pre-owned goods to customers.</li>
<li><strong>Rent the Runway&#8217;s numbers:</strong> We had some issues <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/what-rent-the-runways-ipo-filing-says-about-the-business-of-loaner-garments/">with Rent the Runway&#8217;s business model</a> given that it appears that the company is simply underpricing its clothing items given its cost structure. How Wall Street will price the company, or whether Rent the Runway is hoping to sell to a larger company came into the conversation.</li>
<li><strong>Who else should we have an eye on:</strong> To close, Natasha detailed a number of startups including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/queenly-a16z-seed-extension/">Queenly</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/20/curtsy-a-clothing-resale-app-aimed-at-gen-z-women-raises-11-million-series-a/">Curtsy </a>and Rebag. Oh, and Depop (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/05/get-thrifty-and-your-startup-might-just-acquire-a-generation/">which recently sold to Etsy $1.6 billion</a>).</li>
</ul>
<p>Startups are tearing up old retail models, which we are here for. We are less here for adjusted EBITDA that reads like magical realism.</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/rent-the-runway-adjusted-ebitda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216939</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inside Plaid&#8217;s plans to build a new, global finance network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/inside-plaids-plans-to-build-a-new-global-finance-network/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/inside-plaids-plans-to-build-a-new-global-finance-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Lawler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banking-as-a-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plaid]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Visa announced plans to purchase Plaid for $5.3 billion in January 2020, the deal represented one of the largest acquisitions of a fintech upstart by an incumbent financial powerhouse. But 12 months, one pandemic and one DOJ antitrust lawsuit later, and the credit card network provider decided the “protracted and complex litigation” necessary to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When Visa announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/13/visa-is-acquiring-plaid-for-5-3-billion-2x-its-final-private-valuation/">plans to purchase Plaid for $5.3 billion</a> in January 2020, the deal represented one of the largest acquisitions of a fintech upstart by an incumbent financial powerhouse.</p>
<p>But 12 months, one pandemic and one <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/doj-files-antitrust-lawsuit-challenging-visas-5-3-billion-acquisition-of-plaid/">DOJ antitrust lawsuit later</a>, and the credit card network provider decided the “protracted and complex litigation” necessary to consummate the acquisition would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/visa-will-not-acquire-plaid-after-running-into-regulatory-wall/">take too long to combat</a>. The companies abandoned the deal exactly one year after it was announced.</p>
<p>Visa and Plaid might have chosen to go their own ways in the end, but the year wasn’t a total loss for the data connectivity startup: Plaid claims its customer count grew 60% in 2020, and company execs say it has had similar growth so far this year.</p>
<p>“Despite the outcome not being what we predicted when we went in, I think we as a company grew a lot and learned a lot,” <a href="https://twitter.com/zachperret">Plaid CEO Zach Perret</a> told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>More important than the continued growth could be its peek into how a company like Visa operates and figuring out what it could emulate as the startup targets global reach through deep connections with financial institutions around the world.</p>
<p>“I think we&#8217;ve benefited from having the opportunity to understand how Visa ran their business at scale. It&#8217;s very rare that one gets a look inside a company that has been operating for as many years as they have in financial services,” he added.</p>
<p>Plaid has been fairly quiet about its future plans in the wake of the failed Visa deal. As the company kicks off <a href="https://plaid.com/events/plaid-forum/">Plaid Forum</a> &#8212; its virtual conference for customers &#8212; this week, however, it&#8217;s also unveiling a suite of new data, connectivity and payments features designed to increase trust, provide better insights and expand where and how financial services are delivered.</p>
<h2>Building consumer trust</h2>
<p>For a company that sells primarily to fintech startups and (increasingly) large financial institutions, Plaid sure does talk a lot about the consumer experience. Despite its B2B focus, consumer safety and trust were topics that repeatedly came up in conversations with Plaid execs over recent weeks.</p>
<p>Perret said that’s a relic of the company’s early days when the founders worked out of a small office off of San Francisco’s Union Square while the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/14/us/occupy-san-francisco-is-nothing-like-the-old-days.html">Occupy movement was protesting</a> throughout the city, including right across the street from their first headquarters. “The metric I always wanted to move is: I want consumers to be less frustrated with financial services. I want them to dislike the system a little bit less,” he said.</p>
<p>Rather than build a single budgeting or bookkeeping tool, the team set out to create infrastructure that would power thousands of financial products, with the lens that if financial products went digital they would have more impact on more people, ultimately leading to better outcomes.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/inside-plaids-plans-to-build-a-new-global-finance-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217181</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Space Force partners with VC firm Embedded Ventures under new R&#038;D agreement</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/u-s-space-force-partners-with-vc-firm-embedded-ventures-under-new-rd-agreement/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/u-s-space-force-partners-with-vc-firm-embedded-ventures-under-new-rd-agreement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Space Force]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The space industry used to be dominated by a single player: the U.S. government, which contracted out services to a handful of very large aerospace primes and put their tech to use in long-term, centrally managed programs. Things have rapidly evolved since. Due to an explosive technological acceleration and, in part, venture capital and private [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The space industry used to be dominated by a single player: the U.S. government, which contracted out services to a handful of very large aerospace primes and put their tech to use in long-term, centrally managed programs. Things have rapidly evolved since. Due to an explosive technological acceleration and, in part, venture capital and private equity, the U.S. government is one customer among many – but it doesn’t intend on being left behind.</p>
<p>To that end, the U.S. Space Force’s (USSF) SpaceWERX office has entered into a partnership with the eleven-month-old venture capital firm <a href="https://www.embedded.ventures/">Embedded Ventures</a> that’s aimed at building out research and development opportunities that can both grow the domestic space economy and can be used to defend the country’s interests.</p>
<p>This is the first time the USSF has entered into this kind of R&amp;D agreement, called a Cooperative Research and Development Agreement (CRADA), with a VC firm. It’s also yet another sign that the U.S. government is looking to benefit from the practices and funding model of venture capital.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217210" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>CRADA’s are traditionally used between the U.S. Department of Defense and startups looking to collaborate with the government. But after a few phone calls between Embedded Ventures and government officials, like Lieutenant Colonel Walter McMillan, “the rest is history,” Embedded’s co-founder Jenna Bryant said in a recent interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>There’s a lot of missed opportunity, on both the side of venture capital and the DOD, that this five-year partnership could help alleviate, Embedded co-founder Jordan Noone told TechCrunch. For one, venture capital can move much more quickly than the public entities can. VCs also have their ears to the ground on new and emerging technologies that defense interests could stand to benefit from.</p>
<p>Startups could benefit from the partnership as well. For many young companies, working with the U.S. government is a complicated, intimidating process, one characterized by long contractual timelines or highly regulated processes. Much of it comes down to education: startups making strategic decisions that will set them up to be eligible for a government contract, and it’s there that a VC firm could help.</p>
<p>“There&#8217;s not a lot of positive pressures from the venture capital community to encourage these dual-use tech opportunities,” Noone said. But such opportunities can be lucrative, for those companies willing to overcome the barriers to applying for a contract.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For Embedded’s part, they’re far more likely to take a risk on a company if there&#8217;s a probability that there’s a huge customer – the U.S. government – on the other side. Plus, the space technologies that could play a major role, say, twenty years from now will likely be ones that need a public-private partnership, Noone said, similar to how SpaceX was seeded in part by investments from NASA.</p>
<p>“How did we end up in an ecosystem in the venture community where Silicon Valley was birthed making technologies during the Cold War, and now they solely make consumer apps?” Noone said. “What happened in between and how do you steer the ship back where there is a national security relevance to Silicon Valley?”</p>
<p>Embedded and the USSF will meet regularly to talk progress and to set benchmarks along the way. As this is a new type of partnership under the CRADA program, involving no financial exchange between either entity, part of the goal is actually defining what a successful partnership looks like, so it could be replicated in the future. While there&#8217;s no requirement that the two entities co-invest, it may be one result of the collaboration, an Embedded spokesperson said.</p>
<p>“People in industry are always talking about, &#8216;how we can all work together, move at venture pace,&#8217; but no one&#8217;s actually doing it,” Bryant added. “It matters to me that we do something right now.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/u-s-space-force-partners-with-vc-firm-embedded-ventures-under-new-rd-agreement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217210</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Browser-based hardware design tool Flux raises $12M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/browser-based-hardware-design-tool-flux-raises-12m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/browser-based-hardware-design-tool-flux-raises-12m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outsiders Fund]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2215143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Things were trending toward remote collaboration well before the world ground to a screeching halt under the heels of a global pandemic, but the past year and a half have undoubtedly been a major catalyst for rethinking the way people work. It’s a phenomenon Flux has been thinking about for a while now, beginning development [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Things were trending toward remote collaboration well before the world ground to a screeching halt under the heels of a global pandemic, but the past year and a half have undoubtedly been a major catalyst for rethinking the way people work. It’s a phenomenon <a href="https://www.flux.ai">Flux</a> has been thinking about for a while now, beginning development in 2019 with a team of employees who worked at places like Apple, Facebook and NASA.</p>
<p>The startup designed a web-based, real-time collaboration tool for electronics design and engineering. Today it’s announcing a $12 million seed raise, led by Outsiders Fund and featuring additional investments from Bain Capital Ventures, 8VC and Liquid2 VC. The funding will go toward expanding Flux’s development team, investing R&amp;D for additional features and increasing its marketing reach.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/R63ED-crxXY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2215143" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Flux cites both the explosion of remote work (which won’t be going away any time soon) and ongoing hardware constraints, such as the chip shortage, as major drivers in the interest surrounding its technology.</p>
<p>“The world has changed dramatically since the first commercial chip developers opened shop in the 1970s and 80s. Today’s chip shortage is just the latest sign of that,” co-founder and CEO Matthias Wagner said in a release tied to the news. “The supply chain challenges we’re seeing now aren’t just a pandemic problem, they stem from decades of inattention to the design process itself. We built Flux to finally address these issues and we feel very fortunate to have found so many incredible investors who share our vision.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2215164" style="width: 946px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2215164" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2215164" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-6.png" alt="" width="936" height="624" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-6.png 936w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-6.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-6.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-6.png?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-6.png?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image-6.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 936px) 100vw, 936px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2215164" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Flux</p></div></p>
<p>Flux says its technology is supported by “all modern browsers,” requiring no downloads. The system features a simulator, automated part-sourcing and version control. The Community Library, meanwhile, offers access to schematics, models and open source parts — a little bit GitHub, a little bit Makerbot Thingiverse.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Wagner tells TechCrunch that the company is taking a GitHub-style approach to monetization.</p>
<blockquote><p>We are very inspired by GitHub and how it changed the whole software ecosystem with its open and community-driven repository of reusable code. Similarly, we’re planning on having a freemium SaaS model to make it easy for anyone to get started while also offering teams and organizations the type of features they require. This model enables the hardware community to come together and build and share reusable components like parts, simulator models, and reference schematics that can be forked and improved upon. Of course, engineers will always have control over what they share and publish. As engineers ourselves, we want to empower as many engineers and teams as possible.</p></blockquote>
<p>In addition to funding, the service is also using the opportunity to launch in beta.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/browser-based-hardware-design-tool-flux-raises-12m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2215143</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canadian startup Rose Rocket raises Series A to scale its transport software business</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/canadian-startup-rose-rocket-raises-series-a-to-scale-its-transport-software-business/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/canadian-startup-rose-rocket-raises-series-a-to-scale-its-transport-software-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[addition capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rose rocket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shine Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217078</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Freight transportation-focused Rose Rocket recently raised a $25 million round. The Toronto-based startup calls the round a Series A, with Addition Capital and Shine Capital leading the deal. Per venture data aggregated by Carta, average logistics-themed Series A rounds since the start of 2020 have sported median cash raises of $8 million and post-money valuations [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Freight transportation-focused <a href="https://www.roserocket.com/">Rose Rocket</a> recently raised a $25 million round.</p>
<p>The Toronto-based startup calls the round a Series A, with <a href="https://addition.com/">Addition Capital</a> and <a href="https://www.shine.vc/">Shine Capital</a> leading the deal.</p>
<p>Per venture data <a href="https://carta.com/data-desk/#interactive-data">aggregated by Carta</a>, average logistics-themed Series A rounds since the start of 2020 have sported median cash raises of $8 million and post-money valuations of around $50 million. The Rose Rocket round certainly surpasses its sector median in dollar terms, and we presume if measured by valuation as well.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217078" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>But the money side of the Rose Rocket story isn&#8217;t the most interesting thing about the company. Its market is.</p>
<p>The startup is building in the TMS space. What&#8217;s a TMS? A good question, and one that I had to ask while digging into Rose Rocket. TMS stands for <em>transportation management software</em>, which you can think of as a wide array of products that help truckers and brokers and other players in the freight transport game get work done on a digital basis.</p>
<p>Or, as Rose Rocket co-founder and CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jsky/">Justin Sky</a> explained to TechCrunch in an interview, TMS is a somewhat generic moniker that one might compare to ERP (enterprise resource planning). Sky added that he often describes what Rose Rocket is building as a NetSuite for trucking companies.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s trick is, in Sky&#8217;s phrasing, going &#8220;horizontal inside of a vertical.&#8221; By that, the CEO means that Rose Rocket wants to coordinate more than a single part of the larger freight trucking landscape; instead, the company wants to coordinate <em>all</em> players, allowing for a more integrated, less chaotic market.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For example, Rose Rocket offers the same software to both freight brokers and trucking companies. If a freight broker sends work to a trucking company and both use the startup&#8217;s software, Sky said that the work can proceed as if each company was reading off the same sheet music. Instead, of say, one of the parties playing a Chopin nocturne while the other plunked out a free jazz solo.</p>
<p>Like many vertically themed software plays, Rose Rocket is taking on other market-focused software providers, but also customers&#8217; use of Excel and manual processes. Trucking as an industry, you won&#8217;t be utterly shocked to learn, is not precisely <em>fully</em> digitized yet. That could provide a large total addressable market (TAM) for Rose Rocket to sell into given how large trucking is as both <a href="https://www.trucking.org/economics-and-industry-data">a business</a> (<a href="https://www.statista.com/topics/4912/trucking-industry-in-the-us/">and employer</a>).</p>
<p>Results thus far seem promising, with the company claiming that its customer logo count went up by around 9x in the last year. Sure, logo count is far from GAAP, but contracted deal volume also rose by 9x over the same period, so, presumably, the company&#8217;s business is doing numbers.</p>
<p>That Rose Rocket is a Canadian company &#8212; albeit one with U.S. incorporation, essentially a requirement to raise money in North America &#8212; is notable. The Canadian startup market has come a long way since Shopify broke into the larger business consciousness. We should probably pay it more heed.</p>
<p>Per CB Insights data, Canadian startups have raised some $9.3 billion thus far in 2021, through the end of Q3. That figure is more than what the country&#8217;s upstart tech companies managed in 2019 and 2020 <em>combined</em>. The country is also on pace to hit a record number of discrete venture rounds this year. Rose Rocket is therefore part of a growing trend of larger and more frequent startup investment in the country.</p>
<p>More when someone dumps an inevitable $100 million onto Rose Rocket&#8217;s head.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/canadian-startup-rose-rocket-raises-series-a-to-scale-its-transport-software-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217078</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Karat raises $110M on a $1.1B valuation to grow its technical interviewing-as-a-service platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/karat-raises-110m-on-a-1-1b-valuation-to-grow-its-technical-interviewing-as-a-service-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/karat-raises-110m-on-a-1-1b-valuation-to-grow-its-technical-interviewing-as-a-service-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Base Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chemistry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gold]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[norwest venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott Shleifer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wayfair]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217376</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the global race for technical talent, companies are on the hunt for ways to speed up and scale the hiring process to snap up the best candidates before their competitors get to them. Today, a company that has built a solution to help with one aspect of that &#8212; the interviewing process &#8212; is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the global race for technical talent, companies are on the hunt for ways to speed up and scale the hiring process to snap up the best candidates before their competitors get to them. Today, a company that has built a solution to help with one aspect of that &#8212; the interviewing process &#8212; is announcing a big round of funding that underscores that demand.</p>
<p><a href="https://karat.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Karat</a>, which has built what it calls the &#8220;Interviewing Cloud&#8221; &#8212; essentially, an &#8220;interviewing as a service&#8221; platform that provides customers with a way to funnel candidates to Karat&#8217;s team of trained online interviewers, engineers themselves who screen applicants for skills and problem solving abilities as part of the online assessment &#8212; has closed a round of $110 million, a Series C that values the Seattle startup at $1.1 billion.</p>
<p>The round is being led by Tiger Global, which also led the company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/15/karat-nabs-28m-led-by-tiger-global-to-grow-its-human-powered-online-interview-platform-for-engineering-jobs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$28 million Series B in 2019</a>. Norwest Venture Partners, 8VC, Exor, Base Partners, and Sempervirens Fund &#8212; all previous backers &#8212; also participated.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217376" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Karat plans to use the funding to continue building more technology and data science into its process &#8212; both to train and guide the interviewers, and to analyse the interviewing process to improve it in the future. Longer term, it might also look to bring in interviewers, skillsets, and data to grow beyond technical hiring. Technical hiring, however, remains a huge market for the startup. Working with companies like Roblox, American Express, Intuit, Compass, and Wayfair, Mohit Bhende, Karat&#8217;s co-founder and CEO, said a typical day might see 500 interviews conducted on the platform (not all for one company).</p>
<p>The last time we checked in with Karat, Covid-19 was not even on the horizon &#8212; it was May 2019 &#8212; and so the focus on providing tools to get work done virtually were nice rather than essential in the bigger mix.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Karat&#8217;s position that live, technical interviews were far superior to giving actual tests seemed still to be a subject for debate.</p>
<p>Fast forward seven months and the world has completely changed, and with that so has the world of work. Karat&#8217;s tools have suddenly come into their own as a key way for companies to continue their recruiting activities, and maybe even to do them better than before.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company started out sourcing people to conduct interviews by presenting it as a side-gig for working engineers. Now, Bhende says that the volume of interviews is such that those who run them on the platform now use it as their primary source of income, with a number of them making $250,000 annually via Karat. (That is not to say that they are full-time employees of Karat: Bhende confirms that they are all contractors, and all are working in compliance with their local employment laws.)</p>
<p>That shift in who is running the interview process speaks to the bigger challenge with finding people to conduct technical interviews in-house, and the push to recruit more engineers in general. As Bhende describes it, it&#8217;s nobody&#8217;s job, not formally at least, in part because engineers are too busy.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are not enough engineers in a company to interview engineers,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Typically, one of the ways that the interviewing processed has been compressed is to rely on tests, which Karat believes are not an accurate enough way to determine a candidate&#8217;s real-world problem solving skills and ability to collaborate with others. Plus, especially now, &#8220;people crave and want human-to-human interaction,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Indeed, while the human aspect of the service runs strong throughout the platform, what seems to be the lever for how Karat scales is the technology that underpins the platform. Bhende notes that the company trains the people based on the data that it sources from past interviews, which in theory gives it a stronger strike rate for identifying strong candidates. It can be a tricky area, since Karat is essentially at the center of how companies build new strategies and products: recruitment ads, indeed, are often a way that information leaks out about what a company is trying to work on in secret.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have a team of interview scientists trying to identify the perfect candidate interview,&#8221; said Jeffrey Spector the president and other co-founder of Karat. &#8220;We are a competency-driven company and so we are looking for underlying skills and questions that map to the perfect candidate.&#8221; He says these are represented as modules, which Karat might then map to what a specific company is looking for. This is also one way that an interviewer &#8212; who is not employed by the company for whom s/he is doing the interviewing for &#8212; is able to keep a wall around what might be a company&#8217;s confidential or proprietary information, while still determining if a candidate would be a good fit for the role. &#8220;It means we&#8217;re not learning every single thing.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe Karat’s human + technology Interviewing Cloud is the way most companies will hire engineers,” said Scott Shleifer, partner at Tiger Global, in a statement. “We know the gap between the supply of engineering talent and demand will continue to widen and are excited to deepen our investment in the category creator and leader.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/karat-raises-110m-on-a-1-1b-valuation-to-grow-its-technical-interviewing-as-a-service-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217376</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>General Catalyst, Tiger Global lead $25M investment into Blank Street’s micro specialty coffee shops</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/general-catalyst-tiger-global-lead-25m-investment-into-blank-streets-micro-specialty-coffee-shops/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/general-catalyst-tiger-global-lead-25m-investment-into-blank-streets-micro-specialty-coffee-shops/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[allbirds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blank Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issam Freiha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neil blumenthal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vinay Menda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warby Parker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company now operates 14 locations in a mix of 700-square-foot brick-and-mortar spaces and mobile street carts. Each location hit profitability within two months after opening.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Vinay Menda and Issam Freiha are two coffee-obsessed friends who came to New York from Dubai and Lebanon to study at NYU and Columbia, respectively, and started researching the New York coffee scene.</p>
<p>In the U.S, they saw a coffee shop on every corner, but found the experience slow and overpriced: the shops were either a destination place or for buying coffee to brew at home, not a quality “grab and go” kind of operation, Freiha said. They noticed their friends going to different chain coffee shops for convenience or price point, but as college students, they couldn&#8217;t afford daily $6 cappuccinos.</p>
<p>Soon after graduating, they co-founded Reshape, a venture capital fund with $100 million of assets under management. They saw how successful high-growth, mobile-first, food-retail businesses were in Asia and saw an opportunity to replicate that street vending experience in the United States.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216786" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“There were a lot of cool businesses coming out of Asia and being efficient in real estate, which enables you to cut down and save money on rent and push customers to order ahead,” Menda told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The pair, who have worked together now for about seven years, founded New York-based Blank Street in May 2020 and opened their first mobile coffee cart three months later in Williamsburg in partnership with EV Foods at the Wythe Diner.</p>
<p>Their idea was to shrink their business’ real estate to make it easier to control the location, enable them to have multiple locations in one neighborhood versus one and save money to invest in other places, like lower product prices. They added some technology to improve the consumer ordering experience while also building in quality, speed and convenience.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216790" style="width: 5564px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216790" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2216790 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blank-Streets-Vinay-Menda-Issam-Freiha-Credit_-Liz-Clayman.jpg" alt="Blank Street's Vinay Menda + Issam Freiha" width="5554" height="3708" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blank-Streets-Vinay-Menda-Issam-Freiha-Credit_-Liz-Clayman.jpg 5554w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blank-Streets-Vinay-Menda-Issam-Freiha-Credit_-Liz-Clayman.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blank-Streets-Vinay-Menda-Issam-Freiha-Credit_-Liz-Clayman.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blank-Streets-Vinay-Menda-Issam-Freiha-Credit_-Liz-Clayman.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blank-Streets-Vinay-Menda-Issam-Freiha-Credit_-Liz-Clayman.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blank-Streets-Vinay-Menda-Issam-Freiha-Credit_-Liz-Clayman.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blank-Streets-Vinay-Menda-Issam-Freiha-Credit_-Liz-Clayman.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blank-Streets-Vinay-Menda-Issam-Freiha-Credit_-Liz-Clayman.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 5554px) 100vw, 5554px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216790" class="wp-caption-text">Blank Street&#8217;s co-founders Vinay Menda and Issam Freiha. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Liz Clayman</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Today, the company announced a $25 million Series A round, led by General Catalyst and Tiger Global, with additional strategic investors, including Warby Parker founders Neil Blumenthal and Dave Gilboa, Harry’s founder Jeff Raider and Allbirds founder Joey Zwillinger. This latest round adds to $7 million the company raised in seed funding earlier this year.</p>
<p>Youngme Moon, a Harvard Business School professor, Blank Street board member and General Catalyst advisor, said via email that she learned about the company when she saw their mobile coffee carts popping up across the city. She saw the company was “quickly establishing itself as the newest contender in New York’s high-growth specialty coffee race.”</p>
<p>&#8220;While they&#8217;ve quickly created an impressive coffee business, I was drawn to the way the Blank Street founders are reimagining the entire micro-retail experience for urban customers,” Moon added. “Blank Street competes in a crowded, competitive landscape, yet differentiates itself through a unique customer experience by serving a high-quality product through a digitally native, mobile vendor offering.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company now operates 14 locations across Brooklyn and Manhattan in a mix of 700-square-foot brick-and-mortar spaces and zero emission mobile street carts, serving as a micro-retail marketplace for shops like Parlor Coffee, Gertie bagels, King Street Baking Co. and King David Tacos. Each location hit profitability within two months after opening, Menda said.</p>
<p>“What makes the model work is density,” he added. “To make a difference and impact on the consumer, we plan to have 100 locations by 2022 and enough presence so that people will know the brand.”</p>
<p>The new funding will go toward retail expansion, vendor partners and technology development. Freiha expects to have three to five locations per 20 neighborhoods, each with its own team and resources. Another focus will be on the consumer app for ordering, pick-up and a rewards program.</p>
<p>In addition, the company is now launching its “Powered By Blank Street,” a wholesale partnership agreement for local vendors to sell in new neighborhoods without having to find a storefront, provide their own labor or manage day-to-day operations. King David Tacos is the first to use this new model, which involves its breakfast tacos being sold alongside Blank Street’s coffee and tea.</p>
<p>“We want to offer the same tools to power the experience for other brands, giving them the same infrastructure we have,” Menda said. “Consumers will be able to discover new foods and it is also a great way for vendors to test out new and interesting products and get live feedback.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eLxognjRYw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/europes-quick-commerce-startups-are-overhyped-lessons-from-china/">Europe&#8217;s quick-commerce startups are overhyped: Lessons from China</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe&#8217;s quick-commerce startups are overhyped: Lessons from China&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/europes-quick-commerce-startups-are-overhyped-lessons-from-china/embed/#?secret=eLxognjRYw" data-secret="eLxognjRYw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/general-catalyst-tiger-global-lead-25m-investment-into-blank-streets-micro-specialty-coffee-shops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216786</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple Watch Series 7 review</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/apple-watch-series-7-review/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/apple-watch-series-7-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple watch series 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartwatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watchOS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217073</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The entire smartwatch category had a good Q2, as numbers jumped 27% year over year. That, in turn, was up 20% from a year prior, in spite &#8212; or perhaps because of &#8212; COVID-19 concerns. The popularity of these devices are the proverbial rising tide, with most of the big players benefiting from an overall [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The entire smartwatch category had a good Q2, as numbers jumped 27% year over year. That, in turn, was up 20% from a year prior, in spite &#8212; or perhaps because of &#8212; COVID-19 concerns. The popularity of these devices are the proverbial rising tide, with most of the big players benefiting from an overall increase in adoption.</p>
<p>But one name continues to loom large in a way seldom seen in a fairly mature category. Last quarter, the Apple Watch’s active user base crossed 100 million,<a href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/smartwatch-market-grows-27-yoy-q2-2021-apple-watch-user-base-crosses-100-million/"> according to Counterpoint Research.</a> The company took three of the top four smartwatch spots globally with the Series 6, SE and Series 3, with Samsung managing to sneak into the No. 3 slot with its latest Galaxy Watch Active.</p>
<p>The company has seen competition on the low end of the market, with an influx of sub-$100 devices, but at the premium and mid-range end, Apple continues to be utterly dominate to such a degree that top competitors like Samsung and Google are teaming up to take it on. So, what do you do when you’re Apple? You tweak. You make the screen a bit bigger, you make the charger a bit faster and, most of all, you don’t really mess with a good thing.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217073" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2216731" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216731" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2216731 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0330.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0330.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0330.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0330.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0330.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0330.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0330.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0330.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0330.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216731" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>Some of the more outlandish rumors swirling around health-related changes proved wrong, as the company instead opted to focus on making some aesthetic changes to the device. The Series 7 marks one of the biggest changes to the device’s design in several generations, and even that isn’t what one might deem a radical departure. In fact, it’s the sort of thing you can walk around with undetected.</p>
<p>If, on the other hand, you’re a daily Apple Watch user, you’ll notice the difference on your wrist immediately. The upgrade from Series 6 to Series 7. The larger model (which we’ll be focusing on for the remainder of this review) bumps up from a 1.78-inch screen (measured diagonally, à la a smartphone) to 1.9 inches. That represents a 20% increase over the Series 6 and a 50% increase over the Series 3, which somehow manages to keep sticking around.</p>
<p>It’s not a radical departure, generation over generation. And certainly something like 12% larger buttons on the calculator aren’t enough to sell anyone on an upgrade. The truth is that the nature of wearables generally prohibits designers from making too radical a design change because the product needs to fit on your body. The earliest smartwatches suffered from large designs that prohibited wearability among a wide swath of users.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2216732" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216732" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2216732 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0302.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0302.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0302.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0302.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0302.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0302.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0302.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0302.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0302.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216732" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>Any increase to screen size should be counteracted by a reduction in the surrounding hardware. This is achieved, in part, by a thinning of the bezels, down to 1.7mm. The black border hasn’t gone away entirely here, but it’s noticeably slimmer, even when compared to the Series 6. In spite of this, the company still had to increase the overall size of the case, from 40/44mm to 41/45mm. As someone who’s had some issues with larger smartwatch cases in the past (I’m looking at you, Samsung), I didn’t really notice a difference with the added millimeter here. It feels the same on-wrist and while wearing it to bed. I’m not sure I’ll ever feel fully comfortable wearing a smartwatch to sleep, but your mileage may vary.</p>
<p>Along with the added real estate comes adjustments to the UI that allow for a surprising amount of additional content &#8212; again, when dealing with a sub-two-inch screen, it really becomes a game of millimeters. According to the company, apps like Messages are now capable of fitting in more than 50% additional text than on the Series 6. In other cases, where less content is required, that means two larger font sizes added to the mix, so you get, say, bigger buttons on the passcode screen.</p>
<p>The biggest day to day change, however, is the addition of a full QWERTY keyboard for text input, either by tapping or sliding between letters with QuickPath. I’m surprised at how well both worked on the small screen. As soon as you open up the application, an “Apple Watch Keyboard Input” notification will pop up on your connected iPhone, asking if you’d like to input the text on iOS. In most instances, the answer is probably yes. But it’s nice to have the option if, you’re (gasp) going to be away from your phone for a bit.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216726" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216726" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2216726 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0368.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0368.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0368.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0368.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0368.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0368.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0368.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0368.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0368.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216726" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The new watch features a thicker display crystal, adding some ruggedness. Watches obviously don’t have as much opportunity to shatter as phones, but I have a bad habit of taking turns a little too tightly and smacking my watch on a door jam. Nothing’s shattered yet, but there have been some close calls. This is also the first watch to add dust proofing to the existing WR50 water resistances. At IP6X, the system is completely dust-tight.</p>
<p>The edges of the display curve a touch more, meeting flush with the case, making a bit more of the display visible when viewed from the side. The new Counter watch face, which stretches the numbers along the border, take advantage of this, while the other two new screens &#8212; Modular Duo and World Time &#8212; use the additional real estate to jam in even more watch complications.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216725" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216725" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2216725 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0367.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0367.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0367.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0367.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0367.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0367.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0367.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0367.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0367.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216725" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>One of the upshots of a larger case is the ability to fit in a larger battery. Apple won’t say whether it’s actually increased the capacity here, so we’ll have to wait for the inevitable teardown. It seems likely the company bumped the mAh up a bit, though, in a bid to maintain the same battery life as before. Apple promises 18 hours, and indeed, you should be able to make it through a day no problem, in spite of a larger and significantly brighter (70% when inside, per the company) always-on display.</p>
<p>[gallery ids="2216727,2216739,2216733,2216732,2216731,2216730,2216728,2216726,2216725,2216724,2216723,2216721"]</p>
<p>I was hoping the addition of legitimate sleep tracking would have meant a more aggressive approach to battery life, especially as some of the competition are touting multiple days on a single charge. What we do get, at least, is a new USB-C magnetic charger that is 33% faster than the one on the Series 6, giving you an 80% charge in around 45 minutes. What that means in practical terms is a full night’s charge in less than 10 minutes. So if you’re strategic about charging, you can effectively wear it day and night.</p>
<p>The new charger is backward compatible with older Watches, in that it will charge them at their standard speed. In keeping with Apple’s effort to reduce waste, the Series 7 doesn’t ship with a wall adapter, however. But it should work with the USB-C ones you (hopefully) have lying around. The company has some new bands, as well, though the 7 is also, thankfully, compatible with all of the existing ones on Apple’s site.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216739" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216739" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2216739 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-10.27.15-AM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="696" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-10.27.15-AM.jpg 2392w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-10.27.15-AM.jpg?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-10.27.15-AM.jpg?resize=300,204 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-10.27.15-AM.jpg?resize=768,522 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-10.27.15-AM.jpg?resize=680,462 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-10.27.15-AM.jpg?resize=1536,1044 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-10.27.15-AM.jpg?resize=2048,1392 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-10.27.15-AM.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216739" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The sensors are largely unchanged, and the Series 7 sports the same processor and LTE chip as before. 5G for the Series 8, perhaps? The new colors are nice. Apple sent along the Green Aluminum, which is subtler than I’d anticipated. It’s a dark olive color, which is easily mistaken for a dark gray or black in certain lighting. If you want something that pops a bit more, go with the red or blue.</p>
<p>The Series 7 starts at $399 for the 41mm and $429 for the 45mm. Prices go up accordingly based on band type and finish. If you’ve already got the Series 6, it’s a not a huge upgrade. Assuming yours is still working, maybe wait a year or two to see what Apple has up its sleeve in the future, in terms of health and other features. As is, there are enough bits and bobs to keep Apple at the top of the pack.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/apple-watch-series-7-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217073</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intro’s app attracts Andreessen, Seven Seven Six, Kevin Durant to connect celebrity e-design experts with those seeking advice</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/intros-app-attracts-andreessen-seven-seven-six-kevin-durant-to-connect-celebrity-e-design-experts-with-those-seeking-advice/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/intros-app-attracts-andreessen-seven-seven-six-kevin-durant-to-connect-celebrity-e-design-experts-with-those-seeking-advice/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Chen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anne wojcicki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Durant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lettuce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael ovitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raad Mobrem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seven seven six]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telemedicine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216988</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Intro provides access to in-demand experts through personalized one-on-one video calls.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Advice is not a new concept, but <a href="https://intro.co/">Intro</a> is putting its spin on access to in-demand experts through personalized one-on-one video calls.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles company was founded in 2020 by entrepreneur Raad Mobrem, who previously founded Lettuce, an operating system for small businesses that was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/05/08/intuit-buys-lettuce-apps-to-add-inventory-and-order-management-to-quickbooks/">acquired by Intuit in 2014</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216996" style="width: 462px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216996" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2216996 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Raad-Mobrem-headshot.color_-e1634062562471.jpg?w=452" alt="Raad Mobrem, Intro" width="452" height="680" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216996" class="wp-caption-text">Raad Mobrem, founder of Intro. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Intro</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216988" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>When Mobrem was younger, he had a chance encounter with Kinko’s founder Paul Orfalea and had the opportunity to bend his ear about being an entrepreneur.</p>
<p>“In 15 minutes, I learned more about being an entrepreneur than I could have elsewhere,” Mobrem told TechCrunch. “I left our chat feeling inspired, and as I became an entrepreneur, Paul became a lifelong mentor.”</p>
<p>That conversation gave him the idea for Intro, which has a mission to provide access to people who are great at their craft. Mobrem says most of these people share a common theme: they had access to someone who was also great. If everyone had access to those types of people, they could gain that knowledge and could act on that information.</p>
<p>Users create an account on the Intro website or app, currently available on iOS, and browse a marketplace of style, wellness, business, home, beauty and astrology experts. The company has already curated an expert list touting stylist Rachel Zoe, interior designer Nate Berkus and dietitian McKel Kooienga.</p>
<p>On the expert side, the app offers a self-service model for scheduling, payments and video calls. The expert can set and modify their own prices, manage availability and decide how many sessions they want to offer and when.</p>
<p>Video sessions, what Mobrem calls “micro consultations,” average 15 minutes to two hours, and can price out from $30 to $200 for a 15-minute session, depending on the experts. Working with a high-caliber interior designer could run thousands of dollars, so to have a quick session on refreshing a room, “the virtual access is quite powerful, and the value is incredible,” he added.</p>
<p>Instead of charging the experts a subscription fee, Intro makes money when they do, taking 30% commission for calls the company brings in or 10% when the expert initiates a call through their booking tool.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To continue democratizing this kind of access, the company raised a $10 million seed investment led by Andreessen Horowitz. Joining the firm was Seven Seven Six, CAA founder Michael Ovitz, Goldman Sachs CEO David Solomon, 23 &amp; Me CEO Anne Wojcicki, Kevin Durant, Tiffany Haddish and other strategic investors. The latest funding gives the company $12 million in total funding to date.</p>
<p>”The team at Intro is building a beautiful product in the form of a marketplace that is offering a direct line to some of the world’s leading voices and minds,” said Andrew Chen, general partner at Andreessen Horowitz, in a written statement. ”This platform has enormous potential and is well positioned to scale across multiple disciplines. It also creates opportunities for experts and creators to monetize their followers and diversify their revenue stream in an effective way.”</p>
<p>Intro has been in beta mode, but facilitated 500 sessions within its first two months. Mobrem personally called the first customers after their sessions to find out about the experience. Many told him that as the conversations turned into advice, it was “shocking how much they could get done in a short period of time,” he said.</p>
<p>He plans to use the new funding to hire more people and recruit additional experts. The marketplace has about 75 experts so far, and he anticipates adding experts in career and business categories, parenting and everyday advice, like how to buy your first home.</p>
<p>There are other startups going after service-based providers, but Mobrem sees what Intro is doing to be a new industry catalyzed by the global pandemic. He considers telemedicine being the closest competitor to what Intro is doing, similarly driven by the global pandemic, and enabling doctors to be more efficient with their existing patient base while opening their practice up to additional patients, he said.</p>
<p>“Next up, we will be chipping away at our task list,” Mobrem added. “We think we have already built the best product that is easy to use, but we can always improve. We also want to get more experts, which we will do by helping them make more money, which means consumers will ultimately have more access.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aLyRe5FzU7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/brands-considering-a-live-shopping-strategy-must-lean-on-influencers/">Brands considering a live-shopping strategy must lean on influencers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Brands considering a live-shopping strategy must lean on influencers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/brands-considering-a-live-shopping-strategy-must-lean-on-influencers/embed/#?secret=aLyRe5FzU7" data-secret="aLyRe5FzU7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/intros-app-attracts-andreessen-seven-seven-six-kevin-durant-to-connect-celebrity-e-design-experts-with-those-seeking-advice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216988</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
