<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 21:36:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: The early-stage tech talent crunch is real</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/daily-crunch-the-early-stage-tech-talent-crunch-is-real/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/daily-crunch-the-early-stage-tech-talent-crunch-is-real/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 22:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151329</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>By now everyone is familiar with the tech world’s talent crunch: Developers are scarce and expensive, while data scientists are maybe even scarcer and expensiver. Some folks I’ve spoken to think that rising acceptance of remote work may help reduce the supply-demand imbalance. Hell, every early-stage startup I’ve spoken to in weeks is remote-first. Many were born during COVID, but they all love the ability to hire anywhere in the world.</p>
<p>But if a more distributed workforce is not enough to lower the pain that many companies feel when it comes to attracting and then <em>retaining</em> technical talent, good news could be coming. The sibling product philosophies of no-code and low-code are not only <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/dont-hate-on-low-code-and-no-code/">attracting lots of venture attention</a>, public companies that dabble with either are posting interesting results.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Perhaps the solution to needing lots more code is no code at all? &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<p>Today’s TechCrunch Top 3 come from the three phases of startup life: Early stage, when startups are still getting their product and market in order. Late stage, when they are prepping for an eventual exit. And the exit stage, when a former startup is looking to spread its wings and fly the private markets.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/brazils-divibank-raises-millions-to-become-the-clearbanc-of-latam/">The anti-venture movement is global</a>:</strong> Today <strong><a href="https://twitter.com/bayareawriter">Mary Ann</a></strong> reported that <strong>Divibank</strong>, a Brazilian startup offering revenue-based financing to other startups, has raised $3.6 million in a seed round led by Better Tomorrow Ventures (BTV). TechCrunch thinks it could build something akin to the <strong>Clearbanc</strong> of Latin America.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/uk-fashion-portal-lyst-raises-85m-in-a-pre-ipo-round-reportedly-at-a-500m-valuation/"><strong>London’s Lyst looks to list</strong></a><strong>:</strong> When you raise a pre-IPO round, you’d best be heading toward the public markets. With fashion e-commerce app <strong>Lyst</strong> saying that its new $85 million funding round is pre-IPO money, well, we have big expectations.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-spac-filing-shows-scooter-nomics-just-doesnt-fly/">Bird hopes to take flight</a>:</strong> Bird is going public via a SPAC. TechCrunch has the big news <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-to-go-public-via-spac-at-an-implied-value-of-2-3b/">here</a></strong>, and a more dorky financial analysis <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-spac-filing-shows-scooter-nomics-just-doesnt-fly/">here</a></strong>. I helped write the latter. The short version is that a business-model shakeup is helping the scooter unicorn lose less money over time.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups and VC</h2>
<p>Scootin’ into startup mode, TechCrunch covered a huge number of funding rounds in the last 24 hours, so what follows is a sampling of the most interesting. Enjoy!</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/argentinas-pomelo-raises-9m-to-build-a-new-payments-infrastructure-for-latam-fintechs/">Pomelo raises $9M to build a payments infrastructure for LatAm fintechs</a>:</strong> Building fintech infrastructure is a huge global task, so it’s not a surprise to see companies at work on the problem raising money. In this case, Pomelo is $9 million richer to tackle what might be the most interesting fintech market in the world.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/collective-a-back-office-for-the-self-employed-raises-20m-from-ashton-kutchers-vc/">Collective, a back-office platform for the self-employed, raises $20M from Ashton Kutcher’s VC</a>:</strong> Going indie is not easy, despite what the Substack hype might have you believe. So, Collective is betting that it can make bank off of helping folks run their own microcompany. Both the company and the investment are a wager on the creator economy.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/stampli-raises-50-million-in-series-c-to-help-companies-intelligently-manage-invoices/"><strong>Stampli raises $50 million in Series C to help companies intelligently manage</strong> <strong>invoices</strong></a><strong>:</strong> The Stampli round stood out because it was more capital in a single investment than the startup had raised during all of its previous life &#8212; by around 50%. So, something is going on at the corporate-invoice optimization software shop that has investor attention.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/planck-the-insurance-data-analytics-platform-raises-20m-growth-round/"><strong>Planck, the insurance data analytics platform, raises $20M growth round</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Two of the three Planck co-founders are bald, so I had no choice but to include my follicle-deficient brethren in today’s newsletter. Jokes aside, Planck collects data that it sells to commercial insurance companies. And now it has fresh capital from 3L Capital, Greenfield Partners, Team8, Viola Fintech, Arbor Ventures and Eight Roads to help it grow.</li>
</ul>
<h2>For unicorns, how much does the route to going public really matter?</h2>
<p>Natasha Mascarenhas and Alex Wilhelm recently hosted Yext CFO Steve Cakebread and Latch CFO Garth Mitchell on an episode of TechCrunch&#8217;s Equity podcast.</p>
<p>In their discussion, &#8220;The morality and efficacy of going public earlier,&#8221; the group discussed the myriad paths startups are taking to go public and assessed the pros and cons of each method, and, importantly, the potential impacts on employees and business operations.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think when money’s chasing money, you don’t want to be the last guy holding the money. You want to be the chase,&#8221; said Cakebread.</p>
<p>Since Latch is currently going public via a SPAC and Yext followed a traditional IPO route a few years ago, the discussion is heavily weighted toward experience, not opinion.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="637rQrOrnv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/for-unicorns-how-much-does-the-route-to-going-public-really-matter/">For unicorns, how much does the route to going public really matter?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;For unicorns, how much does the route to going public really matter?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/for-unicorns-how-much-does-the-route-to-going-public-really-matter/embed/#?secret=637rQrOrnv" data-secret="637rQrOrnv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Turning to tech’s largest companies today, we have three things for you to chew on:</p>
<p>First, Waymo is losing key talent in a very public fashion. <a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec">Kirsten</a> reports that “Waymo’s chief financial officer Ger Dwyer and its head of automotive partnerships and corporate development Adam Frost,” both long-time execs, are “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/waymos-cfo-and-head-of-automotive-partnerships-are-leaving-the-autonomous-vehicle-company/?tpcc=ECTW2020">leaving this month</a>.” The exits come after the company’s former CEO also departed.</p>
<p>I guess we’ll have to drive ourselves for a bit longer.</p>
<p>Next up is a story that came out yesterday, but we missed in the newsletter. But after burning up the TechCrunch analytics all day, I decided to make sure that you saw it. With the simply excellent headline <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/chinese-products-get-pulled-from-amazon/">Prime today, gone tomorrow: Chinese products get pulled from Amazon</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/ritacyliao">Rita</a> writes that several Chinese retailers have evaporated from the online megastore. “In total, the suspended accounts contribute over a billion dollars in gross merchandise value (GMV) to Amazon,” she reported.</p>
<p>Changes afoot at Amazon? We’ll have to see, but the news is driving mega-attention from, we presume, confused shoppers.</p>
<p>Finally, looping back to no-code for a hot second, Salesforce is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/salesforce-is-bringing-drag-and-drop-interactive-components-to-its-low-code-toolkit/">only adding to its own efforts</a>. It’s everywhere!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/daily-crunch-the-early-stage-tech-talent-crunch-is-real/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151329</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bessemer&#8217;s Kent Bennett and Toast&#8217;s Aman Narang to discuss how to become a unicorn on ECL</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bessemers-kent-bennett-and-toasts-aman-narang-to-discuss-how-to-become-a-unicorn-on-ecl/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bessemers-kent-bennett-and-toasts-aman-narang-to-discuss-how-to-become-a-unicorn-on-ecl/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 21:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ECL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aman Narang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bessemer Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kent Bennett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2150355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Toast has a reported valuation over $5 billion and has raised more than $900 million since launch. The restaurant POS service has clearly been on a rapid growth trajectory, but how has the company navigated the market during the pandemic, which has pushed and pulled the restaurant industry unlike ever before? On an upcoming episode [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Toast has a reported valuation over $5 billion and has raised more than $900 million since launch. The restaurant POS service has clearly been on a rapid growth trajectory, but how has the company navigated the market during the pandemic, which has pushed and pulled the restaurant industry unlike ever before?</p>
<p>On an upcoming episode of <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-bessemer-and-toast">Extra Crunch Live (May 26 at 3pm ET</a>), we&#8217;ll find out. We&#8217;re sitting down with president and co-founder of Toast, Aman Narang, and one of the company&#8217;s investors, Bessemer Venture Partners&#8217; Kent Bennett.</p>
<p>Bennett is a partner out of the Cambridge office, focusing on consumer products and services as well as consumer-facing software. Before venture, Bennett was a creative executive for an entertainment production company called Licht Entertainment.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>His portfolio includes Bevi, Blue Apron, Xtime and, of course, Toast.</p>
<p>Narang spent seven years at Oracle, then Endeca, working on the development of the company&#8217;s business intelligence platform and mobile commerce platform.</p>
<p>He co-founded Toast in 2011 and has been growing the company ever since, adding new products and features to the restaurant POS system.</p>
<p>On <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">Extra Crunch Live</a>, we&#8217;ll sit down with Narang and Bennett to learn about how they came together for the company&#8217;s Series B deal, which Bessemer led. We&#8217;ll also talk about why Bennett wanted to bet on Toast, how they&#8217;ve worked together since and how they overcome challenges and disagreements. If we&#8217;re lucky, we may even get a peek at Toast&#8217;s original Series B pitch deck.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yH23UrzJSY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/">11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/embed/#?secret=yH23UrzJSY" data-secret="yH23UrzJSY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>From there, we&#8217;ll head into the Extra Crunch Live Pitch-off. Members of the audience can raise their hand to pitch live on the show, and Bennett and Narang will offer their feedback. It&#8217;s always a good time, but the only way to participate is to show up live. <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-bessemer-and-toast">Register here for free!</a></p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live is a free event and accessible to everyone, but only Extra Crunch members get access to the entire library of ECL episodes, all of which are packed with insights on how to raise and run a successful venture-backed company.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-bessemer-and-toast">Register to hang out with myself, Narang and Bennett on Wednesday, May 26 at 3pm ET/noon PT.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bessemers-kent-bennett-and-toasts-aman-narang-to-discuss-how-to-become-a-unicorn-on-ecl/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2150355</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: When Doves Cry</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/gillmor-gang-when-doves-cry/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/gillmor-gang-when-doves-cry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 21:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151293</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Usually we wait a few days until a show has settled. While we stall, our producer and director Tina Chase Gillmor scours the recording for short clips that give a sense of the flavor and tenor of the conversation. This show, recorded a little more than 2 weeks ago, went deep on politics, government, anything [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/1yV1CeEwY48?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Usually we wait a few days until a show has settled. While we stall, our producer and director Tina Chase Gillmor scours the recording for short clips that give a sense of the flavor and tenor of the conversation. This show, recorded a little more than 2 weeks ago, went deep on politics, government, anything but Trump, and eventually a pivot to the tech world and how it was grappling with the possible return to the office. I asked Brent Leary what he thought about the likelihood of working from anywhere, and discovered he was multitasking to the director&#8217;s cut of a famous Prince video.</p>
<p>Brian Solis had sent him this re-edit of George Harrison&#8217;s induction into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame as a solo artist, featuring a wonderful version of his classic White Album track While My Guitar Gently Weeps. An all-star cast of friends of the late Beatle included Tom Petty, Steve Winwood, Jeff Lynne, and a surprise guitar solo by Prince that ended with him tossing his guitar to the heavens in triumph. While the new video doesn&#8217;t reveal what happened to the instrument, it does extend our views of Prince and particularly his interactions with the other players. Re-released 17 years later, it does the impossible, preserving the magic of the event while somehow extending the mechanics of how Prince captivated not just his audience but his peers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It also reminds me of what magic we&#8217;ve come to expect from the technology industry and its band of stars. The success of the vaccines came not just from the miracle of new science and desperate nature of humanity&#8217;s need for rescue from the pandemic, but also from the growing hope that government and even politics can work. The jury has been and will continue to be out on how quickly we can recover, but there&#8217;s a question of recovering what. Is it a binary choice of office or mobile or something in between? Already some tech companies have moved toward the hybrid approach, where the office would reopen and workers would return for some but not all of the week.</p>
<p>As a parent of two girls, I&#8217;ve watched with fascination as they grew up with technology as a given not the revolution that it is. Our youngest has for many years structured her communication with us and her peers as a text-based, emotional video channel, and occasional authorization for face-to-face interaction. The pandemic made this mandatory, but as we get closer to a safer environment, the skills we&#8217;ve been mandated to learn are only going to solidify. Texting can be replied to in a while or treated as just information to be absorbed. Voice calls are optional, Facetime usually accepted as an opportunity to catch up but certainly not a daily proposition. Sneaking a peek at her Instagram feed is good for calming nerves but abstract in terms of any real details. That&#8217;s as it should be; I actually need more emotional buttressing than she does.</p>
<p>Prince was like that when he appeared early in his career, conversant in the history of his craft and matter-of-fact in his approach to the technology innovations unleashed by George Martin and the Beatles with Revolver and transformationally Sgt.Pepper. Prince took that studio process, the multitracking inventions of Stevie Wonder, the extra-worldly funk explorations of Hendrix, the cool mastery of Miles — and did it all. The record business pushed him, he pushed back, changed his name to a symbol, and eventually won control of his recordings. Nothing compares 2 U, he wrote.</p>
<p>The music business, like the movie and TV business, has changed everything about how we consume their products. Musicians have been homebound for more than a year with no way of touring to replace what used to be the major part of their income. Some are turning to the crazy world of packaging their work as crypto objects, the so-called non fungible tokens. Joke projects like Dogecoin have become intertwined with Saturday Night Live as Elon Musk plays a character in Weekend Update avoiding persistent questions about just what is going on here. As one Tweeter noted, they made a good choice watching Dogecoin dropping like a stone as funnier than the comedy broadcast.</p>
<p>Sooner or later the dust will settle and we can choose some Sneak Peeks to nudge the way forward. As much as we buy the idea that we need to return to some kind of normal, the sneaking suspicion is that we deserve some relief from the rigged deck that is our politics, our culture, devoid of empathy and based on power as the ultimate rationale for who can run the show. Like the filters in Zoom that let us change our backgrounds to where we choose to be coming from, it&#8217;s a reasonable choice to define our new office as a blend of the best of our new worlds.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><em>from the <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang/issues/gillmor-gang-newsletter-revue-7-560606"> Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, April 30, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang">Subscribe to the new Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></strong> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="169" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/gillmor-gang-when-doves-cry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151293</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AWS releases tool to open source that turns on-prem software into SaaS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/aws-releases-tool-to-open-source-that-turns-on-prem-software-into-saas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/aws-releases-tool-to-open-source-that-turns-on-prem-software-into-saas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AWS announced today that it&#8217;s releasing a tool called AWS SaaS Boost as open source distributed under the Apache 2.0 license. The tool, which was first announced at the AWS re:Invent conference last year, is designed to help companies transform their on-prem software into cloud-based software as a service. In the charter for the software, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">AWS <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/opensource/aws-saas-boost-released-as-open-source/">announced today</a> that it&#8217;s releasing a tool called <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/partners/saas-boost/">AWS SaaS Boost</a> as open source distributed under the <a href="https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0">Apache 2.0 license</a>. The tool, which was first announced at the AWS re:Invent conference last year, is designed to help companies transform their on-prem software into cloud-based software as a service.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://github.com/awslabs/aws-saas-boost/blob/main/CHARTER.md">the charter for the software</a>, the company describes its mission this way: &#8220;Our mission is to create a community-driven suite of extensible building blocks for Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) builders. Our goal is to foster an open environment for developing and sharing reusable code that accelerates the ability to deliver and operate multi-tenant SaaS solutions on AWS.&#8221;</p>
<p>What it effectively does is provide the tools to turn the application into one that lets you sign up users and let them use the app in a multi-tenant cloud context. Even though it&#8217;s open source, it is designed to get you to move your application into the AWS system where you can access a number of AWS services such as AWS CloudFormation, AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM), Amazon Route 53, Elastic Load Balancing, AWS Lambda (Amazon&#8217;s serverless tool), and Amazon Elastic Container Service (Amazon&#8217;s Kubernetes Service). Although presumably you could use alternative services, if you were so inclined.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MGRYpPq23t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/mongodb-switches-up-its-open-source-license/">MongoDB switches up its open-source license</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MongoDB switches up its open-source license&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/mongodb-switches-up-its-open-source-license/embed/#?secret=MGRYpPq23t" data-secret="MGRYpPq23t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>By making it open source, it gives companies that would need this kind of service access to the source code, giving them a comfort level and an ability to contribute to the project to expand upon the base product and give back to the community. That makes it a win for users who get flexibility and the benefit of a community behind the tool, and a win for AWS, which gets that community working on the tool to improve and enhance it over time.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our objective with AWS SaaS Boost is to get great quality software based on years of experience in the hands of as many developers and companies as possible. Because SaaS Boost is open source software, anyone can help improve it. Through a community of builders, our hope is to develop features faster, integrate with a wide range of SaaS software, and to provide a high quality solution for our customers regardless of company size or location,&#8221; Amazon&#8217;s Adrian De Luca wrote <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/opensource/aws-saas-boost-released-as-open-source/">in a blog post</a> announcing the intent to open source SaaS Boost.</p>
<p>This announcement comes just a couple of weeks after the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/amazon-announces-its-open-sourcing-deep-racer-device-software/">open-sourced its Deep Racer device software</a>, which runs its machine-learning fueled mini race cars. That said, Amazon <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/09/aws-gives-open-source-the-middle-finger/">has had a complex relationship</a> with the open source in the past couple of years, where companies like MongoDB, Elastic and CockroachDB have altered their open-source licenses to prevent Amazon from making their own hosted versions of these software packages.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6DwYvbHDXK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/31/why-aws-is-building-tiny-ai-race-cars-to-teach-machine-learning/">Why AWS is building tiny AI race cars to teach machine learning</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why AWS is building tiny AI race cars to teach machine learning&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/31/why-aws-is-building-tiny-ai-race-cars-to-teach-machine-learning/embed/#?secret=6DwYvbHDXK" data-secret="6DwYvbHDXK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/aws-releases-tool-to-open-source-that-turns-on-prem-software-into-saas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151330</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GasBuddy tops the App Store for the first time due to Colonial Pipeline attack</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/gasbuddy-tops-the-app-store-for-the-first-time-due-to-colonial-pipeline-attack/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/gasbuddy-tops-the-app-store-for-the-first-time-due-to-colonial-pipeline-attack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 20:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colonial pipeline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gasoline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pipeline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The GasBuddy mobile app, which typically helps consumers find the cheapest gas nearby, has now become the No. 1 app on the U.S. App Store for the first time ever, due to the fuel shortages in the U.S. that followed the cyberattack on the Colonial Pipeline. Americans, fearful that gas would become unavailable, began panic-buying [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The <a href="https://www.gasbuddy.com/">GasBuddy</a> mobile app, which typically helps consumers find the cheapest gas nearby, has now become the No. 1 app on the U.S. App Store for the first time ever, due to the fuel shortages in the U.S. that followed the cyberattack on the Colonial Pipeline. Americans, fearful that gas would become unavailable, began panic-buying in ways that haven&#8217;t been seen since the great <a href="https://cnr.ncsu.edu/news/2020/05/coronavirus-toilet-paper-shortage/">toilet paper outage of 2020</a>. As a result,<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/12/business/energy-environment/gas-shortage.html"> thousands of gas stations</a> ran out of fuel entirely. This dramatic situation has greatly benefitted the GasBuddy app, which includes a crowdsourced feature that helps users locate which local stations still have gas for sale.</p>
<p>As of Wednesday afternoon, GasBuddy says the effects of the Colonial Pipeline shutdown are being felt<a href="https://www.gasbuddy.com/go/colonial-pipeline-shutdown-fuel-outages-by-state"> across 11 U.S. states</a>, largely in the Southeast and Washington, D.C. North Carolina had the highest number of gas stations with fuel outages, with 65% of stations reportedly out of gas as of 2:48 p.m. ET on Wednesday. Kentucky has the lowest at only 2%. Because this <a href="https://www.gasbuddy.com/go/colonial-pipeline-shutdown-fuel-outages-by-state">data</a> is self-reported by GasBuddy users, it may not represent the most current information, we should note.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151352" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151352" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2151352" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9254.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9254.png 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9254.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9254.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9254.png?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9254.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9254.png?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9254.png?resize=947,2048 947w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9254.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151352" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> GasBuddy app screenshot</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>During the week, consumers have been turning to GasBuddy to help them find where they can fill up. Yesterday, the app hit No. 1 in the &#8220;Travel&#8221; category on the App Store, while it steadily climbed its way up the App Store&#8217;s Top Overall charts.</p>
<p>This afternoon, GasBuddy became both the No.1 app in the non-games category as well as the highest-ranked app Overall across the U.S. App Store.</p>
<p>According to data from app store intelligence firm Apptopia, GasBuddy yesterday saw 15,203 new downloads &#8212; a 59% increase from its average daily downloads, which were 9,560 for the past 30 days. However, third-party data isn&#8217;t always accurate for sudden shots in rank &#8212; it catches up a few days after the fact.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151326" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151326" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2151326" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/AdKQPr8e.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="329" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/AdKQPr8e.jpg 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/AdKQPr8e.jpg?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/AdKQPr8e.jpg?resize=300,145 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/AdKQPr8e.jpg?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151326" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apptopia</p></div></p>
<p>Reached for comment, GasBuddy says its downloads were actually far higher than the third-party estimates. Across all platforms, including both iOS and Google Play, it saw 20x more downloads yesterday compared with an average day in 2021. The company told TechCrunch it counted 313,001 total downloads yesterday, compared with average daily downloads for the previous 30 days of 15,339.</p>
<p>Broken down by platform, GasBuddy says it saw 104,735 downloads on Android and 208,266 downloads on iOS on Tuesday, May 11, 2021.</p>
<p>Apptopia also noted that GasBuddy hadn&#8217;t been the No. 1 app on the App Store in all the time it&#8217;s been recording app store rankings, which goes back to January 1, 2015. However, it noted the app itself launched back in 2010, making it possible (though not likely) that the app had reached No. 1 at some point.</p>
<p>GasBuddy confirmed that&#8217;s not the case. Today is the first time it has ever topped the App Store, though it got close once before when it reached No. 2 behind a walkie-talkie app <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/07/as-irma-nears-florida-governor-tells-residents-to-use-gas-buddy-expedia-google-maps-more/">during Hurricane Irma in September 2017.</a></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151355" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151355" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2151355" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9255.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9255.png 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9255.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9255.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9255.png?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9255.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9255.png?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9255.png?resize=947,2048 947w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9255.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151355" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Store screenshot on Wed., May 12, 2021</p></div></p>
<p>Consumers can continue to track statewide fuel outages <a href="https://www.gasbuddy.com/go/colonial-pipeline-shutdown-fuel-outages-by-state">here on GasBuddy&#8217;s website</a> as well as <a href="https://fuelinsights.gasbuddy.com/">where highest prices are being found</a>. In the app, they can report whether gas stations have gas or diesel, as well as current prices.</p>
<p>The Colonial Pipeline, which runs 5,500 miles from the Gulf to the Northeast, shut down on Friday due to a ransomware attack from a criminal hacking network known as DarkSide, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/russia-denies-involvement-colonial-pipeline-cyberattack-2021-05-11/">which is suspected to be</a> based in Russia or Eastern Europe. The pipeline delivers <a href="https://apnews.com/article/europe-hacking-government-and-politics-technology-business-b2a867c0705acd953c90d6e2a58fabb9">about 45%</a> of fuel used by the Eastern Seaboard. Reports of the shutdown sent Americans to stock up on gas, worsening the situation further. The U.S. Energy Secretary Jennifer Granholm said the Colonial Pipeline <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/energy-secretary-colonial-pipeline-restored_n_609ad7a0e4b099ba752f7675">intends to restore operations</a> by the end of the week.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fge2eUh3uO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/decrypted-how-bad-was-the-us-capitol-breach-for-cybersecurity/">Decrypted: How bad was the US Capitol breach for cybersecurity?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Decrypted: How bad was the US Capitol breach for cybersecurity?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/decrypted-how-bad-was-the-us-capitol-breach-for-cybersecurity/embed/#?secret=fge2eUh3uO" data-secret="fge2eUh3uO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/gasbuddy-tops-the-app-store-for-the-first-time-due-to-colonial-pipeline-attack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151288</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Waymo to lose its CFO and head of automotive partnerships</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/waymos-cfo-and-head-of-automotive-partnerships-are-leaving-the-autonomous-vehicle-company/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/waymos-cfo-and-head-of-automotive-partnerships-are-leaving-the-autonomous-vehicle-company/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 19:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lidar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waymo&#8217;s chief financial officer Ger Dwyer and its head of automotive partnerships and corporate development Adam Frost — two longtime executives at the autonomous vehicle company — are leaving this month, departures that comes amid some executive shuffling following CEO John Krafcik&#8217;s exit earlier this year. Dwyer and Frost&#8217;s departure was shared internally this week, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Waymo&#8217;s chief financial officer Ger Dwyer and its head of automotive partnerships and corporate development Adam Frost — two longtime executives at the autonomous vehicle company — are leaving this month, departures that comes amid some executive shuffling following CEO John Krafcik&#8217;s exit earlier this year.</p>
<p>Dwyer and Frost&#8217;s departure was shared internally this week, according to multiple sources. Waymo has confirmed to TechCrunch that Dwyer and Frost are leaving.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re grateful to Ger and Adam for all they’ve done for Waymo and wish them all the best,&#8221; a spokesperson said in an emailed statement. &#8220;An executive search is underway for a new CFO to lead us into our next chapter as we continue to build, deploy and commercialize the Waymo Driver.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Dwyer, who reported directly to parent company Alphabet&#8217;s executive leadership finance team, is among several executives who have left the company in the past five months. Krafcik <a href="https://blog.waymo.com/2021/04/capstone-of-my-career-email-from-john.html">announced in April</a> that he was stepping down as CEO. Chief Safety Officer Deborah Hersman left in December and Tim Willis, who was head of manufacturing and global supply and general manager of Waymo&#8217;s Laser Bear lidar business, departed in February. Sherry House, who had been at Waymo since 2017 and was most recently treasurer and head of investor relations, left the company in April. She is now <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/lucid-motors-taps-waymo-intel-veterans-ahead-of-public-listing/">CFO at Lucid Motors</a>.</p>
<p>Still, some of the critical leaders, and the people directly below them, have remained. Tekedra Mawakana, who was COO, and Dmitri Dolgov, the CTO, are now co-CEOs of Waymo and appear to have the support of Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai, according to brief remarks he made during the company&#8217;s first-quarter earnings call. Department heads directly below Mawakana and Dolgov are still at Waymo with a few exceptions, according to LinkedIn profiles. In March, both David Twohig, who was director of Future Automotive at Waymo, and Qi Hommes, who was once head of system safety, left. Hommes is now director of system safety engineering and analysis at Zoox, according to LinkedIn.</p>
<p>Dwyer&#8217;s departure also comes at a time when the demand for CFOs has rocketed alongside the continuous string of public offerings, including those done via mergers with special purpose acquisition companies. House&#8217;s move to Lucid Motors, which is going public via a merger with a SPAC, is one example.</p>
<p>Dwyer is a longtime Google employee, who started at the company in 2006. He made the leap in August 2016 over to Waymo, just a few months before the former Google self-driving project officially announced it had spun out to become a business under parent company Alphabet.</p>
<p>During his tenure, Dwyer oversaw the financial side of the business in a period of explosive growth that took the company from a few hundred employees to more than 2,000 today.</p>
<p>Frost, who headed up automotive partnerships, has also been an important figure at Waymo. He came to Google&#8217;s self-driving project in 2013 after nearly 17 years at Ford Motor Co., according to LinkedIn records. He was initially hired as a chief engineer and then rose through the ranks to chief automotive programs and partnerships officer and eventually chief automotive and corporate development officer. Waymo has locked in a number of what it has described as exclusive partnerships with automakers over the past several years, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/waymo-volvo-partner-to-develop-electric-robotaxis/">including Volvo</a>, Stellantis (formerly FCA), as well as one with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/20/waymo-takes-its-self-driving-car-ambitions-global-in-partnership-with-renault-nissan/">Renault and Nissan</a> to research how commercial autonomous vehicles might work for passengers and packages in France and Japan.</p>
<p>Waymo also expanded its geographic footprint beyond California during both Dwyer and Frost&#8217;s stints. The company brought its autonomous vehicles into cities like Austin and Kirkland, Washington for testing and established operations in the Phoenix suburb of Chandler, where it now operates a ride-hailing service called Waymo One using driverless vehicles as well as those with safety operators behind the wheel.</p>
<p>Last year, Waymo completed its first external round of fundraising, which was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/02/waymo-brings-in-2-25-billion-from-outside-investors-alphabet/">initially $2.25 billion</a> and later <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/waymo-expands-first-external-investment-round-to-3-billion/">expanded to $3 billion</a>. The $2.25 billion round was led by Silver Lake with investments from Canada Pension Plan Investment Board, Mubadala Investment Company, Magna, Andreessen Horowitz and AutoNation and its parent company Alphabet. The extended capital came from new investors, including those managed by T. Rowe Price, Perry Creek Capital, Fidelity Management and Research Company and others.</p>
<p>The external raise followed a flurry of activity that suggested Waymo was ramping up its commercial enterprise, including expanding its core fleet in Mountain View, Calif., the Phoenix area and into Texas. Waymo also began to move beyond its robotaxi testing and began piloting new business applications for its autonomous vehicle technology such as delivery and trucking and even a plan to start selling its custom lidar sensors to companies in the robotics, security and agricultural technology industries.</p>
<p>It has also made numerous partners and at least one acquisition under Dwyer&#8217;s watch. Waymo acquired in December 2019 a U.K. company called Latent Logic that spun out of Oxford University&#8217;s computer science department. The company uses a form of machine learning called imitation learning that could beef up Waymo&#8217;s simulation efforts. The acquisition marked the launch of Waymo&#8217;s first European engineering hub in Oxford, U.K.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nru97aggF3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/automakers-suppliers-and-startups-see-growing-market-for-in-vehicle-ar-vr-applications/">Automakers, suppliers and startups see growing market for in-vehicle AR/VR applications</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Automakers, suppliers and startups see growing market for in-vehicle AR/VR applications&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/automakers-suppliers-and-startups-see-growing-market-for-in-vehicle-ar-vr-applications/embed/#?secret=nru97aggF3" data-secret="nru97aggF3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/waymos-cfo-and-head-of-automotive-partnerships-are-leaving-the-autonomous-vehicle-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151171</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok removes 500k+ accounts in Italy after DPA order to block underage users</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/tiktok-removes-500k-accounts-in-italy-after-dpa-order-to-block-underage-users/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/tiktok-removes-500k-accounts-in-italy-after-dpa-order-to-block-underage-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 19:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[age verification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BEUC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Data Protection Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Video sharing social network TikTok has removed more than 500,000 accounts in Italy following an intervention by the country&#8217;s data protection watchdog earlier this year ordering it to recheck the age of all Italian users and block access to any under the age of 13. Between February 9 and April 21 more than 12.5M Italian [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Video sharing social network TikTok has removed more than 500,000 accounts in Italy following an intervention by the country&#8217;s data protection watchdog <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/">earlier this year</a> ordering it to recheck the age of all Italian users and block access to any under the age of 13.</p>
<p>Between February 9 and April 21 more than 12.5M Italian users were asked to confirm that they are over 13 years old, according to the regulator.</p>
<p>Online age verification remains a hard problem and it&#8217;s not clear how many of the removed accounts definitively belonged to under 13s. The regulator <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9584923">said</a> today that TikTok removed over 500k users because they were &#8220;likely&#8221; to be under the age of 16; around 400,000 because they declared an age under 13 and 140,000 through what the DPA describes as &#8220;a combination of moderation and reporting tools&#8221; implemented within the app.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>TikTok has also agreed to take a series of additional measures to strengthen its ability to detect and block underage users &#8212; including potentially developing AI tools to help it identify when children are using the service.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, TikTok sent us a statement confirming that it is trialling &#8220;additional measures to help ensure that only users aged 13 or over are able to use TikTok&#8221;.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the statement, which TikTok attributed to Alexandra Evans, its head of child safety in Europe:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;TikTok&#8217;s top priority is protecting the privacy and safety of our users, and in particular our younger users. Following continued engagement with the Garante, we will be trialling additional measures to help ensure that only users aged 13 or over are able to use TikTok.</p>
<p>&#8220;We already take industry-leading steps to promote youth safety on TikTok such as setting accounts to private by default for users aged under 16 and enabling parents to link their account to their teen&#8217;s through Family Pairing. There is no finish line when it comes to safety, and we continue to evaluate and improve our policies, processes and systems, and consult with external experts.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Italy&#8217;s data protection regulator made an emergency intervention in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/">January</a> &#8212; ordering TikTok to recheck the age of all users and block any users whose age it could not verify. The action followed reports in local media about a 10-year-old girl from Palermo who died of asphyxiation after participating in a “blackout challenge” on the social network.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GJ2wSDiY6v"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/">TikTok will recheck the age of every user in Italy after DPA order</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok will recheck the age of every user in Italy after DPA order&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/embed/#?secret=GJ2wSDiY6v" data-secret="GJ2wSDiY6v" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Among the beefed up measures TikTok has agreed to take is a commitment to act faster to remove underage users &#8212; with the Italian DPA saying the platform has guaranteed it will cancel reported accounts it verifies as belonging to under 13s within 48 hours.</p>
<p>The regulator said TikTok has also committed to &#8220;study and develop&#8221; solutions &#8212; which may include the use of artificial intelligence &#8212; to &#8220;minimize the risk of children under 13 using the service&#8221;.</p>
<p>TikTok has also agree to launch ad campaigns, both in app and through radio and newspapers in Italy, to raise awareness about safe use of the platform and get the message out that it is not suitable for under-12s &#8212; including targeting this messaging in a language and format that&#8217;s likely to engage underage minors themselves.</p>
<p>The social network has also agreed to share information with the regulator relating to the effectiveness of the various experimental measures &#8212; to work with the regulator to identify the best ways of keeping underage users off the service.</p>
<p>The DPA said it will continue to monitor TikTok&#8217;s compliance with its commitments.</p>
<p>Prior to the Garante&#8217;s action, TikTok&#8217;s age verification checks had been widely criticized as trivially easier for kids to circumvent &#8212; with children merely needing to input a false birth date that suggested they are older than 13 to circumvent the age gate and access the service.</p>
<p>A wider investigation that the DPA opened into TikTok&#8217;s handling and processing of children&#8217;s data last year remains ongoing.</p>
<p>The regulator announced it had begun proceedings against the platform in December 2020, following months of investigation, saying then that it believed TikTok was not complying with EU data protection rules which set stringent requirements for processing children&#8217;s data.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9249681">January</a> the Garante also called for the European Data Protection Board to set up an EU taskforce to investigate concerns about the risks of children&#8217;s use of the platform &#8212; highlighting similar concerns being raised by other agencies in Europe and the U.S.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/tiktok-hit-with-consumer-child-safety-and-privacy-complaints-in-europe/">February</a> the European consumer rights organization, BEUC, also filed a series of complaints against TikTok, including in relation to its handling of kids&#8217; data.</p>
<p>Earlier this year TikTok announced plans to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/tiktok-calls-in-outside-help-with-content-moderation-in-europe/">bring in outside experts in the region</a> to help with content moderation and said it would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/tiktok-to-open-a-transparency-center-in-europe-to-take-content-and-security-questions/">open a &#8216;transparency&#8217; center in Europe</a> where outside experts could get information on its content, security and privacy policies.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sFKpIs8ol0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/">TikTok has until Friday to respond to Italy&#8217;s order to block users it can&#8217;t age-verify after girl&#8217;s death</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok has until Friday to respond to Italy&#8217;s order to block users it can&#8217;t age-verify after girl&#8217;s death&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/embed/#?secret=sFKpIs8ol0" data-secret="sFKpIs8ol0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kLW0EsphR5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/tiktok-calls-in-outside-help-with-content-moderation-in-europe/">TikTok calls in outside help with content moderation in Europe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok calls in outside help with content moderation in Europe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/tiktok-calls-in-outside-help-with-content-moderation-in-europe/embed/#?secret=kLW0EsphR5" data-secret="kLW0EsphR5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LDNArtn0pf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/tiktok-hit-with-consumer-child-safety-and-privacy-complaints-in-europe/">TikTok hit with consumer, child safety and privacy complaints in Europe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok hit with consumer, child safety and privacy complaints in Europe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/tiktok-hit-with-consumer-child-safety-and-privacy-complaints-in-europe/embed/#?secret=LDNArtn0pf" data-secret="LDNArtn0pf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/tiktok-removes-500k-accounts-in-italy-after-dpa-order-to-block-underage-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151250</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>36 hours left to apply to Startup Battlefield at TC Disrupt 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/36-hours-left-to-apply-to-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/36-hours-left-to-apply-to-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neesha A. Tambe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 19:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Battlefield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2149022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do you and your early-stage startup have what it takes to be a modern-day gladiator and compete in Startup Battlefield at TechCrunch Disrupt 2021? You won’t know unless you apply, and time is running out. You have only 48 hours left to throw your helmet into the ring. If you want to compete for glory, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Do you and your early-stage startup have what it takes to be a modern-day gladiator and compete in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/startup-battlefield/">Startup Battlefield</a> at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a>? You won’t know unless you apply, and time is running out. You have only 48 hours left to throw your helmet into the ring.</p>
<p>If you want to compete for glory, global exposure and $100,000 in equity-free prize money, <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/zM4H0xNn">apply to Startup Battlefield here</a> before <strong>May 13 at 11:59 p.m. (PT).</strong></p>
<p>Not familiar with Startup Battlefield? It has launched 922 companies — including the likes of Dropbox, Vurb, Mint and a bunch more — that have collectively raised $9.5 billion and produced 117 exits.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We can tell you what it’s like to compete in Startup Battlefield and about the benefits and opportunities that come from it. But Stacey Hronowski — co-founder and CEO of Canix, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/18/and-the-winner-of-startup-battlefield-at-disrupt-2020-is-canix/#:~:text=Canix,-Lucas%20Matney%40lucasmtny&amp;text=We%20started%20this%20competition%20with,arena%2C%20we%20have%20a%20winner.">winner of Startup Battlefield at Disrupt 2020</a> — describes it best.</p>
<p>“Our experience in Startup Battlefield was excellent. The rigorous training was specific and tailored to our individual business and presentation. I was particularly impressed with the Q&amp;A training. I&#8217;ve fundraised numerous times and the practice questions were some of the most insightful and specific questions I&#8217;ve faced. I feel extremely well prepared for future fundraises.</p>
<p>&#8220;Post Startup Battlefield, we received significant press coverage and reach outs from notable investors. The experience was one of the most special of my life; I never thought I&#8217;d get the chance to share the story of Canix with investors and media across the globe.”</p>
<p>And guess what?! It won’t cost you a thing to apply or to compete. You can be from anywhere in the world and in any industry — but you should have an MVP. Are you detail-oriented? Read more about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/applications-for-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021-are-now-open/">how Startup Battlefield works</a>.</p>
<p>We’re tapping top VC talent to judge the Battlefield. Here are just a few of the experts you’ll need to impress:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/gv-partner-terri-burns-is-joining-us-to-judge-the-startup-battlefield/">Terri Burns</a>, partner at GV</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/shauntel-garvey-of-reach-capital-will-join-us-to-judge-this-years-startup-battlefield/">Shauntel Garvey</a>, general partner at Reach Capital</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/sydney-thomas-is-coming-to-judge-startups-at-disrupt/">Sydney Thomas</a>, principal at Precursor Ventures</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/alexa-von-tobel-will-join-disrupt-2021-as-a-startup-battlefield-judge/">Alexa von Tobel</a>, co-founder and managing partner at Inspired Capita</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> takes place on September 22-23, and if you want a shot at massive exposure and $100,000, you need to <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/zM4H0xNn">apply to Startup Battlefield</a> before the deadline expires — in just 48 hours — on <strong>May 13 at 11:59 p.m. (PT).</strong> Go, gladiators, go!</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZChm9Ky1nu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/">11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/embed/#?secret=ZChm9Ky1nu" data-secret="ZChm9Ky1nu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at Disrupt 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/36-hours-left-to-apply-to-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2149022</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: Does it make sense to sponsor immigrant talent to work remotely?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/dear-sophie-does-it-make-sense-to-sponsor-immigrant-talent-to-work-remotely/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/dear-sophie-does-it-make-sense-to-sponsor-immigrant-talent-to-work-remotely/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 19:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dear Sophie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2150839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My startup is considering individuals who live outside the U.S. for a few positions we are looking to fill. Does it make sense to sponsor them for a visa to work remotely from somewhere in the U.S.?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/dear-sophie-how-does-the-international-entrepreneur-parole-program-work/">Dear Sophie: How does the International Entrepreneur Parole program work?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/dear-sophie-can-i-transfer-my-h-1b-to-a-startup-i-founded/">Dear Sophie: Can I transfer my H-1B to a startup I founded?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>My startup is in big-time hiring mode. All of our employees are currently working remotely and will likely continue to do so for the foreseeable future — even after the pandemic ends. We are considering individuals who are living outside of the U.S. for a few of the positions we are looking to fill. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Does it make sense to sponsor them for a visa to work remotely from somewhere in the United States?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Selective in Silicon Valley</strong></p>
<p>Dear Selective,</p>
<p>Thanks for reaching out &#8212; I’m always happy to hear about another fast-growing startup! If some of your leadership team is also abroad, check out the recent announcement about the new <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/dear-sophie-how-does-the-international-entrepreneur-parole-program-work/">International Entrepreneur Parole program for founders</a>.</p>
<p>It can make great business sense to sponsor international talent for a visa even if the position involves working remotely from a location inside the U.S. With the right legal setup, your team can work from home in Silicon Valley, nearby in California, or in another state where the cost of living is not quite as high. We’ve received this question from many employers, and many of our clients are proceeding with sponsoring international talent with visas and green cards for work-from-home positions.</p>
<p>I discussed this and other issues related to recruiting and work trends with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/katie-lampert-56859389/">Katie Lampert</a> for my <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/070-talent-acquisition-for-startups-with-katie-lampert/">podcast</a>. Lampert leads the talent acquisition and infrastructure group at <a href="https://www.generalcatalyst.com/">General Catalyst</a>, a VC firm that invests in seed to growth-stage startups in the U.S. and abroad. She advises companies in the General Catalyst portfolio on all things talent-related, including establishing company culture, creating a company’s infrastructure for recruiting and retaining talent, and planning for the future.</p>
<p>“Recruiting is going to be more global, which is exciting,” Lampert said during our discussion. “This will have a really positive effect on cultural diversity in the workforce. Studies show that a more diverse workforce leads to greater financial success.”</p>
<p>In fact, the latest McKinsey &amp; Co. report on diversity, “<a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/diversity-and-inclusion/diversity-wins-how-inclusion-matters">Diversity wins: How inclusion matters</a>,” found that companies with ethnically and culturally diverse executive teams are 36% more likely to achieve above-average profitability than companies with less diverse teams. McKinsey has issued three reports on diversity, and with each subsequent report, the business case for ethnic and cultural diversity and gender diversity in corporate leadership has grown stronger.</p>
<p>In addition to boosting profitability, bringing international talent to the United States to join your startup offers a host of other benefits as well.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/dear-sophie-does-it-make-sense-to-sponsor-immigrant-talent-to-work-remotely/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2150839</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Direct-to-consumer orthodontic startup Impress raises $50M to scale across Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/direct-to-consumer-orthodontic-startup-impress-raises-50m-to-scale-across-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/direct-to-consumer-orthodontic-startup-impress-raises-50m-to-scale-across-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 17:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreas Nemeth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barcelona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CareCapital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dentistry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dentists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hillhouse Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael linse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthodontist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portugal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TA Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the famous phrase goes, &#8220;software is eating the world&#8221; &#8212; and now software is eating dentistry. Or, perhaps more accurately, the arena of orthodontics — the specialty of dentistry that deals with things like braces — is slowly but surely being digitalized. To whit, Impress, a Southern European player in direct-to-consumer orthodontics, has raised [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As the famous phrase goes, &#8220;software is eating the world&#8221; &#8212; and now software is eating dentistry. Or, perhaps more accurately, the arena of orthodontics — the specialty of dentistry that deals with things like braces — is slowly but surely being digitalized.</p>
<p>To whit, <a href="https://smile2impress.com/">Impress</a>, a Southern European player in direct-to-consumer orthodontics, has raised a $50 million Series A funding round led by CareCapital (a dental division of Hillhouse Capital in Asia), along with Nickleby Capital, UNIQA Ventures and investors including Michael Linse, Valentin Pitarque, Peter Schiff, Elliot Dornbusch and others. All existing shareholders, such as TA Ventures and Bynd VC, also participated.</p>
<p>Impress is an homage to the direct-to-consumer startups in this area in the U.S., such as SmileDirect, and now plans to scale across Europe from its existing bases in Spain, Italy, Portugal, the U.K. and France.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company was founded in 2019 in Barcelona by orthodontist Dr. Khaled Kasem and serial entrepreneurs Diliara and Vladimir Lupenko.</p>
<p>Speaking from Barcelona, Lupenko told me that the idea was to “combine the best orthodontic tradition with the most innovative technology in the sector.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bdpOQfTdL5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/27/tech-startups-want-to-go-inside-your-mouth/">Tech startups want to go inside your mouth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tech startups want to go inside your mouth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/27/tech-startups-want-to-go-inside-your-mouth/embed/#?secret=bdpOQfTdL5" data-secret="bdpOQfTdL5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As things stand, most of the time, consumers can usually only access cosmetic teeth alignment treatments or orthodontic medical treatments in conventional clinics. The new wave of clinics employs 3D scans and panoramic X-rays to check nerve and bone health.</p>
<p>Impress’s model is to offer these high-quality medical treatments directly to consumers, by developing its own chain of orthodontic clinics, which also put an emphasis on design and a &#8220;modern&#8221; patient experience, it says.</p>
<p>As Diliara Lupenko says: “We didn’t copy what other companies in the space were doing and approached the market from a different angle from the get-go. We doubled down on the doctor-led digital model which brought us way better conversion rates and treatment quality even though on paper it looked complex in the beginning. It&#8217;s still very complex but we were able to crack it and scale exponentially.”</p>
<p>Impress now has 75 clinics in Spain, Italy, the U.K., France and Portugal, which optimize costs and automate key parts of the value chain.</p>
<p>It now says it&#8217;s approaching €50 million in annual run-rate and is projected to grow to €150 million of revenue in 12 months.</p>
<p>Andreas Nemeth, managing partner of UNIQA Ventures GmbH commented: “Impress&#8217;s customer-centric focus, as well as its demonstrated ability to blitzscale, attracted us to the business. Vladimir and his team leverage technology to create a seamless customer journey for invisible orthodontics and optimized their cost structure in a unique way using software.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="H3PFj1YEd0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/06/3-views-on-the-future-of-the-funding-round-story/">Why does TechCrunch cover so many early-stage funding rounds?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why does TechCrunch cover so many early-stage funding rounds?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/06/3-views-on-the-future-of-the-funding-round-story/embed/#?secret=H3PFj1YEd0" data-secret="H3PFj1YEd0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/direct-to-consumer-orthodontic-startup-impress-raises-50m-to-scale-across-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151206</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bird&#8217;s SPAC filing shows scooter-nomics just don&#8217;t fly</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-spac-filing-shows-scooter-nomics-just-doesnt-fly/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-spac-filing-shows-scooter-nomics-just-doesnt-fly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 17:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Extra Crunch Daily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bird]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What drove the company's hugely unprofitable revenues and resulting net losses? Unit economics that were nearly comically destructive.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Scooter unicorn <a href="https://www.bird.co/">Bird</a> is going public, <a href="https://www.bird.co/blog/bird-to-go-public-on-nyse-to-further-mission-of-clean-mobility-access/">per an agreement</a> to merge with a special purpose acquisition company, or SPAC. After rumors and reports circulated for months about an imminent deal, it has finally arrived.</p>
<p>First, a quick overview of the agreement and the players involved: Bird is merging with Switchback II at an implied valuation of $2.3 billion. Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company will lead the deal&#8217;s $160 million in private investment in public equity, or PIPE. Apollo Investment Corp. and MidCap Financial Trust provided an additional $40 million in asset financing. (Disclosure: Apollo is buying TechCrunch&#8217;s parent company.)</p>
<p>Historically &#8212; and based on what we&#8217;re seeing in this fantastical filing &#8212; Bird proved to be a simply awful business. Its results from 2019 and 2020 describe a company with a huge cost structure and unprofitable revenue, <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001829730/000119312521158297/d469014dex994.htm">per filings</a>. After posting negative gross profit in both of the most recent full-year periods, Bird&#8217;s initial model appears to have been defeated by the market.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			What drove the company&#8217;s hugely unprofitable revenues and resulting net losses? Unit economics that were nearly comically destructive.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Some of the numbers Bird shared in its <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001829730/000119312521158297/d469014dex993.htm">investor deck</a> show a business that is growing, in terms of users and geographic footprint. Bird is in 200 cities globally and reports more than 95 million rides to date, and 3 million new riders added during the pandemic. The investor deck also touts year-round positive economics during the COVID-19 era. That all looks positive. But looking into the line-item financials, a different story emerges.</p>
<p>The scooter shop managed to convert a $135.7 million gross loss in 2019 to a smaller gross deficit of $23.5 million in 2020, but it did not manage to shake up its upside-down economics during its full fiscal 2020.</p>
<p><strong>Update</strong>: Bird provided a response to questions about its newer fleet management business and how it expects to stem losses. Their response:</p>
<blockquote>
<div><span id="m_7786247764560253818gmail-docs-internal-guid-6242eab3-7fff-8b98-2d6d-4a4d4aa0e3da">Bird’s history to date has been one of milestones. First was securing product market fit and delivering an eco-friendly way for people to travel in their communities and access opportunities &#8211; education, health and economic. The second milestone focused on unit economics and laying the foundation for a sustainable business. Then came the pandemic, which served as a catalyst for us to identify how to scale in a way that allowed us to be profitable at a ride level. As a result, in H2 2020 our ride profit (after vehicle depreciation) was positive and people are continuing to embrace naturally social distanced eco-friendly options.</span><b><br />
</b></div>
</blockquote>
<div class="yj6qo ajU"></div>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-spac-filing-shows-scooter-nomics-just-doesnt-fly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151114</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok launches a Green Screen Duet feature, tests dedicated &#8216;Topics&#8217; feeds</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/tiktok-launches-a-green-screen-duet-feature-tests-dedicated-topics-feeds/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/tiktok-launches-a-green-screen-duet-feature-tests-dedicated-topics-feeds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 17:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As competition with tech giants heats up, TikTok is rolling out a series of new features to help keep its short-form video app ahead of rivals. The company today announced the launch of a new Green Screen Duet feature, which combines two of TikTok&#8217;s most popular editing tools to allow creators to use another video [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As competition with tech giants heats up, TikTok is rolling out a series of new features to help keep its short-form video app ahead of rivals. The company today <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/green-screen-duet">announced</a> the launch of a new Green Screen Duet feature, which combines two of TikTok&#8217;s most popular editing tools to allow creators to use another video from TikTok as the background in their new video. It also confirmed the test of a new way to discover videos. Called &#8220;Topics,&#8221; these are dedicated interest-based feeds featuring the top, trending videos in a given category.</p>
<p>Green Screen Duet joins an existing set of Duet tools that let creators lay out two videos side-by-side. Today, Duet layouts include &#8220;Left &amp; Right,&#8221; &#8220;React&#8221; and &#8220;Top &amp; Bottom.&#8221; Creators currently use Duets to sing, dance, joke or act alongside another user’s video, react to a video&#8217;s content or even just watch a video from another, sometimes smaller, creator to raise awareness or call attention to its content.</p>
<p>Editing tools like Duet and Stitch are key to what makes TikTok not just a passive video viewing app but, rather, a new type of video-first social network. It&#8217;s also proven so popular, it has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/instagram-officially-launches-remix-on-reels-a-tiktok-duets-like-feature/">since been adopted</a> by Facebook&#8217;s TikTok clone, Instagram Reels, where it&#8217;s known as Remix.<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/snapchat-is-developing-its-own-take-on-tiktok-duets-with-a-new-remix-feature/"> Snapchat has been developing a Remix feature</a> of its own, too.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2151161" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151161" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2151161" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="285" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-2.png 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-2.png?resize=150,63 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-2.png?resize=300,126 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-2.png?resize=768,322 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-2.png?resize=680,285 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-2.png?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151161" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TikTok</p></div></p>
<p>TikTok&#8217;s new Green Screen Duet will now appear as another option alongside the existing layouts, offering users a way to more easily use another video in the background as they record their own video overlaid on top.</p>
<p>This sort of video experience is something TikTok creators already do in a variety of ways. For example, they may capture images or screen recordings, then use other editing tools to create a green screen effect like this. Or they may react to a video using a Stitch instead, as that can be easier. A built-in Green Screen Duet feature simply offers another way to record new videos that include existing videos.</p>
<p>When the feature is used, the Duetted video plays in the background over the new video being recorded. TikTok believes the launch will inspire new formats for creativity and expression, as a result.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PxCDz7v3hq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/as-competition-heats-up-tiktok-announces-six-new-interactive-music-effects-for-creators/">As competition heats up, TikTok announces six new interactive music effects for creators</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As competition heats up, TikTok announces six new interactive music effects for creators&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/as-competition-heats-up-tiktok-announces-six-new-interactive-music-effects-for-creators/embed/#?secret=PxCDz7v3hq" data-secret="PxCDz7v3hq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>TikTok has been busy upgrading its interface to improve recording and discovering new video content in its app in recent weeks, as Facebook, YouTube and Snapchat have tried to reproduce TikTok&#8217;s feature set in their own apps. For instance, TikTok just <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/as-competition-heats-up-tiktok-announces-six-new-interactive-music-effects-for-creators/">launched</a> interactive music features last month in an effort to get ahead.</p>
<p>In another leap, TikTok is also now testing a new Discover page in the app, where instead of only featuring the current trends, as before, it now organizes videos into categories.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151165" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151165" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2151165 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9253.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9253.png 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9253.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9253.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9253.png?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9253.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9253.png?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9253.png?resize=947,2048 947w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9253.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151165" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TikTok</p></div></p>
<p>These categories represent the many areas of interest on TikTok, like gaming, beauty, dance, TV &amp; movies, sports, family, learning and much more. When you tap into any given category, you&#8217;re taken to a feed that includes the community&#8217;s top, trending content. The feeds will be affected by factors like relevance, timeliness and interest, and can help users find new content and creators outside of what their personalized For You page shows.</p>
<p>TikTok confirmed the test has been rolling out in the U.S. over the past few weeks.</p>
<p>The company also is currently testing e-commerce shopping features, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-11/tiktok-begins-testing-in-app-shopping-to-challenge-facebook?sref=gni836kR">where some brands like Hype</a> and Walmart have been given a new &#8220;Shopping&#8221; tab on their TikTok profile where users can shop items, add to cart and then check out without leaving the app. (Walmart enabled its tab during <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/walmart-to-pilot-test-live-streamed-video-shopping-on-tiktok/">its livestream event in December,</a> and it&#8217;s been there ever since.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151168" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151168" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2151168" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9252-1.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9252-1.png 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9252-1.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9252-1.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9252-1.png?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9252-1.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9252-1.png?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9252-1.png?resize=947,2048 947w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9252-1.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151168" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TikTok</p></div></p>
<p>The integration is less elegant than <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/07/instagram-swaps-out-its-activity-tab-for-shop-in-new-global-test/">Instagram&#8217;s Shops</a>, as there&#8217;s not a native, universal cart or integrated payment mechanism. Instead, users are visiting the retailer&#8217;s website directly.</p>
<p>The advances TikTok is making, however, has been paying off in terms of capturing a large Gen Z user base.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/content/more-us-gen-zers-now-use-tiktok-than-instagram">eMarketer</a>, more Gen Z users in the U.S. now use TikTok than Instagram, or 37.3 million monthly active users compared with 33.3 million users, respectively. And by 2023, the firm predicts TikTok will surpass Snapchat in terms of total U.S. users, as well.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lCOIR67Lno"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/tiktok-is-a-marketers-shiny-new-toy-but-how-do-you-optimize-campaigns/">TikTok is a marketer&#8217;s shiny new toy, but how do you optimize campaigns?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok is a marketer&#8217;s shiny new toy, but how do you optimize campaigns?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/tiktok-is-a-marketers-shiny-new-toy-but-how-do-you-optimize-campaigns/embed/#?secret=lCOIR67Lno" data-secret="lCOIR67Lno" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But TikTok&#8217;s global ambitions are impacted not only by its ban in India but also the possibility that creators will find more monetization opportunities on established platforms.</p>
<p>Yesterday, for example, YouTube announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/youtube-announces-a-100m-fund-to-reward-top-youtube-shorts-creators-over-2021-2022/">a $100 million fund for top YouTube Shorts creators</a>, and said it will soon be testing ads on Shorts. That could help creators generate revenue from short-form content, while also converting casual viewers to channel subscribers where there are even more opportunities to monetize. <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/20/snapchat-paying-1-million-a-day-to-video-creators.html">Snapchat</a> and <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-seeks-to-reel-in-tiktok-creators-raising-stakes-in-social-media-rivalry-11595928600">Instagram</a> have also been wooing creators with cash, and ultimately, if creators find they can make more money elsewhere they could shift some of their attention away from TikTok, no matter how many creative new features it adds.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/tiktok-launches-a-green-screen-duet-feature-tests-dedicated-topics-feeds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151135</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Planck, the insurance data analytics platform, raises $20M growth round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/planck-the-insurance-data-analytics-platform-raises-20m-growth-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/planck-the-insurance-data-analytics-platform-raises-20m-growth-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Planck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Planck Data]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2150884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Planck, the AI-based data platform for commercial insurance underwriting, announced today it has raised a $20 million growth round. The funding came from 3L Capital and Greenfield Partners, along with returning investors Team8, Viola Fintech, Arbor Ventures and Eight Roads. This brings the New York-based startup’s total raised to $48 million, including a $16 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2150890" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/570A8822.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2150890" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2150890 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/570A8822.jpg" alt="A group photo of Planck co-founders (from left to right): David Schapiro, CEO Elad Tsur and CTO Amir Cohen" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/570A8822.jpg 3500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/570A8822.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/570A8822.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/570A8822.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/570A8822.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/570A8822.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/570A8822.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/570A8822.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2150890" class="wp-caption-text">Planck co-founders (from left to right): David Schapiro, CEO Elad Tsur and CTO Amir Cohen. Image Credits: Planck</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://planckdata.com/">Planck</a>, the AI-based data platform for commercial insurance underwriting, announced today it has raised a $20 million growth round. The funding came from 3L Capital and Greenfield Partners, along with returning investors Team8, Viola Fintech, Arbor Ventures and Eight Roads.</p>
<p>This brings the New York-based startup’s total raised to $48 million, including a $16 million Series B it announced in June 2020. Planck said it currently works with “dozens of commercial insurance companies in the U.S.,” including more than half of the top-30 insurers. It will use its new funding to build its U.S. team, expand into global markets and add products for new business segments. Ernie Feirer has also joined Planck as its head of U.S. business. He previously held leadership roles at LexisNexis Risk Solutions, building data analytics solutions for property and casualty insurance carriers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XYCyxuTF8h"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/insurance-data-analytics-platform-planck-raises-16-million-series-b/">Insurance data analytics platform Planck raises $16 million Series B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Insurance data analytics platform Planck raises $16 million Series B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/insurance-data-analytics-platform-planck-raises-16-million-series-b/embed/#?secret=XYCyxuTF8h" data-secret="XYCyxuTF8h" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Planck’s database, which includes online images, text, videos, reviews and public records, allows it to give insurance providers real-time information that helps them determine premiums, process claims and give SMEs faster quotes. It covers more than 50 business segments, including restaurants, construction, retail and manufacturing, and can deliver analytics by simply entering a business’ name and address.</p>
<p>For example, if a healthcare business is seeking to buy or renew an insurance policy, Planck can give underwriters information such as the type of equipment used, what kind of drugs it prescribes and the type of surgeries it performs.</p>
<p>In a statement, 3L Capital principal Paige Thacher said, “Commercial carriers and brokers can no longer afford to rely upon traditional data sources as they prospect, assess risk and monitor a small business insured’s changing exposure during the policy life cycle. The new imperative is to leverage AI and machine learning technologies to dynamically harvest business insights from the insured’s digital footprint.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="w2KiU74TIx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/insurtech-startups-are-leveraging-rapid-growth-to-raise-big-money/">Insurtech startups are leveraging rapid growth to raise big money</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Insurtech startups are leveraging rapid growth to raise big money&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/insurtech-startups-are-leveraging-rapid-growth-to-raise-big-money/embed/#?secret=w2KiU74TIx" data-secret="w2KiU74TIx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/planck-the-insurance-data-analytics-platform-raises-20m-growth-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2150884</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don&#8217;t hate on low-code and no-code</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/dont-hate-on-low-code-and-no-code/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/dont-hate-on-low-code-and-no-code/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2150995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You can't dismiss no- and low-code services as a fountain of technical debt and lukewarm dev projects. If you do, the market is kinda saying that you're just elitist and obstinate.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As far as I can tell, low-code and no-code services are rapidly proving that prior models for products as broad as enterprise app creation and AI-powered data analytics were lackluster. My evidence? A mix of public- and private-market low- and no-code companies are putting up impressive results.</p>
<p>The Exchange caught up with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mattcalkins/">Appian CEO Matt Calkins</a> after his enterprise app software company reported its <a href="https://investors.appian.com/news-releases/news-release-details/appian-announces-first-quarter-2021-financial-results">first-quarter performance</a> to discuss the low-code market and what he&#8217;s hearing in customer meetings. To round out our general thesis &#8212; and shore up our somewhat bratty headline &#8212; we&#8217;ve compiled a list of recent low-code and no-code venture capital rounds, of which there are many.</p>
<p>As we&#8217;ll show, the pace at which venture capitalists are putting funds into companies that fall into our two categories is pretty damn rapid, which implies that they are doing well as a cohort. We can infer as much because it has become clear in recent quarters that while today&#8217;s private capital market is stupendous for <em>some</em> startups, it&#8217;s harder than you&#8217;d think for others.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money.  </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>The dividing factor? Signs of impressive present-day traction: Startups that are growing very fast have nearly unlimited access to capital, while those that are growing at merely fast rates are often finding it difficult to find a dance partner.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995214 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>So if we can show that a huge, diverse set of no-code and low-code startups are raising oodles of capital, we can infer something relatively sturdy about market demand for their products. (It also doesn&#8217;t hurt that no-code automation service Zapier is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/zapier-buys-no-code-focused-makerpad-in-its-first-acquisition/">growing like a weed</a> and has reached IPO scale. In other news, Appian just dropped a <a href="https://investors.appian.com/news-releases/news-release-details/appian-unveils-latest-version-appian-low-code-automation">new version of its low-code automation platform</a>, for whatever that is worth.)</p>
<p>First Appian&#8217;s CEO, then a venture capital roundup. This should be fun.</p>
<h2>Public performance</h2>
<p>Briefly, Appian reported $88.9 million in Q1 2021 revenue, of which $39.1 million came from its cloud subscription business. The latter figure rose 38% in the quarter compared to the year-ago period. Appian also swung to adjusted EBITDA profit in the period. Investors responded by hammering the company&#8217;s stock in the wake of the results. From an April share-price range in the mid-$130s, Appian is now trading in the mid-$80s, though only some of those declines came post-earnings.</p>
<p>But the company&#8217;s stock price is only so important. Precisely how conservative any one public company&#8217;s guidance is for the current year and how those forecasts play with investor expectations during a period of generally excessive valuations is not our game. What does matter is what the company&#8217;s CEO had to say about the low-code space itself.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/dont-hate-on-low-code-and-no-code/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2150995</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India offers $2.46B incentive to boost domestic production of batteries</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/india-approves-incentive-to-boost-domestic-production-of-batteries-advanced-energy-storage/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/india-approves-incentive-to-boost-domestic-production-of-batteries-advanced-energy-storage/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151128</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India&#8217;s cabinet on Wednesday approved Department of Heavy Industry&#8217;s proposal to provide incentives to boost domestic production of batteries with advanced energy storage, the latest in a series of efforts by New Delhi to make the world’s second-largest internet market less reliant on other nations for various electronics goods and shrink its trade deficit. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India&#8217;s cabinet on Wednesday approved Department of Heavy Industry&#8217;s proposal to provide incentives to boost domestic production of batteries with advanced energy storage, the latest in a series of efforts by New Delhi to make the world’s second-largest internet market less reliant on other nations for various electronics goods and shrink its trade deficit.</p>
<p>The government’s new $2.46 billion plan, dubbed “National Programme on Advanced Chemistry Cell (ACC) Battery Storage,” is aimed at cutting the nation’s import volume, said Prakash Javadekar, India’s Minister of Heavy Industry and Public Enterprises, in a news conference.</p>
<p>“All the demand of the ACCs is currently being met through imports in India. The National Programme on Advanced Chemistry Cell (ACC) Battery Storage will reduce import dependence,” the ministry <a href="https://pib.gov.in/PressReleasePage.aspx?PRID=1717938">said in a statement</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The government, which said it will conduct a transparent competitive bidding process and disburse incentives over a course of five years, aims to achieve the manufacturing capacity of 50 GWh of ACC and 5 GWh of “Niche” ACC, it said.</p>
<p>The ministry said the firms that are granted the incentives will be expected to set up manufacturing facilities in India, conduct research and development to achieve high energy sensitive and cycles, invest around $6.1 billion in ACC battery storage manufacturing projects and facilitate demand creation for battery storage in the country.</p>
<p>The initiative will also help bring down the &#8220;oil import bill and help in earning green energy credentials. Besides powering electric vehicles, it will also generate clean energy for domestic consumption,&#8221; said Manish Sharma, chair FICCI Energy Storage Committee and CEO of Panasonic India, in a statement.</p>
<p>“The manufacturing of ACCs will facilitate demand for EVs [Electric Vehicles], which are proven to be significantly less polluting. As India pursues an ambitious renewable energy agenda, the ACC program will be a key contributing factor to reduce India&#8217;s GreenHouse Gas (GHG) emissions, which will be in line with India&#8217;s commitment to combat climate change,” the ministry said.</p>
<p>Wednesday&#8217;s announcement follows similar incentives New Delhi has approved in recent quarters. In February, India <a href="https://www.techmeme.com/210224/p13#a210224p13">approved a $1 billion plan</a> to boost local manufacturing and exports of laptops, tablets and PCs. In October, India <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/india-approves-apple-partners-and-samsung-for-143-billion-smartphone-manufacturing-plan/">offered smartphone manufacturers incentives of 4% to 6%</a> over five years on sales of some products made in India. Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-india-semiconductor-exclusive-idUSKBN2BN12J">reported</a> earlier this year that India was also considering giving cash incentives of more than $1 billion to each firm that sets up a chip fabrication unit in the country.</p>
<p>The nation, whose economy has been hit hard by the pandemic, has in recent years tried a combination of tariffs and perks to persuade companies to produce more in India, which also creates local jobs.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1gBzna5BVw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/zomato-juice-indian-unicorns-proposed-ipo-could-drive-regional-startup-liquidity/">Zomato juice: Indian unicorn&#8217;s proposed IPO could drive regional startup liquidity</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zomato juice: Indian unicorn&#8217;s proposed IPO could drive regional startup liquidity&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/zomato-juice-indian-unicorns-proposed-ipo-could-drive-regional-startup-liquidity/embed/#?secret=1gBzna5BVw" data-secret="1gBzna5BVw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/india-approves-incentive-to-boost-domestic-production-of-batteries-advanced-energy-storage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151128</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ahead of Dell&#8217;s spin out, VMware appoints longtime exec Raghu Raghuram as its new CEO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/ahead-of-dells-spin-out-vmware-appoints-longtime-exec-raghu-raghuram-as-its-new-ceo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/ahead-of-dells-spin-out-vmware-appoints-longtime-exec-raghu-raghuram-as-its-new-ceo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vmware]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151047</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Five months after it was announced that Pal Gelsinger would be stepping down as CEO of VMware to take the top job at Intel, the virtualization giant has finally appointed a permanent successor. Raghu Raghuram &#8212; a longtime employee of the company &#8212; has been appointed the new CEO. He will be taking on the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Five months after it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/pat-gelsinger-stepping-down-as-vmware-ceo-to-replace-bob-swan-at-intel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that Pal Gelsinger would be stepping down as CEO of VMware to take the top job at Intel, the virtualization giant has finally appointed a permanent successor. Raghu Raghuram &#8212; a longtime employee of the company &#8212; has been <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210512005362/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">appointed the new CEO.</a> He will be taking on the new role on June 1. Until then, CFO Zane Rowe will continue in the role in the interim.</p>
<p>Raghuram has been with the company for 17 years in a variety of roles, most recently COO of products and cloud services. He&#8217;s also held positions at the company overseeing areas like data centers and VMware&#8217;s server business. Putting a veteran at the helm sends a clear message that VMware has picked someone clearly dedicated to the company and its culture. No drama here.</p>
<p>Indeed, the move is coming at a time when there is already a lot of other change underway and speaks to the company looking for stability and continuity to lead it through that. About a month ago, Dell <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/dell-is-spinning-out-vmware-in-a-deal-expected-to-generate-over-9b-for-the-company/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> long-anticipated news that it would be spinning out its stake in VMware in a deal that&#8217;s expected to bring Dell at least $9 billion &#8212; putting to an end a financial partnership that initially kicked off with an eye-watering <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/07/67-billion-dell-emc-deal-becomes-official-today/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquisition of EMC in 2016</a>. That partnership will not end the strategic relationship, however, which is set to continue and now Raghuram will be in charge of building and leading.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Lb37i2XFro"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/dell-is-spinning-out-vmware-in-a-deal-expected-to-generate-over-9b-for-the-company/">Dell is spinning out VMware in a deal expected to generate over $9B for the company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dell is spinning out VMware in a deal expected to generate over $9B for the company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/dell-is-spinning-out-vmware-in-a-deal-expected-to-generate-over-9b-for-the-company/embed/#?secret=Lb37i2XFro" data-secret="Lb37i2XFro" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>For that reason, you might look at this as a deal nodded through significantly by Dell.</p>
<p>“I am thrilled to have Raghu step into the role of CEO at VMware. Throughout his career, he has led with integrity and conviction, playing an instrumental role in the success of VMware,” said Michael Dell, chairman of the VMware board of directors, in a statement. “Raghu is now in position to architect VMware’s future, helping customers and partners accelerate their digital businesses in this multicloud world.”</p>
<p>Raghuram has not only been the person overseeing some of VMware&#8217;s biggest divisions and newer areas like software-defined networking and cloud computing, but he&#8217;s had a central role in building and driving strategy for the company&#8217;s core virtualization business, been involved with M&amp;A and, as VMware points out, &#8220;key in driving partnerships with Dell Technologies,&#8221; among other partners.</p>
<p>“VMware is uniquely poised to lead the multicloud computing era with an end-to-end software platform spanning clouds, the data center and the edge, helping to accelerate our customers’ digital transformations,” said Raghuram in a statement. “I am honored, humbled and excited to have been chosen to lead this company to a new phase of growth. We have enormous opportunity, we have the right solutions, the right team and we will continue to execute with focus, passion and agility.”</p>
<p>The company also took the moment to update on guidance for its Q1 results, which will be coming out on May 27. Revenues are expected to come in at $2.994 billion, up 9.5% versus the same quarter a year ago. Subscription and SaaS and license revenue, meanwhile, is expected to be $1.387 billion, up 12.5%. GAAP net income per diluted share is expected to be $1.01 per diluted share, and non-GAAP net income per diluted share is expected to be $1.76 per diluted share, it said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fcO48u3bSp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/18/once-vmware-is-free-from-dell-who-might-fancy-buying-it/">Once VMware is free from Dell, who might fancy buying it?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Once VMware is free from Dell, who might fancy buying it?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/18/once-vmware-is-free-from-dell-who-might-fancy-buying-it/embed/#?secret=fcO48u3bSp" data-secret="fcO48u3bSp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/ahead-of-dells-spin-out-vmware-appoints-longtime-exec-raghu-raghuram-as-its-new-ceo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151047</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cisco to acquire Indy startup Socio to bring hybrid events to Webex</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/cisco-to-acquire-indy-startup-socio-to-bring-hybrid-events-to-webex/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/cisco-to-acquire-indy-startup-socio-to-bring-hybrid-events-to-webex/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Socio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cisco announced this morning that it intends to acquire Indianapolis-based startup Socio, which helps plan hybrid in-person and virtual events. The two companies did not share the purchase price. Socio provides a missing hybrid event management component for the company to add to its Webex platform. The goal appears to be to combine this with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://cisco.com">Cisco</a> announced this morning that it intends to acquire Indianapolis-based startup <a href="https://socio.events/">Socio</a>, which helps plan hybrid in-person and virtual events. The two companies did not share the purchase price.</p>
<p>Socio provides a missing hybrid event management component for the company to add to its Webex platform. The goal appears to be to combine this with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/cisco-acquires-slido-to-improve-qa-polls-and-engagement-in-webex-videoconferencing/">the recent purchase of Slido</a> and transform Webex from an application mostly for video meetings into a more comprehensive event platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;As part of Cisco Webex’s vision to deliver inclusive, engaging and intelligent meeting and event experiences, the acquisition of Socio Labs complements Cisco’s recent acquisition of Slido, an industry-leading audience engagement tool, which together will create a comprehensive, cost-effective and easy-to-use event management solution [ … ],&#8221; the company explained in a statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The impact of the pandemic was not lost on Cisco, and it&#8217;s clear that as we can foresee going back to live events, having the ability to combine it with a virtual experience means that you can open up your event to a much wider audience beyond those who can attend in person. That&#8217;s likely not something that&#8217;s going away, even after we get past COVID.</p>
<p>Jeetu Patel, SVP and GM for security and collaboration at Cisco says that the future of work is going to be hybrid, whether it&#8217;s for work meetings or larger events and Cisco is making this acquisition to expand the use cases for the Webex platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;Whether it’s a 1:1 call, a small team huddle, a group meeting or a large external event, we want to remove friction and help people engage with each other in an inclusive manner. Slido allows for every voice to be heard — even when you’re not talking. Socio allows for getting your voice heard by a large number of people,&#8221; Patel said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HplQvUqKWl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/indy-vc-firm-sixty8-capital-launches-20m-fund-aimed-at-underrepresented-founders/">Indy VC firm Sixty8 Capital launches $20M fund aimed at underrepresented founders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Indy VC firm Sixty8 Capital launches $20M fund aimed at underrepresented founders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/indy-vc-firm-sixty8-capital-launches-20m-fund-aimed-at-underrepresented-founders/embed/#?secret=HplQvUqKWl" data-secret="HplQvUqKWl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>And the company believes that Webex provides the platform to make it all happen. &#8220;It’s a really potent combination of technology to make human interactions more engaging, no matter the type of conversation,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Brent Leary, founder and principal analyst at CRM Essentials, says that it&#8217;s a smart move to take advantage of the changing events landscape and that this acquisition helps make Cisco a serious player in this space.</p>
<p>&#8220;As we get closer to a post-pandemic world, the need to create hybrid event experiences is going to quickly accelerate as people start venturing out to attend physical events. So having an event stack that combines local event support/participation with tools to integrate a broader virtual audience will be the future of event management,&#8221; Leary told me.</p>
<p>Socio was founded in 2016 and raised around $7 million in investment capital, according to Crunchbase data. It has a prestigious list of enterprise customers that includes Microsoft, Google, Jet Blue, Greenpeace, PepsiCo and Hyundai.</p>
<p>The deal is expected to close in Q4 of FY2021. When it does close, Socio&#8217;s 135 employees will be joining Cisco. The plan is to incorporate Socio&#8217;s tooling into the Webex platform while allowing it to continue as a stand-alone product, according to a Cisco spokesperson.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TWnUhNGqC5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/for-ma-success-tap-legal-early-and-often/">How to make sure your legal team is M&#038;A ready</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to make sure your legal team is M&#038;A ready&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/for-ma-success-tap-legal-early-and-often/embed/#?secret=TWnUhNGqC5" data-secret="TWnUhNGqC5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="B9kJ1BtCQy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/cisco-acquires-slido-to-improve-qa-polls-and-engagement-in-webex-videoconferencing/">Cisco is buying Slido to improve Q&#038;A, polls and engagement in WebEx videoconferencing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cisco is buying Slido to improve Q&#038;A, polls and engagement in WebEx videoconferencing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/cisco-acquires-slido-to-improve-qa-polls-and-engagement-in-webex-videoconferencing/embed/#?secret=B9kJ1BtCQy" data-secret="B9kJ1BtCQy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/cisco-to-acquire-indy-startup-socio-to-bring-hybrid-events-to-webex/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151106</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fiveable makes first acquisition: A virtual study tool built by a 16-year-old</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/fiveable-hours-acquisition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/fiveable-hours-acquisition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amanda DoMaral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calix huang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiveable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hours]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fiveable, an online learning community for high school students, made its first-ever acquisition earlier this week: Hours, a virtual study platform built by a 16-year-old. The terms of the deal were not disclosed. Fiveable is a free, online learning community for high school students with the focus of helping them pass Advanced Placement (AP) exams. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://fiveable.me/">Fiveable</a>, an online learning community for high school students, made its first-ever acquisition earlier this week: Hours, a virtual study platform built by a 16-year-old. The terms of the deal were not disclosed.</p>
<p>Fiveable is a free, online learning community for high school students with the focus of helping them pass Advanced Placement (AP) exams. It livestreams 5-hour “cram shops” focused on a specific subject, creates study guides and manages a Discord with thousands of students.</p>
<p>“Students have Discord servers, they have subreddits, they have group chats and it&#8217;s happening informally on some of these different platforms,” founder<a href="https://twitter.com/AmandaDoAmanda"> Amanda DoAmaral</a> said in March. “But we need a central place where social learning happens, where students get support, where they can find each other, where they can build toward their goals.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>She estimates that half a million students use Fiveable on a monthly basis — and it’s just so fitting that her company’s first acquisition came from paying attention to those same users.</p>
<p>She noticed students within the Fiveable community were using Hours a few months ago to host group study sessions. Hours allows students to create study sessions where each person has a task list and shared timer and playlist, which she describes as “a multiplayer experience“ that can increase motivation and accountability. There’s also a single-player experience version where students can pick “focus mode” and remove chat and highlight task lists.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151084" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151084" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2151084" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Hours-tasks.png" alt="" width="1024" height="418" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Hours-tasks.png 1883w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Hours-tasks.png?resize=150,61 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Hours-tasks.png?resize=300,122 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Hours-tasks.png?resize=768,313 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Hours-tasks.png?resize=680,277 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Hours-tasks.png?resize=1536,626 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Hours-tasks.png?resize=50,20 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151084" class="wp-caption-text">Task display. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Hours</p></div></p>
<p>Put simply, Fiveable will be able to expand its community feel from an active Discord to a study-specific tool. In its six months as a product, Hours has been used by more than 17,000 students from schools including Stanford University, MIT, NYU and over 120 countries.</p>
<p>“The experience of studying in Discord text or audio chats is similar to the Hours multiplayer mode, but there isn&#8217;t a way in Discord to keep track of tasks or see everyone&#8217;s progress,” she said. “Hours is a better experience because it allows more flexibility within the group version of a study session and has the ability for students to study solo,” she said.</p>
<p>The startup decided to buy the platform rather than try to build the technology itself for two reasons: Students already love the product and it was built by a “very impressive 16-year-old,” Calix Huang.</p>
<p>Huang, a high school junior in the Bay Area with previous tech acquisitions and startups under his belt, founded Hours in October 2020 in response to the siloed experience of studying during a pandemic. As part of Fiveable&#8217;s acquisition, Huang will join its team as a lead product manager to work on Hours part time.</p>
<p>“Calix will be a senior next year, so he will come on part time until he graduates. Then he&#8217;ll have big decisions like the rest of his peers about what he will do next, which includes an offer to come on full time,” DoAmaral said. Employing young talent isn’t new for the startup: Over 118 paid students work on Fiveable staff right now across all teams, from social to product to content. Every student works 5-10 hours per week as a part-time job and Fiveable pays them $15-$23 per hour.</p>
<p>Fiveable plans to keep Hours as a free service along with its guides, trivia and Discord. The company makes money in two ways right now: $25 for a cram-pass or $5 for live events, such as a 5-hour review the night before an exam. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The startup has raised more than $3.5 million in known venture capital to date, from investors including Matchstick Ventures, Cream City Venture Capital, Spero Ventures and, most recently, Tennis legend Serena Williams. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zieXFRklya"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/edtech-zoom-university/">Tired of &#8216;Zoom University&#8217;? So is edtech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tired of &#8216;Zoom University&#8217;? So is edtech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/edtech-zoom-university/embed/#?secret=zieXFRklya" data-secret="zieXFRklya" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/fiveable-hours-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151002</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Qualcomm won’t be exhibiting in-person at MWC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/qualcomm-wont-be-exhibiting-in-person-at-mwc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/qualcomm-wont-be-exhibiting-in-person-at-mwc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mwc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mwc 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another major name in mobile has confirmed that it won’t be exhibiting at Mobile World Congress in Barcelona. Chip giant Qualcomm is joining a list that already includes Google, IBM, Nokia, Sony, Oracle, Ericsson and, most recently, Samsung and Lenovo. In a statement offered to TechCrunch, a spokesperson for the company confirmed that it will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Another major name in mobile has confirmed that it won’t be exhibiting at Mobile World Congress in Barcelona. Chip giant Qualcomm is joining a list that already includes Google, IBM, Nokia, Sony, Oracle, Ericsson and, most recently, Samsung and Lenovo.</p>
<p>In a statement offered to TechCrunch, a spokesperson for the company confirmed that it will be a taking a similar approach as many of the others, opting to “attend” virtually.</p>
<p>“While we appreciate the health and safety measures being put into place by the GSMA for MWC Barcelona, we have decided that it is in the best interest of our employees and customers for Qualcomm’s participation to be virtual this year,” the company said. “We look forward to engaging with the ecosystem through Cristiano Amon’s virtual keynote on June 28th and through our latest announcements and 5G demonstrations.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ohlD5ZUCeb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/samsung-withdraws-from-in-person-mwc/">Samsung withdraws from in-person MWC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Samsung withdraws from in-person MWC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/samsung-withdraws-from-in-person-mwc/embed/#?secret=ohlD5ZUCeb" data-secret="ohlD5ZUCeb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>There are shades of the lead-up to last year’s event, which similarly found companies opting out, one by one. Ultimately the show’s governing body, the GSMA, pulled the plug. Of course, things are different in 2021. After nearly a year and a half, there are fewer unknowns and a vaccination rollout has begun in much of the world.</p>
<p>But there are still plenty of reasons for people and companies to take a cautious approach when it comes to flying around the world and attending an event in a potentially packed room. Ultimately, it&#8217;s probably not worth the perceived risk or discomfort of staff.</p>
<p>For these reasons and more, it’s hard to blame companies like Qualcomm. Given what we know, it seems unlikely that the organization would pull the plug entirely at this late stage, but things look increasingly dependent on the virtual aspect of the show’s hybrid approach. It also seems possible that the in-person trade will be forever changed after the events of the past two years.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vnimJjgfZx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/lenovo-wont-be-attending-mwc-in-person-either/">Lenovo won’t be attending MWC in person, either</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lenovo won’t be attending MWC in person, either&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/lenovo-wont-be-attending-mwc-in-person-either/embed/#?secret=vnimJjgfZx" data-secret="vnimJjgfZx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ohlD5ZUCeb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/samsung-withdraws-from-in-person-mwc/">Samsung withdraws from in-person MWC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Samsung withdraws from in-person MWC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/samsung-withdraws-from-in-person-mwc/embed/#?secret=ohlD5ZUCeb" data-secret="ohlD5ZUCeb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="n8PVc7ZqOD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/apples-first-virtual-wwdc-keynote-set-a-new-standard-for-remote-presentations/">Apple’s first virtual WWDC keynote set a new standard for remote presentations</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple’s first virtual WWDC keynote set a new standard for remote presentations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/apples-first-virtual-wwdc-keynote-set-a-new-standard-for-remote-presentations/embed/#?secret=n8PVc7ZqOD" data-secret="n8PVc7ZqOD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/qualcomm-wont-be-exhibiting-in-person-at-mwc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151071</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The truth about SDK integrations and their impact on developers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/the-truth-about-sdk-integrations-and-their-impact-on-developers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/the-truth-about-sdk-integrations-and-their-impact-on-developers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Marketing Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software development]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2149084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the app ecosystem rapidly expands beyond the borders of mobile, app developers and publishers would benefit immensely from identifying economical and secure ways of adopting more SDKs.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Ken Harlan</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/MobileFuse">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kenharlan/">Ken Harlan</a> is the founder and CEO of <a href="https://mobilefuse.com/">MobileFuse</a>, a U.S.-based. in-app advertising and DOOH platform that serves leading organizations across retail, food and beverage, restaurant, tourism, government, and healthcare.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The digital media industry often talks about how much influence, dominance and power entities like Google and Facebook have. Generally, the focus is on the vast troves of data and audience reach these companies tout. However, there’s more beneath the surface that strengthens the grip these companies have on both app developers and publishers alike.</p>
<p>In reality, software development kit (SDK) integrations are a critical component of why these monolith companies have such a prominent presence. For reference, an SDK is a set of software development tools, libraries, code samples, processes and guides that help developers create or enhance the apps they’re building.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Through a digital marketing lens, SDKs provide in-app analytics, insights on campaign testing, attribution information, location details, monetization capabilities and more.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Through a digital marketing lens, SDKs provide in-app analytics, insights on campaign testing, attribution information, location details, monetization capabilities and more. In the case of companies like Google and Facebook, their ability to provide these insights dovetails with their data and reach.</p>
<p>While that does deliver useful capabilities to developers and publishers alike, it also perpetuates the factors contributing to their perceived monopolistic status &#8212; and the detriments a lack of competition fosters.</p>
<p>Almost all (90%) ad-monetized Android apps have Google’s Admob SDK integrated, <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1035623/leading-mobile-app-ad-network-sdks-android/">data from Statista showed</a>. Additionally, the Facebook Audience Network SDK is present in 19% of all global Android apps utilizing mobile ads. It’s worth noting that the large majority of alternative “leading” advertising SDKs outside these two players are used less than 13% of the time in Android apps.</p>
<p>As the app ecosystem rapidly expands beyond the borders of mobile, app developers and publishers would benefit immensely from identifying economical and secure ways of adopting more SDKs.</p>
<h2>The state of SDK adoption</h2>
<p>While there are many SDKs available in the market today, a few key factors contribute to Google and Facebook’s overall dominance. The most basic is around the respective organizations’ reach and industry notoriety. However, a larger component here is the lack of resources and time app developers have.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/the-truth-about-sdk-integrations-and-their-impact-on-developers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2149084</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
