<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 13:04:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Draft.dev CEO Karl Hughes on the importance of using experts in developer marketing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/draft-dev-ceo-karl-hughes-on-the-importance-of-using-experts-in-developer-marketing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/draft-dev-ceo-karl-hughes-on-the-importance-of-using-experts-in-developer-marketing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 13:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer relations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2181393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Developer marketing came up in our conversation with strategic marketing firm MKT1, so we called on content marketing production company Draft.dev's CEO Karl Hughes to learn more.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Developers can be a tough crowd. They typically hate being marketed to and are often short on time, which sets a particularly high bar for any content marketing aimed at them.</p>
<p>Coming up with relevant content that developers find interesting takes specific know-how, and this is where <a href="https://draft.dev/">Draft.dev</a> comes in. Its Chicago-based founder and CEO <a href="https://www.karllhughes.com/">Karl Hughes</a> describes the firm as &#8220;a superniche content marketing production company, producing technical content for companies that want to reach software engineers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hughes and his agency were recommended multiple times in our growth marketer survey, which we launched to surface experts that startups can work with. (If you have your own recommendation, please <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">fill out the survey</a>!) One of the survey respondents noted that developers are underrated as a target audience: It may be niche, but it is a large one. More importantly, they are an audience a growing number of startups need to reach.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			&#8220;If you are going to have subject matter experts write, you also need to have good editors to work with them.&#8221;					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Developer marketing came up in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/mkt1-developer-marketing-is-what-startup-marketing-should-look-like/">our conversation with strategic marketing firm MKT1</a>, so we called on Hughes to learn more. Our discussion covered a lot of ground, from what he has learned and his ambitions to Draft.dev&#8217;s process.</p>
<p><em>Editor&#8217;s note: The interview below has been edited for length and clarity:</em></p>
<p><b>What kind of clients does Draft.dev work with?</b></p>
<p><strong>Karl Hughes: </strong>Almost all of our clients are developer tools companies. Mostly Series A- and Series B-funded, so they have got some funding and some knowledge that content marketing works for their audience. What they are trying to do with us is scale production and make sure that what they are writing is going to resonate with developers.</p>
<p><b>What inspired you to create Draft.dev?</b></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been a software developer, and then most recently was a CTO at a startup in Chicago, so I knew that there were lots of companies trying to reach developers [ … ] and that a lot of them were doing a poor job of it. So last year I wanted to combine my tech knowledge with writing knowledge, and that&#8217;s where Draft.dev came from — and it&#8217;s been awesome!</p>
<p>We get to work both with technical and non-technical marketing and developer relations people to help them get more content out. And even though it&#8217;s marketing content, it&#8217;s super focused on education, because developer marketing is a bit tricky. Developers can be a bit skeptical of marketing, so you have to be nuanced in your approach. You have to be genuinely helpful, so we really try to focus on helpful content that is also a net positive for the client.</p>
<p><b>What are some mistakes that you see companies making when creating content for developers?</b></p>
<p>There are a couple of big challenges that Draft.dev is specifically built to solve: Relying too much on your own team to create content when they are busy and have other priorities, and thinking that you can just get your general copywriting agency to cover developer topics. It usually doesn&#8217;t work well.</p>
<p>Many companies start off getting their engineers to write content and make the mistake of thinking this will work forever. Let&#8217;s say you&#8217;re a continuous integration tool and you want to write content that shows developers how your tool works and that it&#8217;s a good option. Marketing teams will go to developers and say: &#8220;Hey, could you guys write a blog post?&#8221; And they&#8217;ll usually get a few blog posts here and there, but it&#8217;s really hard to build consistent content when these engineers are building the product and have production deadlines to hit.</p>
<p>When you look at companies that have done developer marketing really successfully, like Okta and DigitalOcean, you see that they have dedicated teams to produce this content. There&#8217;s a reason for that: It&#8217;s almost impossible to get your engineers to write everything that you need to produce high-quality and consistent content over time.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4tMmvMG8bm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/okta-launches-a-new-free-developer-plan/">Okta launches a new free developer plan</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Okta launches a new free developer plan&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/okta-launches-a-new-free-developer-plan/embed/#?secret=4tMmvMG8bm" data-secret="4tMmvMG8bm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The other big mistake that I see companies making is thinking that a general marketing writer or SEO copywriter can write great content for developers. That is super rare. I mean, I&#8217;ve probably met two or three who can do a decent job of making it look like they know enough to speak with some authority. In general, you either want somebody — either at your company or otherwise — who knows the tool.</p>
<p>So for example, if I ask a general SEO copywriter, &#8220;Could you write about how to write a SQL query that does X, Y and Z?&#8221;, maybe they can hack some other articles together and come up with something, but it&#8217;s certainly not going to have the authority that a real software developer has.</p>
<p>This is true in any area where you have to rely on subject matter experts to help you with marketing content, but because my background is in development, I knew that this was a huge problem for companies.</p>
<p><b>How does Draft.dev address that?</b></p>
<p>We are definitely not right for every company. But for companies that are looking to scale-up content production and have technical authority behind those pieces, that&#8217;s where we come in. Typically, these are companies that know they want to do developer content, but are stretched too thin on their engineering team or they have tried freelancers and have a really hard time managing them and keeping quality consistent. So they come to us to do that.</p>
<p>We solve that problem with a huge pool of software developers who write for us on the side. Right now we have about 50 or 60 active monthly writers who are all software developers; they work full-time jobs and do this at night and on weekends. We bring people who are actually in the field, doing these things every day. They bring that technical expertise to the articles that we create for clients.</p>
<p>The mutually beneficial aspect here is that while we obviously pay these writers, they also get a byline out on the client&#8217;s site. We don&#8217;t do a lot of ghostwriting, which is a little unique, but is really good for our style of content because you want to show subject matter expertise. It&#8217;s preferable when you don&#8217;t have your head of marketing listed as the author of every piece of developer content. It&#8217;s nice to have a byline by a real software developer.</p>
<p>All of this goes back to what your content strategy is and who you want to reach. This is not blanket advice for everybody, but for companies trying to reach developers who are writing code every day, I think it&#8217;s super helpful to have some technical authority from people actually doing this.</p>
<p><b>How do you make sure your writers have subject matter expertise?</b></p>
<p>We have a writer vetting and selection process. Once we have vetted the writers who have applied, we also look for the best match for each article. We are looking through their skills and past experience to see who&#8217;d be the best fit.</p>
<p>We also recruit specific writers to write about niche topics. Sometimes that means doing cold outreach; sometimes it means going through our networks and figuring out who we know who&#8217;s written about Rust before. Things like that can be really tricky and time-consuming for a marketing team to do, but because we are doing this full time for lots of clients, we can spread that work around. It makes a lot of sense, and our clients like that we do this for them.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CWRfqsYS4l"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/cockroachdb-ec1-developers/">“Developers, as you know, do not like to pay for things”</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;“Developers, as you know, do not like to pay for things”&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/cockroachdb-ec1-developers/embed/#?secret=CWRfqsYS4l" data-secret="CWRfqsYS4l" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><b>How to you balance your writers&#8217; technical expertise versus writing skills?</b></p>
<p>That is tough! But there are some best practices in this field. If you are going to have subject matter experts write, you also need to have good editors to work with them.</p>
<p>There are two sides to how we get high-quality content from software engineers who may be average writers when they start, and are often ESL speakers. The upfront part is that we plan content pretty thoroughly. We go back and forth with the content to make sure we know what we are producing, and we also have technical content planners who make sure that each article has a story, an outline and lot of structure before we give it to a writer.</p>
<p>The writer fills in the technical details and personal experience, and then every piece will go through three rounds of edits to get it up to our standards: a technical review; a developmental edit for things like structure and flow, and a copy edit.</p>
<p><b>How do you split these tasks?</b></p>
<p>We&#8217;ve refined this process a lot since starting this [in May 2020]. Initially, it was just me and my managing editor Chris [Wolfgang] — she had a lot of experience in editing, so she could do full-stack editing, and I was focused on writing, picking writers, reviewing, etc. That&#8217;s how we divided things in the early days, but as we grew, we realized that we wouldn&#8217;t find an army of Chrises and Karls.</p>
<p>We had to figure out how to split these jobs into specialities where people can do their best work, and that&#8217;s how we managed to scale and keep quality high while growing at the pace we have. We now have five full-time people and we work with over 35 startups of various sizes, so we are still a small business, but it has been growing very quickly.</p>
<p><b>How do you get new clients?</b></p>
<p>Our biggest source of new business has been referrals. Clients who work with us love what we do and refer us to other people. We have also ended up working with companies going through accelerator programs like Y Combinator, so when new YC companies ask who does developer content, they hear about us. Besides us there&#8217;s probably just a couple of other companies that specialize in this. It&#8217;s a very small field so we get mentioned a lot.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Have you worked with a talented individual or agency who helped you find and keep more users?</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-growth-marketers-for-startups/"><i>Respond to our survey</i></a><i> and help other startups find top growth marketers they can work with!</i></em></p>
<hr />
<p>Growth has been so organic at the moment that I haven&#8217;t pursued a lot of active outreach strategies, but we are starting to get better at boosting this [organic growth]. One of the first hires I made this year was an account manager who&#8217;s helped with maintaining relationships with existing clients and getting things like testimonials, case studies, etc. Another thing is that when people see our content, they ask the company who did it, because companies that are selling developers tools really need a way to produce this kind of content, and there aren&#8217;t many providers.</p>
<p><b>How do you complement your clients&#8217; own content production efforts?</b></p>
<p>Our two sweet spots are bigger companies that are looking to augment their in-house content team, because they have a hard time keeping developer content going, and really small teams that are building a tool specifically for software developers and need to get going with content production or ramp it up.</p>
<p>A lot of our clients will have something like a community writer program in addition to what we provide. For instance, we work with Strapi, which is an open-source tool that has a big community with community writers writing about how they use Strapi.</p>
<p>But then they use us to augment that content, because they want to be able to set some topics themselves. A lot of times, community contributions are good for whatever your community happens to be working on, but you can&#8217;t necessarily ask your community to write about X or Y.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GQPho6gT3c"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/headless-cms-company-strapi-raises-another-10-million/">Headless CMS company Strapi raises another $10 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Headless CMS company Strapi raises another $10 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/headless-cms-company-strapi-raises-another-10-million/embed/#?secret=GQPho6gT3c" data-secret="GQPho6gT3c" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The other challenge here is that with any developer-focused community writing program, you are going to need to spend a lot on editing. A lot of companies underestimate the work it is going to take. That&#8217;s where we come in: Instead of hiring all these different people you need and trying to build your own process, you can slot Draft.dev in there for a while. If some day you want to go hire your own team and replace us, that&#8217;s great — we&#8217;d love you to outgrow us. But ideally, we&#8217;d like to stick around and always be part of your developer content efforts.</p>
<p><b>Do you also do anything related to content distribution, such as writing the tweets that go with the articles?</b></p>
<p>We just started doing that; it&#8217;s our first big add-on service, where for each piece of content we&#8217;ll create social media collateral, like a couple of tweets, LinkedIn posts and Reddit submissions with the subreddits they would be most appropriate for. Then the client just has someone on their team copy-paste and schedule it with whatever system they want.</p>
<p>We also send a full promotional checklist they can use to promote the content, because one of the challenges I see with some of the smaller companies we work with is that they sometimes get lost when it comes to getting the content we produce in front of people. If you are not a developer, it&#8217;s hard to come up with copy about a technical piece. So by offering that collateral, we&#8217;re making it a bit easier. It&#8217;s been our first foray into this. We could expand into other things in the future, but that would probably be next year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3R0OQD1N6F"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/3-data-strategies-for-selling-to-developers/">3 data strategies for selling to developers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 data strategies for selling to developers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/3-data-strategies-for-selling-to-developers/embed/#?secret=3R0OQD1N6F" data-secret="3R0OQD1N6F" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/draft-dev-ceo-karl-hughes-on-the-importance-of-using-experts-in-developer-marketing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2181393</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swarm debuts $499 Evaluation Kit for consumers and tinkerers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/swarm-debuts-499-evaluation-kit-for-consumers-and-tinkerers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/swarm-debuts-499-evaluation-kit-for-consumers-and-tinkerers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 13:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[modem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sara spangelo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satellites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swarm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tile]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Satellite connectivity company Swarm has come out with a new product that will give anyone the ability to create a messaging or Internet of Things (IoT) device, whether that be a hiker looking to stay connected off-the-grid or a hobbyist wanting to track the weather. The Swarm Evaluation Kit is an all-in-one product that includes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Satellite connectivity company Swarm has come out with a new product that will give anyone the ability to create a messaging or Internet of Things (IoT) device, whether that be a hiker looking to stay connected off-the-grid or a hobbyist wanting to track the weather.</p>
<p>The Swarm Evaluation Kit is an all-in-one product that includes a Swarm Tile, the company’s flagship modem device, a VHF antenna, a small solar panel, a tripod, a Feather S2 development board and an OLED from Adafruit. The entire kit comes in at less than six pounds and costs $499. The package may sound intimidatingly technical, but Swarm CEO Sara Spangelo explained to TechCrunch that it was designed to be user-friendly, from the most novice consumer all the way through to more advanced users.</p>
<p>It “was super intentional to call it an Evaluation kit because it’s not a finished product,” Spangelo explained. “It serves two different kinds of groups. The first group is people that want to be able to do messaging anywhere that they are on the planet for a really low cost […] The second group of people will be the tinkerers and the hobbyists and educational folks.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2183391" style="width: 663px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183391" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-full wp-image-2183391" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Sara-Spangelo-headshot.png" alt="" width="653" height="900" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Sara-Spangelo-headshot.png 653w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Sara-Spangelo-headshot.png?resize=109,150 109w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Sara-Spangelo-headshot.png?resize=218,300 218w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Sara-Spangelo-headshot.png?resize=493,680 493w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Sara-Spangelo-headshot.png?resize=36,50 36w" sizes="(max-width: 653px) 100vw, 653px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183391" class="wp-caption-text">Swarm CEO and co-founder Sara Spangelo <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Swarm</p></div></p>
<p>This is the second consumer product that Swarm has on offer, after it went commercially live with its flagship Swarm Tile earlier this year. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/swarms-low-cost-satellite-data-network-is-now-available-to-commercial-clients/">The Swarm Tile</a> is a key component of the company’s ecosystem, which is comprised of a few different components: the Tile, a kind of modem that can be embedded in different things and what the customer interfaces with; the satellite network; and a ground station network, which is how the company downlinks data. The Tile is designed for maximum compatibility, so Swarm serves customers across sectors including shipping, logistics, and agriculture.</p>
<p>“One of the cool things about Swarm is that we&#8217;re infrastructure,” she said. “We&#8217;re like cellphone towers, so anyone can use us across any vertical.” Some of the use cases she highlighted included customers using Tile in soil moisture sensors, or in asset tracking in the trucking industry.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="l68jNK3fWc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/swarms-low-cost-satellite-data-network-is-now-available-to-commercial-clients/">Swarm&#8217;s low-cost satellite data network is now available to commercial clients</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Swarm&#8217;s low-cost satellite data network is now available to commercial clients&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/swarms-low-cost-satellite-data-network-is-now-available-to-commercial-clients/embed/#?secret=l68jNK3fWc" data-secret="l68jNK3fWc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>A major part of Swarm’s business model is its low cost, with a Swarm Tile costing $119 and the connectivity service available for only $5 per month per connected device. Spangelo credits not only the engineering innovations in the tiny devices and satellites, but the gains in launch economics, especially for small satellite developers like Swarm. The company also sells direct, which further reduces overhead.</p>
<p>Swarm was founded by Spangelo, a pilot and aerospace engineering PhD who spent time at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Lab and at Google on its drone delivery project, Wing. She told TechCrunch that Swarm started as a hobby project between her and co-founder Ben Longmier, who had previously founded a company called Aether Industries that made high-altitude balloon platforms.</p>
<p>“Then [we] realized that we could do communications at speeds that were similar to what the legacy players are doing today,” Sara Spangelo said. “There was a lot of buzz around connectivity,” she added, noting that initiatives like Project Loon were garnering a lot of funding. But instead of trying to match the size and scale of some of these multi-year projects, they decided to go small.</p>
<p>In the four and a half years since the company’s founding, Swarm has put up a network of 120 sandwich-sized satellites into low Earth orbit and grown its workforce to 32 people. They’ve also been busy onboarding customers that use the Tile. One hope is that the Kit will be an additional way to draw customers to Swarm’s service.</p>
<p>Spangelo said the kit is for “everybody in between, that likes to just play with things. And it&#8217;s not just playing – the playing leads to innovations and ideas, and then it gets deployed out into the world.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="el7a5py3je"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/as-china-shakes-up-regulations-tech-companies-suffer/">As China shakes up regulations, tech companies suffer</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As China shakes up regulations, tech companies suffer&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/as-china-shakes-up-regulations-tech-companies-suffer/embed/#?secret=el7a5py3je" data-secret="el7a5py3je" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/swarm-debuts-499-evaluation-kit-for-consumers-and-tinkerers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183362</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello Divorce raises $2M so that couples can say ‘good-bye’ easier</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/hello-divorce-raises-2m-so-that-couples-can-say-good-bye-easier/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/hello-divorce-raises-2m-so-that-couples-can-say-good-bye-easier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CEAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[divorce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Ong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Erin Levine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaingels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hello Divorce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northwestern Mutual Future Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Divorce is messy and stressful, made even messier and stressful when a couple is unable to go through the legal process because of the cost.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Divorce is messy and stressful, made even messier and stressful when a couple is unable to go through the legal process because of the cost. Online divorce startup Hello Divorce is developing a platform to make this process more affordable and quicker.</p>
<p>To do this, the Oakland, California-based company announced Thursday a $2 million seed round led by CEAS, with additional funds coming from Lightbank, Northwestern Mutual Future Ventures, Gaingels and a group of individuals including Clio CEO Jack Newton, WRG’s Lisa Stone and Equity ESQ led by Ed Diab.</p>
<p>Statistics show there are an average of <a href="https://legaljobs.io/blog/divorce-rate-in-america/">750,000 divorces in the U.S. each year</a>, and the <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/picture-gallery/money/2020/01/21/divorce-us-heres-how-much-costs-separate-each-state/4502754002/">average total cost of divorce</a> can cost anywhere between $8,400 to $17,500 depending on what state you live in. Overall, some sources value the <a href="https://video.vice.com/en_us/topic/conscious-uncoupling">divorce industry at $50 billion</a> annually.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Family law attorney Erin Levine founded the company in 2018 so that couples getting a divorce could access “affordable meaningful legal counsel” and resources beyond online forms. Levine told TechCrunch that the billable hours model for lawyers is “an antiquated process” for consumers that want an easier and clearer path to divorce.</p>
<p>“Right now, lawyers are the keeper of information, and clients keep paying until the divorce is done,” she said. “Divorce is more than forms. It is a challenging time, and most people need or want support. I saw a big hole there to use technology and fixed fees to put couples in the driver’s seat and take down that level of conflict.”</p>
<p>With this seed round, the company plans on rapidly scaling legal filing options across the U.S., improving its ground-breaking product, and giving consumers more of the content and services they need to feel informed and in control of their divorce process.</p>
<p>Hello Divorce provides software and accessible legal services starting at $99 for a do-it-yourself option or for up to an average of $2,000 for legal help along the way to finish the divorce process in a third of the time, and completely remote.</p>
<p>Levine said most people spend between two and five years contemplating divorce, and during that time are scared they will not be able to afford it, and if they have children, are afraid of losing them. Of those people, 80% won’t be able to access counsel.</p>
<p>Though the company is already profitable, Levine went after venture capital to be able to build an infrastructure and tap into the guidance that CEAS and other investors, like Lightbank’s Eric Ong bring to the table, saying “it is clear what I do know and what I don’t know.”</p>
<p>Ong said he met Levine through co-investors on the round, who told him Hello Divorce was something he would resonate with. Lightbank invests in category-stage companies, and he was drawn to what Levine and her team were doing.</p>
<p>“They are a combination of industry expertise and thinking outside of the box,” he said. “Eighty percent of people are still not getting meaningful representation, and we looked for technology that would provide a customer value proposition and we didn’t find one until Hello Divorce.”</p>
<p>The company plans to use the seed funding to scale legal filing options across the U.S., on product development and new content and services to educate people coming to Hello Divorce’s website.</p>
<p>The service is already available in four states — California, Colorado, Texas and Utah. Levine said the choice of initial states was strategic: She is familiar with California law, while Colorado has a complex system for divorce. Texas does not have a streamlined way for same-sex couples to get divorces, something Levine said she wanted to tackle, and Utah has a new regulatory scheme. Up next, she is expanding to New York and Florida, where she will launch in a bilingual format.</p>
<p>Since 2018, Hello Divorce has grown 100% year over year, with divorce success rates of 95% after starting the process on the platform. Over the past year, the company received 2,000 inquiries related to how to shelter in place with someone while contemplating divorce and co-parenting during lockdown.</p>
<p>“The inquiries increased about staying or going, and what divorce will look like,” Levine said. “It will be awhile before we see the total effects of what divorce looks like following the pandemic.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IHp0H27ooz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/11/this-week-in-apps-covid-19-contact-tracing-apps-virtual-dating-on-the-rise-quibi-makes-a-debut/">This Week in Apps: COVID-19 contact tracing apps, virtual dating on the rise, Quibi makes a debut</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;This Week in Apps: COVID-19 contact tracing apps, virtual dating on the rise, Quibi makes a debut&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/11/this-week-in-apps-covid-19-contact-tracing-apps-virtual-dating-on-the-rise-quibi-makes-a-debut/embed/#?secret=IHp0H27ooz" data-secret="IHp0H27ooz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/hello-divorce-raises-2m-so-that-couples-can-say-good-bye-easier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183198</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ConverseNow is targeting restaurant drive-thrus with new $15M round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/conversenow-is-targeting-restaurant-drive-thrus-with-new-15m-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/conversenow-is-targeting-restaurant-drive-thrus-with-new-15m-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ConverseNow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knoll Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LiveOak Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moneta Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rahul Aggarwal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tensility Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vinay Shukla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year after voice-based AI technology company ConverseNow raised a $3.3 million seed round, the company is back with a cash infusion of $15 million in Series A funding.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">One year after voice-based AI technology company <a href="https://www.conversenow.ai">ConverseNow</a> raised a $3.3 million seed round, the company is back with a cash infusion of $15 million in Series A funding in a round led by Craft Ventures.</p>
<p>The Austin-based company’s AI voice ordering assistants George and Becky work inside quick-serve restaurants to take orders via phone, chat, drive-thru and self-service kiosks, freeing up staff to concentrate on food preparation and customer service.</p>
<p>Joining Craft in the Series A round were LiveOak Venture Partners, Tensility Venture Partners, Knoll Ventures, Bala Investments, 2048 Ventures, Bridge Investments, Moneta Ventures and angel investors Federico Castellucci and Ashish Gupta. This new investment brings ConverseNow’s total funding to $18.3 million, Vinay Shukla, co-founder and CEO of ConverseNow, told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As part of the investment, Bryan Rosenblatt, partner at Craft Ventures, is joining the company’s board of directors, and said in a written statement that “post-pandemic, quick-service restaurants are primed for digital transformation, and we see a unique opportunity for ConverseNow to become a driving force in the space.”</p>
<p>At the time when ConverseNow raised its seed funding in 2020, it was piloting its technology in just a handful of stores. Today, it is live in over 750 stores and grew seven times in revenue and five times in headcount.</p>
<p>Restaurants were some of the hardest-hit industries during the pandemic, and as they reopen, Shukla said their two main problems will be labor and supply chain, and “that is where our technology intersects.”</p>
<p>The AI assistants are able to step in during peak times when workers are busy to help take orders so that customers are not waiting to place their orders, or calls get dropped or abandoned, something Shukla said happens often.</p>
<p>It can also drive more business. ConverseNow said it is shown to increase average orders by 23% and revenue by 20%, while adding up to 12 hours of extra deployable labor time per store per week.</p>
<p>Company co-founder Rahul Aggarwal said more people prefer to order remotely, which has led to an increase in volume. However, the more workers have to multitask, the less focus they have on any one job.</p>
<p>“If you step into restaurants with ConverseNow, you see them reimagined,” Aggarwal said. “You find workers focusing on the job they like to do, which is preparing food. It is also driving better work balance, while on the customer side, you don’t have to wait in the queue. Operators have more time to churn orders, and service time comes down.”</p>
<p>ConverseNow is one of the startups within the global <a href="https://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/restaurant-management-software-market">restaurant management software market</a> that is forecasted to reach $6.94 billion by 2025, according to Grand View Research. Over the past year, startups in the space attracted both investors and acquirers. For example, point-of-sale software company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/lightspeed-acquires-upserve/">Lightspeed acquired Upserve</a> in December for $430 million. Earlier this year, Sunday <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/sunday-raises-24-million-seed-round-to-build-a-fast-restaurant-checkout-flow/">raised $24 million</a> for its checkout technology.</p>
<p>The new funding will enable ConverseNow to continue developing its line-busting technology and invest in marketing, sales and product innovation. It will also be working on building a database from every conversation and onboarding new customers quicker, which involves inputting the initial menu.</p>
<p>By leveraging artificial intelligence, the company will be able to course-correct any inconsistencies, like background noise on a call, and better predict what a customer might be saying. It will also correct missing words and translate the order better. In the future, Shukla and Aggarwal also want the platform to be able to tell what is going on around the restaurant — what traffic is like, the weather and any menu promotions to drive upsell.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NHzLsmR1pX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/olos-ipo-could-value-the-company-north-of-3b-as-toast-waits-in-the-wings/">Olo&#8217;s IPO could value the company north of $3B as Toast waits in the wings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Olo&#8217;s IPO could value the company north of $3B as Toast waits in the wings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/olos-ipo-could-value-the-company-north-of-3b-as-toast-waits-in-the-wings/embed/#?secret=NHzLsmR1pX" data-secret="NHzLsmR1pX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/conversenow-is-targeting-restaurant-drive-thrus-with-new-15m-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183176</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nothing Ear (1) review</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/nothing-ear-1-review/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/nothing-ear-1-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 13:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AirPods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bluetooth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carl Pei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ear 1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earbuds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teenage engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless earbuds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s always exciting to see a new company enter the consumer hardware space — and deliver a solid first product out of the game.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Carl Pei says he looked around and saw a lot of the same. He’s not alone in that respect. Apple didn’t invent the fully wireless earbud with the first AirPods, but it did provide a kind of inflection point that sent many of its competitors hurtling toward a sort of homogeneity. You’d be hard-pressed to cite another consumer electronics category that matured and coalesced as quickly as Bluetooth earbuds, but finding something unique among the hordes is another question entirely.</p>
<p>These days, a pair of perfectly serviceable wireless earbuds are one click and $50 away. Spend $200, and you can get something truly excellent. But variety? That’s a different question entirely. Beyond choosing between a long-stemmed AirPods-style design and something a bit rounder, there’s really not a lot of diversification. Up until recently, features like active noise canceling and wireless charging bifurcated the category into premium and non-premium tiers, but they’ve both become increasingly ubiquitous.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2182585" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182585" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2182585" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9591.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9591.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9591.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9591.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9591.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9591.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9591.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9591.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9591.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182585" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>So, let’s say you’re launching a new consumer hardware company in 2021. And let’s say you decided your first product is going to be a pair of earbuds. Where does that leave you? How are you going to not only differentiate yourself in a crowded market but compete alongside giants like Samsung, Google and Apple?</p>
<p>Price is certainly a factor, and $99 is aggressive. Pei seemed to regret pricing the Ear (1) at less than $100 in our first conversation. It’s probably safe to say Nothing’s not exactly going to be cleaning up on every unit sold. And much like his prior company — OnePlus — he seems reluctant to position cost as a defining characteristic.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="K8VARfPYti"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/heres-nothings-99-ear-1-buds/">Here’s Nothing’s $99 Ear (1) buds</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Here’s Nothing’s $99 Ear (1) buds&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/heres-nothings-99-ear-1-buds/embed/#?secret=K8VARfPYti" data-secret="K8VARfPYti" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In a conversation prior to the Ear (1) launch, Pei’s take on the state of the industry was a kind of “feature glut.” Certainly, there’s been a never-ending spec race across different categories over the last several years. And it’s true that it’s getting more difficult to differentiate based on features — look at what smartphone makers have been dealing with the last several years. Wireless headphones, meanwhile, jumped from the “exciting early-stage mess” stage to “the actually pretty good” stage in record time.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2182580" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182580" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2182580" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9599.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9599.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9599.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9599.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9599.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9599.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9599.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9599.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9599.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182580" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>I do think there’s still room for feature differentiation. Take the recently launched <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/nura-finally-goes-fully-wireless-with-the-nuratrue-buds/">NuraTrue headphones</a>. That company has taken an opposite approach to arrive at earbuds, beginning with a specialized audio technology that it’s built three different headphone models around.</p>
<p>Pei noted in the Ear (1) launch presser that the company determined its aesthetic ideals prior to deciding what its first product would be. And true to form, its partnership with the design firm Teenage Engineering was announced well before a single image of the product appeared (the best we got in the early days was an early concept inspired by Pei’s grandmother’s tobacco pipe).</p>
<p>There are other ideals, as well — concepts about ecosystems, but those are the sorts of things that can only come after the release of multiple products. In the meantime, we’ve seen the product from all angles. I’m wearing the product in the ears and holding it in my hand (though I’m putting it down now; too hard to type).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2182569" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182569" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2182569" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9627.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9627.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9627.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9627.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9627.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9627.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9627.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9627.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9627.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182569" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The form factor certainly borrows from the AirPods, from the long stems to the white buds from which they protrude. You can’t say that they’re entirely their own thing in that respect. But perhaps a case can be made that the nature of fully wireless earbuds is, in and of itself, limiting in the manner of form factors it can accommodate. I’m certainly not a product designer, but they need to sit comfortably in your ears, and they can’t be too big or too heavy or protrude too much.</p>
<p>According to Pei, part of the product’s delayed launch was due to the company going back to the drawing board to rethink designs. What they ultimately arrived at was something recognizable as a pair of earbuds, while offering some unique flourishes. Transparency is the primary differentiator from an aesthetic standpoint. It comes into play in a big way with the case, which is unique, as these things go. With the buds themselves, most of the transparency happens on the stems.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2182578" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182578" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2182578" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9602.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9602.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9602.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9602.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9602.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9602.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9602.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9602.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9602.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182578" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>In a vacuum, the buds look a fair bit like an Apple product. The glossy white finish and white silicone tips are a big part of that. The reason the entire buds aren’t transparent, as early renderings showed, is a simple and pragmatic one: the components in the buds are too unsightly. That brings us to another element in the product’s eventual delay: making a gadget clear requires putting thought into how things like components and glue look. It’s the same reason why there’s a big white strip in the middle of an otherwise clear case: charging components are ugly (sorry/not sorry).</p>
<p>It’s a potential recipe for overly busy design, but I think the team landed on something solid — and certainly distinctive. That alone should account for something in the homogeneous world of gadget design. And the company’s partnership with StockX should be a pretty clear indication of precisely the sorts of early adopters/influencers Nothing is going after here.</p>
<p>The Ear (1) buds are a lot more welcoming than any of the style-first experiments <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/01/will-i-am/">Will.i.am made in the category.</a> And while they’re distinct, they don’t really stand out in the wild — which is to say, no one’s going to scream and point or stop you in the street to figure what’s going on with your ears (sorry, Will).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2182577" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182577" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2182577" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9610.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9610.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9610.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9610.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9610.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9610.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9610.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9610.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9610.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182577" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>Ultimately, I dig the look. There are nice touches, as well. A red and white dot indicate the right and left buds, respectively, a nod to RCA and other audio cables. A subtle Nothing logo is etched in dotted text, bringing to mind circuit board printing. The letter extends to most of Nothing’s branding. It’s clear the design was masterminded by people who have spent a lot of time negotiating with supply-chain vendors. Notably, the times I spoke to Pei, he was often in and around Shenzhen rather than the company’s native London, hammering out last-minute supply issues.</p>
<p>The buds feel really great, too. I’ve noted my tendency to suffer from ear pain wearing various earbud designs for extended periods. On Monday, I took a four hour intra-borough walk and didn’t notice a thing. They also stayed in place like champs on visits to the gym. And not for nothing, but there’s an extremely satisfying magnetic snap when you place them back in the charging case (the red and white dots still apply).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2182566" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182566" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2182566" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9631.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9631.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9631.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9631.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9631.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9631.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9631.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9631.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9631.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182566" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The case is flat and square with rounded edges (a squircle, if you please). If it wasn’t clear, it might closely resemble a tin of mints. It also offers a pretty satisfying snap when shutting. Will be curious to see how well that stands up after several hundred — or thousand — openings and closings.</p>
<p>Though the company says it put the product through all of the standard drop and stress tests, it warns that even the strongest transparent plastic is still prone to scratching, particularly with a set of keys in the same pocket. Pei says that kind of battle scarring will ultimately be part of its charm, but the jury’s still out on that one. After a few days and no keys in close proximity, I have one long scratch across the bottom. I don’t feel any cooler, but you tell me.</p>
<p>A large concave circle on the top helps keep the lid from slamming into the earbuds when closing. It’s also a nice spot to put your thumb when fiddling around with the thing. I suspect it doubles to relieve some of that fidgeting we (I) usually release by absentmindedly flipping a case lid up and down. It’s a small, but thoughtful touch. Round back, you’ll find the USB-C charging port and Bluetooth sync button.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2182570" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182570" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2182570" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9626.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9626.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9626.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9626.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9626.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9626.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9626.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9626.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9626.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182570" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>On iOS, you’ll need to connect the buds both through the app and in the Bluetooth settings the first time. There are disadvantages when you don’t make your own operating system, chips and phones in addition to earbuds. That’s a minor (probably one-time) nuisance, though.</p>
<p>The Ear (1) are a decent sounding pair of $99 headphones. I won’t say I was blown away, but I don’t think anyone is going to be disappointed that they don’t really go head-to-head with, say, the Sony WF-1000xM4 or even the new NuraTrue. These aren’t audiophile headphones, but they’re very much suitable for walking around the city, listening to music and podcasts.</p>
<p>The app offers a built-in equalizer tuned by Teenage Engineering with three settings: balanced, more treble/more bass, and voice (for podcasts, et al.). The differences are detectable, but pretty subtle, as far as these things go. As far as equalizer customizations go, it’s more point-and-shoot than DSLR, as Nothing doesn’t want you straying too far from the intended balance. After experimenting with all of the settings, I mostly stuck with the balanced setting. Feel free to judge me accordingly.</p>
<p>[gallery ids="2182572,2182566,2182587,2182586,2182585,2182584,2182583,2182581,2182580,2182579,2182578,2182577,2182575,2182574,2182573,2182571,2182570,2182569,2182568,2182567"]</p>
<p>There are three ANC settings, as well: noise cancellation, transparency and off. You can also titrate the noise cancellation between light and heavy. On the whole, the ANC did a fine job erasing a fair bit of street noise on my New York City walks, though even at heavy, it’s not going to, say, block out the sound of a car altogether. For my sake, that’s maybe for the best.</p>
<p>There’s also a built-in &#8220;find my earbud&#8221; setting that sends out a kind of piercing chirp so you can find the one that is inevitably trapped beneath your couch cushion.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2182573" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182573" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2182573" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9621.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9621.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9621.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9621.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9621.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9621.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9621.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9621.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CMC_9621.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182573" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>My big complaint day today is one I encountered with the NuraTrue. I ran into a number of Bluetooth connection dropouts. It’s a bit annoying when you’re really engrossed in a song or podcast. And again, it’s something you’re a lot less likely to encounter for those companies that build their own buds, phone, chips and operating systems. It’s a pretty tough thing to compete with for a brand-new startup.</p>
<p>I have quibbles, and in spite of months of excited teases, the Ear (1) buds aren’t going to turn the overcrowded category upside down. But it’s always exciting to see a new company enter the consumer hardware space — and deliver a solid first product out of the game. It’s an idiosyncratic take on the category at a nice price from a company worth keeping an eye on.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NctK4O3PbY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/nothing-founder-carl-pei-on-ear-1-and-building-a-hardware-startup-from-scratch/">Nothing founder Carl Pei on Ear (1) and building a hardware startup from scratch</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nothing founder Carl Pei on Ear (1) and building a hardware startup from scratch&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/nothing-founder-carl-pei-on-ear-1-and-building-a-hardware-startup-from-scratch/embed/#?secret=NctK4O3PbY" data-secret="NctK4O3PbY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/nothing-ear-1-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183474</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Student labor marketplace Pangea closes $2M seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/student-labor-marketplace-pangea-closes-2m-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/student-labor-marketplace-pangea-closes-2m-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Alpert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pangea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Providence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rhode island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed stage startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unpopular ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The startup runs a marketplace that links college-age talent to companies in need of their services. Social media and web developer work are popular on the Pangea platform.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.about.pangea.app/">Pangea</a>, a Providence, Rhode Island-based startup that connects youthful talent and businesses in need of freelance labor, announced this morning that it has closed an oversubscribed $2 million seed round.</p>
<p>Pangea CEO and co-founder <a href="https://twitter.com/the_pangean?lang=en">Adam Alpert</a> told TechCrunch that his company had set out to secure $1.5 million, but wound up raising more. We&#8217;re hearing that somewhat often these days.</p>
<p>IDEA Fund Partners&#8217; Lister Delgado led the round. Other investors in the transaction included Unpopular Ventures, Brown Angel Group, PJC and a number of individuals.</p>
<p>The startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/yc-backed-pangea-discusses-growth-fundraising-ahead-of-demo-day/">graduated from Y Combinator earlier in the year</a>, raising a check from the accelerator and another $350,000 since it closed a $400,000 pre-seed round <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/10/pangea-app-raises-400k-seed-round-to-help-connect-student-workers-with-businesses/">last April</a>. All told, Pangea has raised around $3 million.</p>
<p>The startup runs a marketplace that links college-age talent to companies in need of their services. Given the skillset of many college students, social media and web developer work are popular on the Pangea platform.</p>
<p>The model is scaling. Per Alpert and his co-founder <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/johntambunting/">John Tambunting</a>, gross merchandise volume (GMV), or the value of sold services on Pangea&#8217;s market, rose 400% on a year-over-year basis in Q2 2021. And the CEO disclosed earlier in July that the company&#8217;s GMV rose 40% in the preceding four weeks.</p>
<p>For context, TechCrunch reported that Pangea was &#8220;facilitating $50,000 in transactions between college freelancers and businesses&#8221; in March 2021. That figure should now be heading toward the $100,000 monthly GMV run-rate threshold. We&#8217;ll annoy the company for new growth figures when Q3 ends.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The latest Pangea round was a priced event, meaning that the startup has graduated from the comfortable early-stage realm of SAFEs and other related instruments. The seed round values the company into the modest end of the eight-figure range.</span></p>
<p>What will Pangea use the money for? To scale its human capital. The company, currently four full-time staff, intends to more than double to nine.</p>
<p>And because it is based in Providence, a cheaper market than New York or San Francisco, its new capital will give it more time to grow. Alpert told TechCrunch that its seed capital will give it &#8220;20-25 product cycles,&#8221; the first time that we&#8217;ve heard runway expressed in that particular manner. We like it.</p>
<p>The CEO said that building in Providence, a &#8220;smaller city,&#8221; allows Pangea to better focus. And he said that because investors are now willing to invest remotely, the location is not particularly remote.</p>
<p>The startup is not the only upstart technology company in town. Alpert told TechCrunch that the Providence startup scene is starting to grow, saying that &#8220;a year ago, there was very little happening, but now there are now several other venture-backed, seed-stage startups here all working on the same floor as us.&#8221;</p>
<p>TechCrunch recently swung by the company&#8217;s office where its staff and collected summer interns were meeting. (Disclosure: Your scribe is not a very good photographer):</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2183166" style="width: 579px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183166" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2183166 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-28-at-12.40.17-PM.png?w=569" alt="" width="569" height="411" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-28-at-12.40.17-PM.png 569w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-28-at-12.40.17-PM.png?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-28-at-12.40.17-PM.png?resize=300,217 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-28-at-12.40.17-PM.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 569px) 100vw, 569px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183166" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Alex Wilhelm. Look! A startup in an office! Doing things!</p></div></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2183558" style="width: 579px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183558" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2183558" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/techcrunch-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="569" height="379" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/techcrunch-1.png 3370w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/techcrunch-1.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/techcrunch-1.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/techcrunch-1.png?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/techcrunch-1.png?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/techcrunch-1.png?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/techcrunch-1.png?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/techcrunch-1.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 569px) 100vw, 569px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183558" class="wp-caption-text">Adam Alpert, Tae Sam Lee Zamora, Kacie Galligan, John Tambunting. Via the company.</p></div></p>
<p>Pangea now has more capital than it has ever had to keep building out its product lineup, scale GMV and start extending its runway with revenue growth. Let&#8217;s see how far this seed round can take it, and how long it takes the startup to reach Series A scale.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/student-labor-marketplace-pangea-closes-2m-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183155</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Summit invests $215M into Odoo, an open source business management software developer, at a $2.3B+ valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/summit-invests-215m-into-odoo-an-open-source-business-management-software-developer-at-a-2-3b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/summit-invests-215m-into-odoo-an-open-source-business-management-software-developer-at-a-2-3b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Open source has become a major force in the world of IT, and today a startup that has built a profitable operation by developing business management software on the priniciple is announcing a sizable secondary investment on the back of that growth. Odoo &#8212; a Belgium-based provider of open-source-based business software that ranges from inventory [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Open source has become a major force in the world of IT, and today a startup that has built a profitable operation by developing business management software on the priniciple is announcing a sizable secondary investment on the back of that growth.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.odoo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Odoo</a> &#8212; a Belgium-based provider of open-source-based business software that ranges from inventory management and ERP through to human resources and CRM software, marketing tools and more, some 30,000 in all &#8212; has received $215 million from Summit Partners.</p>
<p>This is a secondary investment, meaning Summit is buying shares from existing investors (specifically Sofinnova Partners &amp; XAnge): Odoo is profitable and has been so for years, CEO and founder Fabien Pinckaers explained in an interview earlier, and so it didn&#8217;t need to raise more cash by giving away more equity. He added that this investment values the startup at over €2 billion (or over $2.3 billion at current rates), making Odoo the first &#8220;unicorn&#8221; out of Wallonia, the region in Belgium where it is based.</p>
<p>(That in itself is notable: it&#8217;s a sign of the evolving decentralization of the tech world beyond &#8220;The Valley&#8221;.)</p>
<p>This is the second time Summit, which was one of Odoo&#8217;s earliest (equity) backers, has snapped up secondary shares: the firm made a similar investment of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/17/odoo-grabs-90m-to-sell-more-smes-on-its-business-app-suite/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$90 million in 2019</a>.</p>
<p>With 7 million users on its platform, Odoo is a prime example of the strong payoffs to be had from economies of scale in the most successful open source projects, but it&#8217;s also doing so with a twist.</p>
<p>On the open source front, Odoo provides a version of its services that is &#8220;open source&#8221; and free, which Pinckaers said contains about 80% of all of its features. It then offers a paid, proprietary version of the product with the remaining 20% of features (full details on <a href="https://www.odoo.com/pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pricing here</a>).</p>
<p>About 90% of all of Odoo&#8217;s customer base takes the free tier, he said, with only 10% taking the paid, proprietary tier. But with 7 million users  that is enough to run the business at a profit big enough that it can continue investing in growth without giving away more equity.</p>
<p>On top of this, what is also notable is how Odoo pitches itself. While a lot of open source has been seen as the domain of developers and others in the technical community, what has set Odoo apart from them is the fact that it designs software on its platform that is actually aimed at others in the workplace, not engineers.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are one of the only exceptions of open source built for non-technical users,&#8221; Pinckaers said.</p>
<p>It targets users both directly via its SaaS platform, and via a very extensive channel partner operation where channel partners will host the services themselves. Its traction with these partners is strong, he added, because of the free nature of Odoo (which is not only a contrast to the SAPs, Microsofts and Oracles of the world, but at times a much easier sell around which a channel partner can provide other paid services). There are nearly 4,000 partners now, he added, with another 90,000 individual community members contributing software on the Odoo platform.</p>
<p>The company has been growing revenues and customers at a rate of 50% over the last 10 years (and 63% over the past 15: it&#8217;s been around since 2005), and it now has 1,700 employees with plans to add another 1,000 this year. Billings are expected to be €160 million in 2021. Pinckaers said that Odoo&#8217;s next steps will be to continue growing out the software that it provides to users on its platform. Specifically, the two areas it is focusing on are e-commerce and website development, he said, two areas that he feels could benefit from more non-technical, user-friendly open source tools.</p>
<p>“We are thrilled to support the Odoo team for this next phase of growth,” said Han Sikkens, MD and head of Europe at Summit Partners, in a statement. “We believe the future is bright, and Odoo clearly has the potential to disrupt the market led by software giants like SAP, MS Dynamics and Oracle.” Sikkens is joining the board with this round.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/summit-invests-215m-into-odoo-an-open-source-business-management-software-developer-at-a-2-3b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183548</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GGV Capital gave this real estate startup founder a term sheet 48 hours after meeting</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/ggv-capitals-gave-this-real-estate-startup-founder-a-term-sheet-48-hours-after-meeting/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/ggv-capitals-gave-this-real-estate-startup-founder-a-term-sheet-48-hours-after-meeting/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ggv capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Richards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proptech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Realm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential real estate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Realm, which aims to help homeowners maximize the value of their property with its data platform, has raised $12 million in Series A funding led by GGV Capital. Existing backers Primary Venture Partners, Lerer Hippeau and Liberty Mutual Strategic Ventures also participated in the round, bringing the New York-based startup’s total raised to $15 million. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.myrealm.co/">Realm</a>, which aims to help homeowners maximize the value of their property with its data platform, has raised $12 million in Series A funding led by GGV Capital.</p>
<p>Existing backers Primary Venture Partners, Lerer Hippeau and Liberty Mutual Strategic Ventures also participated in the round, bringing the New York-based startup’s total raised to $15 million.</p>
<p>Liz Young founded Realm, launching the platform earlier this year with the goal of providing “a one-stop-shop for accessible, actionable home advice.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>So far, Realm says it has helped over 20,000 homeowners “uncover” an average of $175,000 in property value. Its user base is growing 20% month over month.</p>
<p>What makes the company different from other valuation offerings out there, according to Young, is that rather than telling owners what their homes are worth today, Realm can tell them what their home could be worth after renovations in months and years to come.</p>
<p>“There are a ton of tools and services that make it easier to buy or sell your home, but once you move, it&#8217;s a total black box,” she said. “You&#8217;re left trying to cobble together advice from fragmented, often biased resources to navigate big, expensive decisions. There&#8217;s nowhere else consumers spend so much money, with such little actionable information.”</p>
<p>For example, using data extracted from a variety of sources such as tax assessors and its own users, Realm can do things like tell a homeowner in real time how their property value will change if they do things like make over a bathroom or add a new deck. Its algorithms can assess a property and offer advice on what projects are most likely to add value.</p>
<p>“The public data that we acquire, the data we ingest from users, and the data that we build ourselves has allowed us to build the most robust and unique actionable real estate data set in the U.S.,” Young told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Realm’s database is free and according to Young, offers insights on over 70 million single family detached homes across the U.S.</p>
<p>Part of that is determined by zoning data, which tells people where they can and cannot build on a property.</p>
<p>“It’s really important because square feet is one of the biggest drivers of home value,” Young said. “So if you&#8217;re trying to understand how much a home&#8217;s worth or could be worth, you really have to understand the local zoning rules.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2183303" style="width: 1033px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183303" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2183303 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-1.jpg" alt="" width="1023" height="529" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-1.jpg 1023w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-1.jpg?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-1.jpg?resize=300,155 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-1.jpg?resize=768,397 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-1.jpg?resize=680,352 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-1.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1023px) 100vw, 1023px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183303" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Realm</p></div></p>
<p>Realm’s marketplace offering, where an adviser connects owners to contractors, architects and lenders that can carry out the company’s recommendations, is currently only live in California, but will be expanding to new markets over the next 12 months.</p>
<p>“People can digitally consume our free insights but a lot want help interpreting them,” Young said.</p>
<p>The company plans to use its new capital to “improve the quality and sophistication of the platform’s data insights” and toward hiring across its data science, engineering, marketing and operations teams. It will also continue to develop its proprietary data sets and models, which offer homeowners across the country personalized analysis of over 70 million homes.<br />
A lot of Realm’s business is driven by its relationships with agents and word of mouth via its existing user base.</p>
<p>Jeff Richards, GGV managing partner and new Realm board member, said that when his firm backs at the Series A level, its bet is “100% on the founder.”</p>
<p>“I met Liz when she was raising her seed round in July 2020 and was blown away,” he told TechCrunch. “She’s smart, ambitious and has a deep background in the space she’s going after. Although it was early, I could tell she was thinking big.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2183301" style="width: 408px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183301" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2183301 " src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="398" height="398" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg 800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image-2.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 398px) 100vw, 398px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183301" class="wp-caption-text">Founder and CEO Liz Young.<strong> Image Credits:</strong> Realm</p></div></p>
<p>He points out that GGV Capital, with $2.5 billion in assets under management, is a long-time investor in other proptechs including Opendoor, Divvy Homes, Belong and Airbnb.</p>
<p>“Zillow made it easy for people to find a home to buy. Opendoor made it easy to buy and sell a home,” Richards told TechCrunch. “Airbnb made it easy to rent a home for a short-term vacation. Belong is making it easy to rent a home for the long term.”</p>
<p>Realm, according to Richards, was right in GGV’s “sweet spot.”</p>
<p>“No one has zeroed in on helping the individual homeowner manage their home, and that’s the opportunity area Liz is going after,” he said. “We kept in touch after the seed round, she pinged me to talk about her A, we met up and I gave her a term sheet 48 hours later.”</p>
<p>In general, Richards believes that residential real estate is one of the biggest spend categories in the U.S. and yet is still virtually untouched by technology.</p>
<p>Home sales are over $1.6 trillion annually, home improvement is one of the biggest categories in the U.S. at over $500 billion annually, and the <a href="https://st.hzcdn.com/static/econ/2021--US-Houzz-and-Home-Study.pdf">average home renovation project in the U.S. is around $15,000</a>, with many spending over $50,000.</p>
<p>“I’ve owned a home for 17 years and almost everything I do with respect to the home is the same as it was over a decade ago. The only thing that has really changed is I can manage my thermostat and cameras with my phone,&#8221; Richards said. “Literally everything else is the same — the way I do renovations, the way I find contractors to do repairs, the way I pay my mortgage, etc. — exactly the same. That’s ridiculous! Liz sees a huge opportunity here, and so do we. The market is enormous. So there will be many, many winners.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a9LS47TsnQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand-discuss-proptechs-biggest-opportunities/">Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss proptech&#8217;s biggest opportunities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss proptech&#8217;s biggest opportunities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand-discuss-proptechs-biggest-opportunities/embed/#?secret=a9LS47TsnQ" data-secret="a9LS47TsnQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/ggv-capitals-gave-this-real-estate-startup-founder-a-term-sheet-48-hours-after-meeting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183286</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rocket Lab returns to flight after failed May mission with successful launch for U.S. Space Force</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/rocket-lab-returns-to-flight-after-failed-may-mission-with-successful-launch-for-u-s-space-force/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/rocket-lab-returns-to-flight-after-failed-may-mission-with-successful-launch-for-u-s-space-force/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183541</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rocket Lab is back in business launching rockets, after an issue during its last launch in May caused a total loss of the payloads on board. The company was quick to investigate the issue, and announced just over a week ago that it had completed that work, identified the problem and implemented corrective action to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rocket Lab is back in business launching rockets, after an<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/15/rocket-labs-20th-electron-launch-ends-in-failure-with-the-loss-of-its-payload/"> issue during its last launch in May</a> caused a total loss of the payloads on board. The company was quick to investigate the issue, and announced just over a week ago that it had completed that work, identified the problem and implemented corrective action to make sure it doesn&#8217;t happen again.</p>
<p>The launch today, which took off from the company&#8217;s Launch Complex 1 in New Zealand, was an important one to get right: It delivered a satellite for the U.S. Space Force to low Earth orbit. This is the second Space Force mission that Rocket Lab has provided launch services for.</p>
<p>On board the Electron launch vehicle for this mission was a demonstration satellite called &#8216;Monolith,&#8217; which is equipped with a new kind of deployable sensor that could, if it works as designed, pave the way for significantly smaller satellite buses in future spacecraft designs for things like weather and observation satellites.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This turnaround after a failed launch and loss of client payload is another benefit of Rocket Lab&#8217;s ability to quickly turnaround rockets and missions. It&#8217;ll definitely be under increased scrutiny for the next little while, however, considering that this latest mishap was the second &#8216;anomaly&#8217; to result in mission failure in just under a year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="owRyLQhqOy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/04/rocket-lab-launch-fails-during-rockets-second-stage-burn-causing-a-loss-of-vehicle-and-payloads/">Rocket Lab launch fails during rocket&#8217;s second-stage burn, causing a loss of vehicle and payloads</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rocket Lab launch fails during rocket&#8217;s second-stage burn, causing a loss of vehicle and payloads&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/04/rocket-lab-launch-fails-during-rockets-second-stage-burn-causing-a-loss-of-vehicle-and-payloads/embed/#?secret=owRyLQhqOy" data-secret="owRyLQhqOy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/rocket-lab-returns-to-flight-after-failed-may-mission-with-successful-launch-for-u-s-space-force/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183541</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Employee engagement platform Culture Amp raises $100M at a $1.5B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/employee-engagement-platform-culture-amp-raises-100m-at-a-1-5b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/employee-engagement-platform-culture-amp-raises-100m-at-a-1-5b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture Amp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employee engagement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employee survey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human relations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2182944</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Culture Amp was founded in 2009 to let companies conduct anonymous employee surveys, but since then, its focus has expanded to helping employers turn the data they collect into action. The company announced today it has raised $100 million in Series F funding, led by returning investors Sequoia Capital China and TDM Growth Partners. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.cultureamp.com/">Culture Amp</a> was founded in 2009 to let companies conduct anonymous employee surveys, but since then, its focus has expanded to helping employers turn the data they collect into action. The company announced today it has raised $100 million in Series F funding, led by returning investors Sequoia Capital China and TDM Growth Partners. The round bumps Culture Amp’s valuation to $1.5 billion, more than double what it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/employee-survey-startup-culture-amp-closes-82m-funding-round/">was after the company’s Series E in 2019</a>.</p>
<p>New investor Salesforce Ventures, along with existing backers Felicis Ventures, Blackbird Ventures, Index Ventures, Sapphire Ventures, Skip Capital, Grok Ventures and Global Founders Capital also participated in the round.</p>
<p>Culture Amp is now used by more than 4,000 organizations with a total of 25 million employees. Its clients range in size from about 20 to 30 people to more than 150,000 employees, and include Salesforce, Unilever, PwC, KIND, SoulCycle and BigCommerce.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XRXFEbuOad"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/employee-survey-startup-culture-amp-closes-82m-funding-round/">Employee survey startup Culture Amp closes $82M round led by Sequoia China</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Employee survey startup Culture Amp closes $82M round led by Sequoia China&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/employee-survey-startup-culture-amp-closes-82m-funding-round/embed/#?secret=XRXFEbuOad" data-secret="XRXFEbuOad" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>From its start as a survey platform, Culture Amp has grown to encompass analytics for managers, like turnover prediction and team goal tracking. It also has a sizable online community where users can connect and book workshops, including ones run by diversity, equity and inclusion experts. Culture Amp recently held a virtual version of Culture First, its annual event, with over 20,000 participants.</p>
<p>Founder and chief executive officer Didier Elzinga told TechCrunch that he sees Culture Amp’s Series F as a “validation of the HR space in general.”</p>
<p>“I think for a long time, the HR space and HR tech space have been viewed as not that interesting or important, but what we see now is that people are the most important thing that most companies have, so what can we do to craft their experiences,” he added. “I think it’s a really interesting step for the space as a whole, for an organization like Culture Amp to have made it to this level of revenue, fundraising and valuation.”</p>
<p>The company still has most of its funds from its Series E, but the new round will allow it to “work at a whole other level of scale,” Elzinga said. Culture Amp launched in Australia, and about two-thirds of its revenue comes from the United States. It is also growing in Europe, so some of its new funding will be used on its dual data centers. Elzinga added that the raise also gives Culture Amp a warchest to spend on acquisitions.</p>
<p>Over the past year and a half, employers have dealt with two major issues: a remote workforce coping with the COVID-19 pandemic and growing calls for diversity, equity and inclusion.</p>
<p>Culture Amp saw more employers addressing DEI in surveys; for example, the number of companies who asked employees questions like do they &#8220;build teams that are diverse&#8221; increased about 30% in 2020. Clients have access to surveys created with behavioral psychologists, including ones designed to see if women, people of color or people who use English as a second language are feeling disengaged and, if so, how to help them.</p>
<p>To understand the pandemic&#8217;s impact, the platform introduced well-being templates, asking if employees are feeling overwhelmed, how they feel about messaging from company leaders and gauging their willingness to return to the office.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TTsq8PQhUZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/eqtble-a-platform-that-uses-data-analytics-to-create-healthier-workplaces-raises-2-7m-seed/">eqtble, a platform that uses data analytics to create healthier workplaces, raises $2.7M seed</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;eqtble, a platform that uses data analytics to create healthier workplaces, raises $2.7M seed&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/eqtble-a-platform-that-uses-data-analytics-to-create-healthier-workplaces-raises-2-7m-seed/embed/#?secret=TTsq8PQhUZ" data-secret="TTsq8PQhUZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Surveys are answered anonymously and data is aggregated to protect the privacy of individual employees. To help companies act on the results they get, Culture Amp provides what it calls an “Inspiration Engine,” or practices that have worked for other companies.</p>
<p>Since Culture Amp works with a large group of employers, it is able to create benchmarks by industry, size and region. This allows companies to see how their employee engagement compares to others in the same space.</p>
<p>Another feature, Skills Coach, is based on behavioral science research and helps managers develop “soft skills” through two-minute interactive exercises that are delivered by Slack or email.</p>
<p>“The experience that employees have is the thing we want to up level, but the way we want to do it and what we’re focused on is lifting managers’ capability to delivery that employee experience,” Elzinga said. Skills Coach was designed to fit into busy workdays and its usage has tripled over the past year, he added.</p>
<p>“We think that for all the progress we have made, we’re still at the beginning of actually delivering on that employee experience,” he added. “I think the last two years have shown us how important mental well-being is, how important diversity and inclusion is, and how important it is for leaders to truly listen to their people and then to act on that and follow up.”</p>
<p>Other employee feedback platforms include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/lattice-a-people-management-platform-picks-up-45m-at-a-400m-valuation/">Lattice</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/08/linkedin-acquires-employee-engagement-and-retention-platform-glint/">Glint</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/qualtrics-ipo-everything-you-need-to-know/">Qualtrics</a>. Elzinga said the main way Culture Amp differentiates is its team of “People Scientists,” or organizational and behavioral psychologists who design surveys, work in its product team as analysts and serve as consultants for clients.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CdNqu1gv0y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/qualtrics-ipo-everything-you-need-to-know/">The long road to the Qualtrics IPO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The long road to the Qualtrics IPO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/qualtrics-ipo-everything-you-need-to-know/embed/#?secret=CdNqu1gv0y" data-secret="CdNqu1gv0y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We see ourselves at the point now where we have enough data that we can start to do primary research on a lot of these issues and we’re looking at how can the data we are developing help inform the space in general, not just ‘here’s what our customers are doing,’ but research that shows how this correlates to that in a situation,” said Elzinga. “The people science component is a hugely important to us.”</p>
<p>In a statement about its investment in Culture Amp, TDM Growth Partners co-founder Hamish Corlett said, “Organizations are living in a world of unprecedented change, and the last 12 months have only accelerated this. We have seen first hand the power that Culture Amp’s unrivaled data set and unique insights have inside boardrooms globally, and we expect this only to amplify in the coming years.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tR5ZleIwYL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/06/optimize-employee-onboarding-to-better-retain-top-talent/">Optimize employee onboarding to better retain top talent</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Optimize employee onboarding to better retain top talent&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/06/optimize-employee-onboarding-to-better-retain-top-talent/embed/#?secret=tR5ZleIwYL" data-secret="tR5ZleIwYL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/employee-engagement-platform-culture-amp-raises-100m-at-a-1-5b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2182944</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exo secures $200M toward commercializing ultrasound device</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/exo-secures-200m-toward-commercializing-ultrasound-device/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/exo-secures-200m-toward-commercializing-ultrasound-device/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackRock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eXo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical equipment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical imaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sands Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ultrasound]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Exo, pronounced “echo,” is commercializing its handheld ultrasound device and point-of-care workflow platform, Exo Works.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.exo.inc/">Exo</a>, pronounced “echo,” raised a fresh cash infusion of $220 million in Series C financing aimed at commercializing its handheld ultrasound device and point-of-care workflow platform, Exo Works.</p>
<p>The round was led by RA Capital Management, while BlackRock, Sands Capital, Avidity Partners, Pura Vida Investments and prior investors joined in.</p>
<p>The new funding gives the Redwood City, California-based company over $320 million in total investments since the company was founded in 2015, Exo CEO Sandeep Akkaraju told TechCrunch. This includes a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/20/exo-raised-40-million-for-its-handheld-medical-imaging-device/">$40 million investment</a> raised in 2020.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Ultrasound machines can cost anywhere from $40,000 to $250,000 for low-end technology and into the millions for high-end machines. Meanwhile, Exo’s device will be around the cost of a laptop.</p>
<p>“It is clear to us that ultrasound is the future — it is nonradiating and has no harmful side effects,” Akkaraju said. “We want to take the technology and put it in the palms of physicians. We also want to bring it down to the patient level. The beauty of having this window into the body is you can immediately see things.”</p>
<p>Using a combination of artificial intelligence, medical imaging and silicon technology, the device enables users to use it in a number of real-world medical environments like evaluating cardiology patients or scanning lungs of a COVID-19 patient. It can also be used by patients at home to provide real-time insight following a surgical procedure or to monitor a certain condition.</p>
<p>Exo then adds in its Exo Works, the workflow platform, that streamlines exam review, documentation and billing in under one minute.</p>
<p>Akkaraju said the immediate focus of the company is commercializing the device, which is where most of the new funding will go. He intends to also build out its informatics platform that is being piloted across the country and to ramp up both production and its sales force.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.medgadget.com/2019/10/point-of-care-ultrasound-market-2019-deep-analysis-of-current-trends-and-future-demand-by-top-key-players-are-analogic-canon-medical-systems-usa-inc-esaote-b-braun-medical-ge-healthcare.html">global point-of-care ultrasound market</a> is expected to reach $3.1 billion by 2025 and will grow 5% annually over that period. In addition to physicians, Akkaraju is hearing from other hospital workers that they, too, want to use the ultrasound device for some of their daily tasks like finding the right vein for an IV.</p>
<p>Once the company’s device is approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration, Exo will move forward with its plan to bring the handheld ultrasound device to market.</p>
<p>Zach Scheiner, principal with RA Capital Management, said he met the Exo team in 2020 and RA made its first investment in the Series B extension later that year.</p>
<p>He was “immediately compelled” by the technology and the opportunity to scale. Scheiner also got to know Akkaraju over the months as well as saw how Exo’s technology was improving.</p>
<p>“We are seeing an expanding opportunity in healthcare technology as it improves and costs go down,” he added. “The vision Sandeep has of democratizing the ultrasound is not a vision that was possible 15 or 20 years ago. We are seeing the market in its early stage, but we also recognize the potential. Every doctor should want one to see what they were not able to see before. As technology and biology improves, we are going to see this sector grow.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jGAiI9ElWP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/05/rd-roundup-ultrasound-ai-imaging-assistive-exoskeleton/">R&#038;D Roundup: Ultrasound/AI medical imaging, assistive exoskeletons and neural weather modeling</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;R&#038;D Roundup: Ultrasound/AI medical imaging, assistive exoskeletons and neural weather modeling&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/05/rd-roundup-ultrasound-ai-imaging-assistive-exoskeleton/embed/#?secret=jGAiI9ElWP" data-secret="jGAiI9ElWP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/exo-secures-200m-toward-commercializing-ultrasound-device/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183165</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Homebase raises $71M for a team management platform aimed at SMBs and their hourly workers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/homebase-raises-71m-for-a-team-management-platform-aimed-at-smbs-and-their-hourly-workers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/homebase-raises-71m-for-a-team-management-platform-aimed-at-smbs-and-their-hourly-workers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Small and medium enterprises have become a big opportunity in the world of B2B technology in the last several years, and today a startup that&#8217;s building tools aimed at helping them manage their teams of workers is announcing some funding that underscores the state of that market. Homebase, which provides a platform that helps SMBs [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Small and medium enterprises have become a big opportunity in the world of B2B technology in the last several years, and today a startup that&#8217;s building tools aimed at helping them manage their teams of workers is announcing some funding that underscores the state of that market. <a href="https://joinhomebase.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Homebase</a>, which provides a platform that helps SMBs manage various services related to their hourly workforces, has closed $71 million in funding, a Series C that values the company at between $500 million and $600 million, according to sources close to the startup.</p>
<p>The round has a number of big names in it that are as much a sign of how large VCs are valuing the SMB market right now, as it is of the strategic interest of the individuals who are also participating. GGV Capital is leading the round, with past backers Bain Capital Ventures, Baseline Ventures, Bedrock, Cowboy Ventures, and Khosla Ventures also participating. Individuals meanwhile include president of Focus Brands Kat Cole, Jocelyn Mangan (a board member at PapaJohns and Chownow and former COO of Snag), former CFO of payroll and benefits company Gusto Mike Dinsdale, Guild Education founder Rachel Carlson, star athletes Jrue and Lauren Holiday and alright alright alright actor and famous everyman and future political candidate Matthew McConaughey.</p>
<p>Homebase has raised $108 million to date.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding is coming on the heels of strong growth for Homebase (which is not to be confused with the UK/Irish <a href="https://www.homebase.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">home improvement chain of the same name</a>, nor the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/yc-backed-homebase-is-an-alternative-to-traditional-mortgages-for-home-buyers-in-vietnam/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YC-backed Vietnamese proptech startup</a>).</p>
<p>The company now has some 100,000 small businesses, with 1 million employees in total, on its platform, which use Homebase to manage all manner of activities related to workers that are paid hourly, including (most recently) payroll, as well as shift scheduling, timeclocks and timesheets, hiring and onboarding, communication, and HR compliance.</p>
<p>John Waldmann, Homebase&#8217;s founder and CEO, said the funding will go towards both continuing to bring on more customers, as well as expand the list of services offered to them, which could include more features geared to front-line and service workers, as well as features for small businesses who might also have some &#8220;desk&#8221; workers who might still work hourly.</p>
<p>The common thread, Waldmann said, is not the exact nature of those jobs, but the fact that all of them, partly because of that hourly aspect, have been largely underserved by tech up to now.</p>
<p class="p5">&#8220;From the beginning, our mission was to help local businesses and their teams,&#8221; he said. Part of his inspiration he said came from people he knew: a childhood friend who owned an independent, expanding restaurant chain, and was going through the challenges of managing his teams there, carrying out most of his work on paper; and his sister who<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> worked in hospitality, which didn’t look all that different from his restaurant friend&#8217;s challenges. She had to call in to see when she was working, writing her hours in a notebook to make sure she got paid accurately. </span></p>
<p class="p5">&#8220;There are a lot of tech companies focused on making work easier for folks that sit at computers or desks, but are building tools for these others,&#8221; Waldmann said. &#8220;In the world of work, the experience just looks different with technology.&#8221;</p>
<p>Homebase currently is focused on the North American market &#8212; there are some 5 million small businesses in the U.S. alone, and so there is a lot of opportunity there. The <a href="https://joinhomebase.com/data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">huge pressure that many them have experienced</a> in the last 18 months of Covid-19 living, leading some to shut down altogether, has also focused the mind on how to manage and carry out work much more efficiently and in a more organized way to ensure you know where your staff is, and that your staff knows what it should be doing at all times.</p>
<p>What will be interesting is to see what kinds of services Homebase adds to its platform over time: in a way it&#8217;s a sign of how the hourly wage workers are becoming a more sophisticated and salient aspect of the workforce, with their own unique demands. Payroll, which is now live in 27 states, also comes with pay advances, opening the door to other kinds of financial services for Homebase, for example.</p>
<p class="p5">“Small businesses are the lifeblood of the American economy, with more than 60% of Americans employed by one of our 30 million small businesses. In a post-pandemic world, technology has never been more important to businesses of all sizes, including SMBs,” said Jeff Richards, managing aartner at GGV Capital and new Homebase board member, in a statement. “The team at Homebase has worked tirelessly for years to bring technology to SMBs in a way that helps drive increased profitability, better hiring and growth. We’re thrilled to see Homebase playing such an important role in America’s small business recovery and thrilled to be part of the mission going forward.”</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">It&#8217;s interesting to see McConaughey involved in this round, given that he&#8217;s most recently made a turn towards politics, with plans to run for governor of Texas in 2022. “Hard working people who work in and run restaurants and local businesses are important to all of us,&#8221; he said in a statement. “They play an important role in giving our cities a sense of livelihood, identity, and community. This is why I’ve invested in Homebase. Homebase brings small business operations into the modern age and helps folks across the country not only continue to work harder, but work smarter.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/homebase-raises-71m-for-a-team-management-platform-aimed-at-smbs-and-their-hourly-workers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183537</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>European Investment Fund puts $30M in Fabric Ventures&#8217; new $130M digital assets fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/european-investment-fund-puts-30m-in-fabric-ventures-new-120m-digital-assets-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/european-investment-fund-puts-30m-in-fabric-ventures-new-120m-digital-assets-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 09:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accelerator Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chinese Communist Party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earlybird]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Investment Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fabric Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[felix capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Railsbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RPX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sun Microsystems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[verifone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoyo wallet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2182624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite their rich engineering talent, Blockchain entrepreneurs in the EU often struggle to find backing due to the dearth of large funds and investment expertise in the space. But a big move takes place at an EU level today, as the European Investment Fund makes a significant investment into a blockchain and digital assets venture [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Despite their rich engineering talent, Blockchain entrepreneurs in the EU often struggle to find backing due to the dearth of large funds and investment expertise in the space. But a big move takes place at an EU level today, as the European Investment Fund makes a significant investment into a blockchain and digital assets venture fund.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.fabric.vc/">Fabric Ventures</a>, a Luxembourg-based VC billed as backing the “Open Economy” has closed $130 million for its 2021 fund, $30 million of which is coming from the European Investment Fund (EIF). Other backers of the new fund include 33 founders, partners, and executives from Ethereum, (Transfer)Wise, PayPal, Square, Google, PayU, Ledger, Raisin, Ebury, PPRO, NEAR, Felix Capital, LocalGlobe, Earlybird, Accelerator Ventures, Aztec Protocol, Raisin, Aragon, Orchid, MySQL, Verifone, OpenOcean, Claret Capital, and more. </p>
<p>This makes it the first EIF-backed fund mandated to invest in digital assets and blockchain technology.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>EIF Chief Executive Alain Godard said:  “We are very pleased to be partnering with Fabric Ventures to bring to the European market this fund specializing in Blockchain technologies… This partnership seeks to address the need [in Europe] and unlock financing opportunities for entrepreneurs active in the field of blockchain technologies &#8211; a field of particular strategic importance for the EU and our competitiveness on the global stage.”</p>
<p>The subtext here is that the EIF wants some exposure to these new, decentralized platforms, potentially as a bulwark against the centralized platforms coming out of the US and China.</p>
<p>And yes, while the price of Bitcoin has yo-yo’d, there is now $100 billion invested in the decentralized finance sector and $1.5 billion market in the NFT market. This technology is going nowhere.</p>
<p>Fabric hasn’t just come from nowhere, either. Various Fabric Ventures team members have been involved in Orchestream, the Honeycomb Project at Sun Microsystems, Tideway, RPX, Automic, Yoyo Wallet, and Orchid.</p>
<p>Richard Muirhead is Managing Partner, and is joined by partners Max Mersch and Anil Hansjee. Hansjee becomes General Partner after leaving PayPal’s Venture Fund, which he led for EMEA. The team has experience in token design, market infrastructure, and community governance.</p>
<p>The same team started the Firestartr fund in 2012, backing Tray.io, Verse, Railsbank, Wagestream, Bitstamp, and others.</p>
<p>Muirhead said: “It is now well acknowledged that there is a need for a web that is user-owned and, consequently, more human-centric. There are astonishing people crafting this digital fabric for the benefit of all. We are excited to support those people with our latest fund.”</p>
<p>On a call with TechCrunch Muirhead added: “The thing to note here is that there&#8217;s a recognition at European Commission level, that this area is one of geopolitical significance for the EU bloc. On the one hand, you have the ‘wild west’ approach of North America, and, arguably, on the other is the surveillance state of the Chinese Communist Party.”</p>
<p>He said: “The European Commission, I think, believes that there is a third way for the individual, and to use this new wave of technology for the individual. Also for businesses. So we can have networks and marketplaces of individuals sharing their data for their own benefit, and businesses in supply chains sharing data for their own mutual benefits. So that&#8217;s the driving view.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/european-investment-fund-puts-30m-in-fabric-ventures-new-120m-digital-assets-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2182624</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coralogix logs $55M for its new take on production analytics, now valued at $300-$400M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/coralogix-logs-55m-for-its-new-take-on-production-analytics-now-valued-at-300-400m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/coralogix-logs-55m-for-its-new-take-on-production-analytics-now-valued-at-300-400m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 08:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coralogix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data observability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Data may be the new oil, but it&#8217;s only valuable if you make good use of it. Today, a startup that has built a new kind of production analytics platform for developers, security engineers and data scientists to track and better understand how data is moving around their networks is announcing a round of funding [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Data may be the new oil, but it&#8217;s only valuable if you make good use of it. Today, a startup that has built a new kind of production analytics platform for developers, security engineers and data scientists to track and better understand how data is moving around their networks is announcing a round of funding that underscores the demand for their technology. <a href="https://coralogix.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Coralogix</a>, which provides stateful streaming services to engineering teams, has picked up $55 million in a Series C round of funding.</p>
<p class="p3">The round was led by Greenfield Partners, with Red Dot Capital Partners, StageOne Ventures, Eyal Ofer’s &#8211; O.G. Tech, Janvest Capital Partners, Maor ventures, and 2B Angels also participating.</p>
<p>This Series C is coming about 10 months after the company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/coralogix-lands-25m-series-b-to-rethink-log-analysis-and-monitoring/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Series B of $25 million</a>, and from what we understand Coralogix&#8217;s valuation is now in the range of $300 million &#8211; $400 million, a big jump for the startup, coming on the back of it growing 250% since this time last year, racking up some 2,000 paying customers, some small teams paying as little as $100/year through to large enterprises paying $1.5 million/year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Previously, Coralogix &#8212; founded in Tel Aviv and with a HQ also in San Francisoc &#8212; had also raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/26/coralogix-announces-10m-series-a-to-bring-more-intelligence-to-logging/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">round of $10 million</a>.</p>
<p class="p6">Coralogix got its start initially as a platform aimed at quality assurance support for R&amp;D and engineering teams. The focus here is on log analytics and metrics for platform engineers, and this still forms a big part of its business today. Added to that, in recent years, Coralogix&#8217;s tools are also being applied to cloud security services, contributing to a company&#8217;s threat intelligence by providing a way to observe data for any inconsistencies that typically might point to a breach or another incident. (It integrates with Alien Vault and others for this purpose.)</p>
<p>The third area that is just picking up now and will be developed further &#8212; one of the uses of this investment, in fact &#8212; will be to develop how Coralogix is used for business intelligence. This is a particularly interesting area because it plays into how Coralogix is built, to provide analytics on data before it is indexed.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s about high volume, but low value data,&#8221; Ariel Assaraf, Coralogix&#8217;s CEO, said in an interview. &#8220;Customers don’t want to store the data [or index it] but want to view it live and visualize it. We are starting to see a use case where business information and our analytics come together for sentiment analysis and other areas.&#8221;</p>
<p>There are dozens of strong companies providing tools these days to cover log analytics and data observability, underscoring the general growth and importance of DevOps these days. They include companies like DataDog, Sumo Logic, Splunk and more.</p>
<p>However, Assaraf believes that what sets his company apart from them is its approach: essentially it has devised a way of observing and analyzing data streams before they get indexed, giving engineers a more flexibility to query the data in different ways, and essentially glean more insights, faster. The other issue with indexing, he said, is that it impacts latency, which also has a big impact on overall costs for an organization.</p>
<p>For many of Coralogix&#8217;s competitors, turning around the nature of the business to focus not first on indexing would be akin to completely rebuilding the business, hard to do at their scale (although in fact this is what Coralogix did, when it pivoted as a small company several years ago, which is when Assaraf took on the role of CEO). One company he believes might be more of a direct rival is Confluent.</p>
<p class="p6">&#8220;I think we will see Confluent getting into observability very soon because they have the streaming capabilities,&#8221; he said, &#8220;but not the tools we have.&#8221; Another potential competitor looming on the horizon: Salesforce, and its potential move into that area, underscores the shifting sands of what is powering enterprise IT investment decisions today.</p>
<p>Salesforce already has Heroku, Slack and Tableau, three major tools developers use for tracking and working with data, Assaraf pointed out, and there were strong rumors of it trying to buy DataDog, &#8220;so we definitely see where they are going. For sure, they understand the way things are changing. All the budgets when Salesforce first started were in marketing and sales. Now you sell to IT. Salesforce understands that shift to developers, and so that is where they are going.&#8221;</p>
<p>It makes for a very interesting landscape and future for companies like Coralogix, one that investors believe the startup will continue to shape as it has up to now.</p>
<p class="p3">“The <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span>dramatic shift in digital transformation is generating an explosion of data, which until now has forced enterprises to decide between cost and coverage,” said Shay Grinfeld, managing partner at Greenfield Partners. “Coralogix’s real-time streaming analytics <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span>pipeline employs proprietary algorithms to break this tradeoff and generate significant cost savings. Coralogix has built a customer roster that comprises some of the largest and most innovative companies in the world. We’re thrilled to partner with Ariel and the Coralogix team on their journey to reinvent the future of data observability.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/coralogix-logs-55m-for-its-new-take-on-production-analytics-now-valued-at-300-400m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183534</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Connected car insurance startup Flock raises $17M Series A led by Chamath Palihapitiya</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/connected-car-insurance-startup-flock-raises-17m-series-a-led-by-chamath-palihapitiya/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/connected-car-insurance-startup-flock-raises-17m-series-a-led-by-chamath-palihapitiya/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 08:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chamath Palihapitiya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulesoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social + capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telematics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cast your mind back to that scene in Minority Report where all those autonomous cars are whizzing through the city. The more practically-minded of you may well have gone: “Yeah, but what about the insurance&#8230;?”. Among the startups building the on-demand, connected insurance world for the vehicles of tomorrow right now are UK-based Zego which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Cast your mind back to that scene in Minority Report where all those autonomous cars are whizzing through the city. The more practically-minded of you may well have gone: “Yeah, but what about the insurance&#8230;?”.</p>
<p>Among the startups building the on-demand, connected insurance world for the vehicles of tomorrow right now are UK-based <a href="http://Zego.com">Zego</a> which has <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/zegocover">raised</a> $201.7 million. Another is <a href="http://flockcover.com/">Flock</a>.</p>
<p>Emerging from an academic project to look at drones, Flock shifted into providing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/29/flock-raises-2-25m-for-its-on-demand-drone-insurance/">drones insurance</a> then commercial vehicle insurance. The twist is that it hooks into the telematics of cars so that the vehicle only triggers insurance cover when it’s actually moving, not when it’s sitting on the lot, incapable of causing any accidents.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Flock has now raised $17 million in a Series A funding led by Social Capital, the investment vehicle run by Chamath Palihapitiya, best known as a SPAC investor and Chairman of Virgin Galactic. Flock&#8217;s existing investors Anthemis and Dig Ventures also participated. This round brings Flock&#8217;s total funding to $22 million. Justin Saslaw (Social Capital’s Fintech Partner) joins Flock’s Board of Directors as does Ross Mason (Founder of Dig Ventures &amp; MuleSoft).</p>
<p>Ed Leon Klinger, CEO of Flock said: &#8220;Transportation is changing faster than ever, but the traditional insurance industry can&#8217;t keep up! The proliferation of electric cars, new business models such as ridesharing, and the emergence of autonomous vehicles pose huge challenges that traditional insurers just aren&#8217;t equipped for.”</p>
<p>He added: “Modern fleets need an equally modern insurance company that moves as fast as they do. Commercial motor insurance is a $160Bn market, crying out for disruption. The opportunity ahead of us is enormous.”</p>
<p>In a statement Chamath Palihapitiya, CEO of Social Capital said: “Flock is bridging the gap between today&#8217;s insurance industry and tomorrow&#8217;s transportation realities. By using real-time data to truly understand vehicle risk, Flock is meeting the demands of our rapidly evolving, hyper-connected world. Flock has the potential to help unlock and enable a truly autonomous world, and even save lives. We&#8217;re excited to be a part of their journey.&#8221;</p>
<p>Speaking to me over a call, Klinger outlined how the company had hit a sweet spot by hooking into Telematics APIs for cars, or by doing special integrations with existing providers and OEMs: “We&#8217;ve built our own integrated approach whereby we partner with some and we build bespoke integrations with them. Often they are not as advanced as others. So we&#8217;ll either use our integration platform or or we&#8217;ll use their approach. We’re highly flexible. The core value proposition at Flock is its flexibility, so we don&#8217;t force our own integration approach.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/connected-car-insurance-startup-flock-raises-17m-series-a-led-by-chamath-palihapitiya/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183054</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unmuted founder Max van den Ingh on success beyond the metrics</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/unmuted-founder-max-van-den-ingh-on-success-beyond-the-metrics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/unmuted-founder-max-van-den-ingh-on-success-beyond-the-metrics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 05:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2181761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["You have to understand that working at a startup often feels like you’re standing on the edge of a cliff. And that’s also the moment you’re at your most creative."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There is no authoritative playbook for marketing these days. Every company must find its own voice, and as it grows and evolves, its marketing needs to evolve as well.</p>
<p>Relying on proven tactics and measurable metrics isn&#8217;t enough — today, the most effective marketers constantly study and learn from innovative approaches while exploring new avenues.</p>
<p>This is where <a href="https://www.unmuted.com/">Unmuted</a> comes in. A growth marketing agency based in Amsterdam, this company focuses on LinkedIn marketing, content marketing, marketing automation and email marketing. Before starting Unmuted, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxvandeningh/">Max van den Ingh</a> was head of growth and product at MisterGreen, an electric vehicle leasing company, and he also served as head of growth marketing at ShopPop, a chat-based marketing platform.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Van den Ingh, who also serves as a guest lecturer at Nyenrode Business University, was recommended to TechCrunch through the TechCrunch Experts project. We’re currently on the lookout for top-tier growth marketers that you can recommend to other startups. If you know of one, let us know by filling out this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">quick survey</a>.</p>
<p>Van den Ingh spoke with us about his “modern” approach to marketing, setting realistic goals, how startups had to shift during the pandemic and more.</p>
<p><em>Editor&#8217;s note: This interview has been edited for length and clarity.</em></p>
<p><strong>You call Unmuted a “modern” growth marketing agency. What do you do that makes your approach to marketing modern?</strong></p>
<p>The way we help our clients is fundamentally different from how most traditional marketing agencies operate. At <a href="https://www.unmuted.com/">Unmuted</a>, our clients don’t come to us to have their ideas executed; they come to us for our process. In a way, we’ve productized a growth marketing process that generates ideas for our clients. They find immense value in that process.</p>
<p>Depending on the customer’s team size and resources, we either guide them during execution or execute autonomously and report back. This process-based service model is, in our opinion, the only way to grow a business in a sustainable way.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			&#8220;The way we help our clients is fundamentally different from how most traditional marketing agencies operate. &#8220;					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>In a practical sense, this is what that process boils down to: We take all that we&#8217;ve learned from fast-growing companies and apply these principles to our clients’ businesses. Typically we focus on what we call &#8220;innovative companies&#8221; — whether that’s because they have a SaaS offering or they’re an innovator within a traditional industry doesn’t really matter. The process we’ve designed works for B2B startups, scaleups and SMBs. That last category can benefit greatly from the way we work.</p>
<p>Our role, then, is threefold: We come up with strategies that we carry out by experimenting with several proven marketing tactics based on our extensive in-house knowledge and experience. This relieves our clients’ marketing teams of potentially stifling tunnel vision.</p>
<p>Our growth program typically unfolds in three stages as well, which we call the Foundation, Acceleration and Transformation stages. In the Foundation stage, we set up the fundamentals based on an extensive audit of the client’s business, and start out with our initial experiments. In the Acceleration stage, we scale the experiments that have shown promising early results. Finally, in the Transformation stage, we teach our clients how to continue growing their business themselves. If necessary, we stick around in a consulting role.</p>
<p><strong>Your work at MisterGreen helped it <a href="https://maxvandeningh.com/about/">grow about 10x</a>. How much can a client expect to grow when working with you? How do you help clients set realistic goals?</strong></p>
<p>Setting goals is always a challenge, especially when it comes to marketing. Why should you aim for a certain number? Why not aim higher, or lower, for that matter? At Unmuted, when we start working with a new client, we perform a series of exercises together. This helps us get a clear picture of where the client is now and where they could be when we’ve optimized marketing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Next, instead of fixed numbers, like a specific amount of new customers in a given period, we focus on growth levers, like month-over-month growth in certain conversion or activation areas. Focusing on growth levers makes our work more actionable.</p>
<p>We then construct a framework as part of our growth program that also allows room for certain beliefs a company has. I feel this &#8220;belief system&#8221; is truly essential to any growth marketing strategy. If you don’t allow room for gut feeling activities and only focus on data-driven projects, you will end up only working on things you can measure. We believe that growth marketing will become more effective when you also invest time and effort in channels and spaces you can’t necessarily measure.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sTkQalyG7q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/25/5-companies-doing-growth-marketing-right/">5 companies doing growth marketing right</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 companies doing growth marketing right&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/25/5-companies-doing-growth-marketing-right/embed/#?secret=sTkQalyG7q" data-secret="sTkQalyG7q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>When people talk about your solution on WhatsApp or during podcast episodes, that’s amazing and will effectively influence revenue, but sometimes there’s just no way to track these activities.</p>
<p>Finally, we don’t make any guarantees when it comes to growth results. That’s not how it works. We’ll always aim to maximize results as part of the process. Diligent focus on continuous improvement and optimization comes first. Results will automatically follow afterward.</p>
<p>For instance, we recently helped a B2B SaaS platform increase demo requests by 350%. But this wasn’t the goal at all. The process we were following was focused on optimizing every aspect of the demo request journey, from acquiring visitors to optimizing the demo page and more. Every experiment we ran increased the demo request metric to some extent. After six months, you start seeing these compounded results.</p>
<p><strong>You were also the head of growth at ShopPop. How did that experience shape the way you help your clients?</strong></p>
<p>Working for a fast-growing B2B SaaS company with a self-serve product taught me quite a few things. For starters, the importance of getting a really clear understanding of what sustainable growth looks like. Especially in growth marketing, there are a lot of things you can do to gain short-term results. But this doesn’t necessarily help, because you might be acquiring customers that you lose in the long run.</p>
<p>For example, running aggressive advertising campaigns in the early stages to acquire new users in sectors that you know won’t benefit considerably from your product. This type of superficial growth will come back in the form of churn sooner rather than later, and simply isn’t sustainable.</p>
<p>At Unmuted, when we start working with a new client, we put a lot of time and effort into understanding their best type of customers, what their problems are, and why that’s the case. Only then do we start looking at how to solve those problems with our client’s products or services.</p>
<p><strong>You’re a guest lecturer at Nyenrode Business University and do speaking engagements as well. What do you hope people take away from your talks? </strong></p>
<p>When I stand in front of a crowd during a speaking engagement, I always share stories about times where I took a pragmatic approach and did things differently. Growth can come in different shapes and forms, and although it often seems simple, it’s never easy. People, and especially management, have to understand that growth takes time and that you need failures to learn.</p>
<p>You need to have conversations to be able to learn and iterate. It’s better to have the wrong type of conversations than not having any at all. Without feedback, there’s no way to grow. And while an eagerness to learn comes naturally to most marketers, this isn’t necessarily the case for your average business person. If I can inspire audiences with my approach to growing by learning, I think that’s a great takeaway.</p>
<p><strong>How have you seen startups change during the pandemic?</strong></p>
<p>A lot of startups have been forced to change their approaches during the pandemic. Some have adapted successfully, while others are now stuck. I experienced it personally when I was still working at ShopPop, where we were focused on the music industry when the pandemic hit.</p>
<p>Music industry clients weren’t buying, for obvious reasons, so we had to pivot somehow. We ended up moving into e-commerce, which was, and still is, booming.</p>
<p><strong>As the pandemic continues, what trends are you seeing in growth marketing?</strong></p>
<p>The biggest trend I’m currently seeing is in the role marketing departments play. These have never been as important as they are now. Digital marketers, especially, are often the ones that come up with new ideas as to how a company can grow online. Nobody will know how the COVID-19 pandemic will play out, but in the meantime, every company is trying to adapt and find new ways to connect with their customers in unique, meaningful ways.</p>
<p>Logically, we’re seeing a surge in demand for online events like webinars and virtual summits. But everybody is doing those. So where can you carve out your own thing that becomes recognizable for your brand? Discovering these new channels and approaches — I think that should be the role of marketing.</p>
<p><strong>How have you seen the startup market develop while working in growth?</strong></p>
<p>The development of the startup market has been most noticeable in how new standards are being set. For example, startups have always been characterized as fast movers, but remote working and the rise of highly collaborative tools have further increased the speed at which startups operate. The whole industry transformed from speedboats into rocket ships. Talent became much more accessible, and through that internal cultures became more diverse and more resilient.</p>
<p>You can always depend on startups adopting new ways of working early on. They need to differentiate in order to survive, and a novel approach can be the one thing that makes them stand out from the crowd.</p>
<p>You have to understand that working at a startup often feels like you’re standing on the edge of a cliff. And that’s also the moment you’re at your most creative. I think this is also how growth marketing as a whole came about. In competitive markets, people have to fight for their right to exist. Marketing is often a way to radically differentiate. When people become really good at that, set new standards and raise the bar, the market develops as a whole.</p>
<p><strong>What do startups continue to get wrong?</strong></p>
<p>It’s been said many times before, but even today, most startups don’t learn quickly and deeply enough. Founders often have an amazing idea and vision of how things will play out. But how much field experience does this person really have? Enough to be able to foresee the future?</p>
<p>Usually, for startups, short-term growth goes well — they get some initial traction from their network, but then the next phase kicks in. Especially when there’s an investment involved, putting more pressure on the commercial side of things, this next phase will mean encountering a lot of hurdles.</p>
<p>When a company doesn’t find a strong enough product-market fit and doesn&#8217;t apply what its learned early on, things will get extremely tough. In this phase, a lot of research and experimentation is necessary. If the founding team isn&#8217;t up for this and they put their heads in the sand, the startup will deteriorate quickly.</p>
<p><strong>On the other side: What are startups doing better now than ever before?</strong></p>
<p>The best thing a startup can do, and I’m seeing it happen more and more, is investing in community early on. When I was leading growth at MisterGreen, we created a community for the first thousand Tesla Model 3 owners in the Netherlands. Everyone wanted to be a part of this founding tribe, learn from each other, get insights and so on.</p>
<p>This group turned out to be our most effective marketing tool. Word-of-mouth went through the roof. We had all of these people talking about our community at birthday parties, in their office, you name it. This is a great example of investing in marketing you can’t really measure, but which you do strongly believe in.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aeRaoUxGqg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/">Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/embed/#?secret=aeRaoUxGqg" data-secret="aeRaoUxGqg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/unmuted-founder-max-van-den-ingh-on-success-beyond-the-metrics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2181761</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Japanese sneaker platform SODA raises $56.4M, acquires rival Monokabu</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/japanese-sneaker-platform-soda-raises-56-4m-accquires-rival-monokabu/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/japanese-sneaker-platform-soda-raises-56-4m-accquires-rival-monokabu/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 01:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monokabu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sneakers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SNKRDUNK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Ventures Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2182998</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just half a year after leading SODA’s Series B, SoftBank Ventures Asia is raising its bet on the Tokyo-based sneaker resell platform. The early-stage venture capital arm of SoftBank Group announced today it has returned to lead SODA’s Series C, which currently totals $56.4 million. Other investors include South Korean sneaker reselling platform KREAM (another [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Just half a year after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/tokyo-based-soda-which-runs-japans-largest-sneaker-resell-platform-lands-22-million-led-by-softbank-ventures-asia/">leading SODA’s Series B</a>, SoftBank Ventures Asia is raising its bet on the Tokyo-based sneaker resell platform. The early-stage venture capital arm of SoftBank Group announced today it has returned to lead <a href="https://soda-inc.jp/">SODA</a>’s Series C, which currently totals $56.4 million.</p>
<p>Other investors include South Korean sneaker reselling platform KREAM (another SoftBank Ventures Asia portfolio company), Altos Ventures and JAFCO.</p>
<p>Launched in 2018, SODA runs <a href="https://snkrdunk.com/">SNKRDUNK</a>, one of Japan’s largest sneaker reselling platforms with about 2.5 million monthly users. Along with its new funding, SODA announced it has acquired rival <a href="https://monokabu.com/">Monokabu</a>. SODA said that the deal means its share of Japan’s sneaker resale industry is now 80%, making it the market leader by far.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A SoftBank Ventures Asia spokesperson told TechCrunch the fund decided to invest in SODA again because the company&#8217;s growth has increased rapidly since its previous funding. SODA&#8217;s post-money valuation is now about 24 billion JPY, or about $218 million USD.</p>
<p class="p1">Part of SODA&#8217;s Series C funding will also be used to expand into other Asian markets, starting with Indonesia and the Philippines next year because both countries have growing e-commerce markets and a large percentage of Generation Zs, an ideal combination for SNKRDUNK. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7l5I4CajuR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/tokyo-based-soda-which-runs-japans-largest-sneaker-resell-platform-lands-22-million-led-by-softbank-ventures-asia/">Tokyo-based SODA, which runs Japan&#8217;s largest sneaker resell platform, lands $22 million led by SoftBank Ventures Asia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tokyo-based SODA, which runs Japan&#8217;s largest sneaker resell platform, lands $22 million led by SoftBank Ventures Asia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/tokyo-based-soda-which-runs-japans-largest-sneaker-resell-platform-lands-22-million-led-by-softbank-ventures-asia/embed/#?secret=7l5I4CajuR" data-secret="7l5I4CajuR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s previous funding, its $22 million Series B, was announced in January. At the time, Uchiyama told TechCrunch demand for sneakers remained high despite the pandemic&#8217;s economic impact and increased adoption of online shopping also helped drive sales.</p>
<p>SODA claims it hit record sales in May 2021, growing 900% year-over-year. Despite COVID-19, many sneaker C2C marketplaces, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/stockx-ec1/">StockX</a>, have also seen their sales increase.</p>
<p>SNKRDUNK will work closely with KREAM to share knowledge about sneaker authentication, inventory management, logistics and other operations-related areas, with the goal of increasing their share of the Asian sneaker resell market.</p>
<p>In addition to KREAM and SODA, SoftBank Ventures Asia is also an investor in China-based sneaker trading platform Nice.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="I5sgKd6Y9F"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/stockx-ec1/">The StockX EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The StockX EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/stockx-ec1/embed/#?secret=I5sgKd6Y9F" data-secret="I5sgKd6Y9F" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/japanese-sneaker-platform-soda-raises-56-4m-accquires-rival-monokabu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2182998</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter shuttering NY, SF offices in response to new CDC guidelines</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/twitter-shuttering-ny-sf-offices-in-response-to-new-cdc-guidelines/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/twitter-shuttering-ny-sf-offices-in-response-to-new-cdc-guidelines/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just two weeks after reopening its New York and San Francisco offices, social media giant Twitter said Wednesday that it will be closing those offices &#8220;immediately.&#8221; The decision came &#8220;after careful consideration of the CDC&#8217;s updated guidelines, and in light of current conditions,&#8221; a spokesperson said. &#8220;Twitter has made the decision to close our opened [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Just two weeks after reopening its New York and San Francisco offices, social media giant Twitter said Wednesday that it will be closing those offices &#8220;immediately.&#8221;</p>
<p>The decision came &#8220;after careful consideration of the CDC&#8217;s updated guidelines, and in light of current conditions,&#8221; a spokesperson said.</p>
<p>&#8220;Twitter has made the decision to close our opened offices in New York and San Francisco as well as pause future office reopenings, effective immediately. We’re continuing to closely monitor local conditions and make necessary changes that prioritize the health and safety of our Tweeps,&#8221; the spokesperson added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company initially just reopened those offices on July 12. It declined to reveal headcount per office.</p>
<p>The CDC this week <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/27/cdc-to-reverse-indoor-mask-policy-to-recommend-them-for-fully-vaccinated-people-in-covid-hot-spots.html">recommended</a> that fully vaccinated people begin wearing masks indoors again in places with high Covid transmission rates amid concerns about the highly contagious Delta variant.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier today, TechCrunch&#8217;s Brian Heater reported that Google CEO <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/want-to-work-at-a-google-campus-youll-need-to-be-vaccinated/">Sundar Pichai announced</a> that the company will require employees to be vaccinated before returning to work on-site. It was part of a larger letter sent to Google/Alphabet staff that also noted the company will be extending its work-from-home policy through October 18, as the COVID-19 delta variant continues to sweep through the global population.</p>
<p>In a message to TechCrunch, Facebook’s VP of People, Lori Goler, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/facebook-will-require-employees-to-be-vaccinated-before-returning-to-campus/">confirmed a similar policy</a> for the social media behemoth.</p>
<p>Amazon also responded to TechCrunch’s inquiry on the matter, noting, “We strongly encourage Amazon employees and contractors to be vaccinated as soon as COVID-19 vaccines are available to them.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/twitter-shuttering-ny-sf-offices-in-response-to-new-cdc-guidelines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183507</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zuckerberg is turning trillion-dollar Facebook into a &#8216;metaverse&#8217; company, he tells investors</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/zuckerberg-is-turning-trillion-dollar-facebook-into-a-metaverse-company-he-tells-investors/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/zuckerberg-is-turning-trillion-dollar-facebook-into-a-metaverse-company-he-tells-investors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Bosworth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CFO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearable devices]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following the quarterly release of Facebook&#8217;s earnings numbers where the company&#8217;s CFO takes time to walk analysts through the nitty gritty of the company&#8217;s financials, CEO Mark Zuckerberg took a moment to zoom out and wax on the company&#8217;s future goals, specifically calling out his ambitions to turn Facebook into &#8220;a metaverse company.&#8221; &#8220;I wanted [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="1627511151.002000" class="c-virtual_list__item" tabindex="-1" role="listitem" aria-expanded="false" data-qa="virtual-list-item">
<div class="c-message_kit__background c-message_kit__background--hovered p-message_pane_message__message c-message_kit__message" role="document" data-qa="message_container" data-qa-unprocessed="false" data-qa-placeholder="false">
<div class="c-message_kit__hover c-message_kit__hover--hovered" role="document" data-qa-hover="true">
<div class="c-message_kit__actions c-message_kit__actions--default">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__right" data-qa="message_content">
<div class="c-message_kit__blocks c-message_kit__blocks--rich_text">
<div class="c-message__message_blocks c-message__message_blocks--rich_text">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer" data-qa="block-kit-renderer">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper--first">
<div class="p-rich_text_block" dir="auto"><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Following the quarterly release of Facebook&#8217;s earnings numbers where the company&#8217;s CFO takes time to walk analysts through the nitty gritty of the company&#8217;s financials, CEO Mark Zuckerberg took a moment to zoom out and wax on the company&#8217;s future goals, specifically calling out his ambitions to turn Facebook into &#8220;a metaverse company.&#8221;</span></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="1627511152.002200" class="c-virtual_list__item" tabindex="-1" role="listitem" aria-expanded="false" data-qa="virtual-list-item">
<div class="c-message_kit__background p-message_pane_message__message c-message_kit__message" role="document" data-qa="message_container" data-qa-unprocessed="false" data-qa-placeholder="false">
<div class="c-message_kit__hover" role="document" data-qa-hover="true">
<div class="c-message_kit__actions c-message_kit__actions--above">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__left">
<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;I wanted to discuss this now so that you can see the future that we&#8217;re working towards and how our major initiative across the company are going to map to that,&#8221; Zuckerberg said on the call. &#8220;What is the metaverse? It&#8217;s a virtual environment where you can be present with people in digital spaces. You can kind of think of this as an embodied internet that you&#8217;re inside of rather than just looking at.&#8221;</p>
<p>These comments echoed an interview he gave to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588022/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-ceo-metaverse-interview">The Verge</a> last week, detailing some of the company&#8217;s future goals.</p>
<p>The metaverse offers Facebook an opportunity to draw a line between its moonshot efforts and its core business, building a wide-reaching hub that shines on augmented reality and virtual reality platforms but feels just as friendly on mobile and desktop. Zuckerberg&#8217;s definition of metaverse is more broad than some others, but comes down to building a version of the web that feels more like an MMO than a collection of web pages.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_1886645" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1886645" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1886645 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Facebook-Horizon-World-Builder.png" alt="Facebook Horizon World Builder" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Facebook-Horizon-World-Builder.png 1140w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Facebook-Horizon-World-Builder.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Facebook-Horizon-World-Builder.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Facebook-Horizon-World-Builder.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Facebook-Horizon-World-Builder.png?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Facebook-Horizon-World-Builder.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1886645" class="wp-caption-text">Early renders of Facebook&#8217;s Horizon platform. Image via Facebook.</p></div></p>
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__left">
<p>It’s hard to imagine now, but Facebook was late to mobile. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">A decade ago, Facebook’s apps were buggy, crash-prone HTML5 experiences, even as smooth native mobile apps were quickly becoming the standard for major software makers. By 2012, Zuckerberg realized that apps were the future — quickly becoming the present — and the Facebook founder scrambled to turn the company’s attention toward mobile at every level. </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Facebook doesn’t intend to make the same mistake twice. That philosophy first became abundantly clear when the company bought the industry-leading VR hardware maker Oculus in 2014.</span></p>
</div>
<p>“Mobile is the platform of today, and now we’re also getting ready for the platforms of tomorrow,” Zuckerberg said around the time of the two billion dollar acquisition. “Oculus has the chance to create the most social platform ever, and change the way we work, play and communicate.”</p>
<p>Becoming &#8220;a metaverse company&#8221; is a further evolution of this thinking. For many, Roblox has seemed to be the clearest embodiment of the metaverse today &#8212;  a social world where users can jump between virtual experiences while creating their own experiences inside it. It&#8217;s notably not a virtual reality experience instead thriving largely on mobile and desktop. Roblox&#8217;s vision has resonated with investors, the now-public company is worth more than $45 billion &#8212; a fraction of Facebook&#8217;s value but more than almost any other games company in the West.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UcyfCTVvyS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/facebook-buys-studio-behind-roblox-like-crayta-gaming-platform/">Facebook buys studio behind Roblox-like Crayta gaming platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook buys studio behind Roblox-like Crayta gaming platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/facebook-buys-studio-behind-roblox-like-crayta-gaming-platform/embed/#?secret=UcyfCTVvyS" data-secret="UcyfCTVvyS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Facebook has been signaling its continued interest in this space. In June they bought a Roblox-like platform called Crayta for an undisclosed sum, and they&#8217;ve spent much of the last several years buying up a host of VR-focused game studios.</p>
<p>The company has tried to build its own VR-centric social hubs but most have fallen flat. Facebook&#8217;s metaverse-like Horizon platform garnered major headlines when it was announced nearly two years ago, but the company has had little to say during its exceedingly quiet beta period. This week, Facebook&#8217;s Andrew Bosworth <a href="https://www.facebook.com/boz/posts/much-of-the-work-weve-been-doing-at-facebook-reality-labs-connects-deeply-to-the/10113772424752191/">detailed</a> that Gaming VP Vivek Sharma would be taking over the effort under a new metaverse-centric product group led by Instagram&#8217;s Vishal Shah.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a very particular distinction in Facebook&#8217;s choice of rebranding itself as a &#8220;metaverse&#8221; company as opposed to an AR/VR one. While some might have seen specialized hardware as essential to a spatial internet, it&#8217;s become increasingly clear that users aren&#8217;t clamoring to embrace early headsets even as other new gaming platforms greatly accelerate their growth. While the company&#8217;s Quest 2 headset has sold much better than its previous devices &#8212; according to Facebook which has yet to release any hard sales numbers &#8212; it&#8217;s unclear whether they truly need a world full of users with Facebook glasses and headsets strapped to their faces in order to embrace this metaverse ideal &#8212; or whether that would just be the cherry on top.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0OXwyTxJTK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/25/facebook-horizon/">Facebook announces Horizon, a VR massive-multiplayer world</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook announces Horizon, a VR massive-multiplayer world&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/25/facebook-horizon/embed/#?secret=0OXwyTxJTK" data-secret="0OXwyTxJTK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/zuckerberg-is-turning-trillion-dollar-facebook-into-a-metaverse-company-he-tells-investors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183477</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>INKR draws in $3.1M to make more comics accessible to worldwide audiences</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/inkr-draws-in-3-1m-to-make-more-comics-accessible-to-worldwide-audiences/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/inkr-draws-in-3-1m-to-make-more-comics-accessible-to-worldwide-audiences/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital comics platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[INKR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[INKR Comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2182960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[INKR is a digital comics platform that crosses cultural and language divides, enabling creators to reach global audiences with its proprietary localization technology. Previously bootstrapped, the company announced today that it has raised $3.1 million in pre-Series A funding led by Monk’s Hill Ventures, with participation from manga distributor TokyoPop founder and chief executive Stu [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2182961" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_2585.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182961" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2182961" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_2585.jpg" alt="A photo of digital comics platform INKR's team" width="1024" height="411" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_2585.jpg 9736w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_2585.jpg?resize=150,60 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_2585.jpg?resize=300,120 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_2585.jpg?resize=768,308 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_2585.jpg?resize=680,273 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_2585.jpg?resize=1536,616 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_2585.jpg?resize=2048,821 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_2585.jpg?resize=50,20 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2182961" class="wp-caption-text">Digital comics platform INKR&#8217;s team</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://inkr.com/">INKR</a> is a digital comics platform that crosses cultural and language divides, enabling creators to reach global audiences with its proprietary localization technology. Previously bootstrapped, the company announced today that it has raised $3.1 million in pre-Series A funding led by Monk’s Hill Ventures, with participation from manga distributor TokyoPop founder and chief executive Stu Levy.</p>
<p>Headquartered in Singapore with an office in Ho Chi Minh City, INKR was founded in 2019 by Ken Luong, Khoa Nguyen and Hieu Tran. The company says that since it launched in October 2020, its monthly average users have grown 200%. It currently partners with more than 70 content creators and publishers, including FanFan, Image Comics, Kodansha USA, Kuaikan, Mr. Blue, SB Creative, TokyoPop and Toons Family, and has more than 800 titles so far, including manga, webtoons and graphic novels.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Luong, INKR’s CEO, told TechCrunch that the platform will focus first on translated comics from top global publishers, but plans to open to small and indie creators in 2022.</p>
<p>At the heart of INKR’s platform is its localization technology, which the company says reduces the time spent on preparing comics for different markets from days to just hours.</p>
<p>“Comics localization is more than just translation. It is a time-consuming process with many steps involving many people—file handling, transcription, translation, typesetting, sound effects, quality control, etc,” Luong said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2182962" style="width: 460px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/INKR_Screenshot_1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182962" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2182962" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/INKR_Screenshot_1.png" alt="A screenshot with some of the titles on digital comics platform INKR" width="450" height="974" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/INKR_Screenshot_1.png 1242w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/INKR_Screenshot_1.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/INKR_Screenshot_1.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/INKR_Screenshot_1.png?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/INKR_Screenshot_1.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/INKR_Screenshot_1.png?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/INKR_Screenshot_1.png?resize=946,2048 946w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/INKR_Screenshot_1.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2182962" class="wp-caption-text">Some of the titles on INKR</p></div></p>
<p>In addition to language, publishers also have to take into account the differences between comic styles around the world, including Japanese manga, Chinese manhua, Korean manhwa, American comics. For example, comics can be laid out page-by-page or use vertical scrolling. Some languages read from left to right, while others go from right to left.</p>
<p>Luong says INKR’s proprietary AI engine, called INKR Comics Vision, is able to recognize different formats and elements on a comic page, including text, dialogue, characters, facial expressions, backgrounds and panels. INKR Localize, its tool for human translators, helps them deliver accurate translations more quickly by automating tasks like text transcription, vocabulary suggestions and typesetting.</p>
<p>Since localization is performed by teams, including people in different locations, INKR provides them with browser-based collaboration software. The platform supports Japanese-English, Korean-English and Chinese-English translations, with plans to add more languages. Some publishers, like Kuaikan Manhua and Mr. Blue, have used INKR to translate thousands of comic chapters from Chinese and Korean into English.</p>
<p>INKR provides content creators with a choice of monetization models, including ad-supported, subscription fees or pay-per-chapter. Luong says the platform analyzes content to tell publishers which model will maximize their earnings, and shares a percentage of the revenue generated.</p>
<p>INKR is vying for attention with other digital comics platforms like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/04/10/amazon-acquires-digital-comic-book-service-comixology/">Amazon-owned Comixology </a>and Webtoon, the publishing portal operated by Naver Corporation.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JS9WZQt9q8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/04/10/amazon-acquires-digital-comic-book-service-comixology/">Amazon Acquires Digital Comic Book Store Comixology</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon Acquires Digital Comic Book Store Comixology&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/04/10/amazon-acquires-digital-comic-book-service-comixology/embed/#?secret=JS9WZQt9q8" data-secret="JS9WZQt9q8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Luong said INKR’s competitive advantages include the diversity of comics it offers and the affordability of its pricing. Before launching, it also invested in data and AI-based technology for both readers and publishers. For example, users get personalized recommendation based on their reading activity, while publishers can access analytics to track title performance based on consumption trends.</p>
<p>In a statement, Monk’s Hill Ventures general partner Justin Nguyen said INKR’s “proprietary AI-driven platform is addressing pain points for creators and publishers who need to go digital and global—localizing for many languages quickly and cost-effectively while also helping them improve reach and readership through analytics and intelligent personalized feeds. We look forward to partnering with them to quench the huge demand for translated comics globally.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wg2zQ5jzAb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/with-new-owner-naver-wattpad-looks-to-level-up-its-user-generated-ip-factory/">With new owner Naver, Wattpad looks to supercharge its user-generated IP factory</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With new owner Naver, Wattpad looks to supercharge its user-generated IP factory&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/with-new-owner-naver-wattpad-looks-to-level-up-its-user-generated-ip-factory/embed/#?secret=wg2zQ5jzAb" data-secret="wg2zQ5jzAb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tqJiJqW9DN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/19/shadows-dylan-flinn-and-kombos-kevin-gould-on-the-business-of-virtual-influencers/">Shadows&#8217; Dylan Flinn and Kombo&#8217;s Kevin Gould on the business of &#8216;virtual influencers&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Shadows&#8217; Dylan Flinn and Kombo&#8217;s Kevin Gould on the business of &#8216;virtual influencers&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/19/shadows-dylan-flinn-and-kombos-kevin-gould-on-the-business-of-virtual-influencers/embed/#?secret=tqJiJqW9DN" data-secret="tqJiJqW9DN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/inkr-draws-in-3-1m-to-make-more-comics-accessible-to-worldwide-audiences/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2182960</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
