<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 14:36:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Shopify expands its one-click checkout, Shop Pay, to any merchant on Facebook or Google</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/shopify-expands-its-one-click-checkout-shop-pay-to-any-merchant-on-facebook-or-google/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/shopify-expands-its-one-click-checkout-shop-pay-to-any-merchant-on-facebook-or-google/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 14:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merchant Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[E-commerce platform Shopify announced this morning its one-click checkout service known as Shop Pay will become available to any U.S. merchant that sells on Facebook or Google &#8212; even if they don&#8217;t use Shopify&#8217;s software to power their online stores. That makes Shop Pay the first Shopify product offered to non-Shopify merchants, the company notes. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">E-commerce platform Shopify <a href="https://news.shopify.com/shop-pay-becomes-first-shopify-product-to-extend-beyond-shopify-merchants-soon-available-to-any-business-selling-on-facebook-and-google">announced</a> this morning its one-click checkout service known as Shop Pay will become available to any U.S. merchant that sells on Facebook or Google &#8212; even if they don&#8217;t use Shopify&#8217;s software to power their online stores. That makes Shop Pay the first Shopify product offered to non-Shopify merchants, the company notes.</p>
<p>First <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/20/shopify-pay-aims-to-complete-the-picture-for-online-checkout/">introduced</a> at its developer conference in 2017, Shop Pay is similar to other instant checkout solutions that offer an easier way to pay online by reducing the number of fields a customer has to fill out during the checkout process. The service remembers and encrypts the customer&#8217;s information, so consumers can check out with just a tap when shopping online and, as of recently, even <a href="https://news.shopify.com/shop-pay-installments-launches-in-the-us">pay for purchase in installments</a>, thanks to a partnership with Affirm.</p>
<p>Shopify in February had <a href="https://news.shopify.com/shop-pay-expands-to-facebook-and-instagram">expanded</a> Shop Pay to Facebook and Instagram, in partnership with Facebook, but it only worked for existing Shopify merchants selling on those social platforms at the time. In May, Google <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-partners-with-shopify-on-online-shopping-expansion/">announced</a> at its I/O developer conference it was <a href="https://news.shopify.com/from-discovery-to-checkout-shopify-and-google-deepen-commerce-collaboration">partnering</a> with Shopify on an online shopping expansion that would give Shopify&#8217;s more than 1.7 million merchants the ability to reach customers through Google Search and other &#8220;shopping journeys&#8221; that began through other Google properties like Search, Maps, Images, Lens, and YouTube.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company declined to share how many of its 1.7 million merchants are already available on Facebook or Google today, but said they are two of the most popular channels.</p>
<p>Following today&#8217;s announcement, other merchants will also have the option to adopt Shop Pay for their own Facebook or Google stores. While how many will actually do so is yet unknown, Shopify notes that every day 1.8 billion people log onto Facebook and a billion shopping sessions take place across Google.</p>
<p>The company also touted Shop Pay&#8217;s advantages, including its 70% faster checkout than a typical checkout offers, with a 1.72x higher conversion rate &#8212; meaning fewer abandoned charts.</p>
<p>For consumers, the advantage of using Shop Pay over a traditional checkout, beyond the speed, is its integration with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/28/shopify-launches-shop-a-new-mobile-shopping-app/">Shopify&#8217;s mobile app, Shop</a>, which organizes and tracks your online orders across merchants, including Amazon,  so you can see when orders are arriving or quickly ask questions and manage returns.</p>
<p>To date, the Shop app has tracked over 430 million orders, the company says.</p>
<p>Over time, the Shop app can also customize a feed including users&#8217; favorite stores to point to other recommendations, including those from local merchants. Shopify confirmed that the Shop app will be able to track the Shop Pay-enabled orders from the non-Shopify merchants.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since launching, Shop Pay has set the standard for checkout experiences, facilitating more than $24 billion in orders,&#8221; noted Shopify VP, Carl Rivera, who heads Product for Shop. &#8220;According to studies, cart abandonment averages 70%, with nearly 20% occurring because of a complicated checkout process. Shop Pay makes that process fast and simple, and the expansion to all merchants selling on Facebook and Google is a mission-critical step in bringing a best-in-class checkout to every consumer, every merchant, every platform, and every device,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>The expansion could be a notable challenge to other payment mechanisms, including PayPal, Venmo, Apple Pay, and those offered by the platforms themselves, thanks to Shopify&#8217;s growing traction with merchants &#8212; one analysis gives its platform a <a href="https://www.oberlo.com/statistics/ecommerce-platform-market-share-in-usa">23% market share</a> in the U.S &#8212; combined with the popularity of the Shop app, now the No. 3 Shopping app on the App Store.</p>
<p>The news follows yesterday&#8217;s <a href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/business/article-shopify-confirms-significant-investment-in-payment-processor-stripe/">confirmation</a> that Shopify has taken a significant stake in payments giant Stripe, the backbone of the Shop Pay service, as well as Shopify&#8217;s partner on merchant services, including bank accounts and debit cards.</p>
<p>Shopify says the Shop Pay service will be enabled for all U.S. merchants selling on Facebook in the &#8220;coming months,&#8221; and will roll out to all merchants on Google by late 2021.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/shopify-expands-its-one-click-checkout-shop-pay-to-any-merchant-on-facebook-or-google/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166240</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sonos and Ikea’s latest collaboration is a picture frame speaker</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/sonos-and-ikeas-latest-collaboration-is-a-picture-frame-speaker/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/sonos-and-ikeas-latest-collaboration-is-a-picture-frame-speaker/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 14:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ikea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sonos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Symfonisk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following a smattering of leaks, Sonos and Ikea just unveiled the newest addition to their three-year-old Symfonisk line of home speakers. As the name implies, the Picture Frame is a medium-size, flat-panel speaker that can either be mounted on a wall or sat on a shelf via kickstand. As with the rest of the Symfonisk [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Following a smattering of leaks, Sonos and Ikea just unveiled the newest addition to their three-year-old Symfonisk line of home speakers. As the name implies, the Picture Frame is a medium-size, flat-panel speaker that can either be mounted on a wall or sat on a shelf via kickstand.</p>
<p>As with the rest of the Symfonisk line, the product is designed to get out of its own way, and blend in its surroundings. It’s a direction much of the industry has gone in over the last several years, with fabric covers aimed at matching the surrounding décor and more or less fade into the background.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2166255" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2166255" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2166255" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH181053.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH181053.jpg 6400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH181053.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH181053.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH181053.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH181053.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH181053.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH181053.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH181053.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2166255" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Ikea/Sonos</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Picture Frame form factor is another logical extension of this, with a design that doesn’t require clearing off desk space. The front grille is covered in either black or white, with a design created by artist Jennifer Idrizi, which Ikea notes was inspired by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cymatics">cymatics</a> – a visualization of sound vibrations. Fitting and simple, though the company also offers a pair of replacement panels with different designs, at $20.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2166261" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH180308.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1365" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH180308.jpg 3466w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH180308.jpg?resize=113,150 113w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH180308.jpg?resize=225,300 225w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH180308.jpg?resize=768,1024 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH180308.jpg?resize=510,680 510w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH180308.jpg?resize=1152,1536 1152w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH180308.jpg?resize=1536,2048 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-PH180308.jpg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>The Picture Frame itself is $199 – not cheap, exactly, but certainly not unreasonable – especially by Sonos hardware standards. It features built-in WiFi, connects with the rest of Sonos’ hardware and works with 100 different streaming services. There are volume and Play/Pause buttons built in and a number of small touches, like the ability to reconfigure the power cord placement, based on how the frame is positioned.</p>
<p>It’s will be available online and in Ikea stores starting a month from today. The Symfonisk line also includes a lamp speaker and a more traditional rectangular form factor, ranging between $100 and $200.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PwihfChhN6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/25/sonos-and-ikeas-symfonisk-wireless-speakers-are-a-symphony-of-sound-and-design/">Sonos and Ikea&#8217;s Symfonisk wireless speakers are a symphony of sound and design</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sonos and Ikea&#8217;s Symfonisk wireless speakers are a symphony of sound and design&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/25/sonos-and-ikeas-symfonisk-wireless-speakers-are-a-symphony-of-sound-and-design/embed/#?secret=PwihfChhN6" data-secret="PwihfChhN6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/sonos-and-ikeas-latest-collaboration-is-a-picture-frame-speaker/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166252</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SkyWatch raises $17.2M for its Earth observation data platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/skywatch-raises-17-2m-for-its-earth-observation-data-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/skywatch-raises-17-2m-for-its-earth-observation-data-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 14:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bullpen Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drive Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Golden Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inventory management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SatRevolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waterloo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waterloo-based SkyWatch was among the first startups to recognize that the key to unlocking the real benefits of the space economy lay in making Earth observation data accessible and portable, and now the company has raised a $17.2 million Series B to help it further that goal. Fresh on the heals of a partnership with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Waterloo-based <a href="https://www.skywatch.com">SkyWatch</a> was among the first startups to recognize that the key to unlocking the real benefits of the space economy lay in making Earth observation data accessible and portable, and now the company has raised a $17.2 million Series B to help it further that goal. Fresh on the heals of a partnership with Poland-based satellite operator SatRevolution, SkyWatch is now set to bridge the gulf between satellite startups and customers in a bigger way as it lowers the barriers to entry for new companies focused on high-tech spacecraft payloads.</p>
<p>The new round of funding was led by new investor Drive Capital, and included participation from existing investors including Bullpen Capital, Space Capital, Golden Ventures and BDC Ventures. SkyWatch CEO and co-founder James Slifierz told me that bringing Drive on was a major win for the Series B.</p>
<p>&#8220;Drive is a firm that has actually been researching the space industry for a few years now, and looking for an opportunity that would be their first space technology investment,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Not their first in the [GTA-Waterloo] area  they&#8217;re based out of Columbus, Ohio, made up of Silicon Valley veterans. They were a little early to the trend of believing that a majority of the really interesting and large opportunities would eventually evolve outside of the Bay Area and outside of New York City.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>SkyWatch definitely fits the bill, having built strong revenue pipeline for an Earth observation data platform that makes the information collected by the many observation satellites on orbit accessible to private industry, in a way that doesn&#8217;t require re-architecting existing systems or handling huge amounts of data in unfamiliar formats.</p>
<p>This fresh funding will help SkyWatch accelerate the rollout of its TerraStream product, a nw platform that the company developed to provide full-service data management, ordering, processing and delivery for satellite companies. This allows SkyWatch to not only make data collected by Earth observation satellites like those operated by SatRevolution accessible to customers — but also to source customers for those companies, too, effectively handling both sales and delivery, which many satellite startups born from a technical or academic background don&#8217;t start out equipped to tackle.</p>
<p>&#8220;My favorite analogy for TerraStream is it&#8217;s Shopify for space companies,&#8221; Slifierz said. &#8220;It takes away a lot of the complexity of going to market. So if you want to build an amazing shoe brand today, Shopify enables you to not have to worry about the logistics, and shipping, and the inventory management, the website, storefront and all that; it allows you to focus on the things that will build value in your company, which is the quality of your product, and your brand.&#8221;</p>
<p>He added that just like Shopify depends on the existence of a rich third-party ecosystem to support its platform, so does SkyWatch, and that ecosystem is only now reaching maturity after years of infrastructure development, including things like the proliferation of launch startups, ground station build out, data warehousing and more.</p>
<p>Ultimately, what SkyWatch provides is the ability to go to market &#8220;faster and more profitably,&#8221; Slifierz says, which is a major shift for hard tech satellite startups working on new and improved sensor capabilities, often spinning out of research labs at academic institutions.</p>
<p>&#8220;The strongest value proposition is that we give you instant access to hundreds of customers, which we&#8217;re growing at a very fast pace on the EarthCache [SkyWatch&#8217;s commercial satellite imagery marketplace] side. So in that way, we sort of joke, it&#8217;s like Shopify for space, but also integrated with the AWS marketplace.&#8221;</p>
<p>SkyWatch can also actually help identify demand, by providing satellite-side customers with real data to back up signals of what the market is actually looking for. Slifierz says that&#8217;s helped them advised partners on how to tweak their offering to meet a real need, which is beneficial in an industry where research and tech development often lead payload design, with actual demand as a somewhat secondary consideration.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/skywatch-raises-17-2m-for-its-earth-observation-data-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166220</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canadians are polite, but we&#8217;re still recruiting your biotech talent, America</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/canadians-are-polite-but-were-still-recruiting-your-biotech-talent-america/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/canadians-are-polite-but-were-still-recruiting-your-biotech-talent-america/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 14:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCUK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STEM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165578</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Canadian leaders remain concerned about the inbound flow of talent to key sectors like advanced manufacturing, clean tech and biotech. They’re doing all they can to chip away at American advantages.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Michael May</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/michaelmay5">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Michael May is the president and CEO of the<a href="https://www.ccrm.ca/"> Centre for Commercialization of Regenerative Medicine</a>.<br>	</div>
	
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jayson Myers</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jaysonmyers_">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jayson Myers is the CEO of<a href="https://www.ngen.ca/"> Next Generation Manufacturing Canada</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Canada <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/01/27/799402801/canada-wins-u-s-loses-in-global-fight-for-high-tech-workers">made headlines</a> during U.S. President Donald Trump’s administration for its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/technologists-consider-canada/">efforts</a> to <a href="https://fortune.com/2020/06/29/h1b-visa-ban-immigration-trump-order-tech-workers-canada/">lure</a> STEM workers north. Trump is gone now, but Canada hasn’t stopped trying to recruit talent from its neighbor — and one of the hottest fronts in this talent war is biotech.</p>
<p>For generations of Canadian engineers, coders and researchers, Silicon Valley’s better salaries and weather were a siren call. But four years of Trump’s anti-immigration rhetoric, policy and visa restrictions gave Canadian tech companies and governments <a href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/business/commentary/article-how-canada-is-fighting-the-war-on-talent/">a competitive advantage</a>.</p>
<p>After Trump took office in 2016, Canada’s federal government boosted the tech ecosystems of cities like Toronto, Montreal and Vancouver by creating<a href="https://www.canada.ca/en/employment-social-development/services/foreign-workers/global-talent/requirements.html"> a program</a> to fast-track immigration. Canadian tech leaders <a href="https://fortune.com/2020/06/29/h1b-visa-ban-immigration-trump-order-tech-workers-canada/">climbed aboard</a> with <a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/business/article/Canada-to-Silicon-Valley-s-international-15470866.php">campaigns to tempt more workers north</a>. In Quebec, the industry even <a href="https://thelogic.co/news/quebec-ink/quebec-ink-on-immigration-the-caq-government-is-listening-to-tech-entrepreneurs/">persuaded</a> Quebec’s notoriously immigration-shy provincial government to accept as many as 14% more newcomers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The pandemic-driven exodus from Silicon Valley has <a href="https://innovationeconomycouncil.com/wp-content/uploads/IEC-Report-Magnetic-North-Dec-2020.pdf">sent large numbers of Canadian expatriates flocking home</a>. The number of Canadians applying for the U.S. H-1B program has fallen dramatically, accelerating a decade-long trend.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Canadians have been broadly supportive of government spending to beat back COVID-19 and hasten the transition to a new economy.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Still, Canadian tech and political leaders remain concerned about the inbound flow of talent to key sectors like advanced manufacturing, clean tech and biotechnology. They’re pressing every button they can to chip away at long-held American advantages.</p>
<p>Much of the action is in biotech. COVID-19 has exposed Canada’s <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2021/04/canada-vaccine-rollout-problems/618516/">lack of vaccine manufacturing capacity</a>, but the country has a vibrant biotech and life-sciences research sector, driven by an excellent university ecosystem and several thousand startup ventures doing cutting-edge research. Many of these firms have cashed in on the pandemic biotech investment boom, racking in a <a href="https://www.bctechnology.com/news/2020/11/26/Booming-Canadian-Biotech-Sector-on-Track-for-Record-Year-After-Raising-1-Billion-in-Venture-Capital-So-Far-in-2020.cfm">record amount</a> of venture capital in 2020.</p>
<p>But while this influx has changed the funding landscape, many Canadian companies are still trying to reach scale. The Canadian tech ecosystem is full of talent but it hasn’t traditionally developed, recruited and <a href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/business/rob-magazine/article-just-say-ehhhhh-when-it-comes-to-the-lucrative-us-drug-discovery/">retained</a> enough of the senior people these firms need to develop into global powerhouses.</p>
<p>They don’t just need scientists &#8212; they need business leaders. A <a href="https://www.marsdd.com/news/canadas-biotech-and-life-sciences-sector-needs-an-infusion-of-talent-to-scale/">recent survey</a> of Toronto-area hubs and ventures revealed that biomedical engineering, regenerative medicine and related firms are suffering significant shortages of senior executives, top managers and scientific specialists, who gravitate toward the better pay and opportunities of the U.S. industries.</p>
<p>At a recent summit of Canada’s Innovation Economy Council (IEC), which both our organizations belong to, industry leaders spoke of unfilled jobs in global regulatory affairs and business development, even chief medical officers. These are hybrid roles that require the kind of technical and business acumen forged from both academic training and progressive leadership roles in the workplace.</p>
<p>Canadian universities, hubs and <a href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/business/article-programs-target-canadas-chronic-biotech-talent-shortage-by-training/">venture-capital firms</a> are reacting to this need by building specialized training institutes and programs. And scaling Canadian companies are trying to fill the gaps by using newly raised cash to recruit heavily in the U.S. and beyond, offering remote work and flexible work hours while striking partnerships and investigating untapped talent pools.</p>
<p>Against this backdrop, Canada’s federal government just delivered its first full budget in two years. It’s one of the <a href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/business/article-budget-promises-more-funding-for-innovative-technologies-including/">most activist tech-spending plans</a> the country has ever rolled out, showing how seriously the federal government is about building out advanced industries and creating STEM jobs at a time when global markets are moving away from the country’s traditional energy exports, natural resources and manufactured goods. The budget includes college research partnerships, hiring subsidies, grants, and support for incubators and hubs. Critically, there is also a $2.2 billion <a href="https://www.canada.ca/en/department-finance/news/2021/04/budget-2021-building-an-innovation-economy-of-the-future.html">commitment</a> for building a life-sciences talent pipeline.</p>
<p>Canadians have been broadly supportive of government spending to beat back COVID-19 and hasten the transition to a new economy. An IEC/Campaign Research poll conducted in early April found 3:1 public support for investments in postsecondary STEM education and similarly strong support for government investment in advanced manufacturing, including biotech. That’s just what it takes to compete with a neighbor 10 times your size.</p>
<p>It’s fair to say that Canada won’t drain the U.S. of all its research scientists and Big Pharma CEOs anytime soon. But with an influx of investment capital, a burgeoning tech ecosystem and a concerted policy effort to build, recruit and retain a self-sustaining talent ecosystem, it’s flying under the radar as a place the industry increasingly wants to be.</p>
<p>In other words, America, take note: Canada is actively working to attract your biotech talent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/canadians-are-polite-but-were-still-recruiting-your-biotech-talent-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165578</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edge computing startup Macrometa gets $20M Series A led by Pelion Venture Partners</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/edge-computing-startup-macrometa-gets-20m-series-a-led-by/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/edge-computing-startup-macrometa-gets-20m-series-a-led-by/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edge computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Macrometa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serverless computing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Macrometa, the edge computing cloud and global data network for app developers, announced today it has raised a $20 million Series A. The round was led by Pelion Venture Partners, with participation from returning investors DNX Ventures (the Japan and US-focused enterprise fund that led Macrometa’s seed round), Benhamou Global Ventures (BGV), Partech Partners, Fusion [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.macrometa.com/">Macrometa</a>, the edge computing cloud and global data network for app developers, announced today it has raised a $20 million Series A. The round was led by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/14/pelion-venture-partners-adds-jeff-kearl-as-a-managing-director-opens-southern-california-presence/">Pelion Venture Partners</a>, with participation from returning investors DNX Ventures (the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/dnx-ventures-launches-315-million-fund-for-u-s-and-japanese-b2b-startups/">Japan and US-focused enterprise fund </a>that led Macrometa’s seed round), Benhamou Global Ventures (BGV), Partech Partners, Fusion Fund, Sway Ventures and Shasta Ventures.</p>
<p>The startup, which is headquartered in Palo Alto with operations in Bulgaria and India, plans to use its Series A on feature development, acquiring more enterprise customers and integrating with content delivery networks (CDN), cloud and telecom providers. It will hire for its engineering and product development centers in the United States, Eastern Europe and India, and add new centers in Ukraine, Portugal, Greece, Mexico and Argentina.</p>
<p>The company’s last round of funding, an $7 million seed, was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/macrometa-an-edge-computing-service-for-app-developers-lands-7m-seed-round-led-by-dnx/">announced just eight months ago</a>. Its Series A brings Macrometa’s total raised since its was founded in 2017 to $29 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Sz80ZcQdo3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/macrometa-an-edge-computing-service-for-app-developers-lands-7m-seed-round-led-by-dnx/">Macrometa, an edge computing service for app developers, lands $7 million seed round led by DNX</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Macrometa, an edge computing service for app developers, lands $7 million seed round led by DNX&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/macrometa-an-edge-computing-service-for-app-developers-lands-7m-seed-round-led-by-dnx/embed/#?secret=Sz80ZcQdo3" data-secret="Sz80ZcQdo3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As part of the new round, Macrometa expanded its board of directors, adding Pelion general partner Chris Cooper as a director, and Pelion senior associate Zain Rizavi and DNX Ventures principal Eva Nahari as board observers.</p>
<p>Macrometa’s global data network combines a globally distributed noSQL database and a low-latency stream data processing engine, enabling web and cloud develops to run and scale data-heavy, real-time cloud applications. The network allows developers to run apps concurrently across its 175 points of presence (PoPs), or edge regions, around the world, depending on which one is closest to an end user. Macrometa claims that the mean roundtrip time (RTT) for users on laptops or phones to its edge cloud and back is less than 50 milliseconds globally, or 50x to 100x faster than cloud platforms like DyanmoDB, MongoDB or Firebase.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2165509" style="width: 460px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2165509" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2165509" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg?w=680" alt="A photo of Macrometa co-founder and CEO Chetan Venkatesh" width="450" height="449" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg 708w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg?resize=680,678 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chetan-Venkatesh-Macrometa-1.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2165509" class="wp-caption-text">Macrometa co-founder and CEO Chetan Venkatesh</p></div></p>
<p>Since its seed round last year, the company has accelerated its customer acquisition, especially among large global enterprises and web scale players, co-founder and chief executive officer Chetan Venkatesh told TechCrunch. Macrometa also made its self-service platform available to developers, who can try its serverless database, pub/sug, event processing and stateful compute runtime for free.</p>
<p>Macrometa recently became one of two distributed data companies (the other one is Fauna) <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/partnership-announcement-db/">partnered with Cloudflare</a> for developers building new apps on Workers, its serverless application platform. Venkatesh said the combination of Macrometa and Cloudflare Workers enables data-driven APIs and web services to be 50x to 100x faster in performance and lower latency compared to the public cloud.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="csheX9vqeB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/27/cloudflare-launches-workers-unbound-the-next-evolution-of-its-serverless-platform/">Cloudflare launches Workers Unbound, the next evolution of its serverless platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cloudflare launches Workers Unbound, the next evolution of its serverless platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/27/cloudflare-launches-workers-unbound-the-next-evolution-of-its-serverless-platform/embed/#?secret=csheX9vqeB" data-secret="csheX9vqeB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic accelerated Macrometa’s business significantly, said Venkatesh, because its enterprise and web scale customers needed to handle the unpredictable data traffic patterns created by remote work. The pandemic also “resulted in several secular and permanent shifts in cloud adoption and consumption,” he added, changing how people shop, consume media, content and entertainment. That has “exponentially increased the need for handling dynamic bursts of demands for application infrastructure securely,” he said.</p>
<p>One example of how enterprise clients use Macrometa is e-commerce providers who implemented its infrastructure with their existing CDN and cloud backends to provide more data and AI-based personalization for shoppers, including real-time recommendations, regionalized search at the edge and local data geo-fencing to comply with data and privacy regulations.</p>
<p>Some of Macrometa’s SaaS clients use its global data network as a global data cache for handling surges in usage and keep regional copies of data and API results across its regional data centers. Venkatesh added that several large telecom operators have used Macrometa’s data stream ingestion and complex event processing platform to replace legacy data ingest platforms like Splunk, Tibco and Apache Kafka.</p>
<p>In a statement, Pelion Venture Partners, general partner Chris Cooper said, “We believe the next phase of computing will be focused on the edge, ultimately bringing cloud-based workloads closer to the end user. As more and more workloads move away from a centralized cloud model, Macrometa is becoming the de facto edge provider to run data-heavy and compute-intensive workloads for developers and enterprises alike, globally.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="o7GcYoY2gb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/deeplite-raises-6m-seed-to-deploy-ml-on-edge-with-fewer-compute-resources/">Deeplite raises $6M seed to deploy ML on edge with fewer compute resources</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Deeplite raises $6M seed to deploy ML on edge with fewer compute resources&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/deeplite-raises-6m-seed-to-deploy-ml-on-edge-with-fewer-compute-resources/embed/#?secret=o7GcYoY2gb" data-secret="o7GcYoY2gb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/edge-computing-startup-macrometa-gets-20m-series-a-led-by/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165508</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BookClub checks out a shiny new $20 million Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/bookclub-checks-out-a-shiny-new-20-million-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/bookclub-checks-out-a-shiny-new-20-million-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 14:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bookclub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david blake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Degreed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Signal Peak Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Serial edtech entrepreneur David Blake, who co-founded Degreed and launched LearnIn, is living the dream of any book worm. He reads at least one book a week, talks to the authors behind it and unpacks his biggest questions around the subtlest of passages. And it’s all thanks to his latest startup, BookClub, which first launched [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Serial edtech entrepreneur David Blake, who co-founded Degreed and launched LearnIn, is living the dream of any book worm. He reads at least one book a week, talks to the authors behind it and unpacks his biggest questions around the subtlest of passages.</p>
<p>And it’s all thanks to his latest startup, BookClub, which first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/the-first-rule-of-bookclub-no-boring-book-clubs/">launched in September</a> to bring author-led book clubs to readers. “With Degreed, it’s big, it’s enterprise and it’s structural. It brought a deep sense of fulfillment, it felt rigorous and challenging” he said. “BookClub has felt joyful, a lot of fun, and like a blessing in my life.”</p>
<p>The platform gives authors a chance to hold book groups, share exclusive video-based interviews and engage in questions readers might have. And months after announcing its existence and $6 million seed raise, BookClub is back to announce a $20 million Series A round, led by Signal Peak Ventures. Other investment firms that participated in the round include GSV Ventures, Maveron, Backstage Capital​ and Pelion Venture Partners​.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Blake often describes BookClub as &#8220;MasterClass meets Goodreads.” It’s fitting that he got the founders of both of those companies on his cap table as well, with Aaron Rasmussen, co-founder of MasterClass and founder of Outlier.org, and Otis Chandler, co-founder and previous CEO of Goodreads, joining the Series A round.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qyxAAQmiQj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/how-is-edtech-spending-its-extra-capital/">How is edtech spending its extra capital?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How is edtech spending its extra capital?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/how-is-edtech-spending-its-extra-capital/embed/#?secret=qyxAAQmiQj" data-secret="qyxAAQmiQj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The capital comes as BookClub prepares to open its private beta, which includes thousands of readers, to the public by July. Along with opening up for business, BookClub is investing heavily in adding more authors to its platform. So far, there are 11 books featured on BookClub’s website from writers such as Emily Chang, Lara Prescott, Colin Bryar and Bill Carr.</p>
<p>Blake declined to give specifics for how many books are in production, but said that BookClub’s plan is to hit 200 books for its service by the end of 2021.</p>
<p>The startup is currently experimenting with two services to bring author-led discussions to readers. One service is that users can find a book and then click through videos as they progress through the book. When BookClub was recording with Emily Chang, the author of &#8220;Brotopia,&#8221; it produced eight to 12 hours of content, which ranges from Q&amp;A to readings to behind-the-scenes musings on writing the book, Blake explained.</p>
<p>“A lot of that sounds simple, but in a lot of ways it is special in its own way,” Blake said. “If you grew up in most places in America, there weren’t New York Times best-sellers coming to your local indie bookstore and just doing readings&#8230;in a lot of ways, this is able to democratize a lot of what authors do to engage the big cities [on book tours] but for everyone else,” he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YTgBw2KTPR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/the-first-rule-of-bookclub-no-boring-book-clubs/">The first rule of BookClub? No boring book clubs.</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The first rule of BookClub? No boring book clubs.&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/the-first-rule-of-bookclub-no-boring-book-clubs/embed/#?secret=YTgBw2KTPR" data-secret="YTgBw2KTPR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The other service is similar to Oprah’s Book Club, a long-existent discussion series where Oprah interviews a different author behind a book each month. BookClub’s version of this is picking an author to discuss their book, as well as a series of books with similar themes, in an interview-style format. For example, Barbara Corcoran is discussing her book, &#8220;Shark Tales,&#8221; as well as five other books in an entrepreneurship-featured club.</p>
<p>One limitation for BookClub is figuring out how to generate enthusiasm through its platform. Book clubs often start off with the best of intentions, but then fall apart due to lack of accountability or limited interest among members to invest in deeper conversations. The startup will have to find a way, beyond author appeal, to integrate excitement without being overly prescriptive in its prompts. Another limitation might be the authors themselves. Because the startup&#8217;s products only work with living authors, it is missing out on a chunk of classical text.</p>
<p>The company might need to figure out a different way to represent authors, the non-living or camera shy, to reach what Blake views as its ultimate goal.</p>
<p>&#8220;Right now, statistically, the chance that we&#8217;ve covered one of the books on your nightstand is pretty low,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We want to get there, fast.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9kp6qM2fxQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/24/what-the-masterclass-effect-means-for-edtech/">What the MasterClass effect means for edtech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What the MasterClass effect means for edtech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/24/what-the-masterclass-effect-means-for-edtech/embed/#?secret=9kp6qM2fxQ" data-secret="9kp6qM2fxQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/bookclub-checks-out-a-shiny-new-20-million-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165729</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robotic landscaping startup Scythe emerges from stealth with $13.8M raise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/robotic-landscaping-startup-scythe-emerges-from-stealth-with-18-6m-raise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/robotic-landscaping-startup-scythe-emerges-from-stealth-with-18-6m-raise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 13:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspired Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landscaping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mowing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scythe robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Founded in 2018, Scythe Robotics is emerging from stealth today by announcing an $13.8 million Series A raise. The round was led by Inspired Capital and features True Ventures, Zigg Capital and Lemnos. It brings the Boulder, Colorado-based landscaping robotics company’s total funding up to $18.6 million, including a $4 million seed, also led by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Founded in 2018, Scythe Robotics is emerging from stealth today by announcing an $13.8 million Series A raise. The round was led by Inspired Capital and features True Ventures, Zigg Capital and Lemnos. It brings the Boulder, Colorado-based landscaping robotics company’s total funding up to $18.6 million, including a $4 million seed, also led by True Ventures.</p>
<p>The startup’s first product is an autonomous mower, offered to customers through a Robot-as-a-Service (RaaS) model. The method is becoming increasingly popular in the enterprise and industrial space, essentially offering clients robotics through a rental model that includes regular updates and maintenance. Interestingly, the company’s charging customers based on acres mowed.</p>
<p>The mower features eight HDR cameras and a variety of sensors designed to help avoid people, animals and various obstacles it might encounter on the job. Naturally, all of those sensors also come with a wealth of data collection aimed at &#8212; among other things &#8212; increasing the robot’s efficiency. Landscaping is a relatively low-hanging fruit for robotics. There&#8217;s certainly a lot to be said for automating the process for those with large swaths of land. Toro, notably, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/toro-acquires-robotic-tractor-snow-blower-maker-left-hand-robotics/">recently acquired Left Hand Robotics</a>, and iRobot has announced its own (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/28/irobots-terra-lawnmower-will-not-launch-in-2020-as-company-reprioritizes/">since delayed</a>) robotic mower.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/qrS_TfJfXKA?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>“To date, commercial landscape contractors haven’t had a technology partner who enables them to keep up with demand and to operate emissions-free. We are that partner,” said co-founder and CEO Jack Morrison in a release. “Our autonomous mower gives them the ability to grow their business, while staying green. It’s designed from the ground up to be an order of magnitude more reliable, more productive, and safer than any existing machine by incorporating state of the art autonomy with a rugged, all-electric design.”</p>
<p>Funding will go toward increasing headcount in its Colorado, Texas and Florida offices, R&amp;D on further products and getting the mower in front of new customers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GPcI91lPQO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/toro-acquires-robotic-tractor-snow-blower-maker-left-hand-robotics/">Toro acquires robotic tractor/snow blower maker, Left Hand Robotics</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Toro acquires robotic tractor/snow blower maker, Left Hand Robotics&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/toro-acquires-robotic-tractor-snow-blower-maker-left-hand-robotics/embed/#?secret=GPcI91lPQO" data-secret="GPcI91lPQO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/robotic-landscaping-startup-scythe-emerges-from-stealth-with-18-6m-raise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165703</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mobile game spending hits record $1.7B per week in Q1 2021, up 40% from pre-pandemic levels</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/mobile-game-spending-hits-record-1-7b-per-week-in-q1-2021-up-40-from-pre-pandemic-levels/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/mobile-game-spending-hits-record-1-7b-per-week-in-q1-2021-up-40-from-pre-pandemic-levels/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 13:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asia pacific]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[super mario run]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xbox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165662</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Covid-19 pandemic drove increased demand for mobile gaming, as consumers under lockdowns looked to online sources of entertainment, including games. But even as Covid-19 restrictions are easing up, the demand for mobile gaming isn&#8217;t slowing. According to a new report from mobile data and analytics provider App Annie in collaboration with IDC, users worldwide [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Covid-19 pandemic drove increased demand for mobile gaming, as consumers under lockdowns looked to online sources of entertainment, including games. But even as Covid-19 restrictions are easing up, the demand for mobile gaming isn&#8217;t slowing. According to a new report from mobile data and analytics provider <a href="https://www.appannie.com/en/insights/">App Annie</a> in collaboration with IDC, users worldwide downloaded 30% more games in the first quarter of 2021 than in the fourth quarter of 2019, and spent a record-breaking $1.7 billion per week in mobile games in Q1 2021.</p>
<p>That figure is up 40% from pre-pandemic levels, the report noted.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2166212" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2166212" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2166212" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-3-Social-1200x6271-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="355" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-3-Social-1200x6271-1.png 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-3-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-3-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=300,157 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-3-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=768,401 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-3-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=680,355 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-3-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=1536,803 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-3-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=2048,1070 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-3-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2166212" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The U.S. and Germany led other markets in terms of growth in mobile game spending year-over-year as of Q1 2021 in the North American and Western European markets, respectively. Saudi Arabia and Turkey led the growth in the rest of the world, outside the Asia-Pacific region. The latter made up around half of the mobile game spend in the quarter, App Annie said.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2166222" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.18.44-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="629" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.18.44-AM.jpg 1490w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.18.44-AM.jpg?resize=150,139 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.18.44-AM.jpg?resize=300,277 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.18.44-AM.jpg?resize=768,710 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.18.44-AM.jpg?resize=680,629 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.18.44-AM.jpg?resize=50,46 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The growth in mobile gaming, in part accelerated by the pandemic, also sees mobile further outpacing other forms of digital games consumption. This year, mobile gaming will increased its global lead over PC and Mac gaming to 2.9x and will extend its lead over home games consoles to 3.1x.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2166211" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2166211" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2166211" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-1-Social-1200x6271-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="355" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-1-Social-1200x6271-1.png 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-1-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-1-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=300,157 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-1-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=768,401 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-1-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=680,355 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-1-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=1536,803 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-1-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=2048,1070 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-1-Social-1200x6271-1.png?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2166211" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>However, this change comes at a time when the mobile and console market is continuing to merge, App Annie notes, as more mobile devices are capable of offering console-like graphics and gameplay experiences, including those with cross-platform capabilities and social gaming features.</p>
<p>Games with real-time online features tend to dominate the Top Grossing charts on the app stores, including things like player-vs-player and cross-play features. For example, the top grossing mobile game worldwide on iOS and Google Play in Q1 2021 was Roblox. This was followed by Genshin Impact, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apple-announces-its-2021-apple-design-award-winners/">just won an Apple Design Award</a> during the Worldwide Developer Conference for its visual experience.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2166208" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2166208" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2166208" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AA-IDC_Gaming-Spotlight-2021_banner-2a-Social-1080x10801-1.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2166208" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>The report also analyzed the ad market around gaming and the growth of mobile companion apps for game consoles, including My Nintendo, Xbox Game Pass, PlayStation App, Steam, Nintendo Switch, and Xbox apps. Downloads for these apps peaked under lockdowns in April 2020 in the U.S., but continue to see stronger downloads than pre-pandemic.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2166225" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2166225" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2166225" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.19.53-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="570" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.19.53-AM.jpg 1664w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.19.53-AM.jpg?resize=150,126 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.19.53-AM.jpg?resize=300,252 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.19.53-AM.jpg?resize=768,644 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.19.53-AM.jpg?resize=680,570 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.19.53-AM.jpg?resize=1536,1289 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-15-at-9.19.53-AM.jpg?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2166225" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>On the advertising front, App Annie says user sentiment towards in-game mobile ads improved in Q3 2020 compared with Q3 2019, but rewarded video ads and playable ads were preferred in the U.S.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/mobile-game-spending-hits-record-1-7b-per-week-in-q1-2021-up-40-from-pre-pandemic-levels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165662</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rocket Lab to design two orbital spacecraft for NASA to study Mars</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/rocket-lab-to-design-two-orbital-spacecraft-for-nasa-to-study-mars/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/rocket-lab-to-design-two-orbital-spacecraft-for-nasa-to-study-mars/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 13:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space Exploration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rocket Lab is developing two spacecraft based on its Photon platform to orbit Mars, studying the planet&#8217;s magnetosphere in order to gain a better understanding of the ways in which Mars&#8217; climate has changed over time. The science mission was awarded through NASA&#8217;s Small Innovative Missions for Planetary Exploration (SIMPLEx) program, and will fly to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rocket Lab is developing two spacecraft based on its Photon platform to orbit Mars, studying the planet&#8217;s magnetosphere in order to gain a better understanding of the ways in which Mars&#8217; climate has changed over time. The science mission was awarded through NASA&#8217;s Small Innovative Missions for Planetary Exploration (SIMPLEx) program, and will fly to Mars in 2024, aboard a yet-to-be-identified commercial lunch vehicle contracted by NASA as a rideshare rocket.</p>
<p>This is a noteworthy development for a few reasons, including that Rocket Lab will realize its earlier announced vision of using Photon as a platform for satellites that travel beyond Earth&#8217;s orbit. It&#8217;s also interesting because it will ostensibly mark the first decoupling of Rocket Lab&#8217;s launch and spacecraft services businesses.</p>
<p>Rocket Lab&#8217;s Photon is a satellite platform that includes the company&#8217;s Curie in-space propulsion system, and they&#8217;ll also be outfitted for this mission with star trackers and reaction wheels to make up a situational control system, as well as a deep space navigation system or way finding. The appeal of Photon is meant to be deep space exploration capability in a small, affordable and relatively low mass for launch package that could broaden access to interplanetary science for more organizations and institutions.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Next up for the Rocket Lab-supported Escapate mission that will use these two Mars-bound Photos is a design review in June, which will be followed up by a final confirmation review in July as a last check before the Photons are built, equipped and readied for their eventual flight.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/rocket-lab-to-design-two-orbital-spacecraft-for-nasa-to-study-mars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166192</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Andreessen Horowitz goes into publishing with Future</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/andreessen-horowitz-goes-into-publishing-with-future/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/andreessen-horowitz-goes-into-publishing-with-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Panzarino]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreesen Horowitz]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, venture firm Andreessen Horowitz is officially launching its media property, called Future. I’m on vacation today but couldn’t resist covering this fascinating new project.  The publication will initially focus on topics related to areas that the firm invests in but will expand over time using a mix of full-time staff, paid contributors and industry [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today, venture firm Andreessen Horowitz is officially launching its media property, called <a href="https://future.a16z.com">Future</a>. I’m on vacation today but couldn’t resist covering this fascinating new project.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The publication will initially focus on topics related to areas that the firm invests in but will expand over time using a mix of full-time staff, paid contributors and industry operators like founders, academics and entrepreneurs. And yes, they did get the dot com.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The <a href="https://future.a16z.com">Future.com</a> that is launching today is an MVP version (on a subdomain initially) of what the firm hopes the publication will be eventually, says Margit Wennmachers, Operating Partner, Marketing and Future at Andreessen Horowitz.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The content will be created by a mixture of staff and outside contributors that run the gamut from big names to up-and-comers says Wennmachers. The publication will cover topics that they find compelling with a broad theme of ‘rational optimism’ — something that the firm feels there isn’t enough of in coverage of tech at large.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>This isn’t a news operation, Wennmachers says, and they will focus on future-focused informational and editorial content, rather than day-to-day tech occurrences. Though when the news dovetails with subject matter that they feel they have expertise to cover either from contributors, staff or A16z partners, there will be topical coverage.</p>
<p>The initial leadership staff includes Wennmachers, Editor in Chief Sonal Chokshi, Executive Editor Maggie Leung and Managing Editor Amelia Salyers.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The contributors and topics that are set for launch sketch out an idea of the scope that Future is shooting for. A short list of some of them was provided, to give an impression:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Betül Kaçar</b> is a professor at the University of Arizona. She directs a NASA research consortium exploring the origins, evolution, and distribution of life in the Universe. Betül is contributing to Future on paleobiology and how the past can help build the future.</li>
<li><b>Marvin Ammori</b>, Chief Legal Officer of Uniswap Labs and advisor to the Harvard Law School Blockchain &amp; Fintech Initiative. Marvin is writing the definitive Defi explainer for Future.</li>
<li><b>Jade Raymond</b> is a Canadian video game creator, best known for helping create the Assassin’s Creed and Watch Dogs franchises, and for building the Ubisoft Toronto and EA Motive Studios. Jade will contribute on the subject of big company IP, gaming, and creators</li>
</ul>
<p>The focus with the initial wave of establishing content will be to produce explainers, how-to content and cohort learning by experienced founders in and outside of the A16z portfolio.</p>
<p>“We want to write about stuff we know and that we invest in,” says Wennmachers. This includes topics like crypto, biotech, fintech and real-estate, which all have dedicated partners at the firm.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>They also want to bring in people who know an extremely technical space particularly well, something like nuclear energy, for instance. They will contextualize and explain these arenas for the hoped-for audience of ‘tech enthusiasts’ as well as founders and entrepreneurs.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>They&#8217;re not starting from zero, here. A16z already has a strong reputation for producing content via its popular podcast and company blog posts that outlines the intricacies of a nascent technology, especially those related to deep tech or coalescing out of research.</p>
<p>The firm is prepared to invest in this publication long-term, and they are prepared to take the time to set a baseline for success metrics, says Wennmachers. The success of the publication will be tracked on some hard and soft metrics related to engagement. Traffic to the site will be considered, for instance, but also whether the targeted audience is ‘sending us around’ or ‘talking about the topics we raise’, says Wennmachers.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>Metrics like time on page or whether people are finishing the articles or podcast episodes will take precedent. One big advantage that Future has over other publications in the tech space, Wennmachers admits, is that they don’t have to monetize. A16z will be footing the bill for the buildout and talent here. This, of course, allows more freedom to choose what kinds of metrics are a part of the success rubric.</p>
<p>Video isn’t initially a focus but eventually YouTube or other video platforms could be on the docket.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The content, overall, is aiming to be action-oriented with information that is helpful in defining legislation, charting the course of your company or bringing a good point to your next meeting, says Wennmachers. Usability of information, basically, is a key sight line.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>Future will be writing ‘to tech people’ and to ‘the tech curious’. It will ideally, Wennmachers acknowledges, also help A16z win deals in the spaces where it demonstrates interest and understanding through publishing. The firm, she says, often wins deals at the intersection of two areas where they have expertise. Partners that specialize in biotech and consumer can come together, for instance, to support firms like Levels, which have a consumer-facing biotech footprint. Future can help to put those ideas out into the world, creating a sense that the firm knows what they’re talking about there and can add value.</p>
<p>Some other overall goals are to boost nascent tech communities like those around crypto and other edge tech endeavors.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>Future, says Wennmachers, should ideally provide content that doesn’t currently exist in the market that can be created from a ‘unique, interesting perch’ that the firm has. The audience, she says, is people who are curious, have an open mind and want to understand complex tech topics from the point of view of operators. People in consumer tech that want to cross-pollinate their ideas with deep tech arenas, for instance. With a sub-line of information about how new companies are built and grown.</p>
<p>The combination of full-time writers, paid contributors, entrepreneurs who probably have more ideas than days behind a pen and a wide array of external voices means that the editors have their work ahead of them. A voice will need to coalesce, as well as a reputation for signal and domain expertise.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>Future isn’t expected to win just because it’s backed by A16, though.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>“We have to win in the market,” Wennmachers acknowledges, “people’s attention is all over.”</p>
<p>Since Future is about, well, the future, I was curious whether they were pursuing any alternative structures. Co-ops, DAOs or distributed contribution systems that reflected the diaspora of talent out of the silos of traditional publishers and into other framing devices like Substack.</p>
<p>Not for now, says Wennmachers, as they want to establish Future as a thing that even exists and to make sure its voice is crisp. This will be a ‘traditional’ publication in all of the major ways that count, for now.</p>
<p>The MVP is launching today, and the team is willing to build in public, rather than continue to polish in private. Given the audience, that will likely attract some of the exact people that they want reading — as well as some of the expected critics.</p>
<p>Future launches into a very interesting time in media. There are a variety of different currents that are shifting the shorelines of publishing, renegotiating the relationships between individuals, organizations and audiences. At the same time, in tech, there is an increasing desire to control and shape the narrative around the next wave of world-altering technologies and companies without the involvement of the journalistic apparatus — or at least in counter to.</p>
<p>There is also a trend by media at large away from the same ‘rational optimism’ that Future is leaning into. Instead, the prevailing attitude seems to align more with ‘collective cynicism’. Many scalar entities in tech have enabled harm, therefore any similarly momentum-driven technologies and companies are to be viewed with a <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjuvYf42pnxAhUpDzQIHQ2bCMIQFjALegQIEhAE&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fminorityreport.fandom.com%2Fwiki%2FPrecogs&amp;usg=AOvVaw3A4WjEnWwpFMTl7LHVECW3">Precog’s</a> eye for future crimes.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>How the media apparatus reacts to a publication like Future will probably say a lot about how the balance is currently being struck between narrative encapsulation and intellectual rigor. For tech journalists who are willing to dig until they hit white paper this may not change much and in fact could become a good source of information about sprouting technical arenas. For those who thrive on access, I&#8217;d expect a good chunk of that access to get swallowed by Future, especially for the firm&#8217;s portfolio companies. Good luck there.</p>
<p>As far as Future&#8217;s chances, the media business is not easy, but the backing is incredibly substantial given that it doesn&#8217;t have to be self-sustaining, and the initial editorial hires say that they’re taking this endeavor pretty seriously.</p>
<p>There has already been chatter about conflict as it relates to the content being produced by efforts like Future &#8212; a huge deal for a journalistic enterprise where you are ostensibly acting as the avatar for the reader. But, if A16z is openly talking their own book with the content on Future then the conflict discussion is really already over. They have a point of view and it is going to be colored by their worldview, deal flow and network. End of story.</p>
<p>Whether the majority of media becomes conflicted ad nauseam and what that means is really another discussion.</p>
<p>I’d also look to see a lot of other firms scrambling to construct a media apparatus out of thin air — shout out to the comms strategists who will have figure out where to begin <i>that</i> discussion with their clients this week.</p>
<p>Whether you view Future as a marketing exercise, a necessary evolution or an immune reaction of the tech ecosystem, it’s doubtful that it will be boring.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>I’m out. I look forward to the hot takes.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><em>Editor&#8217;s Note: Updated list of initial contributors to reflect launch slate. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/andreessen-horowitz-goes-into-publishing-with-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166068</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Messaging social network IRL hits unicorn status with SoftBank-led $170M Series C</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/messaging-social-network-irl-hits-unicorn-status-with-softbank-led-170m-series-c/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/messaging-social-network-irl-hits-unicorn-status-with-softbank-led-170m-series-c/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abraham Shafi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Covid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goodwater capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social calendar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Investment Advisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Vision Fund 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeChat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Social calendar app IRL has been busy building a messaging-based social network, or what founder and CEO Abraham Shafi calls a &#8220;WeChat of the West.&#8221; Following its pandemic-fueled growth and further push into the social networking space with group chat and other features, IRL is today announcing a sizable $170 million Series C growth round, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Social calendar app <a href="https://www.irl.com/">IRL</a> has been busy building a messaging-based social network, or what founder and CEO Abraham Shafi calls a &#8220;WeChat of the West.&#8221; Following its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/02/streaming-events-calendar/">pandemic-fueled growth</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/now-with-over-10m-monthly-users-irl-turns-its-events-website-into-a-social-network/">further push</a> into the social networking space with group chat and other features, IRL is today announcing a sizable $170 million Series C growth round, led by <a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/articles/softbank-earnings-vision-fund-2-fundraising">SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund 2</a>. The fundraise also mints IRL as a new unicorn with a $1.17 billion valuation.</p>
<p>Besides SoftBank, new investor Dragoneer also participated in the oversubscribed round, alongside returning investors Goodwater Capital, Founders Fund and Floodgate. To date, IRL has raised over $200 million.</p>
<p>The startup began its life as a tool for discovering real-world events &#8212; an industry that went to zero almost overnight due to the COVID-19 pandemic. That could have been the end for IRL, but the startup quickly pivoted to prioritize discovery of online events instead. Under COVID lockdowns, users could turn to the app to find things like livestreamed concerts, esports events, Zoom parties and more.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2165857" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2165857" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2165857" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/mobile-social-events-and-group-messaging.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="224" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/mobile-social-events-and-group-messaging.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/mobile-social-events-and-group-messaging.png?resize=150,49 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/mobile-social-events-and-group-messaging.png?resize=300,99 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/mobile-social-events-and-group-messaging.png?resize=768,253 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/mobile-social-events-and-group-messaging.png?resize=680,224 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/mobile-social-events-and-group-messaging.png?resize=1536,506 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/mobile-social-events-and-group-messaging.png?resize=50,16 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2165857" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> IRL</p></div></p>
<p>IRL focused on pulling in popular online events from places like Live Nation, Twitch, YouTube, TikTok and others.</p>
<p>As a result, IRL became more accessible because its audience was no longer limited only to those who had time and money to travel to real-world events.</p>
<p>That focus also helped the app to attract a crowd of younger users who are of the generation that doesn&#8217;t use Facebook.</p>
<p>&#8220;They essentially use Snapchat, Instagram and TikTok,&#8221; explains Shafi. &#8220;But there is no groups and events product for that generation,&#8221; he points out.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the company<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/now-with-over-10m-monthly-users-irl-turns-its-events-website-into-a-social-network/"> doubled down on its social networking features</a> with the launch of a new site that added things like user profiles, support for group chats, the ability to join group events, personalized recommendations and more. As users could now network with friends across both web and mobile, IRL began to feel more like a social network, not just an event-discovery engine.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2165854" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2165854" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2165854" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IRL-College-Network-Overview-large.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="417" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IRL-College-Network-Overview-large.png 10572w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IRL-College-Network-Overview-large.png?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IRL-College-Network-Overview-large.png?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IRL-College-Network-Overview-large.png?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IRL-College-Network-Overview-large.png?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IRL-College-Network-Overview-large.png?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IRL-College-Network-Overview-large.png?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IRL-College-Network-Overview-large.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2165854" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> IRL</p></div></p>
<p>Today, IRL has 20 million users and 12 million who use the app monthly, which are not startling numbers in comparison to major social networks and their billions of users. But the numbers are representative of a steady approach that helped IRL grow 400% over the past 15 months, despite COVID&#8217;s impact to real-world events.</p>
<p>But as of recently, things are starting to change. In-person events are starting to return. California, the home state for San Francisco-based IRL, is <a href="https://abc7.com/california-reopening-mask-mandate-june-15-covid/10787888/">today re-opening</a>, for example. That opens up IRL to once again focus on connecting people not just online, but also &#8220;in real life,&#8221; as its name implies.</p>
<p>That could mean helping people better connect around events with not just their own friend group, as is often the case today, but helping them discover new groups in their local area or on campus. The company is even planning to use a portion of its fundraise to help fuel the new events economy by allocating a certain amount of money per city that will go toward helping people put on real-world events. The exact details are still being worked out, Shafi says, but says the idea is that IRL wants to help &#8220;bring culture back in cities that are opening up again.&#8221;</p>
<p>IRL also plans to expand its international footprint by finding ways to bring in non-U.S. users to its platform &#8212; possibly beginning with the events focused on watching the Olympics. (If the Games are not again delayed or <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/cancel-the-tokyo-olympics-its-unlikely-heres-why/">canceled</a> due to a COVID surge.)</p>
<p>Shafi says IRL hadn&#8217;t been planning to fundraise, but they decided to take the meetings when they were approached.</p>
<p>&#8220;The philosophy is not to raise when you have to, but to raise when it makes sense. And we were scaling like crazy to the point where our servers were melting. It made sense to take those discussions very seriously when they came to us,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>The addition of SoftBank and Dragoneer brings some expertise in scaling large social networks to the IRL team. SoftBank&#8217;s other notable social networking investment is with <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-10-26/bytedance-is-said-to-secure-funding-at-record-75-billion-value">TikTok owner&#8217;s Bytedance</a>, while <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/hub/dragoneer-investment-group-portfolio-companies">Dragoneer</a> has backed Snap. IRL has already has a close relationship with TikTok as it&#8217;s worked with the video app to pull in interesting events for discovery. It <a href="https://www.adweek.com/media/irl-integrates-with-tiktok/">more recently integrated</a> with TikTok&#8217;s new &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/tiktok-expands-integrations-with-third-party-apps-for-logins-sharing-sounds-and-more/">Login Kit</a>,&#8221; too, allowing TikTok users to authenticate with IRL using their TikTok credentials.</p>
<p>Now, IRL plans to add an even deeper TikTok integration &#8212; something that caught SoftBank&#8217;s attention.</p>
<p>Shafi is cagey on the details, but says more will be announced in the &#8220;coming weeks.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;But what I can say is that we&#8217;ve seen a ton of growth of TikTok users linking to IRL group chats and IRL events through their TikTok profiles as a way to communicate and go deeper in relationships,&#8221; he says. &#8220;If you think about it, right now Instagram has really great messaging&#8230;whereas TikTok is still developing that,&#8221; he hints.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2165855" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2165855" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2165855" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Paid-Group-Page.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="536" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Paid-Group-Page.png 919w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Paid-Group-Page.png?resize=150,118 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Paid-Group-Page.png?resize=300,236 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Paid-Group-Page.png?resize=768,605 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Paid-Group-Page.png?resize=680,536 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Paid-Group-Page.png?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2165855" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> IRL</p></div></p>
<p>Beyond its value to growing social networks for the younger, Facebook-less generation, IRL is thinking about how to build a profitable business without ad revenue. On this front, it sees potential in helping people connect through paid events &#8212; although these wouldn&#8217;t have to be influencer-driven as on other platforms. In fact, when IRL recently piloted paid group chats, users were willing to pay for access to things like a calc homework help group, for example.</p>
<p>IRL also sees demand for tools that help groups and clubs collect membership dues and other fees, as well as for events that are too small for Ticketmaster or Eventbrite.</p>
<p>&#8220;Whether we succeed or fail will be based on our ability to execute on our opportunity,&#8221; says Shafi, adding that most social networks today are focused on media more so than helping users make connections. &#8220;What we&#8217;re building isn&#8217;t the media part of social, it&#8217;s the real human interaction part of social, because that hasn&#8217;t been paid attention to as much.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re building a messaging social network,&#8221; he continues, comparing it to the biggest messaging social network in the world, WeChat. &#8220;The big vision that we&#8217;re going for is building the WeChat of the West &#8212; a messaging super social network. And it starts with people organizing groups and doing things together,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>With the additional funding, IRL will invest in product growth, international expansion and its Creator and Culture Fund, and will grow its now 25-person remotely distributed team to 100 by year-end.</p>
<p>&#8220;People are increasingly seeking more in-person social connections and are looking to share meaningful experiences together. As an innovative event-based social network, IRL sits at the intersection of group and event discovery, social calendaring, and group messaging, enabling people to do more together,&#8221; added Serena Dayal, director at SoftBank Investment Advisers, in a statement about its investment. &#8220;We are excited to partner with Abraham and the IRL team to support their ambition of helping everyone deepen their connections to friends and family.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/messaging-social-network-irl-hits-unicorn-status-with-softbank-led-170m-series-c/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165702</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carbyne raises $20M more so when death knocks, you don’t answer the door</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/carbyne-global-medical-response/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/carbyne-global-medical-response/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[911]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amir Elichai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carbyne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Global Medical Response]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166033</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chaos and crisis are sisters, and none more so than when you dial for emergency help. A call to 911 in the United States and urgent numbers globally spins off a number of additional calls to emergency response teams, ambulances, hospitals and other actors who need to coordinate action to save your life. Theoretically, everyone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chaos and crisis are sisters, and none more so than when you dial for emergency help. A call to 911 in the United States and urgent numbers globally spins off a number of additional calls to emergency response teams, ambulances, hospitals and other actors who need to coordinate action to save your life. Theoretically, everyone should be working off the same data, but also theoretically, I should be able to eat ice cream without getting fat.</p>
<p>Israel-based <a href="https://carbyne911.com">Carbyne</a>’s software platform coordinates these calls so that critical details — say, location or medical allergies — don&#8217;t get lost from the 911 call taker to the paramedic in the field.</p>
<p>Now, it’s taking a second scoop on its capital cone in the form of a $20 million new round, following a $25 million Series B that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/carbyne-raises-25m-for-a-next-generation-platform-to-improve-emergency-911-responses/">my colleague Ingrid Lunden reported on in January</a>. The new funding was led by Global Medical Response, one of the world’s largest emergency medical providers who operates fleets of vehicles, trucks, helicopters and planes to get patients to hospital facilities expeditiously. GMR was founded in 2018 from a rollup of emergency services led by private equity giant KKR.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This new round was in the form of a convertible note that will convert into Carbyne’s next fundraise according to CEO and co-founder Amir Elichai. Also joining the round was Hanaco VC, Intercap VC, Elsted Capital and others. Elichai said that the round took about three weeks to fundraise and close, and was held to $20 million given the company’s earlier funding this year, which at the time we reported was “over $100 million” in valuation.</p>
<p>Carbyne and GMR have been partners since late 2020, and their ties are deepening. GMR COO Edward Van Horne will join Carbyne’s board of directors.</p>
<p>In addition to offering more advanced location services for emergency callers, Carbyne’s technology allows for callers to activate a video channel, giving emergency response personnel more live information about what’s happening. That’s critical in GMR’s business, where first responders need the most up-to-date information to increase their effectiveness.</p>
<p>“The ability to get smarter information, and to increase situational awareness to each case whatever it is, will give emergency medical services the ability to better triage and to make faster and smarter responses to events that occur within their jurisdiction,” Elichai explained. “So basically the entire ecosystem is becoming much more reliable and efficient, thanks to the Carbyne ecosystem that we&#8217;re putting together with GMR.”</p>
<p>My colleague <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/carbyne-raises-25m-for-a-next-generation-platform-to-improve-emergency-911-responses/">wrote a great deep dive into the company in January</a>, so read that for some background on the company’s founding and product and how it weathered the pandemic. A few more updates though in the past few months bear mentioning.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="R0f5iHYmSr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/carbyne-raises-25m-for-a-next-generation-platform-to-improve-emergency-911-responses/">Carbyne raises $25M for a next-generation platform to improve emergency 911 responses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Carbyne raises $25M for a next-generation platform to improve emergency 911 responses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/carbyne-raises-25m-for-a-next-generation-platform-to-improve-emergency-911-responses/embed/#?secret=R0f5iHYmSr" data-secret="R0f5iHYmSr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Elichai said that the company has doubled the recurring revenues of its business since the beginning of 2021, although wouldn’t provide those ever elusive absolute figures. The company has also expanded its employee base by 30% over the same period. Among the success stories is New Orleans, which is moving its emergency centers to Carbyne, as well as centers in Texas, Georgia and Florida. Elichai said that much of this transition was prompted by additional federal investment in 911 infrastructure appropriated in recent COVID-19 stimulus bills.</p>
<p>The company’s CTO and co-founder, Alex Dizengof, will move from Israel to the United States to start an R&amp;D center.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/israel-aerospace-industries-and-carbyne-introduce-911-ultra-en-301308432.html">Last week</a>, the company announced a new “Ultra Emergency Network” that it is building with Israel Aerospace Industries that will allow phones to communicate emergency location information in post-disaster scenarios where commercial mobile services degrade or disappear entirely.</p>
<p>The company’s newest investment is in line with growing interest from venture capitalists in the disaster space, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/data-was-the-new-oil-until-the-oil-caught-fire/">with more data</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/08/when-the-earth-is-gone-at-least-the-internet-will-still-be-working/">investments in communications infrastructure</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/09/the-human-focused-startups-of-the-hellfire/">more dollars flowing into the space than ever before</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="57tpYk7fsR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/09/the-human-focused-startups-of-the-hellfire/">The human-focused startups of the hellfire</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The human-focused startups of the hellfire&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/09/the-human-focused-startups-of-the-hellfire/embed/#?secret=57tpYk7fsR" data-secret="57tpYk7fsR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/carbyne-global-medical-response/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166033</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CJEU ruling could open big tech to more privacy litigation in Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cjeu-ruling-could-open-big-tech-to-more-privacy-litigation-in-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cjeu-ruling-could-open-big-tech-to-more-privacy-litigation-in-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 12:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belgium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CJEU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luxembourg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online trackers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166126</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A long running privacy fight between Belgium&#8217;s data protection authority and Facebook &#8212; over the latter&#8217;s use of online trackers like pixels and social plug-ins to snoop on web users &#8212; has culminated in a ruling by Europe&#8217;s top court today that could have wider significance on how cross-border cases against tech giants are enforced [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/">long running privacy fight</a> between Belgium&#8217;s data protection authority and Facebook &#8212; over the latter&#8217;s use of online trackers like pixels and social plug-ins to snoop on web users &#8212; has culminated in a <a href="https://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf;jsessionid=FC1B570EC8016A36873DB5D55DBDB12A?text=&amp;docid=236410&amp;pageIndex=0&amp;doclang=EN&amp;mode=req&amp;dir=&amp;occ=first&amp;part=1&amp;cid=779232">ruling</a> by Europe&#8217;s top court today that could have wider significance on how cross-border cases against tech giants are enforced in the region.</p>
<p>The Court of Justice of the European Union has affirmed that, in certain circumstances, national DPAs can pursue action even when they are not the lead data supervisor under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism (OSS) &#8212; opening up the possibility of litigation by watchdogs in Member States which aren&#8217;t the lead regulator for a particular company but where the local agency believes there is an urgent need to act.</p>
<p>The OSS was included in the GDPR with the idea of simplifying enforcement for businesses operating in more than one EU market &#8212; which would only need to deal directly with one &#8216;lead&#8217; data protection authority. However the mechanism has been criticized for contributing to a bottleneck effect whereby multiple GDPR complaints are stacking up on the desks of a couple of DPAs (most notably Ireland and Luxembourg) &#8212; EU Member States which attract large numbers of multinationals (typically for tax reasons, such as Ireland&#8217;s 12.5% corporate tax rate).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Enforcement of the EU&#8217;s flagship data protection regime against tech giant has thus been hampered by a perception of &#8216;forum shopping&#8217; &#8212; whereby a handful of EU DPAs have a disproportionately large number of major, cross-border cases to deal with vs the (inevitably limited) resources provided for them by their national governments. The resulting bottleneck looks convenient for those companies that face delayed GDPR enforcement.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kCkpXAvuCS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/lack-of-big-tech-gdpr-decisions-looms-large-in-eu-watchdogs-annual-report/">Lack of big tech GDPR decisions looms large in EU watchdog&#8217;s annual report</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lack of big tech GDPR decisions looms large in EU watchdog&#8217;s annual report&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/lack-of-big-tech-gdpr-decisions-looms-large-in-eu-watchdogs-annual-report/embed/#?secret=kCkpXAvuCS" data-secret="kCkpXAvuCS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Some EU DPAs are also considered more active in enforcement of the bloc&#8217;s privacy rules than others &#8212; and it&#8217;s fair to say that Ireland is not among them. (Albeit, it defends the pace of its investigations and enforcement record by saying that it must do due diligence to ensure decisions stand up to any legal challenges.)</p>
<p>Indeed, Ireland has been criticized for (among other things) the length of time it&#8217;s taken to investigate GDPR complaints; for procedural issues (how it&#8217;s gone about investigating or indeed not investigating complaints); and for its enforcement record against tech giants &#8212; which to date is limited to just one <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/">$550k penalty issued against Twitter</a> issued at the end of last year.</p>
<p>The Irish Data Protection Commission (DPC) had originally wanted to give Twitter an even lower fine but other EU DPAs disputed its draft decision &#8212; forcing it to increase the penalty slightly.</p>
<p>As it stands, scores of cases remain open on the DPC&#8217;s desk, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/25/facebook-google-face-first-gdpr-complaints-over-forced-consent/">major complaints against Facebook and Google</a> &#8212; which are now over three years old.</p>
<p>This has led to calls for the Commission to step in and take action over Ireland&#8217;s perceived inaction. Although, for now, the EU&#8217;s executive has limited its intervention to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/">a few words</a> urging Ireland to, essentially, hurry up and get on with the job.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AAK8pIhAbR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/embed/#?secret=AAK8pIhAbR" data-secret="AAK8pIhAbR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Today&#8217;s CJEU ruling may alleviate a little of the blockage around GDPR enforcement &#8212; in some narrow situations &#8212; by enabling national DPAs to take up the baton to litigate over users&#8217; rights when a lead agency isn&#8217;t acting on complaints.</p>
<p>However the ruling does not look set to completely unblock the OSS mechanism, per Luca Tosoni, a research fellow at the Norwegian Research Center for Computers and Law at the University of Oslo who has been following the case closely &#8212; and whose work was cited by the CJEU&#8217;s advocate general in an earlier opinion on the case.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Court has essentially confirmed the views that the Advocate General had expressed in his opinion: Under the GDPR’ one-stop-shop system, those data protection authorities that are not the ‘lead authority’ may start enforcement actions against big tech companies only in very limited circumstances, including in case of urgency,&#8221; he told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>&#8220;However, unfortunately, the Court’s ruling does not elaborate on the criteria to be followed to assess the urgency of an enforcement action. In particular, the Court has not expressly seconded the advocate general’s view that a failure to act promptly from the part of the lead authority may justify the adoption of interim urgent measures by other data protection authorities. Thus, this important point remains partially unclear, and further litigation might be necessary to clarify this issue.</p>
<p>&#8220;Therefore, today’s ruling is unlikely to completely settle the &#8216;Irish issue&#8217;.&#8221;</p>
<p>Article 56 of the GDPR allows for non-lead DPAs to pursue action at a national level in the case of complaints that relate to an issue that substantially affects only users under their jurisdiction, and where they believe there is a need to act urgently (as a lead authority has not). So it does seem fairly narrow.</p>
<p>One recent example of a non-lead DPA intervention is the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/">Italian DPA&#8217;s emergency action against TikTok</a> &#8212; related to child safety on the platform after the death of a local girl who had been reported to have participated in a challenge on the platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;An authority’s wish to adopt a ‘go-it-alone’ approach&#8230; with regard to the (judicial) enforcement of the GDPR, without cooperating with the other authorities, cannot be reconciled with either the letter or the spirit of that regulation,&#8221; runs one paragraph of today&#8217;s judgement, underlining the court&#8217;s view that the GDPR requires careful and balanced joint-working between DPAs.</p>
<p>The ruling does go into some detailed discussion of the &#8220;dangers&#8221; of under-enforcement of the GDPR &#8212; as the concern was raised with the CJEU &#8212; but the court takes the view that it&#8217;s too soon to say whether such a concern affects the regulation or not.</p>
<p>&#8220;If, however, [under-enforcement were to] be evidenced by facts and robust arguments – then I do not believe that the Court would turn a blind eye to any gap which might thereby emerge in the protection of fundamental rights guaranteed by the Charter and their effective enforcement by the competent regulators,&#8221; the CJEU goes on. &#8220;Whether that would then still be an issue for a Charter-conform interpretation of provisions of secondary law, or an issue of validity of the relevant provisions, or even sections of a secondary law instrument, is a question for another case.&#8221;</p>
<p>The ruling, while narrow, may at least unblock the Belgian DPA&#8217;s long-running litigation against Facebook&#8217;s tracking of non-users via cookies and social plug-ins which was the route for the referral of questions over the scope of the OSS to the CJEU.</p>
<p>Although the court also notes that it will be for a Belgian court to determine whether the DPA&#8217;s intervention meets the GDPR&#8217;s bar for starting such proceedings or not.</p>
<p>Contacted for comment on the CJEU judgement, Facebook welcomed the ruling.</p>
<p>“We are pleased that the CJEU has upheld the value and principles of the one-stop-shop mechanism, and highlighted its importance in ensuring the efficient and consistent application of GDPR across the EU,” said Jack Gilbert, associate general counsel at Facebook in a statement.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="n3dRGFz6Cp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/24/in-europe-facebooks-data-law-buffer-looks-to-be-on-borrowed-time/">In Europe, Facebook&#8217;s data law buffer looks to be on borrowed time</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;In Europe, Facebook&#8217;s data law buffer looks to be on borrowed time&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/24/in-europe-facebooks-data-law-buffer-looks-to-be-on-borrowed-time/embed/#?secret=n3dRGFz6Cp" data-secret="n3dRGFz6Cp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GjSDyZTz9Y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/">Facebook&#8217;s tracking of non-users ruled illegal again</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook&#8217;s tracking of non-users ruled illegal again&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/embed/#?secret=GjSDyZTz9Y" data-secret="GjSDyZTz9Y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="m5PdZwMueY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/06/15/facebook-faces-privacy-lawsuit-from-belgian-watchdog/">Facebook Faces Privacy Lawsuit From Belgian Watchdog</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook Faces Privacy Lawsuit From Belgian Watchdog&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2015/06/15/facebook-faces-privacy-lawsuit-from-belgian-watchdog/embed/#?secret=m5PdZwMueY" data-secret="m5PdZwMueY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cjeu-ruling-could-open-big-tech-to-more-privacy-litigation-in-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166126</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Home services platform Thumbtack raises $275M on a $3.2B valuation to double down on home management</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/thumbtack-home-services/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/thumbtack-home-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 12:19:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the heels of making an acquisition in December of home management startup Setter, Thumbtack &#8212; one of the pioneers in the home services gig economy &#8212; has raised a big round to double down on the model. The company has raised a fresh $275 million, money that the company plans to use to built [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On the heels of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/thumbtack-acquires-setter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">making an acquisition</a> in December of home management startup Setter, <a href="https://www.thumbtack.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thumbtack</a> &#8212; one of the pioneers in the home services gig economy &#8212; has raised a big round to double down on the model. The company has raised a fresh $275 million, money that the company plans to use to built out a home management and maintenance business alongside its network of home services professionals. Co-founder and CEO Marco Zappacosta confirmed that the round values Thumbtack at $3.2 billion.</p>
<p>For some context, this is nearly double the valuation Thumbtack had when it last raised money, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/23/thumbtack-raises-150-million-for-its-local-services-marketplace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$150 million round led by Sequoia in 2019</a>. It also comes on the heels of a strong 2020, where its revenue grew more than 50%. Thumbtack&#8217;s gross revenue (what&#8217;s paid in service fees, not Thumbtack&#8217;s cut) is now on track, it says, to cross $2 billion this year.</p>
<p>This latest funding is being led by the Qatar Investment Authority (QIA), with participation also from Blackstone Alternative Asset Management (BAAM) as well as G Squared. Previous backers Ballie Gifford, CapitalG, Founders Circle Capital, Sequoia Capital, and Tiger Global Management also invested.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding and shifting focus of the company underscore some of the changes we have seen among consumers in the last year.</p>
<p>In large part, because of Covid-19, most of us have been staying home &#8212; which has often included also moving to new homes to accommodate spending so much more time in them &#8212; and, as Thumbtack sees it, that has led many more people to paying more attention to how to make those homes better places, and to keep them in better shape overall. This is partly why it sees a big opportunity &#8212; alongside being a marketplace to find pro&#8217;s for one-off jobs you might need done around the house &#8212; in providing a &#8220;home management&#8221; platform to cater to that new attention.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s pretty wild that people&#8217;s homes their biggest assets, the most complicated thing you&#8217;re responsible for, but it doesn&#8217;t come with a manual,&#8221; Zappacosta said in an interview. &#8220;When you think about your car, you need to do regular service. Otherwise, you may have to pay a big emergency bill [to fix something]. That same concept applies to the home. But there&#8217;s never been an easy way to know what you should do, how much to pay for it, and then easily get it done. So that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing.&#8221;</p>
<p>The services include emergency repairs of electrics in the home, plus preventative maintenance that you may need to do to on your property, he said. They don&#8217;t include contractors to refit bathrooms or other elective work.</p>
<p>The move into home management is an interesting turn for another reason, too. It&#8217;s a sign of how Thumbtack is playing into a bigger change in how many consumers engage with services overall: by way of subscriptions.</p>
<p>That is to say, while many of us will still go out and shop for items, or go to a cinema every now and then, we are all also subscribing to at least one video-on-demand service, many of us may well also have Prime accounts to get Amazon&#8217;s various perks, and so on. If we are subscribing for everything and everywhere else, why not throw home maintenance into the mix?</p>
<p>Thumbtack, now over ten years old, is thought by many as one of the earliest movers in the gig economy space to focus on home services. That has not come without challenges, however. As we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/06/thumbtack-series-h/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported back in 2019</a>, the last round was a tough one for the company and looked like it might come in at a flat valuation. That was on the heels of many others in the space &#8212; competitors of Thumbtack&#8217;s that included not just other startups but also heavy hitters like Amazon and Google &#8212; fizzling out in their own efforts in home services.</p>
<p>And Covid-19 proved to be a huge challenge for Thumbtack, too, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/30/thumbtack-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">laid off 250 people</a> in March last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yeah, look, it was a roller coaster of a year,&#8221; Zappacosta said when I asked him about that. &#8220;In the early phases of COVID, there was so much fear that many just shut it all down. People said, &#8216;I&#8217;m not going to have anybody in my home.&#8217; And so those months were really scary &#8212; March, April &#8212; because it was unclear how long that was going to last. And so we made adjustments to ensure that we sort of would stand the test of time.&#8221;</p>
<p>However, that appeared to change later in the year, he continued.</p>
<p>&#8220;Once people began getting more comfortable with masking up, and all the precautions, you know, demand did start to come back. And so by June, July, we saw ot get back to normal levels. And then you know, what happened is the big investments that we&#8217;ve been making in the platform in the last few years to make the hiring experience, much more e-commerce, like really began to pay more and more dividends.&#8221;</p>
<p>He said that 2020 was Thumbtack&#8217;s third year of accelerating growth, &#8220;which is sort of surprising given that Covid was in the middle of that. And so the momentum that we&#8217;re carrying out, is we&#8217;ve never been in a stronger position.&#8221;</p>
<p>That&#8217;s also what helped attract this latest round.</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>“Thumbtack&#8217;s modernization of the home service industry is a boon to both homeowners and home service professionals,” said Bryan Schreier, partner at Sequoia Capital and Thumbtack board member, in a statement. “The number one roadblock for starting new home projects is the headache and hassle. By creating a better, easier way for anyone to take care of their home, Thumbtack will unlock a massive category and spark new economic activity.”</div>
</div>
<p>The company now is focusing on where it might best use technology to get the upper hand with its platform, which competes not just with other home services provider marketplaces, but also a growing number of upstart and incumbent &#8220;home management&#8221; providers like Super, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/super-raises-50m-to-cover-home-repairs-and-maintenance-via-a-subscription-model/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">which raised $50 million last month</a>.</p>
<p>One interesting idea that Zappacosta described to me, which may well be part of a later phase of development, involved providing a way for customers to &#8220;tour&#8221; their homes so that Thumbtack could get a better idea of the space and what needs attention to better personalize its home management to the home and user in question.</p>
<p>That will keep the company working also in the U.S. he said, rather than expanding internationally. Globally the home services and repair market is estimated to be worth some $500 billion annually, and amazingly the U.S. represents a massive 40% of that value.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/thumbtack-home-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166141</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Klaxoon introduces whiteboard-focused conference room for hybrid work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/klaxoon-introduces-whiteboard-focused-conference-room-for-hybrid-work/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/klaxoon-introduces-whiteboard-focused-conference-room-for-hybrid-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 12:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klaxoon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klaxoon Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klaxoon Board Hybrid]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Klaxoon is announcing a product update for its whiteboard collaboration platform as well as a new hardware product. With Hybridity, the company is going to sell ready-to-use conference rooms that optimize hybrid meetings between people currently in the office and people on the go. Let’s start with the software update. Last year, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://klaxoon.com/fr/home">Klaxoon</a> is announcing a product update for its whiteboard collaboration platform as well as a new hardware product. With Hybridity, the company is going to sell ready-to-use conference rooms that optimize hybrid meetings between people currently in the office and people on the go.</p>
<p>Let’s start with the software update. Last year, the company unveiled <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/28/klaxoon-launches-board-an-interactive-meeting-product-for-video-calls/">Board</a>, a visual interface that lets you work together during a video call. It lets you share ideas and collaborate using a whiteboard interface. You can create sticky notes, add text, insert images, move things around and start a video call from there.</p>
<p>Other people on the calls are represented through tiny thumbnails so that you can remain focused on the digital whiteboard. You can also connect Board with your existing video-conferencing tool.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This week, the company is updating Board and renaming it to Board Hybrid. “It’s the new version of Board that isn’t only designed for remote work, but also for hybrid work,” founder and CEO Matthieu Beucher said in a press conference.</p>
<p>Board Hybrid users can now add any type of file to their whiteboard. This way, they don’t have to upload files to a shared drive, create a link and paste the link in the whiteboard. Users can preview PowerPoint presentations, Word files, spreadsheets and more directly from Klaxoon’s interface.</p>
<p>There are some new drawing tools including some new connectors. For instance, you can create mindmaps from there. You can now also share your screen from Klaxoon’s own video-conferencing solution.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2166158" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2166158" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-117fdc9666601af8a4a1374ffb2b494f.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" class="size-full wp-image-2166158" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-117fdc9666601af8a4a1374ffb2b494f.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-117fdc9666601af8a4a1374ffb2b494f.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-117fdc9666601af8a4a1374ffb2b494f.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-117fdc9666601af8a4a1374ffb2b494f.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-117fdc9666601af8a4a1374ffb2b494f.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-117fdc9666601af8a4a1374ffb2b494f.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-117fdc9666601af8a4a1374ffb2b494f.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2166158" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Klaxoon</p></div></p>
<p>The new product is something quite different — it’s a meeting room called Hybridity. It looks like a hexagon-shaped space capsule. There’s no window and it feels like a black box from the outside.</p>
<p>Inside, you’ll find three seats, three screens, three cameras and three <a href="https://klaxoon.com/fr/klaxoon-box">Klaxoon Box</a> devices. “Everyone can see everyone perfectly well and everybody can immerse themselves in content,” Beucher said.</p>
<p>If you’ve joined a hybrid meeting from your home, you’re well aware of the issues involved with that setup. Part of the team is sitting in the same room. They look like tiny action figures and you can’t figure out who’s talking.</p>
<p>With this setup, Klaxoon hopes it’ll be easier to run meetings with people in the office and people at home. A Klaxoon Hybridity conference room requires 5 square meters. You can put it down in a corner and move it to another location a couple of years later. It’s not secured in the ground.</p>
<p>Pre-orders will start this week. The company expects to sell Hybridity with a subscription model with prices starting at €2,000 per month. It’s going to be interesting to see whether Klaxoon has found a new revenue stream of it it’s just a fun experiment. But it could replace those tiny phone booths in your office.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2166159" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2166159" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-aaeb0f79f3f9768ca454e3179b766200.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" class="size-full wp-image-2166159" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-aaeb0f79f3f9768ca454e3179b766200.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-aaeb0f79f3f9768ca454e3179b766200.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-aaeb0f79f3f9768ca454e3179b766200.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-aaeb0f79f3f9768ca454e3179b766200.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-aaeb0f79f3f9768ca454e3179b766200.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-aaeb0f79f3f9768ca454e3179b766200.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-aaeb0f79f3f9768ca454e3179b766200.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Klaxoon-aaeb0f79f3f9768ca454e3179b766200.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2166159" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Klaxoon</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/klaxoon-introduces-whiteboard-focused-conference-room-for-hybrid-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166155</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>G2VP VC raises $500 million to fund sustainable tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/g2vp-vc-raises-500-million-to-fund-tech-that-make-industries-more-sustainable/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/g2vp-vc-raises-500-million-to-fund-tech-that-make-industries-more-sustainable/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[G2 Venture Partners, a firm that spun out of Kleiner and Perkins Caufield &#38; Byers, has raised $500 million to support entrepreneurs that aim to make existing industries more efficient, environmentally friendly and socially responsible.   With Fund II, G2 is most bullish about technologies in transportation, logistics, manufacturing, agriculture and energy, with an increasing focus [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">G2 Venture Partners, a firm that spun out of Kleiner and Perkins Caufield &amp; Byers, has raised $500 million to support entrepreneurs that aim to make existing industries more efficient, environmentally friendly and socially responsible.  </span></p>
<p>With Fund II, G2 is most bullish about technologies in transportation, logistics, manufacturing, agriculture and energy, with an increasing focus on sustainability, according to a spokesperson for the firm.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The launch of our second fund expands our ability to work with companies that are moving the needle to redefine and revolutionize their respective industries,” said G2VP founding partner David Mount in a statement. “We will continue to partner with technology companies that are pushing the future of industry forward, driving economic growth with reduced resource intensity.” </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investors in the new fund include Shell Ventures, Mitsui &amp; Co., Daimler AG, ABB Switzerland Ltd. and The McKnight Foundation, a G2 spokesperson told TechCrunch. John Doerr, famed investor and VC at Kleiner, also personally invested in the fund. </span><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20180615075230/https://fortune.com/2018/06/12/kleiner-perkins-g2vp-350-million-fund/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doerr invested in G2VP’s initial $350 million fund back in 2018</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and he’s known for delivering an </span><a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/john_doerr_salvation_and_profit_in_greentech"><span style="font-weight: 400;">emotional TED Talk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in which he argued for increased investments in clean energy.</span></p>
<p>The firm has already led rounds in AVEVA-acquired industrial data management platform OSIsoft, Oracle-acquired utility customer engagement platform Opower and solar energy company Enphase. Kleiner led Enphase&#8217;s past fundraising rounds <a href="https://www.appliedmaterials.com/en-sg/company/news/press-releases/2010/06/enphase-energy-completes-financing-round-of-63-million">back in 2010</a>, and in 2017, <a href="https://www.greentechmedia.com/articles/read/silicon-valleys-john-doerr-and-tj-rodgers-invest-10m-in-enphases-microin">Doerr stepped back in</a> to help the financially struggling company with another $10 million alongside T.J. Rodgers. G2 would not provide names of portfolio companies for this newest fund yet, but a spokesperson did say Fund II will be investing in a new set of companies. Any follow-on investments in companies from Fund I will be made out of that fund.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The firm invested in 15 late-stage companies in Fund I and expects to invest in a similar number of companies in Fund II. G2VC typically invests $10 million to $50 million in each company. Past portfolio companies include lidar manufacturer Luminar, EV tech company Proterra, computer vision solutions provider Scandit, autonomous robot company Seegrid and agricultural supply chain platform ProducePay, among others. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This team has consistently shown vision and taken action that is ahead of the curve on many aspects of the digital industrial transition the world is in the midst of,” said Robert Linck, chief investment officer of Shell Ventures, a limited partner in G2’s first and second funds, in a statement. “The brain trust at this firm will be a significant asset to the new generation of technology leaders and path breakers that is emerging today.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yfLUCYAlZ2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/rebranded-toyota-ventures-invests-300-million-in-emerging-tech-and-carbon-neutrality/">Rebranded Toyota Ventures invests $300 million in emerging tech and carbon neutrality </a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rebranded Toyota Ventures invests $300 million in emerging tech and carbon neutrality &#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/rebranded-toyota-ventures-invests-300-million-in-emerging-tech-and-carbon-neutrality/embed/#?secret=yfLUCYAlZ2" data-secret="yfLUCYAlZ2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/g2vp-vc-raises-500-million-to-fund-tech-that-make-industries-more-sustainable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165993</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kai-Fu Lee&#8217;s Sinovation bets on Linux tablet maker Jingling in $10M round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/jingos-10-million-linux-tablets-laptops/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/jingos-10-million-linux-tablets-laptops/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 11:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kai-fu Lee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linus torvalds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MediaTek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shenzhen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trustbridge Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kai-Fu Lee&#8217;s Sinovation Ventures has its eyes on a niche market targeting software developers. In April, the venture capital fund led a $10 million angel round in Jingling, a Chinese startup developing Linux-based tablets and laptops, TechCrunch has learned. Other investors in the round included private equity firm Trustbridge Partners. Jingling was founded only in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Kai-Fu Lee&#8217;s Sinovation Ventures has its eyes on a niche market targeting software developers. In April, the venture capital fund led a $10 million angel round in <a href="https://en.jingos.com/">Jingling</a>, a Chinese startup developing Linux-based tablets and laptops, TechCrunch has learned. Other investors in the round included private equity firm Trustbridge Partners.</p>
<p>Jingling was founded only in June 2020 but has quickly assembled a team of 80 employees hailing from the likes of Aliyun OS, Alibaba&#8217;s Linux distribution, Thunder Software, a Chinese operating system solution provider, and China&#8217;s open source community.</p>
<p>The majority of the startup&#8217;s staff are working on its Linux-based operating system called JingOS in Beijing, with the rest developing hardware in Shenzhen, where its supply chain is located.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Operating systems are a highly worthwhile field for investment,&#8221; Peter Fang, a partner at Sinovation Ventures, told TechCrunch. &#8220;We&#8217;ve seen the best product iteration for work and entertainment through the combination of iPad Pro and Magic Keyboard, but no tablet maker has delivered a superior user experience for the Android system so far, so we decided to back JingOS.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The investment is also in line with Sinovation&#8217;s recognition and prediction in ARM powering more mobile and desktop devices in the future,&#8221; the investor added.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/byEN1AnLC4o?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Jingling&#8217;s first device, the JingPad A1 tablet based on the ARM architecture, has already shipped over 500 units in a pre-sale and is ramping up interest through a <a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/jingpad-world-s-first-consumer-level-linux-tablet">crowdfunding campaign</a>. Jingling currently uses processors from Tsinghua Unigroup but is looking into Qualcomm and MediaTek chipsets for future production, according to Liu.</p>
<p>On the software end, JingOS, which is <a href="https://github.com/JingOS-team/JingOS">open sourced on GitHub</a>, has accumulated over 50,000 downloads from users around the world, most of whom are in the United States and Europe.</p>
<p>But how many people want a Linux tablet or laptop? Liu Chengcheng, who launched Jingling with Zhu Rui, said the demand is big enough from the developer community to sustain the startup&#8217;s early-phase growth. Liu is known for founding China&#8217;s leading startup news site 36Kr and Zhu is an operating system expert and a veteran of Motorola and Lenovo.</p>
<p>Targeting the Linux community is step one for Jingling, for &#8220;it&#8217;s difficult to gain a foothold by starting out in the [general] consumer market,&#8221; said Liu.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Linux market is too small for tech giants but too hard for small startups to tackle&#8230; aside from Jingling, Huawei is the only other company in China building a mobile operating system, but HarmonyOS focuses more on IoTs.&#8221;</p>
<p>Launching a new operating system is surely an audacious move and has been done before. Linux laptops <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/05/20/laptop-week-review-the-dell-xps-13-developers-edition-with-ubuntu/">have been around for years</a>, but Jingling wanted to offer something different by enabling both desktop and mobile experiences on one device. That&#8217;s why Jingling made JingOS compatible with both Linux desktop software like WPS Office and Terminal as well as the usual Android apps on smartphones. The JingPad A1 tablet comes with a detachable keyboard that immediately turns itself into a laptop, a setup similar to Apple&#8217;s Magic Keyboard for iPad.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s like a gift to programmers, who can use it to code in the Linux system but also use Android mobile apps on the run,&#8221; said Liu.</p>
<p>Jingling aspires to widen its user base and seize the Chromebook market about two from now, Liu said. The success of Chromebooks, which comprised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/chromebooks-had-a-banner-2020/">10.8% of the PC market in 2020</a> and have been increasingly eating into Microsoft&#8217;s dominance,<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> is indicative of the slowing demand for Windows personal computers, the founder observed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The JingPad A1 is sold at a starting price of $549, compared to Chrome&#8217;s wide price range roughly between $200 and $550 depending on the specs and hardware providers. Tablets, along with PCs, got a bump in sales during the pandemic, thanks to more people working and learning remotely, but in the long term, Jingling will have to get its pricing right and pin down where it sits in the market.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tDuwng7Kl0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/chromebooks-had-a-banner-2020/">Chromebooks had a banner 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chromebooks had a banner 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/chromebooks-had-a-banner-2020/embed/#?secret=tDuwng7Kl0" data-secret="tDuwng7Kl0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/jingos-10-million-linux-tablets-laptops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166043</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Duda, a WordPress rival, raises $50M to help agencies and bigger companies build better websites</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/duda-a-wordpress-rival-raises-50m-to-help-agencies-and-bigger-companies-build-better-websites/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/duda-a-wordpress-rival-raises-50m-to-help-agencies-and-bigger-companies-build-better-websites/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 11:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Self-expression for many consumers today comes in the form of social media and apps. But if you&#8217;re a larger business, even if you can&#8217;t ignore platforms like Facebook, a website still remains central part of your digital equation. Today, Duda &#8212; which has built a platform for larger businesses, and typically the agencies they employ, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Self-expression for many consumers today comes in the form of social media and apps. But if you&#8217;re a larger business, even if you can&#8217;t ignore platforms like Facebook, a website still remains central part of your digital equation. Today, <a href="https://www.duda.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Duda</a> &#8212; which has built a platform for larger businesses, and typically the agencies they employ, to build those websites &#8212; is announcing a round of growth funding of $50 million to expand its business.</p>
<p>This is a Series D, and it&#8217;s being led by Claridge IL with past investors Susquehanna Growth Equity and Vintage Investment Partners also participating. Itai Sadan, Duda&#8217;s CEO who co-founded the company with Amir Glatt, would not disclose the valuation, except to say that it has tripled since its last round. (It didn&#8217;t disclose then, either.) It has now raised $100 million and Sadan believes that the longer-term step will be an IPO in two or three years.</p>
<p>This latest round in the meantime is Duda&#8217;s biggest funding round to date, and it comes on the back of a predictably big year &#8212; one in which online presence for many became their <em>only</em> presence.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Duda has now crossed 1 million published websites from a community of 17,000 developers building on its platform. As a point of comparison, when we covered the company&#8217;s previous round &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/25/duda-nabs-25m-to-take-on-wordpress-with-a-web-development-platform-aimed-at-agencies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$25 million in September 2019</a> &#8212; Duda had crossed 560,000 websites and a community of 6,000 web professionals.</p>
<p>For some further context, these numbers may pale in comparison to WordPress overall, which today says it powers some 41% of the whole of the web (including, disclosure, TechCrunch.com itself) with tens of millions of websites created on its platform.</p>
<p>But Duda is not aiming to directly compete with all of WordPress, or SquareSpace, or Wix, or the wider field of web-building platforms: it describes itself as a &#8220;professional web site builder&#8221; and it specifically creates tools to handle not just large amounts of content, larger audiences, and larger processes (such as mass e-commerce transactions), but also a larger number of people who might need to engage with the site while it&#8217;s being constructed, and after it is built.</p>
<p>Having said that, in the area where it&#8217;s more directly competing &#8212; WordPress and others also provide tools to website building professionals and agencies &#8212; Sadan notes that some 60% of its customers are migrating from WordPress, according to the agencies that Duda has surveyed.</p>
<p>&#8220;The issues include security and, you know, plugins breaking,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The analogy I like to use is that it&#8217;s like Android versus iPhone,&#8221; he added, which to him means  &#8220;you get everything from one vendor: we do the hosting, provide a website builder, the templates, the widgets. And and you have a support team that you can actually call and talk to if you have any problems. That&#8217;s the guarantee that we give to our customers.&#8221; If the customer in question is an agency running tens or hundreds, or even thousands of sites, that is the kind of customer Duda handles.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s more recent turn, he said, has been into SaaS: that is, websites that provide tools on their platforms that others in turn can use, whether those are travel planning tools, or e-commerce platforms, and so on. SaaS was an area Duda entered into back in 2019 and it now accounts for about half of its business, Sadan said.</p>
<p>Within, that, unsurprisingly, e-commerce has been one of the standout areas, growing 65% and now accounting for about 20% of all of Duda&#8217;s business. &#8220;Part of this raise is to double down on that,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>“We look forward to partnering with Duda and its existing shareholders in further cementing Duda’s leadership in its space, as well as fulfilling its vision of making web design easy and scalable for web professionals serving clients across all industries,&#8221; said Oded Tal, Claridge IL’s founding managing partner, said in a statement. &#8220;The company has built an incredible product that is highly regarded by web professionals and operates in a truly massive, high growth market.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/duda-a-wordpress-rival-raises-50m-to-help-agencies-and-bigger-companies-build-better-websites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166114</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Formative, a student learning and analytics platform, raises $70M to challenge the summative, test-based approach to education</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/formative-a-student-learning-and-analytics-platform-raises-70m-to-challenge-the-summative-test-based-approach-to-education/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/formative-a-student-learning-and-analytics-platform-raises-70m-to-challenge-the-summative-test-based-approach-to-education/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 11:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E-Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[formative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tests are king in many school systems and other educational environments: they are seen as an efficient way to assess what knowledge students have retained, and how well they do on a level playing field where everyone has the same exam to take. Some, however, believe that system is flawed, and today a startup that&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tests are king in many school systems and other educational environments: they are seen as an efficient way to assess what knowledge students have retained, and how well they do on a level playing field where everyone has the same exam to take.</p>
<p>Some, however, believe that system is flawed, and today a startup that&#8217;s built a platform to provide another way of assessing and teaching is announcing a big round of funding on the heels of strong growth for its approach.</p>
<p><a href="https://goformative.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Formative</a> &#8212; a platform for K-12 teachers to provision assignments from other digital sources and learning platforms, assess how students handle them, help them based on those results, and then use progressive assignments to build a bigger picture and how that student is acquiring knowledge &#8212; has picked up $70 million, funding that it will be using to continue expanding the reach of its platform.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding is being led by Summit Partners previous investors Fika Ventures, Mac Ventures and Rethink Education also participating, among others. Formative is not disclosing its valuation but this is being described as a minority investment.</p>
<p>More significantly, it&#8217;s a major step up for the startup, which was founded in Santa Monica, CA, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2011/09/23/imagine-k12s-2011-startup-class-aims-to-invigorate-education-with-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">back in 2011</a> and had raised less than $7 million before now.</p>
<p>The funding however matches how well the startup has been doing. On the back of a major surge of interest in digital learning tools &#8212; spurred by the Covid-19 pandemic, the subsequent closure of physical schools, and a huge shift to remote learning &#8212; Formative says that its platform is already in the majority of U.S. school districts (specifically 92% of all U.S. school districts have at least one teacher signed up); that more than four million students have engaged with &#8220;Formatives&#8221; (as the assignments are casually called); and that it is delivering annual recurring revenue growth of around 700%.</p>
<p>And in keeping with that momentum, Formative has a lot of ambitious plans for the funding. They include building more analytical tools for teachers and administrators as well as parents and students; taking Formative to more international markets (it&#8217;s currently most active in English-speaking countries); and more generally (and perhaps most importantly) building technology that&#8217;s helping the system rethink what a quality education might look like, what form that should take.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of our big goals in the future is to really help be a gateway to evaluate the rigor and effectiveness of different curriculum streams,&#8221; said Craig Jones, the CEO who co-founded Formative with Kevin McFarland (the COO), in an interview. &#8220;We&#8217;re using all the data that we&#8217;ve collected, the billions of student responses to facilitate a bigger picture, insights on student learning, to the necessary stakeholders. That can spin off into a lot of different things that we can help our schools and teachers and parents use that data to ultimately drive additional learning.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jones and McFarland came up with the idea for Formative the startup while working on education PhDs at UCLA, where they were looking at how different pedagogic approaches might prove to work better than traditional methods for learning. Formative the startup takes its name from the idea of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formative_assessment" target="_blank" rel="noopener">formative evaluation</a>, where teachers provide regular, sustained assessment to check on students and modify how they are teaching to help them learn. In many ways it sits in opposition to an over-reliance on summative assessment, or the idea of wrapping up learning, and evaluating, based on a final test, although in practice even a shift to more formative can still help a student better prepare for those final summative assessments.</p>
<p>While the idea behind formative assessments has been around for a while, the breakthrough that Jones and McFarland had was to realize that the concept could be truly scaled and expanded if it was digitized, since that would enable efficient assignment delivery, and much more data collation, visualization, communication and analytics.</p>
<p>That concept, of course, took on a whole new profile in the last year and a half: schools and teachers that had already invested in the idea of using more digital tools, and possibly even Formative itself, ramped up their engagement; and they were joined by a new wave of educators scrambling to fill the big gap created by schools closing to slow down the spread of Covid-19, who might have previously had a very tenuous engagement with online learning. That had a big impact on a lot of the edtech sector, with online learning companies like Kahoot also seeing a big rise in use (and taking a bigger initiative into learning management by acquiring tools like Clever), as well as a plethora of other providers.</p>
<p>Formative too seized the moment and set up something it called the Covid-19 Assistance Program, providing free access to its platform &#8212; which is normally <a href="https://goformative.com/pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">priced in different tiers</a>, starting at free for a basic service, then increasing to $12 and $17 or &#8216;contact us&#8217; based on numbers of teachers using the platform that allows for more integrations, more analytics and so on. Some 5,000 teachers and schools signed up for the free service, Jones said, and McFarland noted that as schools reopened, it&#8217;s continued through in what has definitely been an evolving engagement with technology for many in the classroom. (And not all are so quick to shift: my kids&#8217; secondary school in London still strictly forbids people using &#8220;screens&#8221; at school and in classrooms.)</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s been a really big shift in the U.S., where there are more devices in classrooms now than there are students,&#8221; said McFarland, who said that many are taking a hybrid approach of saying, effectively, &#8216;If we want to utilize this, we can utilize it but not necessarily rely on it every single day.&#8217;</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s where you&#8217;ll see a lot of flexibility,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;They&#8217;re using a device, not a toy. We try to work a lot in that flexible hybrid environment.&#8221;</p>
<p>The approach it has taken is to make its system work in as seamless a way as possible for teachers, by not only integrating with all the learning materials that are &#8220;native&#8221; to digital platforms, but also making digitized versions of the most popular publications, and those that they are using as part of their curriculum, also something the teachers can call up and assign through Formative. In that regard, it&#8217;s not a learning content company, but more of a channel for making the content that is there, more accessible and more useful. It also links up with other tools like learning management systems when they are used to create a more efficient process overall.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a model that has resonated with both educators and investors.</p>
<p>“Formative helps to accelerate learning for students, save time for teachers and quantify results for school and district administrators,” said Tom Jennings, an MD at Summit Partners, in a statement. “We believe Formative has a rare combination of rapid, capital-efficient growth, innovative products, delighted customers and a humble, mission-driven team. We admire how Craig, Kevin and the team have built the business and expect our partnership to help Formative accelerate product enhancements and the continued global expansion of the business.” Jennings is joining Formative’s board with this round.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/formative-a-student-learning-and-analytics-platform-raises-70m-to-challenge-the-summative-test-based-approach-to-education/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166057</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter is eyeing new anti-abuse tools to give users more control over mentions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/twitter-is-eyeing-new-anti-abuse-tools-to-give-users-more-control-over-mentions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/twitter-is-eyeing-new-anti-abuse-tools-to-give-users-more-control-over-mentions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 10:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrissy Teigen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet troll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trolling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2166076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter is looking at adding new features that could help users who are facing abusive situations on its platform as a result of unwanted attention pile-ons, such as when a tweet goes viral for a reason they didn&#8217;t expect and a full firehose of counter tweets get blasted their way. Racist abuse also remains a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter is looking at adding new features that could help users who are facing abusive situations on its platform as a result of unwanted attention pile-ons, such as when a tweet goes viral for a reason they didn&#8217;t expect and a full firehose of counter tweets get blasted their way.</p>
<p>Racist abuse also remains a major problem on Twitter&#8217;s platform.</p>
<p>The social media giant says it&#8217;s toying with providing users with more controls over the @mention feature to help people &#8220;control unwanted attention&#8221; as privacy engineer, Dominic Camozzi, puts it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The issue is that Twitter&#8217;s notification system will alert a user when they&#8217;ve been directly tagged in a tweet &#8212; drawing their attention to the contents. That&#8217;s great if the tweet is nice or interesting. But if the contents is abusive it&#8217;s a shortcut to scale hateful cyberbullying.</p>
<p>Twitter is badged these latest anti-abuse ideas as &#8220;early concepts&#8221; &#8212; and encouraging users to submit feedback as it considers what changes it might make.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sometimes you want to talk, and sometimes you just &#8230; don&#39;t.</p>
<p>Check out these early concepts that could help control unwanted attention on Twitter.</p>
<p>Feedback, especially at this beginning stage, is invited (and wanted)! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f9f5.png" alt="🧵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/6SpzqiwFlL">pic.twitter.com/6SpzqiwFlL</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Dominic Camozzi (@_dcrc_) <a href="https://twitter.com/_dcrc_/status/1404578211309056006?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 14, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Potential features it&#8217;s considering include letting users &#8216;unmention&#8217; themselves &#8212; i.e. remove their name from another&#8217;s tweet so they&#8217;re no longer tagged in it (and any ongoing chatter around it won&#8217;t keep appearing in their mentions feed).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also considering making an unmention action more powerful in instances where an account that a user doesn&#8217;t follow mentions them &#8212; by providing a special notification to &#8220;highlight potential unwanted situations&#8221;.</p>
<p>If the user then goes ahead and unmentions themselves Twitter envisages removing the ability of the tweet-composer to tag them again in future &#8212; which looks like it could be a strong tool <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">against strangers who abuse @mentions. </span></p>
<p>Twitter is also considering adding settings that would let users restrict certain accounts from mentioning them entirely. Which sounds like it would have come in pretty handy when president Trump was on the platform (assuming the setting could be deployed against public figures).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2pBR78VZ6n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/trump-banned-from-twitter/">Twitter permanently bans President Trump</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter permanently bans President Trump&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/trump-banned-from-twitter/embed/#?secret=2pBR78VZ6n" data-secret="2pBR78VZ6n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Twitter also says it&#8217;s looking at adding a switch that can be flipped to prevent <em>anyone</em> on the platform from @-ing you &#8212; for a period of one day; three days; or seven days. So basically a &#8216;total peace and quiet&#8217; mode.</p>
<p>It says it wants to make changes in this area that can work together to help users by stopping &#8220;the situation from escalating further&#8221; &#8212; such as by providing users with notifications when they&#8217;re getting lots of mentions, combined with the ability to easily review the tweets in question and change their settings to shield themselves (e.g. by blocking all mentions for a day or longer).</p>
<p>The known problem of online troll armies coordinating targeted attacks against Twitter users means it can take disproportionate effort for the object of a hate pile-on to shield themselves from the abuse of so many strangers.</p>
<p>Individually blocking abusive accounts or muting specific tweets does not scale in instances when there may be hundreds &#8212; or even thousands &#8212; of accounts and tweets involved in the targeted abuse.</p>
<p>For now, it remains to be seen whether or not Twitter will move forward and implement the exact features it&#8217;s showing off via Camozzi&#8217;s thread.</p>
<p>A Twitter spokeswoman confirmed the concepts are &#8220;a design mock&#8221; and &#8220;still in the early stages of design and research&#8221;. But she added: &#8220;We&#8217;re excited about community feedback even at this early stage.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company will need to consider whether the proposed features might introduce wider complications on the service. (Such as, for example, what would happen to automatically scheduled tweets that include the Twitter handle of someone who subsequently flips the &#8216;block all mentions&#8217; setting; does that prevent the tweet from going out entirely or just have it tweet out but without the person&#8217;s handle, potentially lacking core context?)</p>
<p>Nonetheless, those are small details and it&#8217;s very welcome that Twitter is looking at ways to expand the utility of the tools users can use to protect themselves from abuse &#8212; i.e. beyond the existing, still fairly blunt, anti-abuse features (like block, mute and report tweet).</p>
<p>Co-ordinated trolling attacks have, for years, been an unwanted &#8216;feature&#8217; of Twitter&#8217;s platform and the company has frequently been criticized for not doing enough to prevent harassment and abuse.</p>
<p>The simple fact that Twitter is still looking for ways to provide users with better tools to prevent hate pile-ons &#8212; here in mid 2021 &#8212; is a tacit acknowledgment of its wider failure to clear abusers off its platform. Despite <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/12/twitters-abuse-problem-is-absolutely-a-failure-of-leadership/">repeated calls</a> for it to act.</p>
<p>A Google search for &#8220;<a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=*+leaves+twitter+after+abuse&amp;client=opera&amp;hs=o3m&amp;ei=8F7IYPuWBcGca-GZq5gP&amp;oq=*+leaves+twitter+after+abuse&amp;gs_lcp=Cgdnd3Mtd2l6EAMyBQghEKABOgcIABBHELADOggIIRAWEB0QHlCiiwpYwI4KYMiPCmgCcAJ4AIABgwGIAc4EkgEDNC4ymAEAoAEBqgEHZ3dzLXdpesgBBsABAQ&amp;sclient=gws-wiz&amp;ved=0ahUKEwj7zovVlpnxAhVBzhoKHeHMCvMQ4dUDCA0&amp;uact=5">* leaves Twitter after abuse</a>&#8221; returns numerous examples of high profile Twitter users quitting the platform after feeling unable to deal with waves of abuse &#8212; several from this year alone (including a number of footballers targeted with racist tweets).</p>
<p>Other examples date back as long ago as 2013, underlining how Twitter has repeatedly failed to get a handle on its abuse problem, leaving users to suffer at the hands of trolls for well over a decade (or, well, just quit the service entirely).</p>
<p>One recent high profile exit was the model Chrissy Teigen &#8212; who had been a long time Twitter user, spending ten years on the platform &#8212; but who <a href="https://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/chrissy-teigen-exits-twitter-after-10-years-deactivates-account/">pulled the plug on her account in March</a>, writing in her final tweets that she was &#8220;deeply bruised&#8221; and that the platform &#8220;no longer serves me positively as it serves me negatively&#8221;.</p>
<p>A number of soccer players in the UK have also been campaigning against racism on social media this year &#8212; <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/24/sports/soccer/soccer-racism-boycott.html">organizing a boycott of services</a> to amp up pressure on companies like Twitter to deal with racist abusers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">At least 70 racial slurs on my social accounts counted so far. For those working to make me feel any worse than I already do, good luck trying <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f44d-1f3fe.png" alt="👍🏾" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>&mdash; Marcus Rashford MBE (@MarcusRashford) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarcusRashford/status/1397693999872421888?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 26, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>While public figures who use social media may be more likely to face higher levels of abusive online trolling than other types of users, it&#8217;s a problem that isn&#8217;t limited to users with a public profile. Racist abuse, for example, remains a general problem on Twitter. And the examples of celebrity users quitting over abuse that are visible via Google are certainly just the tip of the iceberg.</p>
<p>It goes without saying that it&#8217;s terrible for Twitter&#8217;s business if highly engaged users feel forced to abandon the service in despair.</p>
<p>The company knows it has a problem. As far back as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/30/twitter-turns-to-academics-to-improve-conversational-health-on-the-platform/">2018</a> it said it was looking for ways to improve &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/30/twitter-turns-to-academics-to-improve-conversational-health-on-the-platform/">conversational health</a>&#8221; on its platform &#8212; as well as, more recently, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/05/twitter-bans-hate-speech-around-age-disability-and-in-the-wake-of-the-coronavirus-outbreak-disease/">expanding its policies</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/twitter-claims-increased-enforcement-of-hate-speech-and-abuse-policies-in-last-half-of-2019/">enforcement</a> around hateful and abusive tweets.</p>
<p>It has also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/09/twitter-retweet-changes-quote-tweet-election-misinformation/">added some strategic friction</a> to try to nudge users to be more thoughtful and take some of the heat out of outrage cycles &#8212; such as encouraging users to read an article before directly retweeting it.</p>
<p>Perhaps most notably it has banned some high profile abusers of its service &#8212; including, at long last, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/trump-banned-from-twitter/">president <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">troll</span> Trump himself earlier this year</a>.</p>
<p>A number of other <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/19/twitter-finally-bans-milo-yiannopoulos-one-of-its-most-notorious-trolls/">notorious trolls</a> have also been <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2020/jun/19/katie-hopkins-permanently-removed-from-twitter">booted over the years</a>, although typically only after Twitter had allowed them to carry on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/19/leslie-jones-twitter-harassment/?_ga=2.113856263.1805774279.1623657354-1757155993.1533833482">coordinating abuse of others via its service</a>, failing to promptly and vigorously enforce its policies against hateful conduct &#8212; letting the trolls get away with seeing how far they could push their luck &#8212; until the last.</p>
<p>By failing to get a proper handle on abusive use of its platform for so long, Twitter has created a toxic legacy out of its own mismanagement &#8212; one that continues to land it unwanted attention from high profile users who might otherwise be key ambassadors for its service.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="H2VSQBUImi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/sentropy-launches-tool-for-people-to-protect-themselves-from-social-media-abuse-starting-with-twitter/">Sentropy launches tool for people to protect themselves from social media abuse, starting with Twitter</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sentropy launches tool for people to protect themselves from social media abuse, starting with Twitter&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/sentropy-launches-tool-for-people-to-protect-themselves-from-social-media-abuse-starting-with-twitter/embed/#?secret=H2VSQBUImi" data-secret="H2VSQBUImi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dfRO1PylSC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/twitter-claims-increased-enforcement-of-hate-speech-and-abuse-policies-in-last-half-of-2019/">Twitter claims increased enforcement of hate speech and abuse policies in last half of 2019</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter claims increased enforcement of hate speech and abuse policies in last half of 2019&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/twitter-claims-increased-enforcement-of-hate-speech-and-abuse-policies-in-last-half-of-2019/embed/#?secret=dfRO1PylSC" data-secret="dfRO1PylSC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fyRgnMAloV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/18/twitter-launches-a-way-to-report-abusive-use-of-its-lists-feature/">Twitter launches a way to report abusive use of its Lists feature</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter launches a way to report abusive use of its Lists feature&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/18/twitter-launches-a-way-to-report-abusive-use-of-its-lists-feature/embed/#?secret=fyRgnMAloV" data-secret="fyRgnMAloV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sgEYK5pieg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/30/twitter-launches-its-anti-abuse-filter-for-direct-messages/">Twitter launches its anti-abuse filter for Direct Messages</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter launches its anti-abuse filter for Direct Messages&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/30/twitter-launches-its-anti-abuse-filter-for-direct-messages/embed/#?secret=sgEYK5pieg" data-secret="sgEYK5pieg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/twitter-is-eyeing-new-anti-abuse-tools-to-give-users-more-control-over-mentions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2166076</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
