<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:40:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: What’s the recipe for an H-1B?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/dear-sophie-whats-the-recipe-for-an-h-1b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/dear-sophie-whats-the-recipe-for-an-h-1b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dear Sophie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What goes into an H-1B petition? How has it changed in recent weeks? Is the lottery going to be wage-based or random?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/dear-sophie-how-can-i-sponsor-my-mom-and-stepdad-for-green-cards/">Dear Sophie: How can I sponsor my mom and stepdad for green cards?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/20/dear-sophie-what-are-bidens-immigration-changes/">Dear Sophie: What are Biden’s immigration changes?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie: </strong></p>
<p><strong>I want to sponsor a potential employee for an H-1B but the process for an H-1B petition seems pretty complex. </strong></p>
<p><strong>What goes into an H-1B petition? How has it changed in recent weeks? Is the lottery going to be wage-based or random?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Hungry to Learn in Hillsborough</strong></p>
<p>Dear Hungry:</p>
<p>This is a great time to get started on the H-1B lottery process &#8212; the time is fast approaching. In my most recent podcast episode about <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/055-h-1b-lottery-planning-part-1/">H-1Bs</a> on Immigration Law for Tech Startups, we covered planning for the H-1B lottery.</p>
<p>For all those foodies out there, in this column, I include a recipe for making your very first H-1B, plus the latest on lottery timing, whether the lottery will be wage-based and pay-to-play, the end of Buy American, Hire American, and changes in how H-1B wage levels are calculated.</p>
<h2><strong>New to the H-1B?</strong></h2>
<p>To get started, if you’re a newbie looking to whet your appetite with what’s involved in the H-1B process, there’s no need for the H-1B lottery season to feel complex or daunting. In fact, I wrote out a recipe so you can easily understand how to cook up an H-1B petition. ;)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Composite image credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Joanna Buniak <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2><strong>Alcorn H-1B Petition Recipe</strong></h2>
<h3>Ingredients</h3>
<ul>
<li>1 hungry employer seeking top global talent</li>
<li>&gt; 1 motivated job seeker(s) from around the world</li>
<li>&gt; 1 experienced business immigration attorney</li>
<li>&gt; 1 compassionate business immigration paralegal</li>
<li>1 package clear communication</li>
<li>1 gallon legal strategy; add more to taste</li>
<li>1 gallon hard work, divided</li>
<li>4 cups enthusiasm and dedication</li>
<li>2 questionnaires</li>
<li>1 Labor Condition Application (LCA)</li>
<li>4 forms for USCIS, 5 if you want to broil the case and eat sooner</li>
<li>1 robust letter of support from the company</li>
<li>To taste: Job seekers’ supporting documents, as needed</li>
<li>For startup flavor: sprinkling of company formation documents</li>
</ul>
<h3>Directions</h3>
<ol>
<li>It’s important to start off the H-1B with a solid legal strategy. Start by combining the employer and job seeker with at least one business immigration attorney and at least one business immigration paralegal. Add communication, half gallon of legal strategy and 1 cup of enthusiasm and dedication.</li>
<li>After the legal strategy has been prepped, separate the rest of the ingredients into separate containers (there will be some overlap).</li>
<li>Take the two questionnaires and distribute evenly between the employer and job seeker. Add to pan over medium-low heat or high heat depending on how soon everyone wants to eat.</li>
<li>Once the questionnaires are evenly browned, remove from heat and examine to make sure everything is cooked properly.</li>
<li>Once the questionnaires are reviewed, use some of the flavors to prepare the Labor Condition Application (LCA). Add in 1 cup of legal strategy and 1 quart of hard work. Let simmer for 7-10 days.</li>
<li>While the LCA is simmering, prep your forms one at a time. Add ½ cup of legal strategy and 2 cups of hard work.</li>
<li>After the forms are prepped, use the remaining legal strategy (more if necessary), 2 quarts of hard work, and 1 cup of enthusiasm and dedication to prepare the letter of support.</li>
<li>Once that’s ready, and the LCA is fully cooked, use ½ quart of hard work to add the glazed forms, LCA and letter of support into a bowl (preferably Adobe Acrobat). After adding the letter of support, fold in the job seekers’ supporting documents. Add 1 cup of enthusiasm and dedication. Add startup sprinkles if desired.</li>
<li>Finally, use the remaining 2 cups of enthusiasm and dedication to bake the case with USCIS!</li>
<li>Allow to cool for 15 calendar days if famished, or 4-6 months if you’re not that hungry.</li>
<li>Enjoy!</li>
</ol>
<p>For those experts out there hungering for the latest H-1B updates, here’s a rundown of what we’ve been seeing over the last two weeks since the Biden Administration took office:</p>
<h2>Lottery timing</h2>
<p>We expect an imminent announcement regarding the details of the upcoming FY2022 H-1B lottery registration process for cap-subject nonimmigrant visa petitions. The electronic registration period lasts at least 14 days, and the latest possible start date will be March 18, 2021. We’re also awaiting details on when the initial registration period will begin; last year it lasted from March 1 to 20. Feel free to listen back to <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/046-get-ready-for-h-1b-fy2022-lottery/">Get Ready for the H-1B FY2022 Lottery</a> for more details on how this worked last year and please stay tuned if you’re planning on filing an H-1Bs this year: Following these dates is crucial.</p>
<h2>Will the lottery be pay-to-play?</h2>
<p>A final rule called “Modification of Registration Requirement for Petitioners Seeking To File Cap-Subject H–1B Petitions” issued under Trump is currently scheduled to take effect on March 9, 2021. It would change the lottery from being random to being allocated based on highest to lowest relative wage. On January 20 the Biden administration instructed all agencies to consider delaying the effective date of certain rules not yet in effect, such as this one.</p>
<p>We’re all waiting with bated breath to see if this new change will go through. So far USCIS has not published any rule in the Federal Register indicating that the wage-based H-1B lottery will be delayed until after the scheduled start date. Also, over the past few days, there are some preliminary indications that the system will go forward as Trump planned, even under the Biden administration. This includes changes to the H-1B registration online tool and the form.</p>
<p>Although a wage-based allocation might make H-1B salaries more expensive for some employers, it would also dramatically increase immigrant security and employer predictability. As we all wait to see what USCIS will decide to do here, you can also access our <a href="https://witty-author-184.ck.page/22abd76a87">free H-1B guide</a> for more information on H-1Bs.</p>
<h2><strong>The end of Buy American, Hire American</strong></h2>
<p>On January 25, President Biden issued Executive Order 14005, “Ensuring the Future Is Made in All of America by All of America’s Workers.” This ends Trump’s “Buy American and Hire American” Executive Order and ensures a broader focus of helping American businesses “compete in strategic industries” and helping “America’s workers thrive.” We anticipate that this change will probably lead to higher rates of U.S.-business-based visas and green cards being approved in the future.</p>
<h2>Changes in wage-level calculations</h2>
<p>There are changes to the way that prevailing wages are calculated for visas such as H-1Bs and the PERM portion of the green card process. White House Chief of Staff Ron Klain indicated that new rules may be withdrawn or delayed. We’ve already seen the Department of Labor withdraw the Office of Foreign Labor Certification H-1B Program Bulletin and a Wage and Hour Division Field Assistance Bulletin (FAB) on LCAs, so it is no longer in effect. Additionally, DOL announced this week that it will delay the rule regarding prevailing wage levels, to not take effect until May 14, 2021.</p>
<p>We’re tracking all the major H-1B changes here, so stay tuned to Dear Sophie for all the latest!</p>
<p>All my best,</p>
<p>Sophie</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">Have a question? Ask it here.</a> We reserve the right to edit your submission for clarity and/or space. The information provided in “Dear Sophie” is general information and not legal advice. For more information on the limitations of “Dear Sophie,” please view our full disclaimer <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/attorney-advertising">here</a>. You can contact Sophie directly at Alcorn Immigration Law.</p>
<p>Sophie&#8217;s podcast, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/immigration-law-for-tech-startups/id1497746915">Immigration Law for Tech Startups</a>, is available on all major podcast platforms. If you&#8217;d like to be a guest, <a href="https://forms.gle/TsCtSJabKStwiUk88">she&#8217;s accepting applications!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/dear-sophie-whats-the-recipe-for-an-h-1b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107560</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edtech valuations aren&#8217;t skyrocketing, but investors see more exit opportunities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101325</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite the pandemic, investors don't seem to value remote learning as much as they do tech sectors like e-commerce and fintech.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Less than a year after we put out an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/09/12-major-league-edtech-vcs-discuss-top-trends-opportunities/">initial temperature check survey</a>, it&#8217;s clear that specialist investors are even more bullish on edtech. Bears are hard to find right now: the sector, once undercapitalized, has brought in $10 billion in venture capital funding globally in 2020.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/">As investors told us last week</a>, the biggest consumer opportunity in 2021 and beyond is lifelong learning (and portfolio companies have the profits to prove it).</p>
<p>But despite edtech&#8217;s noise, the second installment of our edtech survey shows that VCs think startups haven&#8217;t enjoyed parallel gains from a valuation perspective. The sentiment suggests that despite an apparent revitalization, edtech isn&#8217;t at the same level of &#8220;value&#8221; in investor eyes like sectors such as e-commerce, consumer and fintech.</p>
<p>As Mercedes Bent of Lightspeed Venture Partners said, &#8220;edtech didn&#8217;t tend to have heady valuations before the pandemic, and through 2020 I&#8217;m seeing edtech companies raise at valuations that are reasonable for Silicon Valley; still nothing like what we see in fintech.&#8221;</p>
<p>Now, valuations aren&#8217;t everything — but they aren&#8217;t nothing, either. Where edtech lacks in impressive valuations, investors see it gaining in exit opportunities. Many investors think that the exit environment is set to dramatically change in the next few years.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve already seen Nerdy and Skillsoft, two edtech companies, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/nerdy-varsity-tutors-spac/?tpcc=ECTW2020">go public via SPACs in the past few months.</a> Private equity ownership is an interesting dynamic to be aware of here, especially as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/vistas-3-5b-purchase-of-pluralsight-signals-a-maturing-edtech-market/">Vista recently scooped up PluralSight for $3.5 billion.</a></p>
<p>Here are the investors we spoke to, along with their areas of interest and expertise:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Deborah Quazzo</strong>, managing partner, GSV Ventures<em> (an education fund backing ClassDojo, Degreed, Clever)</em></li>
<li><strong>Ashley Bittner,</strong> founding partner, Firework Ventures <em>(a future-of-work fund with portfolio companies LearnIn and TransfrVR)</em></li>
<li><strong>Jomayra Herrera,</strong> principal, <a href="https://www.cowboy.vc/team">Cowboy Ventures</a> <em>(a generalist fund with portfolio companies Hone and Guild Education)</em></li>
<li><strong>John Danner</strong>, managing partner, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/dunce-capital">Dunce Capital</a> <em>(an edtech and future-of-work fund with portfolio companies Lambda School and Outschool)</em></li>
<li><strong>Mercedes Bent and Bradley Twohig</strong>, partners, <a href="https://lsvp.com/team/">Lightspeed Venture Partners</a> <em>(a multistage generalist fund with investments including Forage, Clever and Outschool)</em></li>
<li><strong>Ian Chiu,</strong> managing director, <a href="https://owlvc.com/ian.php">Owl Ventures</a> <em>(a large edtech-focused fund backing highly valued companies including BYJU’s, Newsela and Masterclass) </em></li>
<li><strong>Jan Lynn-Matern</strong>, founder and partner, <a href="https://emerge.education/team/">Emerge Education</a> <em>(a leading edtech seed fund in Europe with portfolio companies like Aula, Unibuddy and BibliU) </em></li>
<li><strong>Benoit Wirz</strong>, partner, <a href="https://www.brighteyevc.com/">Brighteye Ventures</a> <em>(an active edtech-focused venture capital fund in Europe that backs YouSchool, Lightneer, and Aula)</em></li>
<li><strong>Charles Birnbaum</strong>, partner, <a href="https://www.bvp.com/team/charles-birnbaum">Bessemer Venture Partners</a> <em>(a generalist fund with portfolio companies including Guild Education and Brightwheel)</em></li>
<li><strong>Daniel Pianko</strong>, co-founder and managing director, <a href="https://universityventures.com/team.php">University Ventures</a> <em>(a higher-ed and future-of-work fund that is backing Imbellus and Admithub)</em></li>
<li><strong>Rebecca Kaden</strong>, managing partner, <a href="https://www.usv.com/people/rebecca-kaden/">Union Square Ventures</a><em> (a generalist fund with portfolio companies including TopHat, Quizlet, Duolingo)</em></li>
<li><strong>Andreata Muforo</strong>, partner, <a href="https://tlcomcapital.com/team">TLCom Capital</a> <em>(a generalist fund backing uLesson)</em></li>
</ul>
<h2>Deborah Quazzo, managing partner, GSV</h2>
<p><strong>How has edtech’s boom impacted your deal-making? Has the new interest from generalist investors made valuations too bubbly, or is the market growth helping everyone?</strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">We met on Zoom with over 800 founding teams in COVID all over the world. We invested in 14 new companies and are just finishing rounds in two more. Valuation pressures are across tech sectors. I&#8217;d argue that education still lags average tech. The question for edtech is whether there is potential for a $100 billion company in the sector — will TAMs support it.</p>
<p><strong>Edtech has traditionally had few exits. When do you expect to see that change? Are you optimistic about the boom in funding lately? On the other hand, what consolidation do you expect to see?</strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Exit volume is rising already with a wide range of strategic and financial buyers of edtech companies — something that didn’t exist before. You will see numerous high-value exits in the first half of 2021. It’s the public market “exits” that have really lagged and that I hope turns around in 2021 and 2022. There are numerous global companies that could go public and the addition of SPAC IPOs creates another positive dynamic.</p>
<h2>Ashley Bittner, founding partner, Firework Ventures</h2>
<p><strong>How has edtech’s boom impacted your deal-making? Has the new interest from generalist investors made valuations too bubbly, or is the market growth helping everyone?</strong></p>
<p>The boom has not directly impacted my deal-making. We tend to work with CEOs looking for category expertise and track record in the space. I do worry about overexuberance creating disappointing returns that sour interest in the sector. There are important TAM, business model, pedagogical and regulatory factors to consider in valuation.</p>
<p><strong>Edtech has traditionally had few exits. When do you expect to see that change? Are you optimistic about the boom in funding lately? On the other hand, what consolidation do you expect to see? </strong></p>
<p>I think that will change shortly … I suspect many of the notable exits will come in future of work/human capital, consumer and in international markets for early education and K-12.</p>
<h2>Jomayra Herrera, principal, Cowboy Ventures</h2>
<p><strong>How has edtech’s boom impacted your deal-making? Has the new interest from generalist investors made valuations too bubbly, or is the market growth helping everyone?</strong><br />
Edtech has a history of going in booms (when investors find new excitement for the sector) and busts (when investors realize the difficulties in scaling companies in the space). We happen to be going through a boom right now, which I think is an overall good thing for market innovation. While valuations across all sectors are expensive right now, I think more capital going toward innovating a sector that has an impact on everyone’s life will result in a net positive. We have a history of investing in the sector and will continue to do so as we see new, category-defining companies arise.</p>
<p><strong>Edtech has traditionally had few exits. When do you expect to see that change? Are you optimistic about the boom in funding lately? On the other hand, what consolidation do you expect to see?</strong><br />
Edtech has had plenty of exits, but they are usually smaller and typically to PE firms or companies that have large distribution channels. There are very few large IPOs. I think we will start to see larger exits for three primary reasons: (I) accelerated consumer adoption of online and hybrid learning will increase market sizes, (II) as educators and institutions get more comfortable with leveraging technology in their practice we may see shorter sales cycle and more budget available, (III) many larger exits tend to be platforms as opposed to content providers (e.g., Canvas, 2U, Instructure) and with a higher standard for infrastructure there is a space for new competitors.<br />
I expect even more consolidation in the bootcamp space. We’re already seeing it with Flatiron, Thinkful, General Assembly, Bloc and many others having already been acquired.</p>
<h2>John Danner, managing partner, Dunce Capital<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101325</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Granulate nabs $30M for software to optimize workloads and latency</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/granulate-nabs-30m-for-software-to-optimize-workloads-and-latency/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/granulate-nabs-30m-for-software-to-optimize-workloads-and-latency/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Services like video streaming, gaming, media-intensive advertising and marketing technology are putting more strain on bandwidth and backend latency than ever before due to the surge of online traffic in the last year. But for most organizations in today&#8217;s usage-based cloud world, that can represent a huge cost in compute power &#8212; or a major [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Services like video streaming, gaming, media-intensive advertising and marketing technology are putting more strain on bandwidth and backend latency than ever before due to the surge of online traffic in the last year. But for most organizations in today&#8217;s usage-based cloud world, that can represent a huge cost in compute power &#8212; or a major investment in a company&#8217;s own latency technology &#8212; to try to address that.</p>
<p>This has created an opportunity for startups building optimization tools. Today, one called <a href="https://granulate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Granulate</a> &#8212; which has built software for organizations to handle those loads more intelligently and cost-effectively &#8212; is announcing a round of funding after seeing a huge boost in business in the last 10 months, with customer growth up 360% and revenues growing 570%.</p>
<p>The Tel Aviv startup has picked up $30 million, a Series B, led by Red Dot Capital Partners, with previous backers Insight Partners, TLV Partners, and Hetz Ventures, and new backer Dawn Capital also participating.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The timing of this Series B speaks to the demand in the market right now: it comes on the back of Granulate <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/22/granulate-announces-12m-series-a-to-optimize-infrastructure-performance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">closing a $12 million Series A</a> only in April last year. Investors say that its business growth is what prompted them to re-up so soon.</span></p>
<p>“Granulate’s unique technology and impressive growth since their last funding round reflects a rising market demand for their game-changing optimization solution,” said Yaniv Stern, Managing Partner at Red Dot Capital Partners, in a statement. “For companies facing rising infrastructure costs or focusing on operating cost reduction, Granulate offers a solution that can drive additional improvement regardless of any other solutions already deployed by their clients.”</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Granulate is not disclosing its valuation with this latest round, which brings the total raised by the startup to $45 million. </span></p>
<p>The opportunity in the market that Granulate is targeting is the fact that media-heavy content, and services like e-commerce that rely on efficient responsiveness on sites and apps to keep people from abandoning their shopping carts, are all on the rise.</p>
<p>But as companies look to keep customers happy with better quality services, they are also trying to keep an eye on margins and therefore want to keep infrastructure and computing costs low.</p>
<p>Granulate&#8217;s solution is software that sits at the server layer &#8212; either in the cloud or on-premises, as a customer prefers &#8212; that uses AI to detect workloads that a customer tags as important and prioritize them so that they work more efficiently. Granulate said that its software can improve response times by up to 40%, and throughput up to five times, while reducing costs by up to 60%. The company today has partnerships with AWS and Microsoft&#8217;s Azure and is in the &#8220;early stages&#8221; of talks with Google Cloud Platform.</p>
<p>Bigger tech companies like Netflix, Google and Amazon typically invest huge sums to build their own optimization technology, but it&#8217;s an area that smaller organizations (and you can still be huge while still being smaller than companies like Google) will not have the bandwith &#8212; pun intended &#8212; to address in the same way.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are aware of similar things going on inside of Netflix as what we have built,&#8221; Asaf Ezra, co-founder and CEO of Granulate, said in an interview. &#8220;But to us, it&#8217;s a testament of how large you need to be to address this issue and the talent you need to hire to address the lowest level issues.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s customers include at least one major retailer (which it can&#8217;t name), AppsFlyer, Period and PicsArt.</p>
<p>What will be interesting to watch is how the growth of 5G will affect the bigger problem: as Ezra notes, it will undoubtedly improve front-end latency.</p>
<p>&#8220;5g will not cannibalize Granulate,&#8221; he said. &#8220;In fact, when it becomes standard, the round trip time will be reduced for data, but the front end will be less of the ratio of the time, while the back-end latency will become more of the problem. 5g would solve only the access to your server, but not latency at the server itself.&#8221;</p>
<p>Longer term, it&#8217;s likely that Granulate will add more optimization and management solutions around those it already offers for latency, Ezra said, while also looking for ways to stand out apart from others in the same space. Competitors are in the process of some consolidation &#8212; witness <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/03/netapp-to-acquire-spot-formerly-spotinst-to-gain-cloud-infrastructure-management-tools/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spot acquired by NetApp</a> last June &#8212; so features based around a wider platform will likely be a key way to keep customers interested.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/granulate-nabs-30m-for-software-to-optimize-workloads-and-latency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107753</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon begins testing customer deliveries using Rivian electric vans</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/amazon-begins-testing-customer-deliveries-using-rivian-electric-vans/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/amazon-begins-testing-customer-deliveries-using-rivian-electric-vans/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon has started making deliveries to customers in Los Angeles using electric vans designed and built by Rivian. The electric vans, which are part of Amazon&#8217;s 2040 climate pledge, won&#8217;t go into series production until the end of the year, according to an update Wednesday by the company. Amazon declined to reveal how many electric [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon has started making deliveries to customers in Los Angeles using electric vans designed and built by Rivian.</p>
<p>The electric vans, which are part of Amazon&#8217;s 2040 climate pledge, won&#8217;t go into series production until the end of the year, <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/transportation/amazons-custom-electric-delivery-vehicles-are-starting-to-hit-the-road">according to an update</a> Wednesday by the company. Amazon declined to reveal how many electric vans were in the test fleet.</p>
<p>The customer deliveries are part of continuous testing being conducted by Amazon and Rivian to measure performance as well as safety durability in various climates and geographies. Road tests first started more than four months ago. The current fleet of vehicles was built at Rivian&#8217;s headquarters in Plymouth, Michigan and can drive up to 150 miles on a single charge. Rivian engineers will continue to refine the vehicles for the start of production at its Normal, Illinois factory.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2107782" style="width: 5589px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107782" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2107782 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg" alt="amazon vans-2" width="5579" height="3719" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg 5579w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 5579px) 100vw, 5579px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2107782" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p>
<p>In the meantime, these electric vehicles will continue to pop up on delivery routes in up to 15 additional cities in 2021. Eventually, Amazon plans to deploy at least 100,000 electric vans — the size of its order with Rivian — over the next several years.</p>
<p>Amazon and Rivian began testing vehicles four months prior to making customer deliveries, as part of the testing and development process. Amazon is also starting to modify its buildings to accommodate the new fleet of vehicles and has installed thousands of electric vehicle charging stations at its delivery stations across North America and Europe, the company said.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re loving the enthusiasm from customers so far&#8211;from the photos we see online to the car fans who stop our drivers for a first-hand look at the vehicle,&#8221; Ross Rachey, director of Amazon&#8217;s global Fleet and products, said in a statement. &#8220;From what we&#8217;ve seen, this is one of the fastest modern commercial electrification programs, and we&#8217;re incredibly proud of that.&#8221;</p>
<p>The exterior of Rivian-built electric vans share some the same design features found in today&#8217;s gas-powered versions. There are a few more rounded edges and an overall sleeker look to the electric vans.</p>
<p>The real difference is in the electric architecture and the custom features that have been integrated into the vans, including, highway driving and traffic assist features; exterior cameras that can provide a 360-degree view for the driver via a digital display, a larger interior floor space in the cabin to help with drivers getting to and from the cabin compartment, surround tail lights for better braking visibility and three-level shelving and a bulkhead cargo compartment separating door. Amazon&#8217;s Alexa voice assistant is also an embedded feature.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kmhWQVHQ5N"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/amazon-debuts-its-first-fully-electric-delivery-vehicle-created-in-partnership-with-rivian/">Amazon debuts its first fully electric delivery vehicle, created in partnership with Rivian</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon debuts its first fully electric delivery vehicle, created in partnership with Rivian&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/amazon-debuts-its-first-fully-electric-delivery-vehicle-created-in-partnership-with-rivian/embed/#?secret=kmhWQVHQ5N" data-secret="kmhWQVHQ5N" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/amazon-begins-testing-customer-deliveries-using-rivian-electric-vans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107767</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scratchpad snags $13M Series A to simplify Salesforce data entry</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/scratchpad-snags-13m-series-a-to-simplify-salesforce-data-entry/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/scratchpad-snags-13m-series-a-to-simplify-salesforce-data-entry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david sacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scratchpad]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Scratchpad is an early stage startup that wants to make it easier for sales people to get information into Salesforce by placing a notation layer on top of it. Today, it announced a $13 million Series A led by Craft Ventures with participation from Accel. The company has now raised a total of $16.6 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://scratchpad.com/">Scratchpad</a> is an early stage startup that wants to make it easier for sales people to get information into Salesforce by placing a notation layer on top of it. Today, it announced a $13 million Series A led by Craft Ventures with participation from Accel.</p>
<p>The company has now raised a total of $16.6 million including<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/scratchpad-announces-3-6m-seed-to-put-work-space-on-top-of-salesforce/"> the $3.6 million seed round</a> we covered in October. Co-founder and CEO Pouyan Salehi says that he wasn&#8217;t really looking to add capital, but the investors understood his vision and the money will help accelerate the product roadmap.</p>
<p>&#8220;To be honest, it actually wasn&#8217;t on our radar to raise again so soon after we raised what I consider a substantial seed. We had plenty of runway, but we started to see a lot of bottom-up user growth, this bottom-up motion just really started to take hold,&#8221; Salehi told me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He says that lead investor David Sacks, who has built some successful startups himself, really got what they were trying to do, and the deal came together fairly easily. In fact, the company caught the attention of Craft because they were hearing about Scratchpad from their portfolio companies.</p>
<p>The bottoms up approach is certainly something we have seen with developer tools and with software for knowledge workers, but companies often take aim at sales through the sales manager, rather than trying directly to get salespeople to use a particular tool. This approach of getting the end users involved early allows them to gain traction with members of the sales team before approaching management about paid versions.</p>
<p>Traditionally, sales teams don&#8217;t like the tools that are thrust upon them. They are essentially databases and even with a visual interface, it doesn&#8217;t really match up with the way they work. Scratchpad gives them an interface like a spreadsheet or notes application that they are typically using to hack together a workflow, but with a direct connection to Salesforce.</p>
<p>What the paid tiers provide is a way to bring all this data together and get a bigger picture view of what&#8217;s happening on the sales team, and it helps ensure that people are using Salesforce because the data in Scratchpad links to the Salesforce database automatically.</p>
<p>The company has completed the initial work of building the individual salesperson&#8217;s workspace, but the next phase, and part of what this capital is going to fund, is building the team workspace and seeing how this data can flow from individuals to a team view to give management more insight into what their individual reps are doing. This includes notes, which usually don&#8217;t make it into Salesforce, but provide a lot of context about interactions with customers.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s resonating with thousands of users (although Salehi didn&#8217;t want to share an exact customer number just yet). Customers include Autodesk, Brex, Lacework, Snowflake and Twilio.</p>
<p>Sacks says that he liked the viral way the product has been spreading. &#8220;Once a rep starts using Scratchpad, two things tend to happen: it becomes a daily habit, and they share it with their teammates. This phenomena of viral spread is rare and indicates a very strong product-market fit,&#8221; he said in a statement.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jnRYoCkB2f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/scratchpad-announces-3-6m-seed-to-put-work-space-on-top-of-salesforce/">Scratchpad announces $3.6M seed to put workspace on top of Salesforce</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Scratchpad announces $3.6M seed to put workspace on top of Salesforce&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/scratchpad-announces-3-6m-seed-to-put-work-space-on-top-of-salesforce/embed/#?secret=jnRYoCkB2f" data-secret="jnRYoCkB2f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/scratchpad-snags-13m-series-a-to-simplify-salesforce-data-entry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107761</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Duality scores $14M DARPA contract for hardware-accelerated homomorphic encryption</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/duality-scores-14m-darpa-contract-for-hardware-accelerated-homomorphic-encryption/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/duality-scores-14m-darpa-contract-for-hardware-accelerated-homomorphic-encryption/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DARPA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duality technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fully homomorphic encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homomorphic encryption]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Training AIs is essential to today&#8217;s tech sector, but handling the amount of data needed to do so is intrinsically dangerous. DARPA hopes to change that by tapping the encryption experts at Duality to create a hardware-accelerated method of using large quantities of data without decrypting it — a $14.5 million contract. Duality specializes in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Training AIs is essential to today&#8217;s tech sector, but handling the amount of data needed to do so is intrinsically dangerous. DARPA hopes to change that by tapping the encryption experts at <a href="https://dualitytech.com/">Duality</a> to create a hardware-accelerated method of using large quantities of data without decrypting it — a $14.5 million contract.</p>
<p>Duality specializes in what&#8217;s called fully homomorphic encryption. Without descending into the technical details, the main issue with everyday encryption methods — though it&#8217;s also sort of the point of them — is that they render the encrypted data totally unreadable, essentially noise unless you have the key to reverse the process. Doing that is computationally expensive with large datasets, and of course once the data is in the clear, it&#8217;s vulnerable to hackers, abuse, and other dangers.</p>
<p>There are methods, however, of encrypting data such that it can be analyzed and manipulated without decrypting it, and one of those is fully homomorphic encryption. Unfortunately FHE is even more computationally intense than ordinary encryption, ruling it out for applications where gigabytes or terabytes of data are called for. There are other methods of accomplishing the same ends but no one would cry if FHE suddenly became ten times easier.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="myHUquFwXj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/26/datafleets-keeps-private-data-useful-and-useful-data-private-with-federated-learning-and-4-5m-seed/">DataFleets keeps private data useful and useful data private with federated learning and $4.5M seed</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DataFleets keeps private data useful and useful data private with federated learning and $4.5M seed&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/26/datafleets-keeps-private-data-useful-and-useful-data-private-with-federated-learning-and-4-5m-seed/embed/#?secret=myHUquFwXj" data-secret="myHUquFwXj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>DARPA is as interested as anyone else in this field, though it has considerably deeper pockets than your garden variety encryption wonk. This contract is part of a <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/news-events/2020-03-02">broader effort called DPRIVE</a>, or Data Protection in Virtual Environments, and the stated goal is to develop a special purpose chip — an ASIC pre-assigned the code name TREBUCHET — to accelerate FHE by, hopefully, an order of magnitude or more.</p>
<p>The Duality team will bring in experts from USC, NYU, CMU, SpiralGen, Drexel University, and TwoSix Labs. The company has been in the game for a long time and has actually worked with DARPA before, so this is not new territory for them.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span lang="en-IL">Duality team members have been supporting DARPA-funded innovation and application of FHE for over a decade. Some members of our team developed the first ever prototype HE hardware accelerators under the DARPA PROCEED program starting in 2010 and are lead developers for the PALISADE open source FHE library, first developed for the DARPA SAFEWARE program in 2015,&#8221; said Duality Labs director and principal investigator for the contract, David Bruce Cousins, in a press release.</span></p>
<p>As you can see, they&#8217;re not short on acronyms either.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not totally clear what the timeline is on this, but considering the state of the technologies involved I wouldn&#8217;t expect results before at least two or three years from now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/duality-scores-14m-darpa-contract-for-hardware-accelerated-homomorphic-encryption/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107583</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple urged to root out rating scams as developer highlights ugly cost of enforcement failure</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-urged-to-root-out-rating-scams-as-developer-highlights-ugly-cost-of-enforcement-failure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-urged-to-root-out-rating-scams-as-developer-highlights-ugly-cost-of-enforcement-failure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fake reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FlickType]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107704</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple is facing calls to beef up enforcement against fake reviews and rating scams after a developer took to social media to shine a light on unfair practices he&#8217;s forced to compete with as a result of fraudulent activity on the App Store not being rooted out by the tech giant. Kosta Eleftheriou, one of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple is facing calls to beef up enforcement against fake reviews and rating scams after a developer took to <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011069395755009">social media</a> to shine a light on unfair practices he&#8217;s forced to compete with as a result of fraudulent activity on the App Store not being rooted out by the tech giant.</p>
<p>Kosta Eleftheriou, one of the founders of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/fleksy/">Fleksy</a> keyboard app (who was acquihired by Pinterest in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/15/pinterest-acquires-the-team-behind-fleksy-a-custom-ios-and-android-keyboard/">2016</a>), has &#8212; since March 2018 &#8212; been applying his expertise in autocorrect algorithms to make typing on the Apple Watch&#8217;s tiny screen not only possible but &#8220;simple, enjoyable and highly effective&#8221;, as <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/davidphelan/2019/03/02/apple-watch-flicktype-gesture-keyboard-app-makes-typing-a-breeze-is-it-any-good/">Forbes&#8217; reviewer put it</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The App Store has a big problem<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f447.png" alt="👇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>You: an honest developer, working hard to improve your IAP conversions.<br />Your competitor: a $2M/year scam running rampant.</p>
<p>1/<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f9f5.png" alt="🧵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011069395755009?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>His app, FlickType, has also been described by app reviewers as &#8220;astonishingly accurate&#8221;, a &#8220;fundamentally better keyboard&#8221; and &#8220;way faster&#8221; than the letter-by-letter scribble method Apple supports natively.</p>
<p>User reviews also include a large amount of glowing five-star ratings. The overall rating from users currently is 3.5 because a number of lower scores have pulled down the average. But if you take the time to dig in the developer can be seen responding consistently and constructively to issues being raised by users who leave lower scores.</p>
<p>Sometimes complaints are related to Watch platform issues outside his control (as Apple limits how third party text input can be accessed). Missing features are another common issue &#8212; and in many responses Eleftheriou responds by saying he&#8217;s added the setting the person was after (such as the ability to disable Auto-Correction) or highlighting a &#8220;brand new look &amp; feel to make typing even easier&#8221;. Other times he thanks users for raising bugs that he says have now been fixed.</p>
<p>Anyone reading how specifically each complaint is addressed would be confident the developer of FlickType is working hard to make sure the app meets customers expectations. Even though the overall rating means other Watch keyboard apps are &#8216;rated&#8217; higher overall.</p>
<p>The problem for Eleftheriou is all his genuine hard work is being undercut by copycat app makers who are able to leverage weak App Store enforcement to profit unfairly and at his expense.</p>
<p>The scam goes like this: A bunch of Watch keyboard apps are published that purport to have the same slick features as FlickType but instead lock users into paying eye-wateringly high subscription fees for what is, at best, a pale imitation.</p>
<p>You might expect quality to float to the top of the App Store but the trick is sustained by the clones being accompanied by scores of fake reviews/ratings which crowd out any genuine crowdsourced assessment of what&#8217;s being sold.</p>
<p>Fake reviews outnumber the real deal. It&#8217;s only if you take the time to read through the comments that alarm bells might start ringing&#8230;</p>
<p>&#8220;Wish I read the reviews before buying. I can&#8217;t even get it to work on my watch,&#8221; runs a one-star review of WatchKey, one of the rival apps Eleftheriou has complained about &#8212; which nonetheless has a higher overall rating than his app owing to also having a very large proportion of five-star reviews.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are so sorry for any inconvenienced caused. Please kindly email us to describe more about your scenario so that we can support you as soon as possible,&#8221; is WatchKey&#8217;s generic response to the one-star review.</p>
<p>&#8220;Terrible,&#8221; writes another one-star reviewer. &#8220;I bought this app to use T9 on my watch. I haven’t been able to get T9 to work on my watch, I’ve also reached out to the customer service email that’s listed on the app. But I haven’t gotten a response, I would advise to find a different app.&#8221;</p>
<p>WatchKey&#8217;s response to another abysmal verdict on its software? More platitudes: &#8220;Thank you for your feedback. Unfortunately, we haven&#8217;t received your email yet. Please kindly email us once more via support@vulcanlabs.co to describe more your scenario so we can support you as soon as possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>The pattern repeats across negative reviews. Even one of the &#8216;five&#8217; star reviews warns: &#8220;You need to pay if you want to use the T9. They make you write a review to &#8216;unlock&#8217; and then they ask for a payment.&#8221;</p>
<p>One component of the manipulation involves posting generic platitudes to do the bare minimum required by Apple to manage (genuine) negative reviews. The other is flooding listings with fake five star reviews to ensure the app&#8217;s overall rating remains high. Step 3: Profit.</p>
<p>Eleftheriou&#8217;s Twitter thread highlights some of what he says are &#8220;hundreds&#8221; of fake five star reviews which are being used to drive Watch owners toward downloading the malicious clones &#8212; using wording that refers to non-existent features or references things you&#8217;d be doing on other types of devices (suggesting the text may have been cut and pasted from genuine reviews elsewhere).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Then their glowing 5-star reviews start rolling in:</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />&quot;Very happy with it has control alt delete what&#39;s your two of my favorite Keys even though they don&#39;t work&quot; says user Munim Flynn, delighted to be able to invoke the Windows task manager on their Apple Watch. Huh?</p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011086265237504?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">There are hundreds of these. And then, there&#39;s hundreds of *real* ones too: <br /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />&quot;SCAM. What shady business. Downloaded this app on concept. It doesn’t even work. There is no free version AT ALL. You are tricked into downloading and then asked to pay $7.99 per FREAKING WEEK. Wow.&quot;</p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011094070841348?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>A quick Google search for &#8216;buy ios reviews&#8217; returns a staggering 643M results &#8212; including ads for companies touting &#8220;app reviews, installs and ratings [as] the best way to improve the rank of your apps at Appstore and Google Play&#8221; and selling &#8220;high quality iOS app reviews with ratings for $2.5&#8230; from 100% Real Users&#8221;.</p>
<p>Clearly selling fake reviews is a booming business &#8212; which in turn speaks to the woeful lack of effective enforcement.</p>
<p>In an extra fake kicker, Eleftheriou found that one of the scammy competitors had even ripped off his own app promo video &#8212; which was demoing the features offered by FlickType &#8212; and used it in ads targeting app consumers on Facebook and Instagram.</p>
<p>Facebook does have policies against third-party infringement (under section 4 of its prohibited content policy) &#8212; but you might as well whistle for pro-active enforcement from the adtech giant. It only acts when it gets a complaint of infringement so preventing abuse of his marketing materials would require Eleftheriou to spend even more of his time hunting for and reporting the malicious ads ripping off his stuff. (&#8220;I did report and Facebook did eventually take it down. But&#8230; I knew this was not going to be any sort of lasting relief,&#8221; he confirms.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">First, they made an app that appeared to fulfill the promise of a watch keyboard &#8211; but was practically unusable. Then, they started heavily advertising on FB &amp; Instagram, using my own promo video, of my own app, with my actual name on it: <a href="https://t.co/knnO6Mbiyb">https://t.co/knnO6Mbiyb</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011076127625217?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Of course the really big kicker here is that Apple&#8217;s rules for developers clearly stipulate that submitting fraudulent reviews is a violation of the developer program licence agreement.</p>
<p>Its App Store review guidelines also warn that developers who attempt to cheat the system (such as by manipulating ratings) may only have their apps removed from the App Store &#8212; and could be expelled from Apple&#8217;s developer program entirely.</p>
<p>So &#8212; to put it politely &#8212; it&#8217;s not a good look for Apple that an indie developer with proven expertise and reputation is having to spend so much resource fighting App Store scams because its own enforcement has failed to stamp them out. To the point where he feels the only path forward is to resort to a public call out on social media to highlight systematic enforcement failures.</p>
<p>Eleftheriou tells TechCrunch he decided to raise the complaint on social media after what he describes as &#8220;simply depressing results&#8221; from engaging with Apple&#8217;s official &#8216;app dispute&#8217; channel.</p>
<p>&#8220;They put you in contact with the other developer in question, and oversee the thread while they hope you will resolve the issue with the other party directly,&#8221; he explains. &#8220;The scammers I complained about in that dispute weren&#8217;t even the bigger scammers I mention in my Twitter thread. Yet, the complaint I had with them barely got addressed, and there was no response from Apple whatsoever on the issue of the fake ratings and reviews. Simply a &#8216;if we don&#8217;t hear back from you very soon we consider the matter resolved&#8217;. We even reached out to Apple privately after that but got no response.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What was most impressive to me, was that in the presence of the Apple legal team, the scammers did not feel threatened one bit &#8212; almost as if they know Apple is unlikely to do anything,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;In my view, Apple simply does not devote enough resources on this area.&#8221;</p>
<p>Since raising the issue on Twitter, Eleftheriou has reported a partial win &#8212; in that some of the apps he had complained about have been taken down from the App Store. (At the time of writing Apple has not made any public statement confirming any action.)</p>
<p>However the developer accounts do not appear to have been banned at this time. &#8220;It&#8217;s astounding that even pulling a scam like that, doesn&#8217;t get your developer account revoked!&#8221; Eleftheriou told us. &#8220;I mean if that didn&#8217;t do it, what would??&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">While the “KeyWatch” $300k/month scam was removed, Apple did *not* take down their developer account. </p>
<p>Not only that, but their other scam, “GPS Speedometer”, remains on the App Store stealing $200k/month from unsuspecting people, with $416/year subscriptions.<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f631.png" alt="😱" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>UNREAL! <a href="https://t.co/gU3R45LskO">pic.twitter.com/gU3R45LskO</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356725679102943232?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 2, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>We reached out to Apple about this issue and it provided some background information related to its developer policies &#8212; which forbid attempts to cheat the system (such as by trying to trick the review process, steal user data, copy another developer’s work, or manipulate ratings or App Store discovery), among other relevant provisions.</p>
<p>We also asked Apple if it&#8217;s considering any policy changes in light of the issues raised by Eleftheriou &#8212; and will update this post with any response.</p>
<p>&#8220;The main issue in my view is not the cloning here. I didn&#8217;t even care that they were using my name, or made their screenshots similar to mine etc. If only there was a system to better prevent fake ratings and reviews, none if this would matter,&#8221; Eleftheriou also told us. &#8220;People would be able to collectively protect themselves through their 1-star &#8216;votes&#8217; but when that system is allowed to get rigged, everything else goes out the window.</p>
<p>&#8220;The promise of ratings and reviews you can trust does not exist any more which erodes consumer trust at an ever accelerating pace,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;I did a Google search to see what those &#8216;companies&#8217; look like, if you want to buy ratings and reviews. These are proper, full blown companies, with support systems, and claims that their ratings won&#8217;t get deleted by Apple, unlike their competitors. It was shocking to see that this is an industry that is thriving.&#8221;</p>
<p>The issue of fake reviews certainly goes far beyond Apple&#8217;s App Store. And is a <a href="https://www.webretailer.com/b/amazon-fake-reviews/">very insidious one</a>.</p>
<p>Fake reviews are pretty much a universal experience across the Internet &#8212; whether you&#8217;re trying to buy stuff on Amazon, looking at places to visit on Tripadvisor or trying to find a local dentist with the help of reviews on Google Maps (in short; don&#8217;t) &#8212; given how many platforms now incorporate user reviews.</p>
<p>But the issue does look especially toxic for Apple.</p>
<p>A core part of the USP for its App Store is the claim that Apple&#8217;s review process sums to a higher quality, more trustworthy experience than alternative marketplaces that aren&#8217;t so carefully overseen.</p>
<p>So a failure to do more to enforce against review scams and rating manipulations risks taking a lot more shine off Apple&#8217;s brand than Cupertino should be comfortable with.</p>
<p>Simply put: Consumers expect a higher standard from Apple. That&#8217;s why they&#8217;re willing to pay a premium for its products. Under-resourcing App Store review and enforcement thus looks like a false economy &#8212; not least because it risks driving quality developers like Eleftheriou away.</p>
<p>If a developer with so much pedigree can&#8217;t reliably sell his wares on the App Store what does that say about Apple&#8217;s &#8216;premium&#8217; marketplace?</p>
<p>The issue is also likely to be increasingly on the radar of consumer watchdogs and regulators in the coming years. The European Union, for example, is planning to bake binding transparency and reporting requirements into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">incoming platform regulations</a> &#8212; as it seeks to promote <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/14/europe-agrees-platform-rules-to-tackle-unfair-business-practices/">fairness and accountability</a> in digital businesses.</p>
<p>While an <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/dir/2019/2161/oj">EU Omnibus Directive</a> that came into force at the start of last year &#8212; with a two year deadline for Member States to transpose it &#8212; aims to beef up consumer rights through enhanced enforcement and transparency requirements &#8212; including directly addressing the issue of fake reviews by placing an obligation on traders to take &#8216;reasonable and proportionate&#8217; steps to ensure reviews are genuine, among other measures.</p>
<p>In the EU platforms will soon start being required to &#8216;justify&#8217; their enforcement failures vis-a-vis fake reviews. And if they can&#8217;t, well, the regime includes tough &#8216;GDPR-level&#8217; fines for breaches of consumer protection law. So the costs won&#8217;t only be reputational, as currently.</p>
<p>The UK&#8217;s Competition and Markets Authority, meanwhile, has also been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/facebook-and-ebay-pledge-to-do-more-to-tackle-trade-in-fake-reviews-after-pressure-from-uk-regulator/">cracking down</a> on the trade in fake reviews &#8212; specifically targeting Facebook, Instagram and eBay in recent years. Further attention to the issue from UK oversight bodies, which are now operating independently of the EU, also seems likely.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LbgUoOgn8I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/facebook-and-ebay-pledge-to-do-more-to-tackle-trade-in-fake-reviews-after-pressure-from-uk-regulator/">Facebook and eBay pledge to do more to tackle trade in fake reviews after pressure from UK regulator</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook and eBay pledge to do more to tackle trade in fake reviews after pressure from UK regulator&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/facebook-and-ebay-pledge-to-do-more-to-tackle-trade-in-fake-reviews-after-pressure-from-uk-regulator/embed/#?secret=LbgUoOgn8I" data-secret="LbgUoOgn8I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-urged-to-root-out-rating-scams-as-developer-highlights-ugly-cost-of-enforcement-failure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107704</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lightspeed and Max Levchin bet on Balance to bring B2B payments into the digital world</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/lightspeed-and-max-levchin-bet-on-balance-to-bring-b2b-payments-into-the-digital-world/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/lightspeed-and-max-levchin-bet-on-balance-to-bring-b2b-payments-into-the-digital-world/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Balance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Consumer payments is by no means a solved problem (I’ll trigger one hundred blockchain people if I say otherwise), but it sure as heck a pretty improved one. Checkout is a breeze with modern tools ranging from Stripe and PayPal to Fast and Rapyd to Apple and Google Pay. If you happen to need financing, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Consumer payments is by no means a solved problem (I’ll trigger one hundred blockchain people if I say otherwise), but it sure as heck a pretty improved one. Checkout is a breeze with modern tools ranging from Stripe and PayPal to Fast and Rapyd to Apple and Google Pay. If you happen to need financing, on-the-spot lending platforms like Affirm, which recently debuted on NASDAQ and is currently valued at $26 billion, will extend that financing nearly instantaneously.</p>
<p>Then you head over to B2B payments … and you recoil in horror as you migrate away from a utopian future of promise to the ruins of an antiquated past. A mash-mash of payment methods from paper checks to wire transfers get sent against invoices, none of which are automatically synchronized across financial information systems. Financing is complicated and offered by a bank through — gasp — an actual phone call. Shudder, because there probably involves a fax machine somewhere in that loop.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.getbalance.com">Balance</a> is looking to modernize all of it, as fast as possible.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Balance offers efficient B2B payments that allows merchants to offer a variety of payment methods including ACH and bank wires as well as a variety of payment terms including payment on delivery, net payment terms, and payment by milestone. Behind the scenes, Balance underwrites the terms of those transactions requiring financing by evaluating the risk of the customer, the merchant, and the specific payment terms selected. Balance is built on top of Stripe and offers all of Stripe’s credit card payment options, but then extends far beyond them.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107342" style="width: 525px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107342" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2107342" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Checkout-When-To-Pay.jpeg?w=515" alt="" width="515" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Checkout-When-To-Pay.jpeg 522w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Checkout-When-To-Pay.jpeg?resize=114,150 114w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Checkout-When-To-Pay.jpeg?resize=227,300 227w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Checkout-When-To-Pay.jpeg?resize=515,680 515w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Checkout-When-To-Pay.jpeg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 515px) 100vw, 515px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107342" class="wp-caption-text">Balance&#8217;s checkout flow includes options to pick financing terms and means of payment. Photo via Balance.</p></div></p>
<p>Take, for instance, your typical SaaS offering. Typically, employees will buy individual seat licenses to the software with their corporate cards (managed maybe with Brex), a payment facilitated through Stripe or PayPal. As a company spends more and more on that particular software, one of the two parties will reach out and negotiate a comprehensive enterprise rate for single payment. It is here that Balance becomes key. That full payment could be done on Balance, with net 30 payment terms using a bank wire all automatically synced against an invoice offered by the service to the customer.</p>
<p>B2B payments is a massive market measured in the tens of trillions globally, which is perhaps one reason why Balance has an all-star fintech investing syndicate behind its seed round. It raised $5.5 million from Tal Morgenstern of Lightspeed, Stripe and Max Levchin through his SciFi VC. Lightspeed previously backed Levchin’s Affirm. Balance was part of the summer 2020 batch of Y Combinator, although declined to appear at demo day and remained in stealth as its seed round had already been locked in. UpWest, which invests in Israeli companies heading to the U.S. market, also invested.</p>
<p>Balance was founded by Bar Geron and Yoni Shuster in late 2019 to early 2020 and came through their experience working at PayPal together. “PayPal is a key part of the story,” Geron said, describing how the duo learned about the consumer payments world. Shuster stayed on at PayPal, while Geron headed to <a href="https://www.behalf.com">Behalf</a>, a company that also works on B2B financing and cash flow management. Geron said that Behalf was a “pain point solution” to the challenge of offering net payment terms, but that the company didn’t attempt to digitize the mostly analog model of payments. Geron saw an opportunity and linked up with Shuster to take a more expansive approach to the problem.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107340" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107340" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2107340" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Founders-Photo-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Founders-Photo-1.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Founders-Photo-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Founders-Photo-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Founders-Photo-1.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Founders-Photo-1.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Founders-Photo-1.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Founders-Photo-1.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Founders-Photo-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107340" class="wp-caption-text">Balance founders Bar Geron and Yoni Shuster. Photo via Balance.</p></div></p>
<p>Our dream is to “make B2B payments as easy as card payments,” Geron said. “What we wanted to do is to make it as easy as Stripe … take a snippet of code and just put it on your site.” With that in place, Balance’s other features like invoice syncing and financing become instant features.</p>
<p>Through Y Combinator, the team learned that other tech companies constantly confronted these problems, and that they would serve as useful first customers. The critical customers though in Geron’s mind are B2B marketplaces where there are few solutions to synchronize the complexities of marketplace transactions. Geron says that “we have several customers in that space.” Another key customer segment are service providers who work on milestone-based payments, such as 20% upfront and 80% on delivery. “We automated [all that] and put it online,” he said.</p>
<p>Balance makes money on what is known as a “factoring fee” where it pays the merchant ahead of the payment from the customer. Geron noted its 2%, although the actual rate varies based on the risk involved.</p>
<p>The two founders are based in Israel, although like most startups these days, they have a distributed workforce.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/lightspeed-and-max-levchin-bet-on-balance-to-bring-b2b-payments-into-the-digital-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106995</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beam raises $9.5 million to build a web browser that collects ideas</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/beam-raises-9-5-million-to-build-a-web-browser-that-collects-ideas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/beam-raises-9-5-million-to-build-a-web-browser-that-collects-ideas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Beam has raised a $9.5 million Series A round. The company is working on a new web browser that completely rethinks the way you start a web session and browse the web. The startup is founded by Dom Leca and Sébastien Métrot. Dom Leca previously worked on Sparrow, an email app with an opinionated design. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://beamapp.co">Beam</a> has raised a $9.5 million Series A round. The company is working on a new web browser that completely rethinks the way you start a web session and browse the web. The startup is founded by Dom Leca and Sébastien Métrot. Dom Leca previously worked on Sparrow, an email app with an opinionated design.</p>
<p><a href="https://pacecapital.com">Pace Capital</a> is leading today’s funding round. Several business angels are also participating, such as Christan Reber, Harry Stebbings and Albert Wenger. Existing investors Spark, Amaranthine, C4V and Alven are also investing once again.</p>
<p>Beam is also announcing that it is acquiring <a href="https://radblock.app">RadBlock</a>, an ad blocker for Safari.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If you’re not familiar with Beam, I encourage you to read <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/beam-is-building-a-web-browser-that-gathers-knowledge-from-your-web-activity/">my previous article</a> on the company — I describe how the product is going to work and the reasoning behind it.</p>
<p>In short, Beam is a web browser focused on knowledge. Many people spend a ton of time mindlessly browsing the web. When you close the last tab, you realize that you didn’t learn much and you don’t have any note.</p>
<p>You can bookmark stuff, but chances are you either don’t use bookmarks or you never check them. And if you want to find something again, you often end up entering a Google query and starting from scratch.</p>
<p>With Beam, every time you search for something, it creates a new session. Each session is represented by a note card. When you’re done browsing, the note card summarizes your findings. Your search query is the title of the card, the most important sites appear near the top of the note. Irrelevant content is listed at the end of the note.</p>
<p>You can then add text, remove links, reorganize stuff and create a full-fledged note. Basically, you end up creating comprehensive notes without even realizing it.</p>
<p>Beam is an ambitious project and the company will have to iterate on that initial idea. But it sounds like a great way to start using the web as a kid. You get to learn more about your passions based on what you do on the web.</p>
<p>Right now, there are seven people working for Beam. The company is going to hire machine learning and natural language processing experts as well as more developers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6TOGD9c8jH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/beam-is-building-a-web-browser-that-gathers-knowledge-from-your-web-activity/">Beam is building a web browser that gathers knowledge from your web activity</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Beam is building a web browser that gathers knowledge from your web activity&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/beam-is-building-a-web-browser-that-gathers-knowledge-from-your-web-activity/embed/#?secret=6TOGD9c8jH" data-secret="6TOGD9c8jH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/beam-raises-9-5-million-to-build-a-web-browser-that-collects-ideas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099117</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Miami won’t be the next Silicon Valley because we don’t need another one</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/miami-wont-be-the-next-silicon-valley-because-we-dont-need-another-one/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/miami-wont-be-the-next-silicon-valley-because-we-dont-need-another-one/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 13:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south florida]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Miami is reflective of the future of global startup hubs. It won’t be the next Silicon Valley, because we don’t need another one.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Laura González-Estéfani</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Lauragestefani">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Laura González-Estéfani is the founder and CEO of <a href="https://theventure.city/en/">TheVentureCity</a>, an international, operator-led venture acceleration model designed to make the global entrepreneurial ecosystem more diverse, international and accessible to fair capital.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The rush of founders and investors from the West Coast to states like Texas and Florida are the precursor for something bigger, a movement decades in the making.</p>
<p>The future of startups is a decentralized, global ecosystem. Where wealth and knowledge isn’t concentrated, but shared and open. Where there aren’t capitals, but networks.</p>
<p>Miami has had a head start.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Let’s set the scene. Miami already <a href="https://startupgenome.com/ecosystems/miami">ranks</a> among the world’s most prominent (nontraditional) startup hubs, and 2020 saw <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/why-miami-is-the-next-hot-tech-hub/">more big names in tech</a> migrate to Florida. Miami Mayor Francis Suarez has been spurring on the influx with an extremely popular Twitter campaign.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Miami already ranks among the world’s most prominent (nontraditional) startup hubs, and 2020 saw more big names in tech migrate to Florida.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>These are signs of what globally minded business savvies already know is true. The world is ready for Miami as the pioneer of future tech hubs. Because the city isn’t just a launching pad for U.S. startups with interests in Latin America. It’s a strategic landing pad for global startups who want a presence in the Western Hemisphere.</p>
<p>Across the globe, international opportunities for founders are growing: There is greater connectivity and greater potential for emerging market entrepreneurs to produce life-changing products.</p>
<p>Where will those entrepreneurs want to have a presence? At the heart of global investor and entrepreneur networks, in true melting pots, and at crossroads between mature and emerging markets.</p>
<p>That’s why Miami is in focus right now, but it’s only the first of many cities that will soon be a part of this global trend.</p>
<p>Here’s why Miami is spearheading this new global grid of startup ecosystems.</p>
<h2>1. Global tech is no longer concentrated — it’s fragmented across the world</h2>
<p>Two-thirds of the world&#8217;s top startup ecosystems are <a href="https://startupgenome.com/article/state-of-the-global-startup-economy">outside of North America</a>. Not only that, but <a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/silicon-valley-exodus-the-majority-of-professionals-said-theyd-follow-tech-leaders-to-emerging-tech-hubs/">70% of professionals</a> believe that technology power is dispersing away from Silicon Valley. The Bloomberg Innovation Index <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2020/dec/20/texas-silicon-valley-austin-tech-workers">bumped</a> the United States down from top spot in 2013, to No. 9 in 2020. Tech knowledge and power is growing in Europe and Asia, flourishing in cities like Shanghai and Berlin.</p>
<p>Similarly, <a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/sanjose/news/2020/12/28/nine-predictions-of-whats-coming-in-startupland.html">microbusinesses</a> will increase (we’re already seeing a <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/3cbb0bcd-d7dc-47bb-97d8-e31fe80398fb">surge in new businesses</a> being created around the world), and less of them will have zip codes.</p>
<p>So, when big businesses or VC firms leave/explore outside Silicon Valley, or the United States entirely, they’re not building more of the same, they’re showing us that Silicon Valley is no longer the only M.O. The emerging M.O. is borderless and connected: an inclusive network. It gives investors greater access to more distant business opportunities. It allows entrepreneurs to choose the most convenient place to build a company — and save huge amounts of overhead — while also sharing more expertise.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xZmxYZQ1Mf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/8-miami-area-investors-assess-americas-southernmost-tech-ecosystem/">8 Miami-area investors assess America&#8217;s southernmost tech ecosystem</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;8 Miami-area investors assess America&#8217;s southernmost tech ecosystem&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/8-miami-area-investors-assess-americas-southernmost-tech-ecosystem/embed/#?secret=xZmxYZQ1Mf" data-secret="xZmxYZQ1Mf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>2. You can build global companies from emerging hubs</h2>
<p>Startups in emerging markets have always received a mere fraction of the funding available to U.S. startups. Which means that when money dries up across the board, they are under even more pressure to come up with the most innovative solutions just to survive.</p>
<p>Empowering these local entrepreneurs is the fact that today’s problems need local solutions — from health to logistics, these verticals all require inherent knowledge of domestic infrastructure and services.</p>
<p>The potential here is huge. Emerging markets house the greatest world populations — China, India, Brazil, Mexico, Nigeria… — and language and connectivity barriers are slowly melting away, with mobile internet use <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/global/2019/02/05/digital-connectivity-growing-rapidly-in-emerging-economies/">surging</a>.</p>
<p>Investors are <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/8bc4a5a0-d5dd-437e-8cea-b737746d57f6">already perking up</a> to the enormous value of emerging markets, from Asia to Latin America, especially as the strength of the U.S. dollar drops. Just in Q4 2020, VC investment in Latin America saw a 93% growth over Q4 2019, according to Pitchbook.</p>
<p>What does this mean for emerging tech hubs? First, there will be more of them, more distributed and with more funding. Second, we’re going to see a stronger flow of emerging market startups serving customers in the United States to offer services with proven traction, rather than vice versa.</p>
<p>The disruptive products these companies develop and test on millions of users back home find fertile markets not only in the United States, but in other emerging markets with similar needs. Many such companies will want to use the United States as a strategic operating base while keeping the engineering teams in their HQs.</p>
<p>That’s because our founders, accelerators, investors and support organizations have historic experience in internationalization, as well as connections across the globe. So where will these foreign companies land — will they be interested in Denver or Austin, or rather a well-connected city that has made a name for itself as an international hub?</p>
<p>Miami is a landing pad where foreign startups can access both the United States and emerging markets with comparable trends. The <a href="https://www.miamiherald.com/opinion/op-ed/article248220415.html">city has made strides</a> to position itself at the intersection between mature and emerging markets, creating an ecosystem that is inclusive (half of the population is foreign-born), prioritizes collaboration over individualism and encourages the arrival of newcomers. As such, it will be a (working) model for diverse startup cities.</p>
<h2>3. The money will follow</h2>
<p>Amid talks of a Silicon Valley &#8220;exodus,&#8221; some have been <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/28/opinion/silicon-valley-exodus.html">quick to point out</a> that the hub has always held strong because of a key feature: access to capital.</p>
<p>But investors will follow the best opportunities. Which means that tech investment will only become more global. Put simply, the concentration of wealth in Silicon Valley is incompatible with the growing demand for tech across the globe. Silicon Valley isn’t going to die, but the pie is getting bigger. And more of that capital is already going to emerging tech hubs.</p>
<p>The symptoms include U.S. VC giants branching into emerging regions — like Sequoia opening its first <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexkonrad/2020/11/17/vc-firm-sequoia-puts-down-roots-in-europe-startup-scene/?sh=71148aeb5eac">European office</a>, and SoftBank funneling <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20190307005336/en/SoftBank-Group-Corp.-Announces-Launch-New-5">billions</a> into Latin America.</p>
<p>This means U.S. investors will favor regions where they can easily connect with global opportunities, like Miami. Last year, VC investment in the Miami region rose to over <a href="https://www.refreshmiami.com/the-year-in-vc-part-2-top-vc-deals-in-2020-for-south-florida-and-more/">$2.2 billion</a>, despite the pandemic (compared to <a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/articles/hot-or-not-where-european-vc-funding-went-in-2020">$1.4 billion</a> in all of Spain). But not only that — there is a lot of funding coming from investors in emerging markets.</p>
<p>In Latin America, local funders play a huge role in supporting promising companies. In 2019, <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/report-vc-funding-in-latin-america-more-than-doubles-to-4-6b-in-2019/">almost 40%</a> of the record-breaking $4.6 billion VC dollars invested in Latin America involved a co-investment with at least one Latin American investor. And from what we&#8217;re seeing, regional investors are increasingly funding U.S.-based organizations.</p>
<p>They — and others like them — will want to find ecosystems where they can connect with local and foreign founders with whom they can foster partnerships across markets.</p>
<p>Places like Miami need to house these kinds of networks. South Florida already has globally minded accelerators and startup programs like <a href="https://www.miami.500.co/">500 Startups</a>, Plug &amp; Play and TheVentureCity; and VC firms with international networks, such as Ocean Azul, Endeavor Catalyst, Starlight Ventures, Level VC and now <a href="https://www.refreshmiami.com/boom-softbank-launching-100m-fund-to-invest-in-miami-startups/">SoftBank</a>.</p>
<h2>4. Miami is better positioned for the future needs of startups</h2>
<p>I’m going to end by underscoring the case for Miami as the U.S. pioneer of international connector startup hubs.</p>
<p>Startups build more with less every five years, and going international from day one, allows them to test their products in more markets straight away. This is feasible given worldwide level of connectivity, and helps to be in an environment that is constantly looking outward, beyond our borders.</p>
<p>It also helps to be in a time zone that is shared by much of South America and is only five hours behind London (San Francisco is only in the same time zone as the rest of the United States and Vancouver).</p>
<p>People who uproot their entire lives to seek success elsewhere want to be welcomed. They appreciate that the mayor of the city is happy to meet them for a “cafecito,” and that other founders are genuinely enthusiastic at their arrival. They don’t want to land in an expensive city where making it big tends to require connections, money and background.</p>
<p>Miami is reflective of the future of global startup hubs. It won’t be the next Silicon Valley, because we don’t need another one. As the entrepreneurial world flourishes in every corner of the globe, emerging market companies will be conquering markets across the United States and Europe, and fortress cities will make way for international networks.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/miami/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg"/></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/miami-wont-be-the-next-silicon-valley-because-we-dont-need-another-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107452</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TouchCast raises $55M to grow its AR-based virtual event platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/touchcast-raises-55m-to-grow-its-ar-based-virtual-event-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/touchcast-raises-55m-to-grow-its-ar-based-virtual-event-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 13:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107730</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Events &#8212; when they haven&#8217;t been cancelled altogether in the last 12 months due to the global health pandemic &#8212; have gone virtual and online, and a wave of startups that are helping people create and participate in those experiences are seeing a surge of attention, and funding. In the latest development, New York video [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Events &#8212; when they haven&#8217;t been cancelled altogether in the last 12 months due to the global health pandemic &#8212; have gone virtual and online, and a wave of startups that are helping people create and participate in those experiences are seeing a surge of attention, and funding.</p>
<p>In the latest development, New York video startup <a href="http://touchcast.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TouchCast</a> &#8212; which has developed a platform aimed at companies to produce lifelike, virtual conferences and other events without much technical heavy-lifting &#8212; has picked up funding of $55 million, money that co-founder and CEO Edo Segal said the startup will use to build out its services and teams after being &#8220;overrun by demand&#8221; in the wake of Covid-19.</p>
<p>The funding is being led by a strategic investor, Accenture Ventures &#8212; the investment arm of the systems integrator and consultancy behemoth &#8212; with Alexander Capital Ventures, Saatchi Invest, Ronald Lauder and other unnamed investors also participating. The startup up to now has been largely self-funded, and while Segal isn&#8217;t disclosing the valuation he said it was definitely in the 9-figures (that is, somewhere in the large region of hundreds of millions of dollars).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Accenture has been using TouchCast&#8217;s technology for its own events, but that is likely just one part of its interest: Accenture also has a lot of corporate customers that tap it to build and implement interactive services, so potentially this could lead to more customers into TouchCast&#8217;s pipeline.</p>
<p>(Case in point: my interview with Segal, over Zoom, found me speaking to him in the middle of a vast aircraft hangar, with a 747 from one of the big airlines of the world &#8212; I won&#8217;t say which &#8212; parked behind him. He said he&#8217;d just come from a business pitch with the airline in question.)</p>
<p>A lot of what we have seen in virtual events, and in particular conferences, has to date has been, effectively, a managed version of a group call on one of the established videoconferencing platforms like Zoom, Google&#8217;s Hangout, Microsoft&#8217;s Teams, Webex, and so on.</p>
<p>You get a screen with participants&#8217; individual video streams presented to you in a grid more reminiscent of the opening credits of the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AzODEdkypdg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brady Bunch</a> or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yW0DNGn3FNY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hollywood Squares</a> than an actual stage or venue.</p>
<p>There are some, of course, who are taking a much different route. Witness Apple&#8217;s online events in the last year, productions that have elevated what a virtual event can mean, with more detail and information, and less awkwardness, than an actual live event.</p>
<p>The problem is that not every company is Apple, able to afford much less execute Hollywood-level presentations.</p>
<p>The essence of what TouchCast has built, as Segal describes it, is a platform the combines computer vision, video streaming technology and natural language processing to let other organizations create experiences that are closer to that of the iPhone giant&#8217;s than they are to a game show.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have created a platform so that all companies can create events like Apple&#8217;s,&#8221; Segal said. &#8220;We&#8217;re taking them on a journey beyond people sitting in their home offices.&#8221;</p>
<p>Yet home office remains the operative phrase: people (the organizers and the on-stage participants) still use basic videoconferencing solutions like Zoom and Teams &#8212; in their homes, even &#8212; but at the back end, TouchCast is taking those videos, using computer vision to trim out the people and place them into virtual &#8220;venues&#8221; so that they appear as if they are on stage in an actual conference.</p>
<p>These venues come from a selection of templates, or the organiser can arrange for a specific venue to be shot and used. In addition to the actual event, TouchCast then also provides tools for audience members to participate with questions and to chat to each other. As the event is progressing, TouchCast also produces transcriptions and summaries of the key points for those who want them.</p>
<p>And while Segal said that TouchCast is not planning to make this a consumer-focused product, not even on the B2B2C side, it&#8217;s preparing a service so that when business conference organisers <em>do</em> want to hold a music segment with a special guest, those can be incorporated, too.</p>
<p>TouchCast&#8217;s growth into a startup serving an audience of hungry event planners has been an interesting pivot that is a reminder to founders (and investors) that the right opportunities might not be the ones you think they are.</p>
<p>You might recall that the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/06/27/co-founded-by-former-tc-editor-erick-schonfeld-touchcast-aims-to-reinvent-online-video-using-interactive-apps/?_ga=2.84357137.907098425.1612175151-209244718.1579131500" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">first came out of stealth back in 2013</a>, with former TechCrunch editor Erick Schonfeld one of the co-founders.</p>
<p>Back then, the company&#8217;s concept was to supercharge online video, by making it easier for creators to build in interactive elements and other media into their work, to essentially make videos closer to the kind of interactivity and media mix that we find on webpages themselves.</p>
<p>All that might have been too clever by half. Or, it was simply not the right time for that technology. The service never made many waves at all, and one of my colleagues even assumed it had deadpooled at some point.</p>
<p>Not at all, it turns out. Segal (a serial entrepreneur who also used to work at AOL as VP of emerging platforms &#8212; AOL being the company that acquired TechCrunch and eventually became a part of Verizon) notes that the technology that TouchCast is using for its conferencing solution is essentially the same as what it built for its original video product.</p>
<p>After launching an earlier, less feature-rich version of what it has on the market today, it took the company about six months to retool it, adding in more mixed reality customization via the use of Unreal Engine, to make it what it is today, and to meet the demand it started to see from customers, who approached the startup after attending events held by others using TouchCast.</p>
<p>&#8220;It took us eight years to get to our overnight success story,&#8221; Segal joked.</p>
<p>Figures from Grand View Research cited by TouchCast estimate that virtual events will be a $400 billion business by 2027, and that has made for a pretty large array of companies building out experiences that will make those events worth attending, and putting on.</p>
<p>They include the likes of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/hopin-raises-125m-for-its-online-events-platform-on-the-back-of-surging-growth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hopin</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/bizzabo-raises-138m-for-a-platform-that-helps-you-build-and-run-virtual-conferences/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bizzabo</a> &#8212; both of which have recently also raised big rounds &#8212; but also more enhanced services from the big, established players in videoconferencing like Zoom, Google, Microsoft, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/cisco-acquires-slido-to-improve-qa-polls-and-engagement-in-webex-videoconferencing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cisco</a> and more.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s no surprise to see Accenture throwing its hat into that ring as a backer of what it&#8217;s decided is one of the more interesting technology players in that mix. The reason is because many understand and now accept that &#8212; similar to working in general &#8212; it&#8217;s very likely that even when we do return to &#8220;live&#8221; events, the virtual component, and the expectation that it will work well and be compelling enough to watch, is here to stay.</p>
<p>“Digital disruption, distributed workforces, and customer experience are the driving forces behind the need for companies to transform how they do business and move toward the future of work,&#8221; said Tom Lounibos, managing director, Accenture Ventures, in a statement. &#8220;For organizations to harness the power of virtual experiences to deliver business impact, the pandemic has shown that quality interactions and insights are needed. Our investment in Touchcast demonstrates our commitment to identifying the latest technologies that help address our clients’ critical business needs.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/touchcast-raises-55m-to-grow-its-ar-based-virtual-event-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107730</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok to flag and downrank &#8216;unsubstantiated&#8217; claims fact checkers can&#8217;t verify</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-to-flag-and-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims-fact-checkers-cant-verify/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-to-flag-and-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims-fact-checkers-cant-verify/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 13:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fact check]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videos]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok this morning announced a new feature that aims to combat the spread of misinformation on its platform. In addition to removing videos that are identified to be spreading false information, as verified by fact checking partners, the company says it will now also flag videos where fact checks are inconclusive. These videos may also [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok this morning <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/new-prompts-to-help-people-consider-before-they-share">announced</a> a new feature that aims to combat the spread of misinformation on its platform. In addition to removing videos that are identified to be spreading false information, as verified by fact checking partners, the company says it will now also flag videos where fact checks are inconclusive. These videos may also become ineligible for promotion into anyone&#8217;s For You page, TikTok notes.</p>
<p>The new feature will first launch in the U.S. and Canada, but will become globally available in the &#8220;coming weeks.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company explains that fact checkers aren&#8217;t always able to verify the information being reported in users&#8217; videos. This could be because the fact check is inconclusive or can&#8217;t be immediately confirmed, such as in the case of &#8220;unfolding events.&#8221; (The recent storming of the U.S. Capitol comes to mind as an &#8220;unfolding event&#8221; that led to a surge of social media posts, only some of which were able to be quickly and accurately fact-checked.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>TikTok today works with partner fact checkers to help the company determine which videos are sharing misinformation. In the U.S., its partners include PolitiFact, Lead Stories, and SciVerify, who work to assess the accuracy of content in area related to civic processes, like elections, as well as health (e.g. COVID-19, vaccines), climate and more.</p>
<p>Internationally, TikTok works with Agence France-Presse (AFP), Animal Político, Estadão Verifica, Lead Stories, Logically, Newtral, Pagella Politica, Politifact, SciVerify, and Teyit.</p>
<p>Typically, TikTok&#8217;s internal investigation and moderation team works to first verify misinformation using readily available information, like existing public fact checks. If it can&#8217;t do so, it will sent the video to a fact-checking partner. If the fact check determines content is false, disinformation, manipulated media, or anything else that violates TikTok&#8217;s <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/community-guidelines?lang=en#37">misinformation policy,</a> it&#8217;s simply removed.</p>
<p>These fact checks can be returned in as fast as one our and most happen within less than one day, TikTok tells TechCrunch.</p>
<p>But going forward, if the fact checker can&#8217;t confirm the accuracy of the video&#8217;s content, it will be flagged as unsubstantiated content instead.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107544" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107544" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2107544" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-banner-on-videos.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107544" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TikTok</p></div></p>
<p>A viewer who comes across one of these flagged videos will see a banner that says the content has been reviewed but can&#8217;t be conclusively validated. Unlike <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-gb/supporting-our-community-through-covid-19">the COVID-19 banner</a>, which appears at the bottom of the video, this new banner is more prominently overlaid across the video at the top of screen.</p>
<p>If the user then tries to share that flagged video, they&#8217;ll receive a prompt that reminds them the video has been flagged as unverified content. This additional step is meant to give the user a moment to pause and reconsider their actions. They&#8217;ll they need to choose whether to click the brightly-colored &#8220;cancel&#8221; button or the unhighlighted choice, &#8220;share anyway.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107545" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107545" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2107545" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/New-share-prompt.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107545" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TikTok</p></div></p>
<p>The video&#8217;s original creator will also be alerted if their video is flagged as unverified content.</p>
<p>TikTok said it tested this labeling system in the U.S. late last year and found that viewers decreased the rate at which they shared videos by 24%. It also found that &#8220;likes&#8221; on unsubstantiated content decreased by 7%.</p>
<p>This system itself isn&#8217;t all that different from efforts made at other social networks to reduce the sharing of false content. For example, Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/help/2593586717571940?id=673052479947730">now labels misinformation</a> after it&#8217;s reviewed by fact-checking partners and determined to be false. It also notifies people before they try to share the information and downranks the content so it appears lower in users&#8217; News Feeds.</p>
<p>Twitter, too, uses a labeling system to identify misinformation and discourage sharing.</p>
<p>But on other platforms, only verifiably false information is labeled as such. TikTok&#8217;s new system moves to tackle the viral spread of unverified content, as well.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107543" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107543" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2107543" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Video-creator-notification.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107543" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TikTok</p></div></p>
<p>That doesn&#8217;t mean users won&#8217;t see the videos. If someone follows the account, they could still see the flagged video in their Following feed or by visiting the account profile directly.</p>
<p>But TikTok believes the new system will encourage users to &#8220;be mindful about what they share.&#8221;</p>
<p>It could also potentially defer people from making vague but incendiary claims meant to draw viewers and attention. Knowing that these videos could be downranked to the point that they may not ever reach the &#8220;For You&#8221; page could have a dampening effect on a certain type of social media content &#8212; the kind that comes from creators who post first, then ask questions later. Or those who largely shrug their shoulders over the impact of their rumors.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jIhix04DTy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/tiktok-updates-policies-to-ban-deepfakes-expand-fact-checks-and-flag-election-misinfo/">TikTok updates policies to ban deepfakes, expand fact-checks and flag election misinfo</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok updates policies to ban deepfakes, expand fact-checks and flag election misinfo&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/tiktok-updates-policies-to-ban-deepfakes-expand-fact-checks-and-flag-election-misinfo/embed/#?secret=jIhix04DTy" data-secret="jIhix04DTy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The new feature was designed and tested with <a href="https://irrationallabs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://irrationallabs.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1612387419893000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF_fivssOJXEcXseXfVM_Vro_YJdg">Irrational Labs</a>, a behavioral science lab that uses the psychology of decision-making to develop solutions that aim to drive positive user behavior changes. TikTok also says the addition was a part of its ongoing work to advance media literacy, which had included the &#8220;Be Informed&#8221; <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/tiktoks-be-informed-series-stars-tiktok-creators-to-educate-users-about-media-literacy">educational videos it created</a> in partnership with the National Association of Media Literacy Education.</p>
<p>The banner will begin appearing in the U.S. and Canada starting today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-to-flag-and-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims-fact-checkers-cant-verify/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107515</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vivino raises $155 million for wine recommendation and marketplace app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/vivino-raises-155-million-for-wine-recommendation-and-marketplace-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/vivino-raises-155-million-for-wine-recommendation-and-marketplace-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creandum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gp bullhound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kinnevik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sprints Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;re at all interested in wine, chances are you&#8217;ve turned to Vivino at least a few times for recommendations. The app and the company behind it have been helping people enjoy better wine since 2010, and now the startup has raised $155 million with its Series D round – a sum over twice as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you&#8217;re at all interested in wine, chances are you&#8217;ve turned to <a href="https://www.vivino.com/">Vivino</a> at least a few times for recommendations. The app and the company behind it have been helping people enjoy better wine since 2010, and now the startup has raised $155 million with its Series D round – a sum over twice as large as all of its previous funding to date. Spurred by rapid growth that has seen its user base grow from 29 million in 2018, to 50 million currently, Vivino wants to use the large cash injection to significantly boost its core tech and personalized recommendation engine, while also expanding its presence in key growth markets globally.</p>
<p>Vivino is an interesting company for many reasons, but chief among them might be just how similar its vision today is to the one it started out with. Founder and CEO Heini Zachariassen told me in an interview that the app has been remarkably immune to the pivot – something as natural as breathing in the fast-flowing startup world.</p>
<p>&#8220;I can look at my slide, from when I pitched this 10 years ago,&#8221; he told me. &#8220;It says, &#8216;Hey, you scan a bottle of wine, then you can buy it.&#8217; That just makes a lot of sense to anybody, so it really hasn&#8217;t changed much.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s been very, very difficult to build much – much harder to build than building that slide,&#8221; he joked. But it&#8217;s always been the same – we always knew that was going to be the model.&#8221;</p>
<p>That core value proposition is what leads to a lot of Vivino&#8217;s initial downloads and subsequent usage. The scenario is likely familiar: You&#8217;re sitting in a restaurant and browsing the wine menu, or staring at a crowded shelf in a wine store. For myself, I think I likely searched for something like &#8216;wine recommendation app&#8217; and found Vivino via the App Store, installed it and was snapping photos of labels or menus within minutes. The recommendations provided somewhere to start, and since then the app has grown more personalized as I&#8217;ve provided input about my tastes.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107739" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107739" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2107739" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-vivino-press-kit-product-shots-trio.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="783" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-vivino-press-kit-product-shots-trio.jpg 2720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-vivino-press-kit-product-shots-trio.jpg?resize=150,115 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-vivino-press-kit-product-shots-trio.jpg?resize=300,229 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-vivino-press-kit-product-shots-trio.jpg?resize=768,587 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-vivino-press-kit-product-shots-trio.jpg?resize=680,520 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-vivino-press-kit-product-shots-trio.jpg?resize=1536,1175 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-vivino-press-kit-product-shots-trio.jpg?resize=2048,1566 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-vivino-press-kit-product-shots-trio.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107739" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Vivino</p></div></p>
<p>Vivino&#8217;s marketplace component means you can often buy the wines you find and enjoy directly from the app, via partnerships the company fosters and maintains with merchants large and small around the world. Zachariassen explained that they strive to maintain high standards when it comes to these partners, since the experience a user has with them is largely a reflection on Vivino itself because the app provides the means for the purchase.</p>
<p>Building more relationships with more merchants in more geographies is one part of their expansion goal for addressing their primary growth markets, but the company is also going to put a lot more capital behind improving and extending its recommendation engine. A lot of the building blocks are in place to make big improvements there, not least of which is the wine database that Vivino spent a decade building essentially from zero.</p>
<p>&#8220;Stage one of the hurdles we faced, even before we got commercial, was really building the data,&#8221; Zachariassen told me. &#8220;There is no aggregated data anywhere. So we&#8217;ve basically built this data totally from scratch. So it means taking a picture of bottle of wine, then having people just entering info every single day to fill it. We have 1.5 billion pictures of wine labels right now, so building that mass of data in a good and structured way really is 10 years of work.&#8221;</p>
<p>He adds that wine is a particularly long-tail marketplace, with highly individual tastes and very little indication in the company&#8217;s history that that&#8217;s likely to change in any significant way. Vivino&#8217;s marketplace approach, which is highly local on both the supply and the demand side, is particularly well-suited to addressing the sector&#8217;s needs, and Zachariassen believes Vivino has only really begun to scratch the surface on that thus far. I asked him why now was the right time to take on this sizeable round, given they&#8217;ve been very modest with prior funding amounts.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107736" style="width: 464px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107736" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2107736" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Heini_Zachariassen_vivino_2.jpg?w=454" alt="" width="454" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Heini_Zachariassen_vivino_2.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Heini_Zachariassen_vivino_2.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Heini_Zachariassen_vivino_2.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Heini_Zachariassen_vivino_2.jpg?resize=768,1151 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Heini_Zachariassen_vivino_2.jpg?resize=454,680 454w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Heini_Zachariassen_vivino_2.jpg?resize=1025,1536 1025w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Heini_Zachariassen_vivino_2.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 454px) 100vw, 454px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107736" class="wp-caption-text">Vivino wine app in San Francisco. Photo Copyright Nader Khouri 2018.</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;I think we we&#8217;ve reached sort of a critical mass,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We saw last year massive growth, and actually reaching [&#8230;] like a quarter of a billion dollars in sales, and we&#8217;ve really seen that the unit economics are healthy for us. At the same time, unlike other marketplaces – you know, the order of things when you have a marketplace might be if you&#8217;re like Uber, is that you go into market, you spend money, do marketing, a lot of money to build up the demand, and then you build the supply on top. We&#8217;re a little bit different in the way that demand is already there, because we have 50 million users around the world. So we just follow our demand.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;But the hardest thing about that is that we&#8217;re now a 200 person company that sells wine in 17 countries,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;Which means we&#8217;re relatively thin in all these markets. So so one of the big things here, is actually to go much deeper in each market and say, okay, we now know it works here, let&#8217;s put more resources in every single market.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zachariassen also added that the company spends very little on marketing to date, so it&#8217;s going to begin spending more on that to extend its organic growth. Finally, it wants to really build out product engineering, since he says that while users love the existing app, they really &#8220;want to do so much more with it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Vivino has worked to modernize a product category that has long relied on local expertise and individual storehouses of highly-specific information, with an approach that provides all the benefits of a connected and global marketplace, while retaining regional and particular appeal at the granola level of the individual user. Now, the company is read to tap the rest of the massive submerged demand it has identified, and this fresh fundings would help it do just that.</p>
<p>The $155 million series D round was led by Sweden&#8217;s Kinnevik, and also includes participation by Sprints Capital, GP BullHound, and existing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/12/12/vivino-raises-1m-from-creandum-for-mobile-wine-cellar/">investor Creandum which led its Series A</a>. This brings the company&#8217;s total funding to $221 million to date.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/vivino-raises-155-million-for-wine-recommendation-and-marketplace-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107707</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Good Eggs raises $100M and plans to launch in Southern California</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/good-eggs-funding-2/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/good-eggs-funding-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 13:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bentley hall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glade Brook Capital Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Good Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san diego]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grocery delivery startup Good Eggs is announcing that it has raised $100 million in new funding, and that it&#8217;s planning to launch in Southern California in either the summer or fall of this year. Parts of this story might sound familiar to readers familiar with Good Eggs — when the startup raised its most recent, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Grocery delivery startup <a href="https://www.goodeggs.com/">Good Eggs</a> is announcing that it has raised $100 million in new funding, and that it&#8217;s planning to launch in Southern California in either the summer or fall of this year.</p>
<p>Parts of this story might sound familiar to readers familiar with Good Eggs — when the startup raised its most recent, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/15/good-eggs-funding/">$50 million funding round</a> in 2018, CEO Bentley Hall also mentioned plans for geographic expansion.</p>
<p>It seems, however, that the company has found plenty of opportunity for growth while remaining focused on the San Francisco Bay Area. Good Eggs says that in the past year, revenue has grown to the nine figures (more than $100 million), hired more than 400 employees and nearly doubled its customer base.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Hall also noted that the company opened a new, larger warehouse in Oakland just a few days before shelter-in-place orders took effect last March. So the team was busy enough trying to operate a new warehouse, meet increased demand for grocery delivery and keep workers safe in the process.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107602" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107602" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2107602" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Good_Eggs_Box.jpg?w=490" alt="Good Eggs box" width="490" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Good_Eggs_Box.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Good_Eggs_Box.jpg?resize=108,150 108w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Good_Eggs_Box.jpg?resize=216,300 216w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Good_Eggs_Box.jpg?resize=768,1067 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Good_Eggs_Box.jpg?resize=490,680 490w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Good_Eggs_Box.jpg?resize=36,50 36w" sizes="(max-width: 490px) 100vw, 490px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107602" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Good Eggs</p></div></p>
<p>And while the grocery delivery market has become increasingly competitive, Hall argued that Good Eggs stands out thanks to the quality and breadth of its products — 70% of its products are locally sourced, and it often delivers them within 48 hours of harvesting.</p>
<p>&#8220;There’s lots of people offering groceries, meal kits, prepared meals, alcohol — we do all of that, with a certain sourcing criteria,&#8221; Hall said. As a result, Good Eggs has become the &#8220;primary source&#8221; for many of its consumers, representing 65% to 85% of their home food purchases.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also worth noting that this represents a bit of a turnaround for the company, after the it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/08/05/good-eggs-layoffs/">shut down operations</a> in Los Angeles, New York City and New Orleans in 2015, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/12/01/good-eggs-has-a-new-ceo/">Hall coming on as CEO</a> shortly afterwards. And it sounds like he isn&#8217;t in a rush to launch in a bunch of new markets.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think of [Southern California] not as one big region, but as several small sub-regions,&#8221; Hall said. &#8220;There&#8217;s the LA region, northern San Diego, Orange County — those areas collectively are the size of two or three Bay Areas. That&#8217;s a meaningful increase in our addressable market.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107605" style="width: 554px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107605" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Bentley_Hall_1.jpg?w=544" alt="Good Eggs CEO Bentley Hall" width="544" height="680" class="size-large wp-image-2107605" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Bentley_Hall_1.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Bentley_Hall_1.jpg?resize=120,150 120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Bentley_Hall_1.jpg?resize=240,300 240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Bentley_Hall_1.jpg?resize=768,960 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Bentley_Hall_1.jpg?resize=544,680 544w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Bentley_Hall_1.jpg?resize=40,50 40w" sizes="(max-width: 544px) 100vw, 544px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107605" class="wp-caption-text">Good Eggs CEO Bentley Hall</p></div></p>
<p>The new funding was led by Glade Brook Capital Partners, with participation from GV, Tao Invest, Finistere Ventures and Rich’s, as well as previous investors Benchmark Partners, Index Ventures, S2G, DNS Capital and Obvious Ventures. Glade Brook&#8217;s J.P. Van Arsdale is joining the company&#8217;s board of directors.</p>
<p>&#8220;The grocery market is undergoing fundamental change and the shift to e-commerce and higher quality products and services is accelerating,&#8221; Van Arsdale said in a statement. &#8220;Good Eggs is experiencing rapid growth with strong unit economics and is well-positioned to become a category-defining leader. We are excited to partner with their team to help drive future growth and expansion.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition to geographic expansion, Hall said the money will allow Good Eggs to continue adding new products and to find ways to improve the e-commerce experience.</p>
<p>In addition to the funding, Good Eggs is also announcing that it has hired Vineet Mehra as its chief growth and customer experience officer. Mehra was previously chief marketing officer and chief customer officer at Walgreens Boots Alliance, and before that as executive vice president and global chief marketing and revenue officer at Ancestry.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kG0Jpra702"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/15/good-eggs-funding/">Good Eggs raises $50M and eyes West Coast expansion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Good Eggs raises $50M and eyes West Coast expansion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/15/good-eggs-funding/embed/#?secret=kG0Jpra702" data-secret="kG0Jpra702" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/good-eggs-funding-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107581</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WorkStep, a startup that helps large employers find and retain frontline workers, raises $10.5M Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/workstep-a-startup-that-helps-large-employers-find-and-retain-frontline-workers-raises-10-5m-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/workstep-a-startup-that-helps-large-employers-find-and-retain-frontline-workers-raises-10-5m-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adam nelson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FirstMark Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[staffing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Finding, and retaining, frontline workers has likely never been as critical as it is in these pandemic days. Enter WorkStep, a four-year-old startup that was founded with the mission of helping large supply chain employers do just that. The fully distributed company announced this morning that it has closed on a $10.5 million Series A [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finding, and retaining, frontline workers has likely never been as critical as it is in these pandemic days.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enter </span><a href="http://www.workstep.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">WorkStep</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a four-year-old startup that was founded with the mission of helping large supply chain employers do just that. The fully distributed company announced this morning that it has closed on a $10.5 million Series A round, building on top of a previously unannounced $6.7 million seed funding that included equity and a convertible note.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">FirstMark Capital led the Series A financing, which included participation from returning backer and strategic partner Prologist Ventures.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dan Johnston, co-founder and CEO of WorkStep, said the Employee Lifecycle Management (ELM) software platform was designed to not only help large supply chain employers source new frontline employers, but to also onboard, train, and keep them happier with the goal of them staying on board longer. Johnston experienced some of the challenges firsthand  when he managed a warehouse in Portland, Oregon, more than a decade ago.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The COVID-19 pandemic has only highlighted the importance of the work frontline employees do – from serving food to delivering packages. But with the increasing dependence on supply chain labor came record turnover, points out Johnston – leaving many companies understaffed and remaining workers stretched thin.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">WorkStep claims to provide human resources, recruiting and operations leaders “full transparency” across the employee lifecycle to help companies minimize that churn. The company had previously built out its cloud-based Hire<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> offering and then last fall, launched its Retain<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> product. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “The pandemic has forced companies of all sizes to prioritize the health, safety and satisfaction of frontline teams,” he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its customers include hundreds of industrial, logistics, transportation and warehousing employers across North America –– including regional 3PLs (third-party logistics companies) and distribution centers, as well as 16 of the Fortune 500. Customers include grocery chain Kroger, Alpine Food Distributing and TransPak, among others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">WorkStep says it has “reached” 500,000 supply chain workers over the years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">WorkStep claims that its Retain offering reduced turnover by up to 29 percent for a Fortune 100 food &amp; beverage company with whom it conducted a <a href="https://www.workstep.com/case-study-fortune-100-fb-company">case study</a>. This saves companies money in replacement and retraining expenses, which can add up. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a result of launching Retain last fall, according to Johnston, WorkStep saw its business more than double in the second half of 2020. This led the company to end the year as “bottom line profitable,&#8221; meaning that its revenue exceeded expenses in the last two months of the year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And while WorkStep did not necessarily need to take on new capital, the company saw an opportunity to double down so it could continue to scale, Johnston said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This was an opportunistic round,” he told TechCrunch. “The turnover in this segment has become a core focus.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">WorkStep plans to use its new funding to more than double the size of its existing team of 14 employees across engineering, product, sales and customer success departments this year and triple it by the end of fiscal year 2022.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">FirstMark Capital’s </span><a href="https://firstmarkcap.com/team/adam-nelson/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adam Nelson</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was in the room with the company during its first whiteboard sessions and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">believes WorkStep is addressing a &#8220;massive&#8221; opportunity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We think the real differentiator between WorkStep and the existing solutions in the space is that WorkStep doesn’t see temporary staffing/gig liquidity as a solution,” Nelson told TechCrunch. “They see it as a symptom of a multi-hundred billion dollar deadweight loss that’s created when employers aren’t able to find, train and retain the right people.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">WorkStep, he added, is addressing the full employee lifecycle and leveraging the data  “to give a voice to frontline workers while also making employers smarter and more proactive.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/workstep-a-startup-that-helps-large-employers-find-and-retain-frontline-workers-raises-10-5m-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107570</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India warns Twitter over lifting block on accounts and noncompliance of order</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/india-sends-warning-to-twitter-over-lifting-block-on-accounts-and-noncompliance-of-order/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/india-sends-warning-to-twitter-over-lifting-block-on-accounts-and-noncompliance-of-order/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 11:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107712</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India has issued a notice to Twitter, warning the American social firm to comply with New Delhi’s order to block accounts and content related to a protest by farmers and not “assume the role of a court and justify non-compliance.” Failure to comply with the order may prompt penal action against Twitter, the notice warns. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India has issued a notice to Twitter, warning the American social firm to comply with New Delhi’s order to block accounts and content related to a protest by farmers and not “assume the role of a court and justify non-compliance.” Failure to comply with the order may prompt penal action against Twitter, the notice warns.</p>
<p>The warning comes days after Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/twitter-restricts-over-a-dozen-high-profile-accounts-in-india-following-legal-demand/">blocked dozens of high-profile accounts in India</a> in compliance with New Delhi’s request, but later lifted the restriction.</p>
<p>Twitter “cannot assume the role of a court and justify non-compliance. Twitter being an intermediary is obliged to obey the directions as per satisfaction of authorities as to which inflammatory content will arouse passion and impact public order. Twitter cannot sit as an appellate authority over the satisfaction of the authorities about its potential impact on derailing public order,” said the notice, a copy of its summary was reviewed by TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>India’s IT ministry has also expressed concerns over what it deemed derogatory and factually incorrect tweets and hashtags that have been circulating in India this week that it said were designed to spread hate. &#8220;It is thus clear that, the offending tweets/ hashtag remained in public domain and must have been tweeted and re-tweeted several times at the risk and cost of public order and at the risk of incitement to the commission of offences,&#8221; the notice said.</p>
<p>Twitter declined to comment.</p>
<p>For more than three months, tens of thousands of farmers (if not more) in India and elsewhere have been protesting against three laws passed by Prime Minister Narendra Modi&#8217;s government last year that they say allow greater private sector competition.</p>
<p>Twitter, which reaches more than 75 million users through its apps in India, has emerged as the single-most important online forum for people seeking to voice their opinion on this matter. Singer Rihanna, who has more followers on Twitter than any Indian actor or politician, tweeted a CNN news story on Tuesday about the protests in India and asked &#8220;why are&#8217;t we talking about this!?</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">why aren’t we talking about this?! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FarmersProtest?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FarmersProtest</a> <a href="https://t.co/obmIlXhK9S">https://t.co/obmIlXhK9S</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Rihanna (@rihanna) <a href="https://twitter.com/rihanna/status/1356625889602199552?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 2, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We stand in solidarity with the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FarmersProtest?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FarmersProtest</a> in India.<br /> <a href="https://t.co/tqvR0oHgo0">https://t.co/tqvR0oHgo0</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Greta Thunberg (@GretaThunberg) <a href="https://twitter.com/GretaThunberg/status/1356694884615340037?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 2, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Several Indian politicians and high-profile Indian actors including Akshay Kumar, Ajay Devgn, Karan Johar, and Ekta Kapoor cautioned Indians on Wednesday to not fall for &#8220;propaganda.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Farmers constitute an extremely important part of our country. And the efforts being undertaken to resolve their issues are evident. Let’s support an amicable resolution, rather than paying attention to anyone creating differences. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f64f-1f3fb.png" alt="🙏🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/IndiaTogether?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#IndiaTogether</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/IndiaAgainstPropaganda?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#IndiaAgainstPropaganda</a> <a href="https://t.co/LgAn6tIwWp">https://t.co/LgAn6tIwWp</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Akshay Kumar (@akshaykumar) <a href="https://twitter.com/akshaykumar/status/1356884526815842304?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 3, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Raman Chima, a senior international counsel and Asia Pacific Policy director at Access Now, a non-profit internet advocacy organization, <a href="https://twitter.com/tame_wildcard/status/1356929181943218176">said</a> in a series of tweets that instead of threatening social media platforms, India&#8217;s IT ministry &#8220;needs to explain why blocking entire handles &amp; seeking the banning of hashtags does not violate the Indian Constitution.&#8221; He said the ministry has neither been transparent nor respected the rights.</p>
<p>&#8220;You can choose to disagree, correct, ridicule, or engage with such fears, outcry. Seeking to ban &amp; precensor such discussions is a travesty of India&#8217;s Constitution + international human rights law. This is not what 21st Century India should permit, nor what our founders envisaged. The Ministry of Electronics and IT should release its actual orders and all documentation behind the Govt&#8217;s decisions to &#8211; (1) issue these orders and (2) press the matter with Twitter and other social media platforms. Don&#8217;t hide; explain &amp; justify how this is not unconstitutional.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/india-sends-warning-to-twitter-over-lifting-block-on-accounts-and-noncompliance-of-order/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107712</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Embedded finance startup Banxware raises €4M seed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/banxware/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/banxware/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 09:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banxware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[embedded finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online marketplaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Embedded finance &#8212; the idea of offering financial products where customers are already congregating via white label solutions and APIs &#8211; isn&#8217;t an entirely new concept. In fact, in one form or another, such as point of sale credit, the concept has existed for years and long before Silicon Valley venture capital firm and media [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Embedded finance &#8212; the idea of offering financial products where customers are already congregating via white label solutions and APIs &#8211; isn&#8217;t an entirely new concept. In fact, in one form or another, such as point of sale credit, the concept has existed for years and long before Silicon Valley venture capital firm and media company (ha!) Andreessen Horowitz <a href="https://a16z.com/2020/01/21/every-company-will-be-a-fintech-company/">made it a thing</a>. However, fuelled by cloud technology and a plethora of new fintech and Banking-as-a-Service startups, there is no doubt the embedded finance trend is accelerating.</p>
<p>The latest company to declare its hand is Berlin-based <a href="https://www.banxware.com/">Banxware</a>, which offers embedded finance in the form of loans for SMEs, in partnership with marketplaces, payments providers, and others. It launched in December and today is disclosing that it has raised €4 million in seed funding.</p>
<p>Leading the round is Force over Mass, and VR Ventures. They are joined by HTGF, and private investors in banking, payment and e-commerce.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Banxware says it will use the investment to develop and grow its embedded white label financial services offering, and expand its team. In addition to lending, the startup will also soon offer card-based products and other financial services.</p>
<p>Banxware’s tech and infrastructure enables any company to offer loans and other banking services to SME customers. The idea is to act as the link between banks (lenders), digital platforms, and merchants. Banks get access to hard to reach SME customers. Platforms, such as online marketplaces, can up-sell financial products beyond their core offering. And merchants benefit from speedy access to working capital.</p>
<p>“SMEs have a hard time to access capital when needed, especially when they are less than three years old or do not have the most pristine credit history,” explains co-founder and CEO Jens Röhrborn. “On top of this, loan applications, i.e. loan decisions and loan payout, still take several weeks in most cases.</p>
<p>“More and more sellers and merchants are using digital platforms through which they sell their products or process their digital payments. By using the recent historic data on these merchants provided by the platforms, we can lend against their future revenues”.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Oo47FW5pzb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/liberis-the-embedded-finance-provider-for-smes-raises-additional-70m-in-equity-and-debt/">Liberis, the embedded finance provider for SMEs, raises additional £70M in debt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Liberis, the embedded finance provider for SMEs, raises additional £70M in debt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/liberis-the-embedded-finance-provider-for-smes-raises-additional-70m-in-equity-and-debt/embed/#?secret=Oo47FW5pzb" data-secret="Oo47FW5pzb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This has seen Banxware build an instant lending tool that includes AML and KYC compliance, and a scoring engine that analyzes historic platform data and data from third party providers, such as account information providers and external scoring services. The promise is an instant loan decision and loan payout, “all in less than 15 minutes”.</p>
<p>“On the lending side, we work with both balance sheet lenders and lending vehicles with whom we pre-agree on lending terms and loan decision criteria and on whose behalf we execute the loan decision,” says Röhrborn. “Merchants repay their loan in such a way that platforms subtract a certain percentage of the future merchant payouts”.</p>
<p>Röhrborn says the company&#8217;s instant lending tool is &#8220;only the beginning&#8221; and that Banxware will develop additional embedded financial services and expand internationally.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the German fintech currently generates revenue by charging a one time fee for each loan that is processed through its platform and via a one off customization fee.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/banxware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107306</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alibaba Cloud turns profitable after 11 years</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/alibaba-cloud-turns-profitable-after-11-years/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/alibaba-cloud-turns-profitable-after-11-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 08:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alibaba Cloud, the cloud computing arm of Chinese e-commerce giant Alibaba, became profitable for the first time in the December quarter, the company announced in its earnings report. The firm&#8217;s cloud unit achieved positive adjusted EBITA (earnings before interest, taxes, and amortization) during the quarter, after being in business since 2009. The milestone is in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Alibaba Cloud, the cloud computing arm of Chinese e-commerce giant Alibaba, became profitable for the first time in the December quarter, the company announced in its <a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/en/news/press_pdf/p210202.pdf">earnings report</a>.</p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s cloud unit achieved positive adjusted EBITA (earnings before interest, taxes, and amortization) during the quarter, after being in business since 2009. The milestone is in part a result of the &#8220;realization of economies of scale,&#8221; Alibaba said.</p>
<p>Alibaba Cloud, which incorporates everything from database, storage, big data analytics, security, machine learning to IoT services, has dominated China&#8217;s cloud infrastructure market for the past few years and its market share worldwide continues to grow. As of 2019, the cloud behemoth was the third-largest public cloud company (providing infrastructure-as-a-service) in the world with a 9% market, trailing behind Amazon and Microsoft, according to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-admin/post-new.php">Gartner</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>COVID-19 has been a boon to cloud and digital adoption around the world as the virus forces offline activities online. For instance, Alibaba notes in its earnings that demand for digitalization in the restaurant and service industry remains strong in the post-COVID period in China, a trend that benefits its food delivery and on-demand services app, Ele.me. The firm&#8217;s cloud revenue grew to $2.47 billion in the December quarter, primarily driven by &#8220;robust growth in revenue from customers in the internet and retail industries and the public sector.&#8221;</p>
<p>Commerce remained Alibaba&#8217;s largest revenue driver in the quarter accounting for nearly 70% of revenue, while cloud contributed 7%.</p>
<p>Tencent&#8217;s cloud segment is Alibaba Cloud&#8217;s closest rival. As of 2019, it had a 2.8% market globally, according to Gartner. The industry in China still has ample room for growth, as Alibaba executive vice-chairman Joe Tsai pointed out in an analyst call from <a href="https://www.fool.com/earnings/call-transcripts/2020/08/20/alibaba-group-holding-ltd-baba-q1-2021-earnings-ca/">last August</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Based on the third-party studies that we&#8217;ve seen, the China cloud market is going to be somewhere in the $15 billion to $20 billion total size range, and the U.S. market is about eight times that. So the China market is still at a very early stage,&#8221; said Tsai.</p>
<p>&#8220;We feel very good, very comfortable to be in the China market and just being an environment of faster digitization and faster growth of usage of cloud from enterprises because we&#8217;re growing from such a smaller base, about one-eighth the base of that of the U.S. market.&#8221;</p>
<p>A key strategy to grow Alibaba Cloud is the<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/14/apple-remove-podcasts-in-china-alibaba-new-cloud-strategy/"> integration of cloud into Alibaba&#8217;s enterprise chat app Dingtalk</a>, which the company hopes can drive industries across the board onto cloud services. It’s a relationship that echoes that between Microsoft 365 and Azure, as president of Alibaba Cloud, Zhang Jianfeng, previously suggested in an <a href="https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/61159778">interview</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;We don&#8217;t want to just provide cloud in terms of infrastructure services,&#8221; said Alibaba CEO Daniel Zhang in the August earnings call. &#8220;If we just do it as an infrastructure service, as SaaS services, then price competition is inevitable, and then all the cloud service is more like a commodity business. Today, Alibaba&#8217;s cloud is cloud plus intelligence services, and it&#8217;s about cloud plus the power of the data usage.&#8221;</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/alibaba-cloud-turns-profitable-after-11-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Could eyelash extensions become a huge market? This robotics startup thinks so</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/could-eyelash-extensions-become-a-huge-market-this-robotics-startup-thinks-so/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/could-eyelash-extensions-become-a-huge-market-this-robotics-startup-thinks-so/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 07:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106854</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Eyelash extensions have taken off in recent years &#8212; particularly in Asia &#8212;  but the audience is only so broad. Getting extensions &#8212; semi-permanent fibers that are attached to one&#8217;s natural eyelashes &#8212; can require hundreds of dollars and hours in the seat of a lash stylist. There&#8217;s always the risk, too, of irritation or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Eyelash extensions have taken off in recent years &#8212; particularly in Asia &#8212;  but the audience is only so broad. Getting extensions &#8212; semi-permanent fibers that are attached to one&#8217;s natural eyelashes &#8212; can require hundreds of dollars and hours in the seat of a lash stylist. There&#8217;s always the risk, too, of irritation or worse. Little wonder that, even accounting for low-budget lashes that can be applied at home, the market stands at around $2 billion, which is too small a market to capture the attention of most venture capitalists.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.luumlash.com/">Luum</a>, a four-year-old, 15-person, Berkeley, Ca.-based robotics company, thinks it can change the math &#8212; and attract investment &#8212;  by &#8220;exponentially&#8221; expanding the market, says its CEO, Philippe Sanchez, who has overseen large chain businesses, including as a managing director for Starbucks in France.</p>
<p>The way forward, he says, is through robotics, artificial intelligence, and machine learning, which Luum says it&#8217;s using to ultimately create a robot that that can apply lashes in 20 minutes and, if all goes as planned, will be widely available in beauty shops. More, because lash extensions need to be replaced every two to four weeks as the lashes fall, customers will come back again and again.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Right now, there&#8217;s a bit of magical thinking involved, admits Sanchez. The tech currently relies on Epson industrial robots to which a variety of arms and sensors are attached, making it look a little like something you might see in the dentist&#8217;s office. The procedure of applying lashes has been tried out 100 times on 25 brave souls alone. The process currently takes as long as it would to apply lashes by hand, too, meaning a couple of hours.</p>
<p>Still, Luum, which has raised $10 million to date from Foundation Capital and others and is about to begin talking with investors about a Series A round, is convinced it has the right team to chase and grow what it sees as a big and underserved opportunity in the beauty space.</p>
<p>We talked with Sanchez yesterday afternoon about the company and its next steps. Our chat has been edited for length and clarity.</p>
<p><strong>TC: So you are targeting this popular treatment in what seems like a very fragmented industry.</strong></p>
<p>PS: It&#8217;s very popular and yet a little bit undiscovered and yes, it&#8217;s very fragmented. There are 34,000 lash extension services being offered right now in the U.S. alone, where you&#8217;ve got an artist coming over to you and selecting one lash extension at a time, dipping it in an adhesive, and gluing it to an existing lash, then waiting a few seconds to get the next one and the next one, and two hours later, you have amazing lashes that look extremely natural.</p>
<p>But these are individual lash artists. And we see this as a great opportunity to reinvent the category and take a service that&#8217;s already popular and make it even more popular with high-level execution and a new world-class brand.</p>
<p><strong>TC: So the idea is that you create a brand and develop a chain of walk-in centers around the country and world where these eyelashes will be robotically attached?</strong></p>
<p>PS: Correct. We want to leverage our technology to build our brand and launch a chain of studios, as well as to license the technology to people who already sell beauty services and products and and offer them a chance to either be much better at what they do if they are lash artists or, if you know, they have a hair salon or a large cosmetic retailer, they can [add lashes as an ancillary business]. They love the idea of returning customers having to come back every month for services, and lash extensions bring them back into their stores.</p>
<p><strong>TC: This obviously requires the same or better precision than human fingers, along with high safety requirements given this hardware is so near to someone&#8217;s eyes. How does the robot work right now?</strong></p>
<p>PS: The machine is pretty large and pretty soft and very advanced. There is a bed just like you would have in a first-class business flight. And the machine nearby that is about the size of a human, and so you lay in the bed and the machine work overs your face &#8212; you have a mask, just like if you were to do a manual extension &#8212; and it has a little robotic arm that does the job of a person but is much faster and more precise than any manual application. And it&#8217;s very safe. It&#8217;s got little prongs in the plastic at the end of these arms that are very light held by very light magnets because you need only a few grams of force to manipulate the lash.</p>
<p><strong>TC: So if there was any type of external event &#8212; an earthquake or something . . .</strong></p>
<p>PS:  . . . the arms literally fall because they&#8217;re held by these little very light magnets. If you you shake the machine or somebody sneezes, the arms will fall. It creates an environment that simply cannot hurt you, which is critical to the service itself.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Are you licensing anyone else&#8217;s tech or building everything in-house eventually?</strong></p>
<p>PS: It&#8217;s all built in house. We&#8217;re leveraging advanced robots from Epson that are very good at doing precise manipulation and that are fast. But [as for] IP in the beauty space, there was essentially no prior art, so we have secured a patent already in the U.S and Korea and Australia and [have] 25 patent cases around the world that are very broad and provide us with a moat and protection for the company at large.</p>
<p><strong>TC: How much will these robots cost?</strong></p>
<p>PS: They will cost about $125,000 or so, but this one-time capital expense can boost productivity of labor by four or six times, so you&#8217;ve essentially increased the throughput of one bed, one lash artist, by six. And the machine lasts four to five years.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Plus other costs.</strong></p>
<p>PS: You will have maintenance costs, but it&#8217;s essentially pure margin. For most of those consumer service business, most of the cost goes goes into the labor. That was for my experience at Starbucks.</p>
<p><strong>TC: How far away are you from realizing this vision?</strong></p>
<p>PS: COVID [slowed us down], though we can conduct consumer tests again right now [as California reopens slightly], so we&#8217;re testing the machine, which is already able to deliver a simple style at about the speed of a human. And as we continue to develop and work over the next few months and get closer to opening our first studio,  the performance of the machines will increase to twice the speed and three times the speed and four times the speed of a human application.</p>
<p><strong>TC: You need more capital toward that end. How much are you looking to raise?</strong></p>
<p>PS: A $15 million Series A. That will allow us to open our first studio and validate the unit economic model, as well as to build our third-generation machine. The capital will also be deployed to start to build the foundation of a world class beauty brand.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Who should investors know is on your team?</strong></p>
<p>PS: The company was founded by Nathan Harding, who also founded the [robotic exoskeleton pioneer] Ekso Bionics, and Kurt Amundson [who worked with Harding at Ekso Bionics for a decade]. They&#8217;ve got tremendous experience and expertise already in the world of advanced robotics, and also computer vision on the computer vision side.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What&#8217;s to keep a company like Dyson from jumping into this market if you&#8217;re able to prove there is one?</strong></p>
<p>PS: Some folks will realize that this is an attractive space and it&#8217;s worth looking at, but we&#8217;ve got a couple of years on them already.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/could-eyelash-extensions-become-a-huge-market-this-robotics-startup-thinks-so/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106854</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bot MD, an AI-based chatbot for doctors, raises $5 million for expansion into more Asian markets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/bot-md-an-ai-based-chatbot-for-doctors-raises-5-million-for-expansion-into-more-asian-markets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/bot-md-an-ai-based-chatbot-for-doctors-raises-5-million-for-expansion-into-more-asian-markets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 01:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bot MD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatbot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doctors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monk’s Hill Venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107098</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Time is critical for healthcare providers, especially in the middle of the pandemic. Singapore-based Bot MD helps save time with an AI-based chatbot that lets doctors look up important information from their smartphones, instead of needing to call a hospital operator or access its intranet. The startup announced today it has raised a $5 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Time is critical for healthcare providers, especially in the middle of the pandemic. Singapore-based <a href="https://www.botmd.com/en/">Bot MD </a>helps save time with an AI-based chatbot that lets doctors look up important information from their smartphones, instead of needing to call a hospital operator or access its intranet. The startup announced today it has raised a $5 million Series A led by Monk’s Hill Ventures.</p>
<p>Other backers include SeaX, XA Network and SG Innovate, and angel investors Yoh-Chie Lu, Jean-Luc Butel and Steve Blank. Bot MD was also part of Y Combinator&#8217;s summer 2018 batch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UvprMbNatM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/21/all-59-startups-that-launched-today-at-y-combinators-s18-demo-day-2/">All 59 startups that launched today at Y Combinator&#8217;s S18 Demo Day 2</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;All 59 startups that launched today at Y Combinator&#8217;s S18 Demo Day 2&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/21/all-59-startups-that-launched-today-at-y-combinators-s18-demo-day-2/embed/#?secret=UvprMbNatM" data-secret="UvprMbNatM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The funding will be used to expand in the Asia-Pacific region, including Indonesia, the Philippines, Malaysia and Indonesia, and to add new features in response to demand from hospitals and healthcare organizations during COVID-19. Bot MD’s AI assistant currently supports English, with plans to release Bahasa Indonesian and Spanish later this year. It is currently used by about 13,000 doctors at organizations including Changi General Hospital, National University Health System, National University Cancer Institute of Singapore, Tan Tock Seng Hospital, Singapore General Hospital, Parkway Radiology and the National Kidney Transplant Institute.</p>
<p>Co-founder and chief executive officer Dorothea Koh told TechCrunch that Bot MD integrates hospital information usually stored in multiple systems and makes it easier to access.<a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Bot-MD_Radiology_Phone_1-e1612251270188.png"><img loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2107101" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Bot-MD_Radiology_Phone_1-e1612251270188.png?w=680" alt="A smartphone with Bot MDs medical AI assistant for doctors displayed on it" width="680" height="468" /></a></p>
<p>Image Credits: Bot MDWithout Bot MD, doctors may need to dial a hospital operator to find which staffers are on call and get their contact information. If they want drug information, that means another call to the pharmacy. If they need to see updated guidelines and clinical protocols, that often entails finding a computer that is connected to the hospital’s intranet.</p>
<p>&#8220;A lot of what Bot MD does is to integrate the content that they need into a single interface that is searchable 24/7,&#8221; said Koh.</p>
<p>For example, during COVID-19, Bot MD introduced a new feature that takes healthcare providers to a form pre-filled with their information when they type &#8220;record temperature&#8221; into the chatbot. Many were accessing their organization&#8217;s intranet twice a day to log their temperature and Koh said being able to use the form through Bot MD has significantly improved compliance.</p>
<p>The time it takes to onboard Bot MD varies depending on the information systems and amount of content it needs to integrate, but Koh said its proprietary natural language processing chat engine makes training its AI relatively quick. For example, Changi General Hospital, a recent client, was onboarded in less than 10 days.</p>
<p>Bot MD plans to add new clinical apps to its platform, including ones for electronic medical records (EMR), billing and scheduling integrations, clinical alerts and chronic disease monitoring.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d57ng5YxTT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/mit-and-boston-dynamics-team-up-on-dr-spot-a-robot-for-remote-covid-19-vital-sign-measurement/">MIT and Boston Dynamics team up on &#8216;Dr. Spot,&#8217; a robot for remote COVID-19 vital sign measurement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MIT and Boston Dynamics team up on &#8216;Dr. Spot,&#8217; a robot for remote COVID-19 vital sign measurement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/mit-and-boston-dynamics-team-up-on-dr-spot-a-robot-for-remote-covid-19-vital-sign-measurement/embed/#?secret=d57ng5YxTT" data-secret="d57ng5YxTT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/bot-md-an-ai-based-chatbot-for-doctors-raises-5-million-for-expansion-into-more-asian-markets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107098</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
