<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:58:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Google is building its own chip for the Pixel 6</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-is-building-its-own-chip-for-the-pixel-6/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-is-building-its-own-chip-for-the-pixel-6/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Pixel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PIXEL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google just dumped a whole bunch of news about its upcoming Pixel 6 smartphone. Maybe the company was looking to get out in front of August 11’s big Samsung event &#8212; or perhaps it’s just hoping to keep people interested in the months leading up to a big fall announcement (and beat additional leaks to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google just dumped a whole bunch of news about its upcoming Pixel 6 smartphone. Maybe the company was looking to get out in front of August 11’s big Samsung event &#8212; or perhaps it’s just hoping to keep people interested in the months leading up to a big fall announcement (and beat additional leaks to the punch).</p>
<p>In either case, we got the <a href="https://blog.google/products/pixel/google-tensor-debuts-new-pixel-6-fall/">first look at the upcoming Android smartphone</a>, including a fairly massive redesign of the camera system on the rear. The company has traded its square configuration for a big, black bar that appears to indicate an even larger push into upgraded hardware after a couple of generations spent insisting that software/AI are the grounds on which it has chosen to fight.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="onmrSUvyrN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-gives-the-world-its-first-glimpse-of-the-pixel-6/">Google gives the world its first official glimpse of the Pixel 6</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google gives the world its first official glimpse of the Pixel 6&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-gives-the-world-its-first-glimpse-of-the-pixel-6/embed/#?secret=onmrSUvyrN" data-secret="onmrSUvyrN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>More interesting, however, is the arrival of Tensor, a new custom SoC (system on a chip) that will debut on the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro. It’s an important step from the company, as it looks to differentiate itself in a crowded smartphone field &#8212; something the company has admittedly struggled with in the past.</p>
<p>That means moving away from Qualcomm chips on these higher-end systems, following in Apple’s path of creating custom silicon. That said, the chips will be based on the same ARM architecture that Qualcomm uses to create its otherwise ubiquitous Snapdragon chips, and Google <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/google-tensor-pixel-6-pro/">will still rely</a> on the San Diego company to supply components for its budget-minded A Series.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184612" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184612" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184612" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pixel-6.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="425" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pixel-6.jpg 1060w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pixel-6.jpg?resize=150,62 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pixel-6.jpg?resize=300,125 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pixel-6.jpg?resize=768,319 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pixel-6.jpg?resize=680,282 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pixel-6.jpg?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184612" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>The Tensor name is a clear homage to Google’s TensorFlow ML, which has driven a number of its projects. And unsurprisingly, the company sites AI/ML as foundational to the chip’s place in the forthcoming phones. The Pixel team has long pushed software-based solutions, such as computational photography, as a differentiator.</p>
<p>“The team that designed our silicon wanted to make Pixel even more capable. For example, with Tensor we thought about every piece of the chip and customized it to run Google&#8217;s computational photography models,” Google writes. “For users, this means entirely new features, plus improvements to existing ones.”</p>
<p>Beyond the upgraded camera system, Tensor will be central to improving things such as speech recognition and language learning. Details are understandably still thin (the full reveal is happening in the fall, mind), but today’s announcement seems geared toward laying out what the future looks like for a revamped Pixel team &#8212; and certainly these sorts of focuses play into precisely what Google ought to be doing in the smartphone space: focusing on its smarts in AI and software.</p>
<p>In May of last year, key members of the Pixel team left Google, pointing to what looked to be a transition for the team. Hardware head Rick Osterloh was reported to have had harsh words at the time.</p>
<p>“AI is the future of our innovation work, but the problem is we’ve run into computing limitations that prevented us from fully pursuing our mission,” Osterloh wrote in today’s post. “So we set about building a technology platform built for mobile that enabled us to bring our most innovative AI and machine learning (ML) to our Pixel users.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oknLuNUYyY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/top-members-of-googles-pixel-team-have-left-the-company/">Top members of Google’s Pixel team have left the company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Top members of Google’s Pixel team have left the company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/top-members-of-googles-pixel-team-have-left-the-company/embed/#?secret=oknLuNUYyY" data-secret="oknLuNUYyY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-is-building-its-own-chip-for-the-pixel-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184646</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Salesforce steps into RPA buying Servicetrace and teaming it with Mulesoft</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/salesforce-steps-into-rpa-buying-servicetrace-and-teaming-it-with-mulesoft/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/salesforce-steps-into-rpa-buying-servicetrace-and-teaming-it-with-mulesoft/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RPA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the last couple of years, Robotic Process Automation or RPA has been red hot with tons of investor activity and M&#38;A from companies like SAP, IBM and ServiceNow. UIPath had a major IPO in April and has a market cap over $30 billion. I wondered when Salesforce would get involved and today the company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Over the last couple of years, Robotic Process Automation or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/no-code-workflow-and-rpa-line-up-for-their-automation-moment/">RPA has been red hot with tons of investor activity</a> and M&amp;A from companies like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/sap-is-buying-berlin-business-process-automation-startup-signavio/">SAP</a>, IBM and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/servicenow-takes-rpa-plunge-by-acquiring-india-based-startup-intellibot/">ServiceNow</a>. UIPath <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/as-uipath-closes-above-its-final-private-valuation-cfo-ashim-gupta-discusses-his-companys-path-to-market/">had a major IPO in April</a> and has a market cap over $30 billion. I wondered when Salesforce would get involved and today the company dipped its toe into the RPA pool, <a href="https://blogs.mulesoft.com/news/mulesoft-to-acquire-servicetrace/">announcing its intent</a> to buy German RPA company Servicetrace.</p>
<p>Salesforce intends to make Servicetrace part of Mulesoft, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/20/salesforce-is-buying-mulesoft-at-enterprise-value-of-6-5-billion/">it bought in 2018 for $6.5 billion</a>. The companies aren&#8217;t divulging the purchase price, suggesting it&#8217;s a much smaller deal. When Servicetrace is in the fold, it should fit in well with Mulesoft&#8217;s API integration, helping to add an automation layer to Mulesoft&#8217;s tool kit.</p>
<p>&#8220;With the addition of Servicetrace, MuleSoft will be able to deliver a leading unified integration, API management, and RPA platform, which will further enrich the Salesforce Customer 360 — empowering organizations to deliver connected experiences from anywhere. The new RPA capabilities will enhance Salesforce’s Einstein Automate solution, enabling end-to-end workflow automation across any system for Service, Sales, Industries, and more,&#8221; Mulesoft CEO Brent Hayward wrote<a href="https://blogs.mulesoft.com/news/mulesoft-to-acquire-servicetrace/"> in a blog post</a> announcing the deal.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BTaUjRrR7e"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/no-code-workflow-and-rpa-line-up-for-their-automation-moment/">No code, workflow and RPA line up for their automation moment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;No code, workflow and RPA line up for their automation moment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/no-code-workflow-and-rpa-line-up-for-their-automation-moment/embed/#?secret=BTaUjRrR7e" data-secret="BTaUjRrR7e" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While Einstein, Salesforce&#8217;s artificial intelligence layer, gives companies with more modern tooling the ability to automate certain tasks, RPA is suited to more legacy operations, and this acquisition could be another step in helping Salesforce bridge the gap between older on-prem tools and more modern cloud software.</p>
<p>Brent Leary, founder and principal analyst at CRM Essentials says that it brings another dimension to Salesforce&#8217;s digital transformation tools. &#8220;It didn&#8217;t take Salesforce long to move to the next acquisition after closing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">their biggest purchase with Slack</a>. But automation of processes and workflows fueled by realtime data coming from a growing variety sources is becoming a key to finding success with digital transformation. And this adds a critical piece to that puzzle for Salesforce/MulseSoft,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>While it feels like Salesforce is joining the market late, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/07/5-investors-discuss-the-future-of-rpa-after-uipaths-ipo/">in an investor survey we published in May</a> Laela Sturdy, general partner at CapitalG told us that we are just skimming the surface so far when it comes to RPA&#8217;s potential.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re a long way from needing to think about the space maturing. In fact, RPA adoption is still in its early infancy when you consider its immense potential. Most companies are only now just beginning to explore the numerous use cases that exist across industries. The more enterprises dip their toes into RPA, the more use cases they envision,&#8221; Sturdy responded in the survey.</p>
<p>Servicetrace was founded in 2004, long before the notion of RPA even existed. Neither Crunchbase nor Pitchbook shows any money raised, but the website suggests a mature company with a rich product set. Customers include Fujitsu, Siemens, Merck and Deutsche Telekom.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wddzRuT7yu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/07/5-investors-discuss-the-future-of-rpa-after-uipaths-ipo/">5 investors discuss the future of RPA after UiPath&#8217;s IPO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 investors discuss the future of RPA after UiPath&#8217;s IPO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/07/5-investors-discuss-the-future-of-rpa-after-uipaths-ipo/embed/#?secret=wddzRuT7yu" data-secret="wddzRuT7yu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/salesforce-steps-into-rpa-buying-servicetrace-and-teaming-it-with-mulesoft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184606</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>All-electric 2022 Audi e-tron GT and RS e-tron GT provide a pop of tech in understated packaging</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/all-electric-2022-audi-e-tron-gt-and-rs-e-tron-gt-provide-a-pop-of-tech-in-understated-packaging/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/all-electric-2022-audi-e-tron-gt-and-rs-e-tron-gt-provide-a-pop-of-tech-in-understated-packaging/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Abigail Bassett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Luxury, technology and a whole lot of flash often go hand in hand. In the age of space-faring billionaires, we all expect the latest wiz-bang gadget to look like something from the future, right? Not in Audi&#8217;s view. The 2022 Audi e-tron GT and RS e-tron GT are a pair of all-electric grand touring halo [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Luxury, technology and a whole lot of flash often go hand in hand. In the age of space-faring billionaires, we all expect the latest wiz-bang gadget to look like something from the future, right?</p>
<p>Not in Audi&#8217;s view. The 2022 Audi e-tron GT and RS e-tron GT are a pair of all-electric grand touring halo cars that don&#8217;t look like something from 2060. They look just like sleek gasoline-powered GTs, but beneath the skin, there&#8217;s a whole lot more power, technological pop and panache than the design implies at first glance.</p>
<p>The 2022 Audi e-tron GT and RS e-tron GT get a low-slung roofline, wide track and long wheelbase like those grand tourers of the past, with the addition of a few design flourishes to bring it in line with Audi&#8217;s subtle, yet luxurious aesthetic. While the e-tron GT and the RS e-tron GT were both produced alongside the Audi R8 (its roofline is lower than the R8) and borrow a few things from that iconic design, these electric grand tourers are a pair of beasts all their own.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>Nuts and bolts</h2>
<p>Based on the same 800-volt architecture as the Porsche Taycan, the e-tron GT makes 469 combined horsepower (up to 522 hp with overboost) from a pair of dual, permanent-magnet motors powering the front and rear wheels. The RS e-tron GT makes 590 (637 hp with overboost) horsepower from those same motors and Audi says it can do 0-60 in 3.1 seconds.</p>
<p>Both vehicles are capable, confident and quick and don&#8217;t tarry on mountain roads or long highway stretches. Acceleration is almost seamless, as it is in most electric vehicles.</p>
<p>Thanks to Audi&#8217;s electric quattro all-wheel drive with torque vectoring system, both vehicles are sure-footed and well sorted, even when the wheels start to squeal. This system allows a variable amount of power to be sent to wheels that slip when cornering hard, making a sudden lane change, or driving in slippery conditions.</p>
<p>The vehicles I drove were outfitted with summer tires, and I got to test a bit of this out on a closed slalom course with a sudden lane change at the end at the Agua Dulce Airpark about 50 miles northeast of downtown Los Angeles. I ran the RS e-tron GT through the cones three consecutive times to get a feel for the system and each time the car felt secure, planted and under control.</p>
<h2>Steering, speed and range</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2184599" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_03.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184599" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2184599 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_03.jpg" alt="Audi RS e-tron GT Tango Red_03" width="2000" height="1334" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_03.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_03.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_03.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_03.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_03.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_03.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_03.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2184599" class="wp-caption-text">2022 Audi RS e-tron GT. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Audi</p></div></p>
<p>Both the e-tron GT and the RS e-tron GT also get optional rear-wheel steering. Under 30 mph, the rear wheels can turn up to 2.8 degrees in the opposite direction to the front wheels to help make the turning radius of the e-tron GT and the RS e-tron GT smaller. Above 30 mph the rear wheels turn in the same direction as the front. This system is similar (with fewer degrees of rotation) to that in the Porsche Taycan.</p>
<p>While I did not get to try out overboost in either vehicle on the smooth tarmac at the airpark, I did run a series of back-to-back 0 to 100 mph accelerations using launch control in the RS e-tron GT. Amongst the cohort of journalists there, I came in second, doing 0-60 in 3.24 seconds and 0-100 in 7.29 seconds. In 102-degree heat, on cold tires, those numbers are plenty impressive. By the end of the runway, I saw speeds approaching 120 mph, 32 mph short of the electronically limited 155 mph, (152 mph in the e-tron GT) before hitting the brakes. After three back-to-back runs, the fully charged RS e-tron GT had only lost 20 miles of range.</p>
<p>The EPA-estimated range for the RS e-tron GT is 232 miles while the e-tron GT is estimated to get 239 miles of range.</p>
<h2>Charging up</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2184603" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_54.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184603" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2184603 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_54.jpg" alt="2022 Audi e-tron GT Ascari Blue_54" width="2000" height="1334" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_54.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_54.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_54.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_54.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_54.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_54.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_54.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2184603" class="wp-caption-text">2022 Audi e-tron GT. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Audi</p></div></p>
<p>Those estimated EPA ranges are a result of the low-slung 93 kWh battery pack (the same in both vehicles) that Audi says can charge up to 80% in 23 minutes on 270-volt chargers (DC fast charging).</p>
<p>The e-tron GT starts at $99,900 and the RS e-tron GT pops to a higher $139,900 (both excluding the $1,045 destination charge). That price tag does come with one-time limited benefit.</p>
<p>Audi paired up with Electrify America to offer free, unlimited public charging for three years (without time restrictions). They also offer at-home charging stations set up through Qmerit. Both the e-tron GT and the RS e-tron GT come with standard dual charging ports and a 9.6 kW charging system with 240-volt capability so that owners can charge anywhere. Electrify America was launched by the Volkswagen Group, which owns Audi, following the Dieselgate scandal.</p>
<p>Finding any charger is available through the infotainment system, known as the MMI, and the 10.1-inch touchscreen in the center console. Head to navigation and then hit the icon marked with a plug and a list of chargers near you will populate.</p>
<p>While I didn&#8217;t get the opportunity to try to find chargers on the one-day drive, Audi says that finding EA chargers and their status and availability is easy through both Audi&#8217;s MyAudi app (available via smartphone and desktop), and through the MMI.  Audi says that drivers can sort by their preferred charging level (Level 1 through DC fast chargers) and navigate to the charger all without leaving Audi&#8217;s in-vehicle interface.</p>
<p>Drivers can also perform the search on their phone through EA&#8217;s app or through the MyAudi app and send directions to the car either via wireless CarPlay, which is currently available or wireless Android Auto, which is coming on production models, though it wasn&#8217;t available in the e-tron GT or the RS e-tron GT that I drove. Drivers can also connect their smartphone through a USB-C port located in the center armrest.</p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t get to try the MyAudi app since I am not an owner (it requires tying the vehicle&#8217;s VIN to the app to ensure that privacy is maintained), but Audi says that drivers can plan a route on their MyAudi app, and the system will automatically include charge stops along the way to ensure that they arrive with plenty of battery in reserve.</p>
<p>For those luxury buyers who want a bit more support to make a seamless transition to an all-electric luxury car, Audi is launching what they call Audi Care for EVs with the e-tron GT and RS e-tron GT. At participating dealers, owners can pay an additional $999 plus tax to get vehicle servicing for four years that includes high-wear items like wipers and brake pads, available valet pick-up and drop-off for service appointments, mobile service (tire changes, basic maintenance) and, if an owner needs it, up to 10 free tows to an Audi center per year. Audi is also offering seven free days of rentals from Audi by Silvercar with the purchase of an e-tron GT or a RS e-tron.</p>
<h2>That virtual cockpit, though</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2184595" style="width: 6610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_74.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184595" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2184595 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_74.jpg" alt="Audi-e-tron GT Ascari Blue" width="6600" height="4402" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_74.jpg 6600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_74.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_74.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_74.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_74.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_74.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_74.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/e-tron-GT-Ascari-Blue_74.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 6600px) 100vw, 6600px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2184595" class="wp-caption-text">2022 Audi e-tron GT. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Audi</p></div></p>
<p>The e-tron GT and the RS e-tron GT blend features from both the e-tron (the SUV) and the Audi R8, and both GTs get dual screens that offer tons of features for drivers and passengers. The 12.3-inch virtual cockpit in front of the driver is highly customizable, like it is on most modern Audis today, offering everything from map views to battery status access with few simple inputs on the steering wheel.</p>
<p>The system makes navigating a breeze and drivers or passengers can use voice control to set destinations by simply pressing the button on the steering wheel and giving the car an address, point of interest or city.</p>
<p>The voice system is surprisingly robust and while it was a bit laggy when I used it, it recognizes natural language inputs and verbally prompts the speaker to use specific terms when choosing between two options &#8212; say canceling a route and putting in a new destination versus making a stopover. Never once did I have to try multiple times to get the system to recognize what I wanted to do.</p>
<p>The 10.1-inch infotainment system in the center console offers everything from drive mode selection to specific Audi apps, navigation options, optional massage, heat and cooled seats, and much more.</p>
<p>The Audi MMI center screen is touch capacitive and users can drag and drop icons around, allowing owners and their passengers to customize the home screen in any way. The seat heater, cooler and the massage can all be run at the same time, should someone so desire (and have the right equipment), all from the MMI.</p>
<h2>Maybe just a little flash?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2184604" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_23.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184604" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2184604 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_23.jpg" alt="2022 Audi RS e-tron GT Tango Red_23" width="2000" height="1334" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_23.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_23.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_23.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_23.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_23.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_23.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RS-e-tron-GT-Tango-Red_23.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2184604" class="wp-caption-text">2022 Audi RS e-tron GT. I<strong>mage Credits:</strong> Audi</p></div></p>
<p>Both GTs are pushing $100,000, and for that, some buyers may want just a little bit more razzle dazzle.</p>
<p>For the launch year, Audi is offering one pricey, but special option on the RS e-tron GT: the Year One package. For $20,350, owners get the &#8220;carbon performance&#8221; package with features like carbon-fiber trim, illuminated door sills, black badges and rear-wheel steering, along with special 21-inch wheels, red ceramic brake calipers, red seatbelts and red stitching inside.</p>
<p>For those who want the prestige, power and advanced technology of a luxury brand, in an electric halo grand tourer that doesn&#8217;t (necessarily) come with all the flash, the 2022 Audi e-tron GT and Audi RS e-tron GT fit the bill. Both are on sale now.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zvYLUufb4e"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/automakers-have-battery-anxiety-so-theyre-taking-control-of-the-supply/">Automakers have battery anxiety, so they&#8217;re taking control of the supply</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Automakers have battery anxiety, so they&#8217;re taking control of the supply&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/automakers-have-battery-anxiety-so-theyre-taking-control-of-the-supply/embed/#?secret=zvYLUufb4e" data-secret="zvYLUufb4e" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/all-electric-2022-audi-e-tron-gt-and-rs-e-tron-gt-provide-a-pop-of-tech-in-understated-packaging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184581</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google gives the world its first official glimpse of the Pixel 6</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-gives-the-world-its-first-glimpse-of-the-pixel-6/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-gives-the-world-its-first-glimpse-of-the-pixel-6/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PIXEL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While the company isn&#8217;t revealing everything about it just yet, this morning Google gave the world its first official peek at its next flagship phone: the Pixel 6. Here&#8217;s what we know so far: It&#8217;ll come in two forms: Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro. The base 6 will have a matte aluminum finish with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While the company isn&#8217;t revealing everything about it just yet, this morning Google gave the world its first official peek at its next flagship phone: the Pixel 6.</p>
<p><strong>Here&#8217;s what we know so far:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>It&#8217;ll come in two forms: Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro.</li>
<li>The base 6 will have a matte aluminum finish <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml">with a 6.4&#8243; display</a>, while the Pro has a shinier polished aluminum finish with a 6.7&#8243;.</li>
<li>Pixel 6 has two cameras (wide and ultra wide), while the 6 Pro adds a telephoto zoom lens</li>
<li>If you were hoping the increasingly common &#8220;camera bump&#8221; trend was on the way out&#8230; not quite. The bump has now evolved into the &#8220;camera bar&#8221;, with Google&#8217;s Rick Osterloh noting that better sensors and lenses just won&#8217;t fit in a smaller package.</li>
<li>These will be the first phones to run Tensor, Google&#8217;s first entirely custom system-on-a-chip. Previous Pixels have run on Qualcomm&#8217;s Snapdragon platform. Google CEO Sundar Pichai says <a href="https://twitter.com/sundarpichai">they&#8217;ve been working on the chip for 4+ years</a>. In a blog post <a href="https://blog.google/products/pixel/google-tensor-debuts-new-pixel-6-fall/">announcing the devices</a>, Osterloh suggests that the focus here is making a chip tuned for on-device AI and ML.</li>
<li>They&#8217;ll ship sometime &#8220;this fall.&#8221;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-is-building-its-own-chip-for-the-pixel-6/</span></li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5bneurnsLW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-is-building-its-own-chip-for-the-pixel-6/">Google is building its own chip for the Pixel 6</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google is building its own chip for the Pixel 6&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-is-building-its-own-chip-for-the-pixel-6/embed/#?secret=5bneurnsLW" data-secret="5bneurnsLW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Lots of details, including pricing and much of the spec sheet (CPU, RAM, etc.) are still a mystery for now — though <a href="https://www.frontpagetech.com/2021/07/08/exclusive-full-final-specifications-for-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro/">earlier leaks</a> seem to be spot on, so far.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2184629" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pixel-6-2.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="583" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pixel-6-2.jpg 824w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pixel-6-2.jpg?resize=150,129 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pixel-6-2.jpg?resize=300,257 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pixel-6-2.jpg?resize=768,659 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pixel-6-2.jpg?resize=680,583 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pixel-6-2.jpg?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-gives-the-world-its-first-glimpse-of-the-pixel-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184602</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pokémon GO influencers threaten a boycott after Niantic removes COVID safety measures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/pokemon-go-influencers-threaten-a-boycott-after-niantic-removes-covid-safety-measures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/pokemon-go-influencers-threaten-a-boycott-after-niantic-removes-covid-safety-measures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ingress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[niantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pokemon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pokémon Go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The creators of Pokémon GO, Niantic developed one of the first mainstream augmented reality games, boasting 166 million users and over a billion dollars in revenue last year. Taking inspiration from the main series Pokémon games, Pokémon GO uses in-game incentives to encourage users to explore their surroundings, team up with other users to fight [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The creators of Pokémon GO, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/the-niantic-ec-1/">Niantic</a> developed one of the first mainstream augmented reality games, boasting <a href="https://www.businessofapps.com/data/pokemon-go-statistics/">166 million users and over a billion dollars in revenue</a> last year. Taking inspiration from the main series Pokémon games, Pokémon GO uses in-game incentives to encourage users to explore their surroundings, team up with other users to fight legendary beasts, and travel to places they&#8217;ve never been before.</p>
<p>Before the pandemic, this posed an accessibility issue &#8212; when certain tasks could only be completed by walking a certain distance, for example, it alienated users with physical conditions and disabilities that prevent them from easily taking a walk around the neighborhood. Plus, for players in wheelchairs, it might be impossible to access certain PokéStops and Gyms. It&#8217;s necessary to interact with these <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/05/what-is-ingress-prime/">real-world landmarks</a> to play the game to its fullest.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xxk2pbomGL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/how-niantic-evolved-pokemon-go-for-the-year-no-one-could-go-anywhere/">How Niantic evolved Pokémon GO for the year no one could go anywhere</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Niantic evolved Pokémon GO for the year no one could go anywhere&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/how-niantic-evolved-pokemon-go-for-the-year-no-one-could-go-anywhere/embed/#?secret=xxk2pbomGL" data-secret="xxk2pbomGL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>When much of the world entered lockdown March 2020, Pokémon Go doubled the size of the radius that players can be within to interact with a PokéStop or Gym, widening the radius from 40 meters to 80 meters. So, you could now be further away from a landmark but still reap its rewards. This made it easier for users to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/30/niantic-is-updating-pokemon-go-and-other-titles-to-support-indoor-gaming/">play from home</a>, or play outside while social distancing &#8212; but it also made the game much more accessible. Plus, for a game that still gets a bad rep for causing <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/pokemon-go-linked-to-traffic-deaths-accidents-and-hundreds-of-thousands-of-dollars-in-vehicular-damage-2017-11">traffic accidents</a>, the increased radius helped pedestrian players access landmarks without brazenly jay-walking across the street (to be fair, it&#8217;s on users to make smart decisions while gaming in augmented reality &#8212; but, Niantic has responsibility here too). And for businesses that happened to be located in a prime location for raid battles, which require players to gather in-person within a Gym&#8217;s radius to defeat rare monsters, this meant that Pokémon players could maintain a respectful distance from store fronts while playing the game (later in the pandemic, it became possible to join raid battles remotely &#8212; this feature will remain in the game, probably because it proved profitable).</p>
<p>These pandemic incentives were always framed as <a href="https://pokemongolive.com/post/gyminteractionupdate-20200331/?hl=en">temporary bonuses</a>, but players embraced the changes &#8212; in 2020, Pokémon GO had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/how-niantic-evolved-pokemon-go-for-the-year-no-one-could-go-anywhere/">its highest-earning year yet</a>. Now, the increased landmark radius has been removed &#8220;<a href="https://pokemongolive.com/post/hello-world-pokemon-go">as a test</a>&#8221; in the U.S. and New Zealand.</p>
<p>&#8220;As we return to the outside world again, these changes are aimed at restoring the focus of Pokémon GO on movement and exploration in the real world,&#8221; the company wrote in <a href="https://pokemongolive.com/post/hello-world-pokemon-go">a blog post</a>. &#8220;These changes will be introduced slowly and carefully to make it more exciting to explore the world around you.&#8221;</p>
<p>One new incentive gives users 10x XP for visiting a new PokéStop for the first time (or, in real-world terms, visiting a new place). But as the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/07/27/health/cdc-mask-guidance-vaccinated-people-bn/index.html">Delta variant spreads</a> in the U.S., players find these changes to be frustrating and misguided. Why roll back features that made the game more accessible while also netting the company more money?</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The removal of double distance is nothing short of a slap in the face towards the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PokemonGO?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#PokemonGO</a> Community.</p>
<p>I’ll realistic and say I that I’ll quit GO if changes aren’t being made ASAP.</p>
<p>I REFUSE to cover a game that doesn’t have it’s player base in its best interest.</p>
<p>&mdash; REVERSAL &#8211; Pokémon GO (@REVERSALxPoGO) <a href="https://twitter.com/REVERSALxPoGO/status/1421812857549819906?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 1, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The Pokémon Go YouTuber, Reversal, who has created sponsored content for Niantic, wrote that he will quit the game if changes aren&#8217;t being made ASAP. Other players launched <a href="https://www.change.org/p/niantic-keep-increased-pokestop-and-gym-interaction-distance">a petition</a> with over 130,000 signatures to keep increased PokéStop and Gym interaction distance. Prominent Pokémon Go content creators like <a href="https://youtu.be/tGqg1qYKKGI?t=120">ZoëTwoDots</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lpG8asGli4c">The Trainer Club</a> have referenced a potential boycott of the game in videos they uploaded today, citing Niantic&#8217;s refusal to listen to community concerns after they announced the <a href="https://pokemongolive.com/post/hello-world-pokemon-go">impending end</a> of pandemic bonuses in June.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m more than down to boycott the game with everyone if we&#8217;re vibing that,&#8221; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-10uJUkzxSXa9sEtV67YcA">ZoëTwoDots</a>, who has also partnered with Niantic, told her 212,000 subscribers. &#8220;I know for myself personally, I&#8217;m just straight up not spending money in the game going forward until they address it publicly.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">My opinion on the Pokéstop radius hasn&#39;t changed. It was a clear quality of life change that was only fully realised because of a (ongoing) pandemic. It has provided accessibility to disabled players, safety to all players, and NEVER affected our enjoyment of exploration. <a href="https://t.co/DK1VWkw0ga">https://t.co/DK1VWkw0ga</a></p>
<p>&mdash; ZoëTwoDots <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f380.png" alt="🎀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@_ZoeTwoDots) <a href="https://twitter.com/_ZoeTwoDots/status/1421968491762970624?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 1, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>As the game celebrates its five year anniversary, the conflict it now faces isn&#8217;t about players wishing for the game to be easier. Rather, this represents a failure by Niantic to listen to its user base, prioritize accessibility, and incentivize users to stay home as COVID-19 cases <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/us/covid-cases.html">rise again</a> in the U.S.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="77GncjipbJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/the-niantic-ec-1/">The Niantic EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Niantic EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/the-niantic-ec-1/embed/#?secret=77GncjipbJ" data-secret="77GncjipbJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/pokemon-go-influencers-threaten-a-boycott-after-niantic-removes-covid-safety-measures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184518</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The next generation of global payments: Afterpay + Square</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/the-next-generation-of-global-payments-afterpay-square/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/the-next-generation-of-global-payments-afterpay-square/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 16:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matrix Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Square]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sunday was a big day in fintech: Afterpay has agreed to merge with Square. This agreement sets two of the most admired financial technology companies in recent history on a path to becoming one.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Dana Stalder</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dcstalder">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Dana Stalder is a partner at <a href="https://matrixpartners.com">Matrix Partners</a>. The former commercial chief (Product, Sales and Marketing) at PayPal, he now leads fintech investing at Matrix Partners, where he also invests in consumer marketplaces and enterprise software.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/fintechs-could-see-100-billion-of-liquidity-in-2021/">Fintechs could see $100 billion of liquidity in 2021</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/09/2019-saw-a-stampede-of-fintech-unicorns/">2019 saw a stampede of fintech unicorns</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Sunday was a big day in fintech: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/">Afterpay has agreed to merge with Square</a>. This agreement sets two of the most admired financial technology companies in recent history on a path to becoming one.</p>
<p>Afterpay and Square have the potential to build one of the world’s most important payments networks. Square has built a very significant merchant payment network, and, via Cash App, a thriving high-growth consumer payment service. However, these two lines of business have historically not been integrated. Together, Square and Afterpay will be able to weave all of these services together into a single integrated experience.</p>
<p>Afterpay and Cash App each have double-digit millions of consumers, and Square’s seller ecosystem and Afterpay’s merchant network both record double-digit billions of payment volume per year. From the offline register and the online checkout flow to sending money in just a few taps, Square and Afterpay will tell a complete story of next-generation economic empowerment.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As Afterpay’s only institutional venture investor, I wanted to share some perspective on how we got here and what this merger means for the future of consumer finance and the payments industry.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Afterpay and Square have the potential to build one of the world’s most important payments networks.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<h2>Critical innovations in fintech</h2>
<p>Every five to 10 years, the global payments industry undergoes a critical innovation cycle that determines the winners and losers for the next several decades. The last major transition was the shift to NFC-based mobile payments, which I <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/05/31/the-first-battle-in-the-mobile-payments-war-is-over/">wrote about in 2015</a>. The major mobile OS vendors (Apple and Google) cemented their position in the global payments stack by deftly bridging the needs of the networks (Visa, Mastercard, etc.) and consumers by way of the mobile devices in their pockets.</p>
<p>Afterpay sparked the latest critical innovation cycle. Conceived in a living room in Sydney by a millennial, Nick Molnar, for millennials, Afterpay had a key insight: Millennials don’t like credit.</p>
<p>Millennials came of age during the global mortgage crisis of 2008. As young adults, they watched their friends and family lose their homes by overextending on mortgage debt, bolstering their already lower trust for banks. They also have record levels of student debt. Therefore, it’s no surprise that millennials (and Gen Z right behind them) strongly prefer debit cards over credit cards.</p>
<p>But it’s one thing to recognize the paradigm shift and quite another to do something about it. Nick Molnar and Anthony Eisen did something, ultimately building one of the fastest-growing payments startups in history on their core product: Buy now, pay later … and never any interest.</p>
<p>Afterpay’s product is simple. If you have $100 in your cart and choose to pay with Afterpay, it will charge your bank card (typically a debit card) $25 every two weeks in four installments. No interest, no revolving debt and no fees with on-time payments. For the millennial consumer, this meant they could get the primary benefit of a credit card (the ability to pay later) with their debit card, without the need to worry about all the bad things that come with credit cards — high interest rates and revolving debt.</p>
<p>All upside, no downside. Who could resist? For the early merchants, virtually all of whom relied on millennials as their key growth segment, they got a fair trade: Pay a small fee above payment processing to Afterpay, get significantly higher average order values and conversions to purchase. It was a win-win proposition and, with lots of execution, a new payment network was born.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184506" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184506" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184506" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image001.png" alt="The rise of Afterpay" width="1024" height="570" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image001.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image001.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image001.png?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image001.png?resize=768,428 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image001.png?resize=680,379 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image001.png?resize=1536,855 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image001.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184506" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Matrix Partners</p></div></p>
<h2>Imitation is the greatest form of flattery</h2>
<p>Afterpay went somewhat unnoticed outside Australia in 2016 and 2017, but once it came to the U.S. in 2018 and built a business there that broke $100 million net revenues in only its second year, it got attention.</p>
<p>Klarna, which had struggled with product-market fit in the U.S., pivoted their business to emulate Afterpay. And Affirm, which had always been about traditional credit — generating a significant portion of their revenue from consumer interest — also noticed and introduced their own BNPL offering. Then came PayPal with “Pay in 4,” and just a few weeks ago, there has been news that Apple is expected to enter the space.</p>
<p>Afterpay created a global phenomenon that has now become a category embraced by mainstream players across the industry — a category that is on track to take a meaningful share of global retail payments over the next 10 years.</p>
<p>Afterpay stands apart. It has always been the BNPL leader by virtually every measure, and it has done it by staying true to their customers&#8217; needs. The company is great at understanding the millennial and Gen Z consumer. It’s evident in the voice, tone and lifestyle brand you experience as an Afterpay user, and in the merchant network it continues to build strategically. It&#8217;s also evident in the simple fact that it doesn’t try to cross-sell users revolving debt products.</p>
<p>Most importantly, it&#8217;s evident in the usage metrics relative to competition. This is a product that people love, use and have come to rely on, all with better, fairer terms than were ever available to them than with traditional consumer credit.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184508" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184508" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184508" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image002.png" alt="Consumer loyalty and frequency drives powerful network effect, securing the lifetime value of a consumer" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image002.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image002.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image002.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image002.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image002.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image002.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image002.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184508" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Afterpay H1 FY21 results presentation</p></div></p>
<h2>Square + Afterpay: The perfect fit</h2>
<p>I’ve been building payment companies for over 15 years now, initially in the early days of PayPal and more recently as a venture investor at Matrix Partners. I’ve never seen a combination that has such potential to deliver extraordinary value to consumers and merchants. Even more so than eBay + PayPal.</p>
<p>Beyond the clear product and network complementarity, what’s most exciting to me and my partners is the alignment of values and culture. Square and Afterpay share a vision of a future with more opportunity and fewer economic hurdles for all. As they build toward that future together, I’m confident that this combination is a winner. Square and Afterpay together will become the world’s next generation payment provider.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XCJ1Bd9991"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/">Why Square is shelling out $29B to snag BNPL player Afterpay</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Square is shelling out $29B to snag BNPL player Afterpay&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/embed/#?secret=XCJ1Bd9991" data-secret="XCJ1Bd9991" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/the-next-generation-of-global-payments-afterpay-square/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184503</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lilium in talks with Brazilian airline for $1B order</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/lilium-in-talks-with-brazilian-airline-for-1b-order/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/lilium-in-talks-with-brazilian-airline-for-1b-order/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 16:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eVTOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lilium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban air mobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[German electric aircraft startup Lilium is negotiating the terms for a 220-aircraft, $1 billion order with one of Brazil’s largest domestic airlines, the companies said Monday. Should the deal with Azul move forward, it would mark the largest order in Lilium’s history and its first foray into South American markets. &#8220;A term sheet has been [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">German electric aircraft startup Lilium is negotiating the terms for a 220-aircraft, $1 billion order with one of Brazil’s largest domestic airlines, the companies said Monday. Should the deal with Azul move forward, it would mark the largest order in Lilium’s history and its first foray into South American markets.</p>
<p>&#8220;A term sheet has been signed and we will move towards a final agreement in the coming months,&#8221; a Lilium spokesperson told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The 220 aircraft would fly as part of a new, co-branded airline network that would operate in Brazil. Should the two companies come to an agreement, Azul would operate and maintain the fleet of the flagship 7-seater aircraft, and Lilium would provide custom spare parts, including replacement batteries, and an aircraft health monitoring platform.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Deliveries would commence in 2025, a year after Lilium has said it plans to begin commercial operations in Europe and the United States. These timelines are dependent upon Lilium receiving key certification approvals from each country’s requisite aerospace regulator. Azul said in a statement it would “support Lilium with the necessary regulatory approval processes in Brazil” as part of the agreement.</p>
<p>Even if a deal is reached, it would likely be subject to Lilium hitting certain performance standards and benchmarks, similar to the conditions of Archer Aviation’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/archer-lands-1-1b-order-from-united-airlines-and-a-spac-deal/">$1 billion order</a> with United Airlines. Still, orders of this value are seen as a positive signal to markets and investors that an electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft is more than smoke and mirrors.</p>
<p>Also like Archer, Lilium is planning on taking the SPAC route to going public. The company in March announced its intention to merge with Qell Acquisition Corp. and list on Nasdaq under ticker symbol “LILM.” SPACs have become a popular vehicle for public listing across the transportation sector, but they’ve become especially popular with capital-intensive eVTOL startups.</p>
<p>The merger may be necessary for the company’s continued operations. According to the German news website <em>Welt</em>, Lilium added a risk warning to its 2019 balance sheet noting that it will run out of money in December 2022 should the SPAC merger not be completed.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SNBS5MH92V"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/the-air-taxi-market-prepares-to-take-flight/">The air taxi market prepares to take flight</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The air taxi market prepares to take flight&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/the-air-taxi-market-prepares-to-take-flight/embed/#?secret=SNBS5MH92V" data-secret="SNBS5MH92V" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/lilium-in-talks-with-brazilian-airline-for-1b-order/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184522</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cloud  infrastructure market kept growing in Q2 reaching $42B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/cloud-infrastructure-market-kept-growing-in-q2-reaching-42b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/cloud-infrastructure-market-kept-growing-in-q2-reaching-42b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 16:09:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canalys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure market share]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Synergy Research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184490</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s often said in baseball that a prospect has a high ceiling, reflecting the tremendous potential of a young player with plenty of room to get better. The same could be said for the cloud infrastructure market, which just keeps growing with little sign of slowing down any time soon. The market hit $42 billion [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s often said in baseball that a prospect has a high ceiling, reflecting the tremendous potential of a young player with plenty of room to get better. The same could be said for the cloud infrastructure market, which just keeps growing with little sign of slowing down any time soon. The market hit $42 billion in total revenue with all major vendors reporting, up $2 billion from Q1.</p>
<p>Synergy Research <a href="https://www.srgresearch.com/articles/quarterly-cloud-market-leaps-to-42b-amazon-microsoft-google-pocket-63-of-dollars-spent">reports that the revenue grew</a> at a speedy 39% clip, the fourth consecutive quarter that it has increased. AWS led the way per usual, but Microsoft continued growing at a rapid pace and Google also kept the momentum going.</p>
<p>AWS continues to defy market logic, actually increasing growth by 5% over the previous quarter at 37%, an amazing feat for a company with the market maturity of AWS. That accounted for $14.81 billion in revenue for Amazon&#8217;s cloud division, putting it close to a $60 billion run rate, good for a market leading 33% share. While that share has remained fairly steady for a number of years, the revenue continues to grow as the market pie grows ever larger.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Microsoft grew even faster at 51%, and while Microsoft cloud infrastructure data isn&#8217;t always easy to nail down, with 20% of market share according to Synergy Research, that puts it at $8.4 billion as it continues to push upward with revenue up from $7.8 billion last quarter.</p>
<p>Google too continued its slow and steady progress under the leadership of Thomas Kurian, leading the growth numbers with a 54% increase in cloud revenue in Q2 on revenue of $4.2 billion, good for 10% market share, the first time Google Cloud has reached double figures in Synergy&#8217;s quarterly tracking data. That&#8217;s up from $3.5 billion last quarter.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184493" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184493" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2184493" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CIS-Q221.jpg?w=680" alt="Synergy Research cloud infrastructure market share chart." width="680" height="335" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CIS-Q221.jpg 1310w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CIS-Q221.jpg?resize=150,74 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CIS-Q221.jpg?resize=300,148 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CIS-Q221.jpg?resize=768,378 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CIS-Q221.jpg?resize=680,335 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CIS-Q221.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184493" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Synergy Research</p></div></p>
<p>After the Big 3, Alibaba held steady over Q1 at 6% (but will only report this week) with IBM falling a point from Q1 to 4% as Big Blue continues to struggle in pure infrastructure as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/ibm-ceo-arvind-krishna-wants-to-completely-transform-his-organization/">it makes the transition to more of a hybrid cloud management player</a>.</p>
<p>John Dinsdale, chief analyst at Synergy, says that the big three are spending big to help fuel this growth. &#8220;Amazon, Microsoft and Google in aggregate are typically investing over $25 billion in capex per quarter, much of which is going towards building and equipping their fleet of over 340 hyperscale data centers,&#8221; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Meanwhile <a href="https://canalys.com/newsroom/global-cloud-services-q2-2021">Canalys had similar numbers</a>, but saw the overall market slightly higher at $47 billion. Their market share broke down to Amazon with 31%, Microsoft with 22% and Google with 8% of that total number.</p>
<p>Canalys analyst Blake Murray says that part of the reason companies are shifting workloads to the clouds is to help achieve environmental sustainability goals as the cloud vendors are working toward using more renewable energy to run their massive data centers.</p>
<p>&#8220;The best practices and technology utilized by these companies will filter to the rest of the industry, while customers will increasingly use cloud services to relieve some of their environmental responsibilities and meet sustainability goals,&#8221; Murray said in a statement.</p>
<p>Regardless of whether companies are moving to the cloud to get out of the data center business or because they hope to piggyback on the sustainability efforts of the big 3, companies are continuing a steady march to the cloud. With some estimates of worldwide cloud usage at around 25%, the potential for continued growth remains strong, especially with many markets still untapped outside the U.S.</p>
<p>That bodes well for the big three and for other smaller operators who can find a way to tap into slices of market share that add up to big revenue. &#8220;There remains a wealth of opportunity for smaller, more focused cloud providers, but it can be hard to look away from the eye-popping numbers coming out of the big three,&#8221; Dinsdale said.</p>
<p>In fact, it&#8217;s hard to see the ceiling for these companies any time in the foreseeable future.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yIUOieSbJA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/with-a-50b-run-rate-in-reach-can-anyone-stop-aws/">With a $50B run rate in reach, can anyone stop AWS?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With a $50B run rate in reach, can anyone stop AWS?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/with-a-50b-run-rate-in-reach-can-anyone-stop-aws/embed/#?secret=yIUOieSbJA" data-secret="yIUOieSbJA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/cloud-infrastructure-market-kept-growing-in-q2-reaching-42b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184490</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech leaders can be the secret weapon for supercharging ESG goals</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/tech-leaders-can-be-the-secret-weapon-for-supercharging-esg-goals/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/tech-leaders-can-be-the-secret-weapon-for-supercharging-esg-goals/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 16:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon footprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ESG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Etsy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughtworks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the past few years, we have seen an uptick in organizations setting long-term sustainability goals. However, CEOs and CSOs typically forecast these often long-term and aspirational goals.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jeff Sternberg</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/sternb0t">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jeff Sternberg is a technical director in the Office of the CTO (OCTO) at Google Cloud, a team of technologists and industry experts that help Google Cloud's customers solve challenging problems and disrupt their industries.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Environmental, social and governance (ESG) factors should be key considerations for CTOs and technology leaders scaling next generation companies from day one. Investors are increasingly prioritizing startups that focus on ESG, with the growth of <a href="https://www.blackrock.com/us/individual/investment-ideas/sustainable-investing">sustainable investing</a> skyrocketing.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s driving this shift in mentality across every industry? It’s simple: Consumers are no longer willing to support companies that don’t prioritize sustainability. According to a <a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2021-04-22-IBM-Study-COVID-19-Pandemic-Impacted-9-in-10-Surveyed-Consumers-Views-on-Sustainability">survey</a> conducted by IBM, the COVID-19 pandemic has elevated consumers&#8217; focus on sustainability and their willingness to pay out of their own pockets for a sustainable future. In tandem, federal action on climate change is increasing, with the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/20/paris-climate-agreement/">U.S. rejoining</a> the Paris Climate Agreement and a recent executive order on <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/20/executive-order-on-climate-related-financial-risk/">climate commitments</a>.</p>
<p>Over the past few years, we have seen an uptick in organizations setting long-term sustainability goals. However, CEOs and chief sustainability officers typically forecast these goals, and they are often long term and aspirational — leaving the near and midterm implementation of ESG programs to operations and technology teams.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Until recently, choosing cloud regions meant considering factors like cost and latency to end users. But carbon is another factor worth considering.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>CTOs are a crucial part of the planning process, and in fact, can be the secret weapon to help their organization supercharge their ESG targets. Below are a few immediate steps that CTOs and technology leaders can take to achieve sustainability and make an ethical impact.</p>
<h2>Reducing environmental impact</h2>
<p>As more businesses digitize and more consumers use devices and cloud services, the energy needed by data centers continues to rise. In fact, data centers account for an <a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/367/6481/984">estimated</a> 1% of worldwide electricity usage. However, a forecast from <a href="https://gcn.com/articles/2021/03/16/green-cloud.aspx">IDC</a> shows that the continued adoption of cloud computing could prevent the emission of more than 1 billion metric tons of carbon dioxide from 2021 through 2024.</p>
<p><strong>Make compute workloads more efficient</strong>: First, it’s important to understand the links between computing, power consumption and greenhouse gas emissions from fossil fuels. Making your app and compute workloads more efficient will reduce costs and energy requirements, thus reducing the carbon footprint of those workloads. In the cloud, tools like compute instance auto scaling and sizing recommendations make sure you’re not running too many or overprovisioned cloud VMs based on demand. You can also move to serverless computing, which does much of this scaling work automatically.</p>
<p><strong>Deploy compute workloads in regions with lower carbon intensity</strong>: Until recently, choosing cloud regions meant considering factors like cost and latency to end users. But carbon is another factor worth considering. While the compute capabilities of regions are similar, their carbon intensities typically vary. Some regions have access to more carbon-free energy production than others, and consequently the carbon intensity for each region is different.</p>
<p>So, choosing a cloud region with lower carbon intensity is often the simplest and most impactful step you can take. Alistair Scott, co-founder and CTO of cloud infrastructure startup <a href="https://www.infracost.io/">Infracost</a>, underscores this sentiment: &#8220;Engineers want to do the right thing and reduce waste, and I think cloud providers can help with that. The key is to provide information in workflow, so the people who are responsible for infraprovisioning can weigh the CO2 impact versus other factors such as cost and data residency before they deploy.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another step is to estimate your specific workload’s carbon footprint using open-source software like <a href="https://www.cloudcarbonfootprint.org/">Cloud Carbon Footprint</a>, a project sponsored by ThoughtWorks. Etsy has open-sourced a similar tool called <a href="https://codeascraft.com/2020/04/23/cloud-jewels-estimating-kwh-in-the-cloud/">Cloud Jewels</a> that estimates energy consumption based on cloud usage information. This is helping them track progress toward their target of reducing their energy intensity by 25% by 2025.</p>
<h2>Make social impact</h2>
<p>Beyond reducing environmental impact, CTOs and technology leaders can have significant, direct and meaningful social impact.</p>
<p><strong>Include societal benefits in the design of your products</strong>: As a CTO or technology founder, you can help ensure that societal benefits are prioritized in your product roadmaps. For example, if you’re a fintech CTO, you can add product features to expand access to credit in underserved populations. Startups like <a href="https://startup.google.com/stories/loanwell/">LoanWell</a> are on a mission to increase access to capital for those typically left out of the financial system and make the loan origination process more efficient and equitable.</p>
<p>When thinking about product design, a product needs to be as useful and effective as it is sustainable. By thinking about sustainability and societal impact as a core element of product innovation, there is an opportunity to differentiate yourself in socially beneficial ways. For example, Lush has been a pioneer of package-free solutions, and launched Lush Lens — a virtual package app leveraging cameras on mobile phones and AI to overlay product information. The company hit <a href="https://weare.lush.com/press-releases/lush-lens-hits-2-million-scans/">2 million scans</a> in its efforts to tackle the beauty industry’s excessive use of (plastic) packaging.</p>
<p><strong>Responsible AI practices should be ingrained in the culture to avoid social harms</strong>: Machine learning and artificial intelligence have become central to the advanced, personalized digital experiences everyone is accustomed to — from product and content recommendations to spam filtering, trend forecasting and other “smart” behaviors.</p>
<p>It is therefore critical to incorporate responsible AI practices, so benefits from AI and ML can be realized by your entire user base and that inadvertent harm can be avoided. Start by establishing clear principles for working with AI responsibly, and translate those principles into processes and procedures. Think about AI responsibility reviews the same way you think about code reviews, automated testing and UX design. As a technical leader or founder, you get to establish what the process is.</p>
<h2>Impact governance</h2>
<p>Promoting governance does not stop with the board and CEO; CTOs play an important role, too.</p>
<p><strong>Create a diverse and inclusive technology team</strong>: Compared to individual decision-makers, diverse teams make better decisions <a href="https://www.peoplemanagement.co.uk/experts/research/diversity-drives-better-decisions">87% of the time</a>. Additionally, <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/human-resources/trends/workforce-diversity#:~:text=Gartner%20research%20finds%20that%20in,intent%20to%20stay%20by%2020%25.&amp;text=This%20research%20details%20seven%20key,results%20from%20diversity%20and%20inclusion.">Gartner research</a> found that in a diverse workforce, performance improves by 12% and intent to stay by 20%.</p>
<p>It is important to reinforce and demonstrate why diversity, equity and inclusion is important within a technology team. One way you can do this is by using data to inform your DEI efforts. You can establish a voluntary internal program to collect demographics, including gender, race and ethnicity, and this data will provide a baseline for identifying diversity gaps and measuring improvements. Consider going further by baking these improvements into your employee performance process, such as objectives and key results (OKRs). Make everyone accountable from the start, not just HR.</p>
<p>These are just a few of the ways CTOs and technology leaders can contribute to ESG progress in their companies. The first step, however, is to recognize the many ways you as a technology leader can make an impact from day one.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eg8v87Jx4A"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-sosvs-climate-tech-100-tells-founders-about-investors-in-the-space/">What SOSV&#8217;s Climate Tech 100 tells founders about investors in the space</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What SOSV&#8217;s Climate Tech 100 tells founders about investors in the space&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-sosvs-climate-tech-100-tells-founders-about-investors-in-the-space/embed/#?secret=eg8v87Jx4A" data-secret="eg8v87Jx4A" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/tech-leaders-can-be-the-secret-weapon-for-supercharging-esg-goals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184454</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reese Witherspoon&#8217;s Hello Sunshine sold to new media firm from former Disney execs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/reese-witherspoons-hello-sunshine-sold-to-new-media-firm-from-former-disney-execs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/reese-witherspoons-hello-sunshine-sold-to-new-media-firm-from-former-disney-execs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 15:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackstone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hello sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Mayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reese witherspoon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Morning Show]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello Sunshine, Reese Witherspoon&#8217;s media company that has produced content for streaming services like Hulu, Apple and HBO, among others, has been sold to a yet-unnamed new media firm run by former Disney execs, Kevin Mayer and Tom Staggs, the company announced this morning. The Wall St. Journal first reported on the sale. Deal terms [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://hello-sunshine.com/">Hello Sunshine,</a> Reese Witherspoon&#8217;s media company that has produced content for streaming services like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/13/hulu-outbids-rivals-for-little-fires-everywhere-from-reese-witherspoon-and-kerry-washington/">Hulu</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/17/apple-greenlights-new-reese-witherspoon-backed-comedy-series-starring-kristen-wiig/">Apple</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Little_Lies_(TV_series)">HBO</a>, among others, has been sold to a yet-unnamed new media firm run by former Disney execs, Kevin Mayer and Tom Staggs, the company <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210802005519/en/Hello-Sunshine-Announces-Majority-Investment-from-Newly-Formed-Next-Generation-Media-Company-Backed-by-Kevin-Mayer-Tom-Staggs-and-Blackstone">announced</a> this morning.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/reese-witherspoons-hello-sunshine-to-be-sold-to-media-company-backed-by-blackstone-11627914600">The Wall St. Journal</a> first reported on the sale.</p>
<p>Deal terms were not officially disclosed, but reportedly, the sale values Hello Sunshine&#8217;s business at around $900 million, The WSJ says. The news outlet had previously <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/reese-witherspoons-media-company-hello-sunshine-is-exploring-a-sale-11625605587">reported</a> Hello Sunshine was exploring a sale after receiving interest from a number of suitors, including Apple.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Hello Sunshine was co-founded by Witherspoon and Strand Equity founder and managing partner Seth Rodsky in 2016, and is best known for producing series like HBO&#8217;s &#8220;Big Little Lies,&#8221; Hulu&#8217;s &#8220;Little Fires Everywhere,&#8221; and Apple&#8217;s &#8220;The Morning Show,&#8221; which feature Witherspoon in starring roles.</p>
<p>But the company has also invested in other film and media projects, ranging from <a href="https://deadline.com/2018/05/reese-witherspoon-hello-sunshine-meet-my-mom-facebook-watch-1202387374/">Facebook Watch series</a> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/10/reese-witherspoons-hello-sunshine-to-debut-an-exclusive-lineup-of-audible-originals/">collaborations</a> with Amazon&#8217;s Audible. It now has upcoming film and TV projects on the slate with Netflix, Amazon, ABC and Starz, and recently announced a Kids &amp; Animation division as well as the acquisition of Sara Rea&#8217;s SKR Production to expand into unscripted content.</p>
<p>In addition, the company operates an online and mobile book club app, <a href="https://reesesbookclub.com/">Reese&#8217;s Book Club</a>, now with 2.1 million followers. The club&#8217;s more popular picks are often turned into the shows and movies Hello Sunshine later produces.</p>
<p>Per Hello Sunshine&#8217;s announcement, the company will be the first acquisition by the new media venture run by Mayer and Staggs, which is backed by private equity firm Blackstone. The firm is spending more than $500 million in cash to purchase shares of Hello Sunshine from its investors, including AT&amp;T and Emerson Collective, The WSJ noted.</p>
<p>Following the deal&#8217;s closure, the senior management team will continue to run Hello Sunshine&#8217;s day-to-day operations. Witherspoon and Hello Sunshine Chief Executive Sarah Harden will join the board of new company and retain significant equity holders in the new business.</p>
<p>Hello Sunshine will become a cornerstone of the new media company&#8217;s strategy, which will involve being an &#8220;independent, creator-friendly home for cutting-edge, high-quality, category-defining brands and franchises,&#8221; it says.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today marks a tremendous moment for Hello Sunshine. I started this company to change the way all women are seen in media. Over the past few years, we have watched our mission thrive through books, TV, film and social platforms. Today, we’re taking a huge step forward by partnering with Blackstone, which will enable us to tell even more entertaining, impactful and illuminating stories about women’s lives globally. I couldn’t be more excited about what this means for our future,&#8221; said Witherspoon in a statement about the deal.</p>
<p>The deal arrives at a time when there&#8217;s an uptick in consolidation happening the media business, as companies adjust to the shift away from traditional TV and standard movie releases to the always-on world of streaming and cord cutting. For example, Amazon in May <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/amazon-is-buying-mgm-studios-for-8-45b/">announced</a> it would buy MGM Studios for $8.45 billion &#8212; a deal being <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ftc-amazon-mgm-investigation-195722033.html">investigated</a> by the FTC for potential antitrust issues. Meanwhile, WarnerMedia and Discovery around the same time <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ftc-amazon-mgm-investigation-195722033.html">announced</a> their plans to merge operations, in hopes of taking a bigger bite out of the streaming market. Now, Comcast and ViacomCBS are <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/20/comcast-and-viacomcbs-consider-partnership-to-bolster-streaming-tv.html">exploring</a> ways to work together, too.</p>
<p>But as traditional media companies begin to stream, like NBCU did with Peacock, for instance, they also<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/nielsen-says-the-office-was-the-most-popular-streaming-series-of-2020/"> pull back content</a> licensed to other streamers, like Netflix. That drives demand for new sources of independent programming, like what Hello Sunshine produces.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s value in this market comes from its pipeline of quality projects, many of which are pre-vetted by its book club members, who serve as a built-in audience and fan base for the later film or televised release. Plus, the projects it backs are also those that tell women&#8217;s stories &#8212; a historically neglected segment of the market, and one that Hello Sunshine&#8217;s success proves there&#8217;s pend-up demand for among viewers.</p>
<p>Blackstone&#8217;s investment in the new company is being made through its private equity business, which previously acquired a majority stake in dating app Bumble. Blackstone has made other entertainment industry investments, as well, including music rights organization <a href="https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/leading-music-rights-organization-sesac-to-be-acquired-by-blackstone/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/leading-music-rights-organization-sesac-to-be-acquired-by-blackstone/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628003833085000&amp;usg=AFQjCNErIc4waoXaiccK2104r0WGVnyo4A">SESAC</a>; a <a href="https://www.blackstone.com/insights/article/three-reasons-why-blackstone-is-investing-in-content-production/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.blackstone.com/insights/article/three-reasons-why-blackstone-is-investing-in-content-production/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628003833085000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG21UMrrYI7YW5kjfUzI8_DBAnwKQ">Hollywood</a> <a href="https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/hudson-pacific-properties-and-blackstone-to-develop-los-angeles-area-studio-facility/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/hudson-pacific-properties-and-blackstone-to-develop-los-angeles-area-studio-facility/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628003833085000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHNuwgeGBuP00VQq9jnvT8_m6M3iA">studio space</a> and Burbank office real estate portfolio; global theme park operator <a href="https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/kirkbi-blackstone-and-cppib-agree-terms-of-a-recommended-offer-for-merlin-entertainments-plc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/kirkbi-blackstone-and-cppib-agree-terms-of-a-recommended-offer-for-merlin-entertainments-plc/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628003833085000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGLjy4_9sXtGnPd0suRvSwgcLWmUg">Merlin Entertainments</a>; online genealogy platform <a href="https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/blackstone-completes-acquisition-of-ancestry-leading-online-family-history-business-for-4-7-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/blackstone-completes-acquisition-of-ancestry-leading-online-family-history-business-for-4-7-billion/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628003833085000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFxNwntZ46LSzIX_IsfGIX5QnxjYw">Ancestry.com</a>; online mobile ad platforms <a href="https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/blackstone-closes-acquisition-of-vungle-a-leading-mobile-performance-marketing-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/blackstone-closes-acquisition-of-vungle-a-leading-mobile-performance-marketing-platform/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628003833085000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHOgNKbAQfcHWNQwL5VI6oeTGnuaA">Vungle</a> and <a href="https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/blackstone-to-invest-in-liftoff-to-help-fuel-future-growth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.blackstone.com/press-releases/article/blackstone-to-invest-in-liftoff-to-help-fuel-future-growth/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628003833085000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG3-f3muMQ0ZXW27b0-N6Rk--GZaw">Liftoff</a>; and <a href="https://www.epidemicsound.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.epidemicsound.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628003833085000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGVh6hq2p1RX2fqX9AzAX0USibJbg">Epidemic Sound</a>, which delivers music to internet content creators.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/reese-witherspoons-hello-sunshine-sold-to-new-media-firm-from-former-disney-execs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184511</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Square is shelling out $29B to snag BNPL player Afterpay</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 15:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online purchases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With PayPal, Klarna, Afterpay, Affirm and a host of smaller BNPL providers proving that customers like fee-based installment loans for online purchases, Square had to join the fight or miss a trick]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Shares of Square are up this morning after the company announced its second-quarter earnings and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/">that it will buy Afterpay</a>, an Australian buy now, pay later (BNPL) player in a $29 billion deal. As TechCrunch reported this morning, Afterpay shareholders will receive 0.375 shares of Square in exchange for their existing equity.</p>
<p>Shares of Afterpay are sharply higher after the deal was announced thanks to its implied premium, while shares of Square are up 7% in early-morning trading.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Over the past year, we&#8217;ve written extensively about the BNPL market, usually from the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/as-bnpl-startups-raise-a-look-at-klarna-affirm-and-afterpay-earnings/">perspective of earnings from companies in the space</a>. Afterpay has been a key data source, along with the yet-private Klarna and U.S. public BNPL outfit Affirm. Recall that each company has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/as-buy-now-pay-later-startups-keep-raising-capital-a-dive-into-klarna-afterpay-and-affirms-earnings/">posted strong growth in recent periods</a>, with the United States arising as a prime competitive market.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995211 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Most recently, consumer hardware and services giant Apple is reportedly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/what-impact-will-apples-buy-now-pay-later-push-have-on-startups/">preparing a move into the BNPL space</a>. Our read at the time was that any such movement by Cupertino would impact mass-market BNPL players more than niche-focused companies. Apple has a fintech base and broad IRL payment acceptance, making it a potentially strong competitor for BNPL services aimed at consumers; BNPL services targeted at particular industries or niches would likely see less competition from Apple.</p>
<p>From that landscape, let&#8217;s explore the Square-Afterpay deal. We want to know what Afterpay brings to Square in terms of revenue, growth and reach. We also want to do some math on the price Square is willing to pay for the company &#8212; and what that might tell us about the value of BNPL and fintech revenues more broadly. Then we&#8217;ll eyeball the numbers and try to decide if Square is overpaying for Afterpay.</p>
<h2>What Afterpay brings to Square</h2>
<p>As with most major deals these days, Square and Afterpay released an <a href="http://s27.q4cdn.com/311240100/files/doc_financials/2021/q2/Square-Plans-to-Acquire-Afterpay-Transaction-Overview.pdf">investor presentation</a> detailing their argument in favor of their combination. Let&#8217;s dig through it.</p>
<p>Square is a two-part company. It has a large consumer business via Cash App, and it has a large business division that offers payments tech and other fintech services to corporate customers. Recall that Square is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/square-launches-business-bank-accounts/">also building out banking services</a> for its business customers and that Cash App also serves some banking and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/how-trading-apps-are-responding-to-the-gamestop-fustercluck/">investing functionality</a> for consumers.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184465</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hear Startup Alley companies pitch expert VC judges on the next episode of Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/hear-startup-alley-companies-pitch-expert-vc-judges-on-the-next-episode-of-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/hear-startup-alley-companies-pitch-expert-vc-judges-on-the-next-episode-of-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 15:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disrupt Startup Alley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edith Yeung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laela Sturdy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2181412</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We know how much you love a good startup pitch-off. Who doesn’t? It combines the thrill of live, high-stakes entertainment with learning about the hottest new thing. Plus, you get to hear feedback from some of the smartest folks in the industry, thus learning how to absolutely crush it at your next pitch meeting with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We know how much you love a good startup pitch-off. Who doesn’t? It combines the thrill of live, high-stakes entertainment with learning about the hottest new thing. Plus, you get to hear feedback from some of the smartest folks in the industry, thus learning how to absolutely crush it at your next pitch meeting with a VC.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">With all that in mind, we’re introducing a special summer edition of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">Extra Crunch Live</a> that’s all pitch-off, all the time.</p>
<p>On August 4, Extra Crunch Live will feature startups exhibiting in the Startup Alley at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=ecljuly2021suapost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=eclsuajuly&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> in September. Those startups will pitch their products/businesses to a pair of expert VC judges, who will then give their live feedback.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Extra Crunch Live is usually a combination of an interview with a founder/investor duo and an audience pitch-off. But as it’s summer, and Disrupt is right around the corner, we thought it would be fun to bring you even more pitches and even more feedback.</p>
<p>On August 4, our expert VC judges will be Edith Yeung from Race Capital and Laela Sturdy of CapitalG. <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-startup-alley-edition-w-edith-yeung-and-laela-sturdy?ref=8e6debd80dd4">Register here for free!</a></p>
<p>Edith Yeung started out as an investor at 500 Startups and is now a general partner at Race Capital. She&#8217;s an expert on both the China and Silicon Valley investment landscape and has made more than 50 investments, with a portfolio that includes 50 startups, including Lightyear/Stellar (valued $1.2 billion), Silk Labs (acquired by Apple), Chirp (acquired by Apple), Fleksy (acquired by Pinterest), Human (acquired by Mapbox), Solana, Oasis Labs, Nebulas, Hooked, DayDayCook, AISense and many more.</p>
<p>Laela Sturdy is a 10x unicorn operator-turned-investor whose investments are worth nearly $200 billion. She joined CapitalG, the investment arm of Alphabet, in 2013, and her portfolio includes Stripe, UiPath, Duolingo, Gusto, Webflow and Unqork, among many others.</p>
<p>As a special thank you, all attendees of this episode of Extra Crunch Live will be entered into a random drawing for a chance to win one of three free tickets to TechCrunch Disrupt 2021. Following the event, we’ll randomly select three winners and send details on how to redeem their passes. Do you need to submit any additional information to enter the drawing? Nope. All you need to do is register for Extra Crunch Live by clicking <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-startup-alley-edition-w-edith-yeung-and-laela-sturdy?ref=8e6debd80dd4">here</a> and attend the event on August 4.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/hear-startup-alley-companies-pitch-expert-vc-judges-on-the-next-episode-of-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2181412</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The tale of two edtech IPOs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/the-tale-of-two-edtech-ipos/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/the-tale-of-two-edtech-ipos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duolingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[powerschool]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183897</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. Last week, Natasha and Alex jumped on Twitter Spaces to discuss the tale of two edtech IPOs: Duolingo, the consumer language learning company, and PowerSchool, the enterprise K-12 software platform. It was a rare moment in the sun for the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/ff160dc5-e97a-4ecb-a4ff-296468849d31?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. Last week, <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> jumped on Twitter Spaces to discuss the tale of two edtech IPOs: Duolingo, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1/">the consumer language learning company</a>, and PowerSchool, the enterprise K-12 software platform. It was a rare moment in the sun for the recently revitalized sector, which saw two companies list on the stock market on the same dang day.</p>
<p>Special shout out to our producer <a href="https://twitter.com/CGates123">Chris Gates </a>for handling this impromptu live chat, tech difficulties and all, and bringing it to your ears on this lovely Monday. Don&#8217;t forget that Equity is largely on break this week!</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what we got into, featuring some edtech entrepreneurs nice enough to drop on by:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/as-china-shakes-up-regulations-tech-companies-suffer/">China&#8217;s edtech crackdown</a> and how it is impacting startups both internationally and domestically. The regulations, one of which will force for-profit tutoring companies to turn into nonprofits,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/edtechs-venture-backed-globalization-pauses-at-china/?tpcc=ECTW2020"> are also getting the cold shoulder from U.S. edtech VCs,</a> it seems.</li>
<li> As Lightspeed Ventures investor <a href="https://twitter.com/mercebent">Mercedes Bent </a>so aptly put it, the news is somewhat ironic: &#8220;[T]he U.S. edtech IPO market is on fire (after being dormant for so long) and the China edtech market is crumbling (after being on fire for so long).&#8221;</li>
<li>Evidence of that can be found in the Duolingo IPO pricing arc. The company first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/duolingos-ipo-could-cast-golden-halo-on-edtech-startups/">posted a strong estimate of its worth</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/duolingo-boosts-ipo-price-target-in-boon-to-edtech-startups/">raised its range</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/duolingos-ipo-pricing-is-great-news-for-edtech-startups/">priced <em>above </em>that raised interval</a>, and still managed to trade higher. The company is still up more than $30 from its IPO price.</li>
<li>PowerSchool was a bit different. It priced at $18 per share, the low end of its $18 to $20 range. The company is up from its IPO price, albeit a much more modest 2 or 3% in today&#8217;s early trading.</li>
</ul>
<p>In the second half of the show, we brought on the following host of edtech founders to share their hot takes about the current state of edtech:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/pacutler">Philip Cutler</a>, the founder and CEO of <a href="https://paper.co/">PAPER</a>, gave us an enterprise perspective. The startup recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/paper-series-c-ivp/">raised $100 million in a Series C round led by IVP.</a></li>
<li><a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://twitter.com/Taylor_Nieman">Taylor Nieman</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, the founder and CEO of </span><a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://t.co/5Eal21E4at?amp=1">Toucan</a>,<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> spoke language learning &#8212; and how she&#8217;s using Duolingo&#8217;s S-1 as a competitive advantage.</span></li>
<li><a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://twitter.com/AnadaLakra">Anada Lakra</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, the founder and CEO of </span><a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://t.co/nIj5Qn9B0O?amp=1">BoldVoice</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, a startup that wants to help non-native English speakers hone their accents. TechCrunch covered the company </span><a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/boldvoice-y-combinator-pre-seed/">here</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">.</span></li>
<li><a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yeva-hyusyan-5a16a220/?originalSubdomain=am">Yeva Hyusyan</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, the founder of </span><a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://www.sololearn.com/home">Sololearn</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, a Duolingo-like company that wants to teach coding instead of languages. The company </span><a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/sololearn-raises-24m-for-its-bite-sized-duolingo-like-mobile-first-coding-education-app/">recently raised $24 million</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Before we go, Equity is on a &#8220;break&#8221; this week, as we do some soul searching and refresh before our next run of shows. Obviously we still had to share this episode, and um, are recording another episode this week too, but you, my dear friend, will hear from us again next Monday.</p>
<p><em>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PDT, Wednesday, and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PDT, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ph4VeRJmWg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1/">The Duolingo EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Duolingo EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1/embed/#?secret=Ph4VeRJmWg" data-secret="Ph4VeRJmWg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/the-tale-of-two-edtech-ipos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183897</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zoom reaches $85M settlement in &#8216;Zoombombing&#8217; lawsuit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/zoom-reaches-85m-settlement-in-zoombombing-lawsuit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/zoom-reaches-85m-settlement-in-zoombombing-lawsuit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 13:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video conferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web conferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ZoomBombing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Zoom has agreed to pay $85 million to settle a lawsuit that accused the video conferencing giant of violating users&#8217; privacy by sharing their data with third parties without permission and enabling &#8220;Zoombombing&#8221; incidents. Zoombombing, a term coined by TechCrunch last year as its usage exploded because of the pandemic, describes unapproved attendees entering and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/zoom/">Zoom</a> has agreed to pay $85 million to settle a lawsuit that accused the video conferencing giant of violating users&#8217; privacy by sharing their data with third parties without permission and enabling &#8220;Zoombombing&#8221; incidents.</p>
<p>Zoombombing, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/03/zoom-waiting-rooms-default/">a term coined by TechCrunch</a> last year as its usage exploded because of the pandemic, describes unapproved attendees entering and disrupting Zoom calls by sharing offensive imagery, using backgrounds to spread hateful messages or spouting slurs and profanities.</p>
<p>The lawsuit, filed in March 2020 in the U.S. District Court in the Northern District of California, also accused the firm of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/31/zoom-at-your-own-risk/">sharing personal user data</a> with third parties, including Facebook, Google and LinkedIn.</p>
<p>In addition to agreeing to an $85 million settlement, which could see customers receive a refund of either 15% of their subscription of $25 if the lawsuit achieves class-action status, Zoom has said it will take additional steps to prevent intruders from gatecrashing meetings. This will include alerting users when meeting hosts or other participants use third-party apps in meetings and offering specialized training to employees on privacy and data handling.</p>
<p>&#8220;The privacy and security of our users are top priorities for Zoom, and we take seriously the trust our users place in us,&#8221; Zoom said in a statement. “We are proud of the advancements we have made to our platform, and look forward to continuing to innovate with privacy and security at the forefront.”</p>
<p>The settlement requires approval from U.S. District Judge Lucy Koh in San Jose, California, to be finalized.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BjKemODFqL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/zoombombing/">Beware of &#8216;ZoomBombing&#8217;: screensharing filth to video calls</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Beware of &#8216;ZoomBombing&#8217;: screensharing filth to video calls&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/zoombombing/embed/#?secret=BjKemODFqL" data-secret="BjKemODFqL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CxHWSMoFyQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/20/zoom-ux-teardown-five-fails-and-how-to-fix-them/">Zoom UX teardown: 5 fails and how to fix them</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zoom UX teardown: 5 fails and how to fix them&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/20/zoom-ux-teardown-five-fails-and-how-to-fix-them/embed/#?secret=CxHWSMoFyQ" data-secret="CxHWSMoFyQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/zoom-reaches-85m-settlement-in-zoombombing-lawsuit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184466</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yaydoo secures $20M, aims to simplify B2B collections, payments</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/yaydoo-secures-20m-aims-to-simplify-b2b-collections-payments/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/yaydoo-secures-20m-aims-to-simplify-b2b-collections-payments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accounts payable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Base10 Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leap Global Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mexico city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monashees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sergio Almaguer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Latin America Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yaydoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183836</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s no secret that the technology for easy business-to-business payments has not yet caught up to its peer-to-peer counterparts, but Yaydoo thinks it has the answer.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s no secret that the technology for easy business-to-business payments has not yet caught up to its peer-to-peer counterparts, but <a href="https://kcpr.mxfig.com/5c538c40d7ccca0f92010099/l/lBE7t0JG2VGVrQi3S?messageId=!!!MESSAGE_ID!!!&amp;rn=!!!RECIPIENT_NAME_ENC!!!&amp;re=!!!EMAIL_ADDR_ENC!!!&amp;sc=!!!IS_SENDER_COPY!!!">Yaydoo</a> thinks it has the answer.</p>
<p>The Mexico City-based B2B software and payments company provides three products, <a href="https://kcpr.mxfig.com/5c538c40d7ccca0f92010099/l/FOHC2mS4qiu64agN6?messageId=!!!MESSAGE_ID!!!&amp;rn=!!!RECIPIENT_NAME_ENC!!!&amp;re=!!!EMAIL_ADDR_ENC!!!&amp;sc=!!!IS_SENDER_COPY!!!">VendorPlace</a><a href="https://kcpr.mxfig.com/5c538c40d7ccca0f92010099/l/mlJV8aSj6821DRyzE?messageId=!!!MESSAGE_ID!!!&amp;rn=!!!RECIPIENT_NAME_ENC!!!&amp;re=!!!EMAIL_ADDR_ENC!!!&amp;sc=!!!IS_SENDER_COPY!!!">,</a> P-Card and <a href="https://kcpr.mxfig.com/5c538c40d7ccca0f92010099/l/GNmnVO8Ng5zqvxsmM?messageId=!!!MESSAGE_ID!!!&amp;rn=!!!RECIPIENT_NAME_ENC!!!&amp;re=!!!EMAIL_ADDR_ENC!!!&amp;sc=!!!IS_SENDER_COPY!!!">PorCobrar</a>, for managing cash flow, optimizing access to smart liquidity, and connecting small, midsize and large businesses to an ecosystem of digital tools.</p>
<p>Sergio Almaguer, Guillermo Treviño and Roberto Flores founded Yaydoo — the name combines “yay” and “do” to show the happiness of doing something — in 2017. Today, the company announced the close of a $20.4 million Series A round co-led by Base10 Partners and monashees.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Joining them in the round were SoftBank’s Latin America Fund and Leap Global Partners. In total, Yaydoo has raised $21.5 million, Almaguer told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Prior to starting the company, Almaguer was working at another company in Mexico doing point-of-sale. His large enterprise customers wanted automation for their payments, but he noticed that the same tools were too expensive for small businesses.</p>
<p>The co-founders started Yaydoo to provide procurement, accounts payable and accounts receivables, but in a simpler format so that the collection and payment of B2B transactions was affordable for small businesses.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2183840" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183840" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2183840" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Group-2083.png" alt="" width="1024" height="893" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Group-2083.png 3655w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Group-2083.png?resize=150,131 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Group-2083.png?resize=300,262 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Group-2083.png?resize=768,670 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Group-2083.png?resize=680,593 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Group-2083.png?resize=1536,1340 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Group-2083.png?resize=2048,1786 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Group-2083.png?resize=50,44 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183840" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Yaydoo</p></div></p>
<p>The idea is taking off, and vendors are adding their own customers so that they are all part of the network to better link invoices to purchase orders and then connect to accounts payable, Almaguer said. Yaydoo estimates that the automation workflows reduced 80% of time wasted paying vendors, on average.</p>
<p>Yaydoo is joining a sector of fintech that is heating up — the <a href="https://www.pymnts.com/earnings/2019/mastercard-contactless-b2b-cross-border-growth/">global B2B payments market is valued at $120 trillion annually</a>. Last week, B2B payments platform Nium announced a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/nium-crosses-1b-valuation-with-200m-riverwood-capital-led-round/">$200 million in Series D</a> funding on a $1 billion valuation. Others attracting funding recently include Paystand, which raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/paystand-banks-50m-to-make-b2b-payments-cashless-and-with-no-fees/">$50 million in Series C</a> funding to make B2B payments cashless, while Dwolla <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/dwolla-raises-21m-to-bring-more-customizable-payment-and-money-transfer-options-to-fintechs-and-brands/">raised $21 million</a> for its API that allows companies to build and facilitate fast payments.</p>
<p>The new funding will enable the company to attract new hires in Mexico and when the company expands into other Latin American countries. Yaydoo is also looking at future opportunities for its working capital business, like understanding how many invoices customers are setting, the access to actual payments, and how money flows out and in so that it can provide insights on working capital funding gaps. The company will also invest in product development.</p>
<p>The company has grown to over 800 customers, up from 200 in the first quarter of 2020. Its headcount also grew to 100 from 30 during the same time. In the last 12 months, over 70,000 companies have transacted on the Yaydoo network, and total payment volume grew to hundreds of millions of dollars.</p>
<p>Yaydoo is a SaaS subscription model, but the new funding will also enable the company to create a pool of potential customers with a “freemium” offering with the goal of converting those customers into the subscription model as they grow, Almaguer said.</p>
<p>Rexhi Dollaku, partner at Base10 Partners, said the firm saw the way B2B payments were becoming modernized and “was impressed” by the Yaydoo team and how it built a complicated infrastructure, but made it easy to use.</p>
<p>He believes Latin America is 10 years behind in terms of B2B payments but will catch up sooner than later because of the digital transformation going on in the region.</p>
<p>“We are starting to see early signs of the network being built out of the payments product, and that is a good indication,” Dollaku said. “With the funding, Yaydoo will be also able to provide more financial services options for businesses to address a working fund gap.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9CXm568oAY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/all-b2b-startups-are-in-the-payments-business/">All B2B startups are in the payments business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;All B2B startups are in the payments business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/all-b2b-startups-are-in-the-payments-business/embed/#?secret=9CXm568oAY" data-secret="9CXm568oAY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/yaydoo-secures-20m-aims-to-simplify-b2b-collections-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183836</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Newtopia closes first fund of $50M to invest in LatAm startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/newtopia-closes-first-fund-of-50m-to-invest-in-latam-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/newtopia-closes-first-fund-of-50m-to-invest-in-latam-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argentina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mariano Mayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Newtopia VC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patricio Jutard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early-stage venture capital fund Newtopia VC launched Monday with $50 million to invest in tech startups based in Latin America.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Early-stage venture capital fund <a href="https://newtopia.vc/">Newtopia VC</a> launched Monday with $50 million to invest in tech startups based in Latin America.</p>
<p>The fund will invest between $250,000 and $1 million in startups at the seed stage to help them achieve the milestones needed on the path to raising a Series A.</p>
<p>Newtopia is led by five major players in the regional entrepreneurial ecosystem:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Patricio Jutard, co-founder of MURAL;</li>
<li aria-level="1">Mariano Mayer, former national secretary for entrepreneurs and SMEs in Argentina and founder of Marea Venture Partners;</li>
<li aria-level="1">Sacha Spitz, co-founder and partner of Yavu Ventures and former director at the Universidad de San Andrés incubation program;</li>
<li aria-level="1">Jorge Aguado, former national science, technology and innovation secretary in Argentina;</li>
<li aria-level="1">Juan Pablo Lafosse, founder and former CEO of Almundo.</li>
</ul>
<p>The group has already invested in startups in Mexico, Brazil and Argentina, including Aleph (B2B SaaS for e-commerce), Apperto (social commerce), Choiz (healthtech), Exactly (DeFi), Elevva (e-commerce brands), Inipay (fintech), Leef (sustainability), Wibson (e-privacy) and Yerbo (wellness).</p>
<p>Mayer told TechCrunch that he sees a great moment happening in Latin America around global venture capital firms &#8212; like Sequoia Capital, Andreessen Horowitz and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/30/softbank-makes-a-huge-bet-on-latin-america/">SoftBank &#8212;</a>making bets in the region, especially targeting later-stage investments. There are home-grown venture capital firms doing well, too, citing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/the-latam-funding-boom-continues-as-kaszek-raises-1b-across-a-duo-of-funds/">Kaszek’s $1 billion funds</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="y4ENbDZboU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/">Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/embed/#?secret=y4ENbDZboU" data-secret="y4ENbDZboU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“However, we see a gap in investments in seed and road to Series A,” he added. “We aim to help entrepreneurs in those stages. Newtopia started with conversations during the pandemic, and now we see a big momentum for transformation of traditional sectors and the talent to make businesses out of these opportunities.”</p>
<p>Newtopia is offering both investment and a hands-on mentorship model to guide startups through the initial stages so they can grow regionally or globally. The fund has already amassed a community of more than 70 founders to invest, advise and be venture partners to the portfolio companies.</p>
<p>The Newtopia 10-Week Program works with companies to find product-market fit, achieve initial goals and set a foundation for further growth. The firm opened the call for applicants and will select 10 startups to receive a spot in the program and $100,000 each.</p>
<p>By taking a lead in early-stage investing, it will feed the rest of the venture capital firms that are doing later-stage investing, Mayer said.</p>
<p>He sees investments growing in Latin America every year, estimating there was a record $4 billion spread across the region, turning some companies into unicorns, including Jutard’s Mural, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/mural-raises-50m-series-c-after-tripling-its-arr-in-the-last-year/">raised $50 million</a> in July. That has more than validated that there will be more money in coming years, Mayer added.</p>
<p>Jutard said the fund’s founders were all investing or mentoring companies on their own, but the new funding will enable them to structure that assistance to help hundreds of startups rather than a handful.</p>
<p>“Early-stage companies go through an emotional rollercoaster where they feel alone, encounter times when it is hard to sell their product or recruit, so we are focused on building a community of support,” Jutard added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0Jkh0Xmsam"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/why-is-andreessen-horowitz-and-everyone-else-investing-in-latin-america-now/">Why is Andreessen Horowitz (and everyone else) investing in Latin America now?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why is Andreessen Horowitz (and everyone else) investing in Latin America now?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/why-is-andreessen-horowitz-and-everyone-else-investing-in-latin-america-now/embed/#?secret=0Jkh0Xmsam" data-secret="0Jkh0Xmsam" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/newtopia-closes-first-fund-of-50m-to-invest-in-latam-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183750</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finite State lands $30M Series B to help uncover security flaws in device firmware</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/finite-state-lands-30m-series-b-to-help-uncover-security-flaws-in-device-firmware/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/finite-state-lands-30m-series-b-to-help-uncover-security-flaws-in-device-firmware/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 13:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battelle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Columbus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energize Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finite State]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firmware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Huawei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184004</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Columbus, Ohio-based Finite State, a startup that provides supply chain security for connected devices and critical infrastructure, has raised $30 million in Series B funding.  The funding lands amid increased focus on the less-secure elements in an organizations’ supply chain, such as Internet of Things devices and embedded systems. The problem, Finite State says, is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Columbus, Ohio-based Finite State, a startup that provides supply chain security for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/connected-devices/">connected devices</a> and critical infrastructure, has raised $30 million in Series B funding.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The funding lands amid increased focus on the less-secure elements in an organizations’ supply chain, such as Internet of Things devices and embedded systems. The problem, Finite State says, is largely fueled by device firmware, the foundational software that often includes components sourced from third-party vendors or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/12/how-open-source-software-took-over-the-world/">open-source</a> software. This means if a security flaw is baked into the finished product, it’s often without the device manufacturers&#8217; knowledge.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>“Cyberattackers see firmware as a weak link to gain unauthorized access to critical systems and infrastructure,” Matt Wyckhouse, CEO of Finite State, tells TechCrunch. “The number of known cyberattacks targeting firmware has quintupled in just the last four years.”</p>
<p>The Finite State platform brings visibility to the supply chains that create connected devices and embedded systems. After unpacking and analyzing every file and configuration in a firmware build, the platform generates a complete bill of materials for software components, identifies known and possible zero-day vulnerabilities, shows a contextual risk score and provides actionable insights that product teams can use to secure their software.</p>
<p>“By looking at every piece of their supply chain and every detail of their firmware — something no other product on the market offers — we enable manufacturers to ship more secure products so that users can trust their connected devices more,” Wyckhouse says.</p>
<p>The company’s latest funding round was led by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/energize-ventures/">Energize Ventures</a>, with participation from Schneider Electric Ventures and Merlin Ventures, and comes a year after Finite State raised a $12.5 million Series A round. It brings the total amount of funds raised by the firm to just shy of $50 million.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The startup says it plans to use the funds to scale to meet the demands of the market. It plans to increase its headcount too; Finite State currently has 50 employees, a figure that’s expected to grow to more than 80 by the end of 2021. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>“We also want to use this fundraising round to help us get out the message: Firmware isn’t safe unless it’s safe by design,&#8221; Wyckhouse added. &#8220;It’s not enough to analyze the code your engineers built when other parts of your supply chain could expose you to major security issues.”</p>
<p>Finite State was founded in 2017 by Matt Wyckhouse, founder and former CTO of Battelle’s Cyber Business Unit. The company showcased its capabilities in June 2019, when its widely cited Huawei Supply Chain Assessment revealed numerous backdoors and major security vulnerabilities in the Chinese technology company’s networking devices that could be used in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/5g/">5G</a> networks.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Read more:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/thistle-technology-seed-security-iot/">Window Snyder’s new startup Thistle Technologies raises $2.5M seed to secure IoT devices</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/microsoft-pluton-security-chip-intel-amd-qualcomm/">Microsoft reveals Pluton, a custom security chip built into Intel, AMD and Qualcomm processors</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/alaris-infusion-pump-security-flaws/">A widely used infusion pump can be remotely hijacked, say researchers</a></li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ky7hYxoXcg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/">To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/embed/#?secret=Ky7hYxoXcg" data-secret="Ky7hYxoXcg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/finite-state-lands-30m-series-b-to-help-uncover-security-flaws-in-device-firmware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184004</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How one founder turned her extensive retail experience into an entirely new kind of shopping</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/how-one-founder-turned-her-extensive-retail-experience-into-an-entirely-new-kind-of-shopping/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/how-one-founder-turned-her-extensive-retail-experience-into-an-entirely-new-kind-of-shopping/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 12:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julie Bornstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Yes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Yes founder and CEO Julie Bornstein helped some of the world&#8217;s biggest and best-loved brands develop industry-leading e-commerce operations, and also served as COO at Stitch Fix, arguable one of the top success stories of digital-first fashion. The Yes is her first foray into entrepreneurship, however, and we got the chance to talk to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Yes founder and CEO Julie Bornstein helped some of the world&#8217;s biggest and best-loved brands develop industry-leading e-commerce operations, and also served as COO at Stitch Fix, arguable one of the top success stories of digital-first fashion. The Yes is her first foray into entrepreneurship, however, and we got the chance to talk to Julie all about her experience as a founder.</p>
<p>On this week&#8217;s episode of Found, our weekly interview podcast, we hear from Julie all about how she identified the gap The Yes was created to address, and how she changed some of the longtime fundamentals about how fashion brands sell their wares and work with customer sales channels. Julie also tells us about why The Yes knew it needed a larger-than-average seed to accomplish its goals, and how she went out and got it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NbsmkUGvRe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/former-stitch-fix-coo-julie-bornstein-just-took-the-wraps-off-her-app-only-e-commerce-startup-the-yes/">Former Stitch Fix COO Julie Bornstein just took the wraps off her app-only e-commerce startup, The Yes</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Former Stitch Fix COO Julie Bornstein just took the wraps off her app-only e-commerce startup, The Yes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/former-stitch-fix-coo-julie-bornstein-just-took-the-wraps-off-her-app-only-e-commerce-startup-the-yes/embed/#?secret=NbsmkUGvRe" data-secret="NbsmkUGvRe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>We loved our time chatting with Julie, and we hope you love yours listening to the episode. And of course, we’d love if you can subscribe to <a href="http://apple.co/found">Found in Apple Podcasts</a>, on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0Dqmcq2aDrZkS9v1fITOKV?si=Hfp6dAwAQKyenJnprGxnqg">Spotify</a>, on <a href="https://podcasts.google.com/feed/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5zaW1wbGVjYXN0LmNvbS9lMmI0QU5vYg?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwiYisj3nZfwAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQCQ">Google Podcasts</a> or in <a href="https://pod.link/found">your podcast app of choice</a>. Please leave us a review and let us know what you think, or send us direct feedback either on <a href="https://twitter.com/found">Twitter </a>or via email at <a href="mailto:found@techcrunch.com">found@techcrunch.com</a>, or leave us a voicemail at (510) 936-1618. And please join us again next week for our next featured founder.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/92e4bd48-151b-43ad-8d17-44139c854434?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/how-one-founder-turned-her-extensive-retail-experience-into-an-entirely-new-kind-of-shopping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184464</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Element Ventures pulls in $130M to double-down on the fintech enterprise trend</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/element-ventures-pulls-in-130m-to-double-down-on-the-fintech-enterprise-trend/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/element-ventures-pulls-in-130m-to-double-down-on-the-fintech-enterprise-trend/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 12:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asset Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Element Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hsbc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the rise of Open Banking, PSD2 Regulation, insurtech and the whole, general fintech boom, tech investors have realized there is an increasing place for dedicated funds which double down on this ongoing movement. When you look at the rise of banking-as-a-service offerings, payments platforms, insurtech, asset management and infrastructure providers, you realize there is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With the rise of Open Banking, PSD2 Regulation, insurtech and the whole, general fintech boom, tech investors have realized there is an increasing place for dedicated funds which double down on this ongoing movement. When you look at the rise of banking-as-a-service offerings, payments platforms, insurtech, asset management and infrastructure providers, you realize there is a pretty huge revolution going on.</p>
<p>European fintech companies have raised $12.3 billion in 2021 according to Dealroom, but the market is still wide open for a great deal more funding for B2B fintech startups.</p>
<p>So it’s no surprise that B2B fintech-focused <a href="https://elementventures.vc/">Element Ventures</a> has announced a $130 million fund to double down on this new fintech enterprise trend.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded by financial services veterans Stephen Gibson and Michael McFadgen, and joined by Spencer Lake (HSBC&#8217;s former vice chairman of Global Banking and Markets), Element is backed by finance-oriented LPs and some 30 founders and executives from the sector.</p>
<p>Element says it will focus on what it calls a “high conviction investment strategy,” which will mean investing in only around a handful of companies a year (15 for the fund in total) but, it says, providing a &#8220;high level of support&#8221; to its portfolio.</p>
<p>So far it has backed B2B fintech firms across the U.K. and Europe, including Hepster (total raised $10 million), the embedded insurance platform out of Germany <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/german-insuretech-platform-hepster-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-element-ventures/">which I recently reported on</a>; Billhop (total raised $6.7 million), the B2B payment network out of Sweden; Coincover (total raised $11.6 million), a cryptocurrency recovery service out of the U.K.; and Minna (total raised $25 million), the subscription management platform out of Sweden.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OB4Mh4MpqB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/german-insuretech-platform-hepster-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-element-ventures/">German insurtech platform Hepster raises $10M Series A led by Element Ventures</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;German insurtech platform Hepster raises $10M Series A led by Element Ventures&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/german-insuretech-platform-hepster-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-element-ventures/embed/#?secret=OB4Mh4MpqB" data-secret="OB4Mh4MpqB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Speaking to me over a call, McFadgen, partner at Element Ventures, said: “Stephen and I have been investing in B2B fintech together for quite a long time. In 2018 we had the opportunity to start element and Spencer came on board in 2019. So Element as an independent venture firm is really a continuation of a strategy we&#8217;ve been involved in for a long time.”</p>
<p>Gibson added: “We are quite convinced by the European movement and the breakthrough these fintech and insurtech firms in Europe are having. Insurance has been a desert for innovation and that is changing. And you can see that we’re sort of trying to build a network around companies that have those breakthrough moments and provide not just capital but all the other things we think are part of the story. Building the company from A to C and D is the area that we try and roll our sleeves up and help these firms.”</p>
<p>Element says it also will be investing in the U.S. and Asia.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vJ25a3xEZh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/as-eu-venture-capital-soars-will-the-region-hold-onto-future-ipos/">As EU venture capital soars, will the region hold onto future IPOs?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As EU venture capital soars, will the region hold onto future IPOs?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/as-eu-venture-capital-soars-will-the-region-hold-onto-future-ipos/embed/#?secret=vJ25a3xEZh" data-secret="vJ25a3xEZh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/element-ventures-pulls-in-130m-to-double-down-on-the-fintech-enterprise-trend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184463</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BoxGroup closes on $255M across two funds to back startups at their earliest stages</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/boxgroup-closes-on-255m-across-two-funds/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/boxgroup-closes-on-255m-across-two-funds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 12:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boxgroup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[classpass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Tisch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flatiron Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matterport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oscar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PillPack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plaid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scopely]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[titan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trello]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VC firm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warby Parker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BoxGroup has quietly, yet diligently, been funding companies at the early stage for over a decade. The 11-year-old firm in fact was the first investor in Plaid, a fintech company that nearly got sold to Visa last year for billions of dollars. It has seen a number of impressive exits over the years, proving an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://boxgroup.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">BoxGroup</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has quietly, yet diligently, been funding companies at the early stage for over a decade. The 11-year-old firm in fact was the first investor in Plaid, a fintech company that nearly got sold to Visa last year for billions of dollars.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It has seen a number of impressive exits over the years, proving an eye that can detect winners before the winners themselves may even realize it. In fact, it’s that early faith in companies that partner David Tisch believes has been key to BoxGroup’s success.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“If you’re starting a company and you’re going to raise money, that first yes is the hardest. And it’s the one that</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> gives you the confidence, the excitement &#8212; to know that there&#8217;s somebody out there that&#8217;s going to believe in this and give you money for it,” Tisch told TechCrunch. “We really do try to pride ourselves on being that first yes on a regular basis. So the earlier we meet companies, the better.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, BoxGroup is announcing it has beefed up its war chest so that it can be that “first yes” to more companies with the closure of two new funds </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">totaling $255 million of capital. BoxGroup Five is the firm’s fifth early-stage fund, and is aimed at investing in emerging tech companies at the pre-seed and seed stages. BoxGroup Strive is its second opportunity fund that will back companies in their subsequent follow-on rounds. Each fund amounts to $127.5 million. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the years, BoxGroup has </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">made more than 300 investments, including having invested in the earliest rounds of Ro, Plaid, Airtable, Workrise, Scopely, Bowery Farms, Ramp, Titan, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Warby Parker, ClassPass, Guideline and Glossier. It has had a number of impressive exits in Flatiron Health, PillPack, Matterport, Oscar, Mirror, Bark, Bread and Trello. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zmMhkAHnhO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/titan-valued-at-450m-as-a16z-leads-58m-series-b/">Titan, a platform aimed at the &#8216;everyday investor,&#8217; valued at $450M as a16z leads $58M Series B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Titan, a platform aimed at the &#8216;everyday investor,&#8217; valued at $450M as a16z leads $58M Series B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/titan-valued-at-450m-as-a16z-leads-58m-series-b/embed/#?secret=zmMhkAHnhO" data-secret="zmMhkAHnhO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides being the first firm to write Plaid a check, BoxGroup was also the first investor in PillPack, which ended up </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/28/amazon-buys-pillpack-an-online-pharmacy-that-was-rumored-to-be-talking-to-walmart/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">selling to Amazon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for just under $1 billion in 2018.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BoxGroup Five will</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> invest in about 40 to 50 new companies a year with investments ranging from $250,000 to $1 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We want to be the second or third biggest check in a round,” Tisch said.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184319" style="width: 403px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184319" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2184319 " src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/571F37E2-FEFA-47DD-A65E-C32567B458A8EMC_8211.jpeg?w=293" alt="" width="393" height="402" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/571F37E2-FEFA-47DD-A65E-C32567B458A8EMC_8211.jpeg 1999w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/571F37E2-FEFA-47DD-A65E-C32567B458A8EMC_8211.jpeg?resize=146,150 146w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/571F37E2-FEFA-47DD-A65E-C32567B458A8EMC_8211.jpeg?resize=293,300 293w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/571F37E2-FEFA-47DD-A65E-C32567B458A8EMC_8211.jpeg?resize=768,787 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/571F37E2-FEFA-47DD-A65E-C32567B458A8EMC_8211.jpeg?resize=664,680 664w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/571F37E2-FEFA-47DD-A65E-C32567B458A8EMC_8211.jpeg?resize=1499,1536 1499w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/571F37E2-FEFA-47DD-A65E-C32567B458A8EMC_8211.jpeg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/571F37E2-FEFA-47DD-A65E-C32567B458A8EMC_8211.jpeg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/571F37E2-FEFA-47DD-A65E-C32567B458A8EMC_8211.jpeg?resize=64,64 64w" sizes="(max-width: 393px) 100vw, 393px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184319" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> BoxGroup; Adam Rothenberg (left), Nimi Katragadda (bottom), Greg Rosen (top), David Tisch (right)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The opportunity fund occasionally makes later-stage investments in new companies, but mostly just continues to support companies it invested in at an earlier stage. For example, BoxGroup first invested in <a href="https://www.id.me/">id.me</a> in 2010.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The company is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">sort of an eleven-year overnight success that we&#8217;ve been backing for over a decade now,” Tisch said. “It’s an example of us just continuing to support companies through their life cycle.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BoxGroup also pre-seeded digital healthcare startup Ro, but also funded every round it has raised since, including its most recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/22/ro-raises-500m-to-grow-its-remote-and-in-home-primary-care-platform/">$500 million funding at a $5 billion valuation</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tisch describes the BoxGroup six-person team as “generalists” in terms of the spaces it invests in, with a portfolio consisting of startups in the consumer, enterprise, fintech, healthcare, marketplace, synthetic biology and climate sectors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interestingly, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/boxgroup-raises-its-first-externally-backed-fund-to-invest-in-seed-stage-startups/">BoxGroup’s last fund closures</a> &#8212; which totaled $165 million &#8212; marked the first time the firm had accepted outside capital in nine years. Prior to that point, it had been funded with only personal capital. Its LPs are a mixed group of endowments, foundations and family offices.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For BoxGroup, building authentic relationships with founders is at the root of what the firm does, says p</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">artner Nimi Katragadda. That includes taking bets on founders, sometimes more than once, even if one of their companies didn’t work out. It means backing just ideas in some cases, and people.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This cannot be transactional, it has to be personal,” she said. “We want to go on a journey with someone for a decade as they build their business&#8230;. We&#8217;re comfortable with what <em>early</em> means, including a lot of assumptions, more vision t</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">han traction, and raw product.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Partner Adam Rothenberg agrees, saying: &#8220;Our goal is to be the friend in the room. We believe in honesty, tough love and transparency in building relationships with founders. We focus on the &#8220;how&#8221; more than the &#8220;what&#8221; — how a founder thinks, how they will build product and how they think about attracting talent.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With offices in San Francisco and New York, the firm will likely be growing in the near future as BoxGroup is looking to add on some “first-line investors,” Tisch said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Recently, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Greg Rosen was named a partner at the firm. Rosen originally joined BoxGroup in 2015, where he spent three years before leaving to join Benchmark. He re-joined BoxGroup in early 2020 and joins the firm&#8217;s three other partners: Tisch, Rothenberg and Katragadda. </span></p>
<p>While the world of venture is crazy-hot right now, Tisch said the firm keeps itself grounded with a wisdom that can only be gained with experience and in time.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is seemingly infinite capital waiting to be deployed,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Without calling the cycle, we know that over time markets go up and down&#8230;No matter where we are in a given cycle, smart and determined minds will come together to build important technology companies. Our job is to make sure we are meeting those founders and choosing wisely about which ones to partner with for 10+ year journeys.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Q6Gj729n3w"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/boxgroup-raises-its-first-externally-backed-fund-to-invest-in-seed-stage-startups/">BoxGroup raises its first externally backed fund to invest in seed-stage startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BoxGroup raises its first externally backed fund to invest in seed-stage startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/boxgroup-raises-its-first-externally-backed-fund-to-invest-in-seed-stage-startups/embed/#?secret=Q6Gj729n3w" data-secret="Q6Gj729n3w" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/boxgroup-closes-on-255m-across-two-funds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184306</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
