<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 14:01:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Utopia Labs is building an operating system for DAOs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/utopia-labs-is-building-an-operating-system-for-daos/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/utopia-labs-is-building-an-operating-system-for-daos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Panzarino]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distributed computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindred Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[major]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The DAO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Decentralized Autonomous Organizations, or DAOs, are all the rage at the moment. We’re seeing explosive growth in this sector as people experiment with building companies on top of tokens and smart contracts. And where new organization types bloom, so does the need for infrastructure. Utopia Labs is a team of 4 founders who met on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Decentralized Autonomous Organizations, or DAOs, are all the rage at the moment. We’re seeing explosive growth in this sector as people experiment with building companies on top of tokens and smart contracts. And where new organization types bloom, so does the need for infrastructure.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Utopia Labs is a team of 4 founders who met on Discord and Twitter over the past few months &#8212; a story that is getting increasingly familiar in the crypto-driven web3 space where everything is moving incredibly fast at the moment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/0xkaito">Kaito Cunningham</a> recently worked at crypto firm M31 and is in the On Deck Catalyst program. Utopia’s co-founders <a href="https://twitter.com/pryceandstuff">Pryce Adabe Yebesi</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/alexanderwu2000">Alexander Wu</a> and Jason Chong, also have held a scattering of tech builder background gigs from Facebook internships to LunchClub to Microsoft. The collective interest in DAOs, though, was what brought them together to begin chatting and eventually building for the space. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re not familiar with the DAO explosion happening, what we’re seeing is communities come together around a thesis that in the past may have required an LLC or C-corp structure in order to execute instead turning to blockchain solutions. Basically, company structure governed by a smart contract instead of legacy legal structures. Some current estimates put the value governed by DAO </span><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2021/08/03/biggest-daos-now-hold-6b-worth-of-digital-assets-consensys/#:~:text=The%2020%20largest%20decentralized%20autonomous,ConsenSys%2C%20an%20Ethereum%20software%20company."><span style="font-weight: 400;">treasuries at over $6B</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, up from $1B earlier this year. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you plot the curve, you’ll see the potential for growth is pretty enormous. And with the vast majority of DAOs operating across international boundaries on a global scale, there is a big need for infrastructure build out that takes over where the contract ends, nemly in areas like payroll, expenses, token distribution and HR management. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Utopia Labs is building out a stack of infrastructure tools for DAOs and they’re starting with the payments bit. They’ve raised $1.5M from a group of investors to begin hiring a </span><a href="https://utopia-labs.notion.site/47eac0e68b9a461c8daf473d0f61ca06#8839ae25306b473ea0f1bdcaf61e4d6a"><span style="font-weight: 400;">full stack engineer and front-end engineer</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The round was led by Kindred Ventures who has invested in other bleeding edge crypto </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/crypto-driven-marketplace-zora-raises-2m-to-build-a-sustainable-creator-economy/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">platforms like Zora</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and Bitski. Other investors participating include Syndica DAO, 4th Revolution Capital and angels like Trevor McFedries at Brud, Alex Zhang at Friends With Benefits (another major DAO), Tyson Battistella from Zora, Anirudh Pai at On Deck, Colin Goltra at Binance, Gabby Dizon from YGG, Jason Choi from Spartan Fund, Jeff Weinstein from Stripe and several others.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If all of this sounds incredibly bleeding edge, it is. The team literally founded the company earlier in September &#8212; yes, the month that we are at the end of currently. They saw the opportunity to build out in this space that has energized the web3 space and dove in. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many DAOs pay members in their own tokens, increasing ownership stakes to provide members with an opportunity for greater rewards down the line or immediate liquidity. Utopia is building right on top of Gnosis SAFE, the financial core of most DAOs. The V1 product is focused on member payments and invoice workflows. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The vast majority of DAOs are operating token distribution and payments based on raw dumps of data. As the saying goes, where you see a CSV, there’s a business opportunity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The team says they’ve build invoices and reimbursements workflows so that DAOs can receive, pay out and manage invoices and reimbursement requests. They’ve also built all-in-one transactions to allow DAOs to batch payments in one transaction across multiple people and coins. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next up is financial analysis and accounting to attach labels and metadata to payments in order to avoid manual accounting via Etherscan dump. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The forward looking roadmap includes traditional fiat currency services, cross-chain DAOs, real-world compliance workflows and DAO ecosystem partnerships. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The world of DAOs is currently on fire, with dozens of viable organizations that have significant momentum &#8212; but not nearly enough infrastructure to make them truly efficient. It&#8217;s a truly interesting and diverse landscape that has come a long way since The DAO <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/02/the-only-thing-that-really-worried-me-was-the-ether/">nearly derailed Ethereum</a> back in 2016. Today&#8217;s DAOs are more company scale than network scale but are moving faster and building cooler things than containers for money.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;On-chain payroll make DAOs truly crypto-native,” says <a href="https://twitter.com/Cooopahtroopa">Cooper Turley</a>, a co-founder of <a href="https://twitter.com/fwbtweets">FWB</a> and full-time DAO explorer. “In a world where dozens of members are contributing from every corner of the world, automating salaries, incentives and bounties are the only way in which DAOs can scale.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to what Utopia Labs is doing, Multisafe, Commonwealth, Parcel and Colony are all names to watch in the DAO infrastructure space. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/utopia-labs-is-building-an-operating-system-for-daos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210663</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here for influencer-branded mac and cheese</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/here-for-influencer-branded-mac-and-cheese/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/here-for-influencer-branded-mac-and-cheese/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Natasha and Mary Ann and Alex were all aboard this week under the guidance of Chris and Grace, meaning that we were running full-strength for our roundup of this super busy week. Before we hop into the topics, you can follow the show on Twitter &#8212; all the cool kids do! &#8212; and keep in mind that on Mondays Equity provides a short kickoff [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/04566457-b353-4bfe-8bce-b04ff7569a2f?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/bayareawriter">Mary Ann </a>and <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> were all aboard this week under the guidance of <a href="https://twitter.com/CGates123">Chris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall">Grace</a>, meaning that we were running full-strength for our roundup of this <em>super</em> busy week.</p>
<p>Before we hop into the topics, you can follow the show on Twitter &#8212; all the cool kids do! &#8212; and keep in mind that on Mondays Equity provides a short kickoff to the week, we chat a single topic on Wednesdays, and Fridays are when we go through the full week. Make sense? Hell yeah:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fiveable landed a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/fiveable-lands-10m-series-a-to-become-the-hallways-of-the-educational-internet/">$10 million Series A to become the digital hallways of the educational internet</a>. It&#8217;s their words, not ours, and Mary Ann had some fair questions on how they&#8217;ll differentiate from other competitors.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/cobalt-launches-from-beta-with-a-2-8m-seed-to-help-creators-launch-products/">Cobalt raised $2.8 million</a> to help creators build and sell more stuff. As part of our continuing focus on creators more broadly, we had a few questions!</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/weight-health-startup-found-comes-out-of-stealth-with-32m-in-funding-former-bumble-exec-as-new-ceo/">Found came out of stealth</a> with $32 million in total funding from GV, Atomic and Define Ventures. The startup is focused on &#8220;weight care management&#8221; and it&#8217;s notable that the co-founder of Atomic, which incubated this company, also co-founded hims and hers &#8212; which also has a telehealth component. Found&#8217;s new CEO is the former COO of Bumble, who drafted its S-1 while getting chemo treatment for stage 3 breast cancer.</li>
<li>From there we dug into trends! First up was the trend of startups going full-stack, which we kicked off with a look at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/angellist-stack-founder/">AngelList&#8217;s new Stack &#8212; har har &#8212; product</a>. The suite screams Carta and Stripe, but then again, doesn&#8217;t everything compete with each other these days?</li>
<li>Next up was consolidation, which echoed our first conversation. Discussing a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/rpa-industry-consolidation-continues-with-sale-of-blue-prism-to-vista-for-1-095b/">recent deal in the RPA space</a>, the Equity team made predictions about which sectors in the startup world are the most likely to see consolidation in the coming quarters.</li>
<li>And we closed with climate tech, a startup niche that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/the-enormous-challenges-and-abundant-opportunities-in-climate-tech/">could bring a small sliver of hope to our heating planet</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>All this, and we still managed to sneak a Froyo metaphor into the running for best Official Equity comment of all time.</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><em>Equity drops every Monday, Wednesday and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PDT, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/here-for-influencer-branded-mac-and-cheese/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210941</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM&#8217;s US factories will switch to renewable energy five years ahead of schedule</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/gms-us-factories-will-switch-to-renewable-energy-five-years-ahead-of-schedule/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/gms-us-factories-will-switch-to-renewable-energy-five-years-ahead-of-schedule/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 13:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211154</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this year, GM announced plans to go green by 2035 with the vehicles it produces and by 2030 for its production facilities. Now it says it'll achieve the factory goal five years early.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Steve Dent</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Steve Dent is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/youtube-tv-may-drop-14-nbc-universal-channels-over-a-contract-dispute/">YouTube TV may drop 14 NBC Universal channels over a contract dispute</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/24/dji-mavic-3-drone-leak-details-improved-camera-and-a-46-minute-flight-time/">DJI Mavic 3 drone leak details improved camera and a 46-minute flight time</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this year, GM <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-to-exclusively-sell-zero-emissions-cars-by-2035-164418993.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">announced</a> plans to go green by 2035 with the vehicles it produces and by 2030 with how it produces them. Now, the company has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/gm-expects-renewable-energy-powered-us-sites-by-2025-ahead-plan-2021-09-30/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1">announced</a> that it will be early on the &#8220;how&#8221; part, using 100 percent renewable energy across its US operations by 2025 — five years ahead of schedule.</p>
<p>To achieve the goal, GM said it would increase energy efficiency and source renewables for its facilities. It also plans to create technology to store renewable energy over the medium and long term and &#8220;create microgrids that help deploy renewable energy.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p>“We know climate action is a priority and every company must push itself to decarbonize further and faster,” said GM Chief Sustainability Officer Kristen Siemen. “That’s what we are doing by aiming to achieve 100 percent renewable energy five years earlier in the US.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>It also detailed plans to work with a company called PJM Interconnection to track energy usage based on carbon output of the grid at any given time. &#8220;When the power being supplied consists mostly of fossil fuels, GM can make informed decisions about tapping into stored renewable energy or reduce the amount of power being consumed,&#8221; the company said.</p>
<p>As for the vehicles it produces, GM plans to have 30 EVs globally by 2025, and still plans to &#8220;eliminate tailpipe emissions for new light-duty vehicles (i.e., cars, SUVs and pickups) by 2035.&#8221; The wording suggests that could include hydrogen-powered cars, though GM appears to be focusing mostly on EVs.</p>
<p>GM&#8217;s plans to reduce pollution have drifted with the political winds, however. It was one of several automakers that backed the Trump administration&#8217;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-19-trump-administration-national-emissions-standards.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1">plan</a>to bar California and other states from setting their own pollution and zero-emission requirements. That would have allowed manufacturers to raise fuel efficiency by just 1.5 percent per year, well below the previous administration&#8217;s five percent requirement. GM withdrew from the litigation shortly after Joe Biden was elected President.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/g-ms-us-factories-will-switch-to-renewable-energy-five-years-ahead-of-schedule-085010165.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/gms-us-factories-will-switch-to-renewable-energy-five-years-ahead-of-schedule/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211154</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Orchest raises $3.5M to provide a simpler way to build data pipelines</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/orchest-raises-3-5m-to-provide-a-simpler-way-to-build-data-pipelines/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/orchest-raises-3-5m-to-provide-a-simpler-way-to-build-data-pipelines/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 13:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Orchest is building a tool for data scientists to develop and deploy data pipelines without having to rely on an infrastructure or engineering team.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.orchest.io/">Orchest</a> co-founder and CEO Rick Lamers calls himself, his co-founder Yannick Perrenet and his team “a bunch of data nerds” that love making data tools.</p>
<p>In this case the company is building an open source integrated development environment tool for data scientists so they can develop, iterate and deploy data pipelines without having to rely on an infrastructure or engineering team.</p>
<p>On Friday, the company announced a $3.5 million seed round led by Gradient Ventures and Basis Set Ventures. Joining the round were Seedcamp, Data Council founder Pete Soderling and Kaggle founder Anthony Goldbloom.</p>
<p>“Data scientists get overwhelmed with technology that they have to know,” Lamers told TechCrunch. “They have it the worst: they have a good understanding of mathematics, modeling and what you can say from the data, but they are not as familiar with cloud computing, containerization and the infrastructure side.”</p>
<p>Orchest makes that type of workflow more autonomous so data scientists don’t have to solve those technology issues themselves, but can go from an initial idea to deployment in the same environment, he added.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2210933" style="width: 3186px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2210933" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2210933 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/3.-Orchest-UI-Environment-builds.png" alt="" width="3176" height="2042" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/3.-Orchest-UI-Environment-builds.png 3176w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/3.-Orchest-UI-Environment-builds.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/3.-Orchest-UI-Environment-builds.png?resize=300,193 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/3.-Orchest-UI-Environment-builds.png?resize=768,494 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/3.-Orchest-UI-Environment-builds.png?resize=680,437 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/3.-Orchest-UI-Environment-builds.png?resize=1536,988 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/3.-Orchest-UI-Environment-builds.png?resize=2048,1317 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/3.-Orchest-UI-Environment-builds.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3176px) 100vw, 3176px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2210933" class="wp-caption-text">Orchest&#8217;s user interface environment. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Orchest</p></div></p>
<p>The company, founded in 2020, started out as an open source project on GitHub before running a private beta of clouding hosting. Today is also the debut of the company’s first public version, Lamers said. It has a SaaS business model and offers a version where Orchest takes care of all of the operational hosting and an enterprise version with additional features.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He and Perrenet were studying computer science at Delft University of Technology and dropped out to start the company. They were already coding open source software and were racking up a large amount of GitHub stars in a short period of time when investors began reaching out, Lamers recalls.</p>
<p>Orchest already has over 1,300 stars, and over 150 companies using the product. It saw over 2,500 unique installs of the open source software, including from organizations like Accenture and Georgetown University.</p>
<p>Chang Xu, partner at Basis Set, met Lamers and Perrenet early in 2020 and recalls them standing out as “exceptional founders,” and ended up participating in the company’s pre-seed round at the end of 2020.</p>
<p>Xu’s area of expertise is early-stage B2B infrastructure and developer tools. She said that software engineers often have many tools at their disposal, but data scientists don’t. They may learn how to use certain resources, like Jupyter Notebooks or Google Colab, during their education, but once they have a job and are out there manipulating the data, they realize they don’t have the software engineering prowess.</p>
<p>“Rick and Yannick were telling us that once data scientists get to companies they don’t know how to apply what they have used, and companies don’t have the money to staff a full engineering team, so there is white space in the tools there,” she said. “Orchest enables data scientists to self-serve what they need and can just use it.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="L4FU7CTTQK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/how-to-ensure-quality-in-the-era-of-big-data/">How to ensure data quality in the era of big data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to ensure data quality in the era of big data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/how-to-ensure-quality-in-the-era-of-big-data/embed/#?secret=L4FU7CTTQK" data-secret="L4FU7CTTQK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/orchest-raises-3-5m-to-provide-a-simpler-way-to-build-data-pipelines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210926</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>All Day Kitchens wants to expand every independent restaurant’s delivery network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/all-day-kitchens-wants-to-expand-every-independent-restaurants-delivery-network/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/all-day-kitchens-wants-to-expand-every-independent-restaurants-delivery-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Taussig]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[All Day Kitchens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Base10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GIC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ken Chong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khosla Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Sawchuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber Eats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210984</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company is partnering with restaurants to share their food across a city via a network of satellite kitchens without having to put up any upfront costs.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The pandemic ushered in the popularity of shared workspaces, known as cloud kitchens or ghost kitchens, for restaurants to cook meals exclusively for delivery.</p>
<p>But for small, independent restaurants that couldn’t afford the upfront costs for expansion, Uber Eats alums Ken Chong and Matt Sawchuk came up with another approach. They founded <a href="https://alldaykitchens.com/">All Day Kitchens</a> in 2018 to partner with restaurants to share their food across a city through use of a network of satellite kitchens, without having to put up any upfront costs.</p>
<p>With their model, distributed kitchens are situated in residential and business areas, closer to customers. When a new restaurant is onboarded to the platform, their food goes to all locations, which streamlines how restaurants expand in large geographies and delivery zones, CEO Chong told TechCrunch. The model also enables the ability for customers to order from multiple restaurants in one order and it will all be delivered together.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2210985" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2210985" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2210985" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/VKC_335.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/VKC_335.jpg 8103w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/VKC_335.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/VKC_335.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/VKC_335.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/VKC_335.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/VKC_335.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/VKC_335.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/VKC_335.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2210985" class="wp-caption-text">All Day Kitchens founders Ken Chong and Matt Sawchuk</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Consumer preference was spoken for pre-COVID and the entire restaurant world was not going to be the right model for how digital demand was to be filled,” he added. “We set out to build a turn key solution for restaurants for which warehouse ghost kitchens were not working for them. Instead, we built a platform for micro-fulfillment so they could expand their reach.”</p>
<p>On Friday, the food tech and logistics company announced a $65 million Series C round of financing led by Lightspeed Venture Partners with participation from GIC to fund expansion into new markets, R&amp;D and hiring. Existing investors Andreessen Horowitz, Founders Fund, Khosla Ventures and Base10 also participated in the round along with new investors, including Tishman Speyer, Lime CEO Wayne Ting and Forward co-founders Adrian Aoun and Ilya Abyzov.</p>
<p>The new investment brings All Day Kitchens’ total funding to date to $102.5 million. It is the latest company in the ghost kitchen space to receive funding in a hot industry that includes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/30/muy-raises-15m-to-grow-its-new-cloud-kitchen-concept/">Muy</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/justkitchen-is-using-cloud-kitchens-to-create-the-next-generation-of-restaurant-franchising/">JustKitchen</a> and even <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/robotic-kitchen-startup-ypc-raises-a-1-8m-seed-round/">robotic kitchens like YPC</a>.</p>
<p>The company doubled the number of satellite kitchens in its network this year and now operates more than 15 locations throughout the Bay Area and Chicago, with new markets expected to go into Texas and Southern California next year, Chong said. It is also hiring at its headquarters in San Francisco and as it opens the new markets.</p>
<p>Though the global pandemic was a tough environment for its restaurant partners, All Day Kitchens saw the number of partners joining the platform grow by four times over the past year. It is working with brands like Honey Butter Fried Chicken, Mott St and HaiSous. It’s revenue has also increased 18 times over the past 18 months.</p>
<p>“The part that we honestly found surprising and striking is the misconception that restaurants are late adopters,” Chong said. “Similar to Uber, it is really that no one was building something like this for them. A lot of the apps out there are for consumers, and that is why restaurants are our focus. The restaurant partners we work with are always looking to improve.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DDxyfRfra8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/19/in-the-ghost-kitchen-race-gv-backed-kitchen-united-aims-to-kill-with-kindness-heres-its-playbook/">In the heated cloud kitchens race, Kitchen United aims to kill with kindness; here&#8217;s its playbook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;In the heated cloud kitchens race, Kitchen United aims to kill with kindness; here&#8217;s its playbook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/19/in-the-ghost-kitchen-race-gv-backed-kitchen-united-aims-to-kill-with-kindness-heres-its-playbook/embed/#?secret=DDxyfRfra8" data-secret="DDxyfRfra8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As part of the investment, Alex Taussig, partner at Lightspeed, is joining the company’s board as a director and GIC&#8217;s Jeremy Kranz is joining as a board observer.</p>
<p>Taussig met Chong over a year ago and said Lightspeed has made a number of investments in the food and commerce space over the past decade. One of the areas Taussig was looking into was ways to solve the demand for delivery. He recalls looking at different startups and models and was “underwhelmed” by the warehouse models.</p>
<p>In talking to Chong about All Day Kitchens, Taussig saw something different: a model where the focus was getting the food closer to the customer. It not only correlated with the quality of food, but also delivery times so that items weren&#8217;t sitting in someone’s car for an hour. As a result, there would be higher utilization of the platform, he said.</p>
<p>“I was blown away by that insight and spent a year watching Ken build the company,” Taussig added. “The Chicago launch was also a big deal because most companies start in the Bay Area. This market size is measured in billions and is almost limitless and faster growing on the independent side. It is going to be hard for another company to come in and do what All Day Kitchens is already doing.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6MKg5UOJv0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/">10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/embed/#?secret=6MKg5UOJv0" data-secret="6MKg5UOJv0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/all-day-kitchens-wants-to-expand-every-independent-restaurants-delivery-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210984</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LeadIQ&#8217;s rapid growth snags venture attention as sales software market stays hot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/leadiqs-rapid-revenue-growth-snags-venture-attention-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/leadiqs-rapid-revenue-growth-snags-venture-attention-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cathay innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gong.io]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadiq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zoominfo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning LeadIQ, a startup working in the sales software market, announced that it has closed a $30 million Series B led by Cathay Innovation. Other investors in the transaction include Fresco Capital, Strong Ventures, and Eight Road Ventures. LeadIQ frames its product from the perspective of missed revenue targets at companies, which it claims [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://leadiq.com/">LeadIQ</a>, a startup working in the sales software market, announced that it has closed a $30 million Series B led by <a href="https://cathayinnovation.com/">Cathay Innovation</a>. Other investors in the transaction include <a href="https://fresco.vc/">Fresco Capital</a>, <a href="http://www.strongvc.com/">Strong Ventures</a>, and <a href="https://eightroads.com/en/">Eight Road Ventures</a>.</p>
<p>LeadIQ frames its product from the perspective of missed revenue targets at companies, which it claims impact nearly two-thirds of today&#8217;s deals. The startup&#8217;s service is designed to save sales staff time by taking on the brunt of data entry work from the sales prospecting process by automating lead capture. The LeadIQ product also <a href="https://leadiq.com/features">includes analytics</a> covering a customer&#8217;s prospecting efficiency, which can then be segmented by worker performance and more general breakdowns like industry and company size.</p>
<p>Previously, LeadIQ <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/leadiq/company_financials">raised around $12 million</a>, though the company told TechCrunch that it had only spent $6 million of that total, despite reaching eight-figure ARR (the $10 million threshold).</p>
<p>Why raise more capital if it didn&#8217;t need the funds? According to CEO and co-founder <a href="https://twitter.com/djiaoMei">Mei Siauw</a>, LeadIQ is moving towards supporting account management instead of merely lead management. Building new products is expensive, and thus more capital will help the company staff up for the work.</p>
<p>Why work towards sales account management over simply focusing on leads? According to Siauw, the effort will help sales teams better work with marketing teams, allowing for more complete information sharing and hopefully better sales results. The CEO likened marketing as similar to fishing with a net. Sales, she said, is more akin to hunting fish with a spear. With account-level tooling leading to more complete information sharing, she hopes to give sales teams a better shot at catching more fish, to extend the analogy.</p>
<p>The company has been efficient to date, as noted above. Frugality, however, is only a virtue in startup-land when it is coupled to rapid growth. LeadIQ hits that mark, having grown its annual recurring revenue (ARR) by around 3x in the last year. The company also sports net retention figures of around 125%, and a strong ratio of account size versus customer acquisition costs. Those are the sorts of metrics that SaaS investors covet.</p>
<p>The LeadIQ round is another datapoint in our understanding of the current market for sales-focused software. It appears to be an active sector with fellow sales software service Gongo.io raising rapid-fire rounds in recent quarters including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/gong-going-gangbusters-grabs-250m-series-e-on-7-25b-valuation/">a $250 million investment earlier this year</a>, and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/12/gong-raises-another-200m-on-2-2-billion-valuation/">$200 million check in August of 2020</a>. Gong works in what it calls &#8220;the revenue intelligence&#8221; market when it raised this June.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The sales software market has also seen exits recently including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/zoominfo-drops-575m-on-chorus-ai-as-ai-shakes-up-the-sales-market/">a $575 million deal between ZoomInfo and the smaller Chorus.ai</a>. Chorus had posted rapid revenue growth ahead of its exit, raising north of $100 million before it sold to the larger company.</p>
<p>LeadIQ has around 115 employes, its CEO said, a number that it intends to double in the next 18 months or so. Today those workers hail from 22 countries, making LeadIQ the epitome of the now-standard micro-multinational model that many early-stage startups are pursuing. Notably LeadIQ has two main hubs, one in the United States and one in Singapore. Siauw says that Europe may be nextLe.</p>
<p>Now flush with more funds than ever, let&#8217;s see how quickly LeadIQ can expand its revenues in the next year. That next milestone should help us understand both if the company will become an IPO candidate, and how deep its market truly is.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/leadiqs-rapid-revenue-growth-snags-venture-attention-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211133</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Battery chemistry company Sila&#8217;s founder Gene Berdichevsky on the science of scaling up</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/battery-chemistry-company-silas-founder-gene-berdichevsky-on-the-science-of-scaling-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/battery-chemistry-company-silas-founder-gene-berdichevsky-on-the-science-of-scaling-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 12:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery chemistry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battery Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sila]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sila Nanotechnologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silicon anode]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Before Gene Berdichevsky became the co-founder and CEO of battery chemistry company Sila Nano, he was the seventh employee at Tesla Motors. As principal engineer on the Roadster battery, Berdichevsky was one of the first people crazy enough to experiment with shoving a lithium-ion battery pack into a combustion engine vehicle. The result? The Roadster [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Before Gene Berdichevsky became the co-founder and CEO of battery chemistry company Sila Nano, he was the seventh employee at Tesla Motors. As principal engineer on the Roadster battery, Berdichevsky was one of the first people crazy enough to experiment with shoving a lithium-ion battery pack into a combustion engine vehicle. The result? The Roadster became the first highway legal serial production all-electric car fueled by lithium-ion battery cells and able to travel over 200 miles per charge.</p>
<p>In 2011, Sila was founded with a mission of not only building the next generation of battery chemistry, but also being able to scale it. Since then, the company has figured out how to replace the graphite in the anode of a lithium-ion cell with silicon, which Berdichevsky says makes for a denser, cheaper battery cell. He explains why:</p>
<blockquote><p>There are four key components in a battery. The anode stores lithium when the batteries charge. The cathode stores lithium when the battery is discharged, and the lithium goes back and forth between charge and discharge, moving through an electrolyte liquid. The separator keeps them from short-circuiting.</p>
<p>For the last 30 years, the anode has been graphite, and that material in graphite requires a ring of six carbon atoms for one lithium atom to come and sit in the middle when the battery is charging. So it takes six carbon atoms to store one lithium atom. In silicon, you can have one silicon atom bonding with four lithium atoms. So instead of six to one, you&#8217;re one to four. You literally have 42x atomic advantage with silicon, which means you can use a lot less material to store the same amount of lithium. Essentially, you&#8217;re using a lot less material in a much smaller space to store your energy, the lithium, in the anode.</p></blockquote>
<p>Sila&#8217;s first commercial product, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sila-nanotechnologiess-first-next-gen-battery-will-launch-in-whoop-wearables/">released in September on the newest Whoop fitness tracker wearable</a>, proves not only that the company&#8217;s recipe works, but that it can scale — the launch also marks Sila&#8217;s 10-year anniversary. The next step is scaling up 100x to put the same chemistry in automobiles.</p>
<p>The company already has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/automakers-have-battery-anxiety-so-theyre-taking-control-of-the-supply/">joint battery ventures</a> with BMW and Daimler and aims to provide battery chemistry for electric vehicles at scale by 2025. With nearly every major automaker promising new lineups of EVs, ensuring a sustainable and affordable battery pack is of the utmost importance.</p>
<p>As a battery technology pioneer, Berdichevsky is playing the long game, already thinking in terms of the next few decades worth of work, not just the next few years. He talks us through his long-term strategy, his thoughts on fundraising and his insights into the battery industry.</p>
<p><i>The following interview, part of an ongoing series with founders who are building transportation companies, has been edited for length and clarity.</i></p>
<p><b>What is Sila&#8217;s long-term vision? </b></p>
<p>We want to be a world leader and do for the energy storage industry what Intel did for the personal computing industry. Intel didn&#8217;t make every single chip or the motherboards or the PCs. They made the most important components whose performance drove the adoption of the devices people actually wanted, and the better the microprocessor got, the better computers got, the more people used them and the more the world changed.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/battery-chemistry-company-silas-founder-gene-berdichevsky-on-the-science-of-scaling-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202953</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PSPDFkit raises $116M, its first outside money; now nearly 1B people use apps powered by its collaboration, signing and markup tools</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/pspdfkit-raises-116m-its-first-outside-money-now-nearly-1b-people-use-apps-powered-by-its-collaboration-signing-and-markup-tools/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/pspdfkit-raises-116m-its-first-outside-money-now-nearly-1b-people-use-apps-powered-by-its-collaboration-signing-and-markup-tools/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 11:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[APIs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[austria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[document processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DocuSign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dropbox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flutter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north carolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software development kit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vienna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volkswagen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An under-the-radar, bootstrapped startup from Vienna, Austria &#8212; a hit with developers for technology that underpins user experience for some of the world&#8217;s most popular apps &#8212; is doubling down on momentum and announcing its first outside investment, in the form of a large growth round of funding. PSPDFkit &#8212; which provides APIs and an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">An under-the-radar, bootstrapped startup from Vienna, Austria &#8212; a hit with developers for technology that underpins user experience for some of the world&#8217;s most popular apps &#8212; is doubling down on momentum and announcing its first outside investment, in the form of a large growth round of funding.</p>
<p><a href="https://pspdfkit.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PSPDFkit</a> &#8212; which provides APIs and an SDK that developers use to power document processing features like e-signing, document viewing and editing, collaboration and <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/products/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">much more</a> &#8212; has raised €100 million ($116 million). The funding is coming from a single investor, Insight Partners.</p>
<p>PSPDFkit is already profitable, and it has been for a while, so this investment is about stepping up its pace of growth. It plans to use the investment to build more developer tools, make strategic acquisitions (co-founder and CEO Jonathan Rhyne is mum about what, except to say that it will be to expand the suite of useful tools that it provides); and, for the first time, make some concerted efforts in the areas of sales and marketing.</p>
<p>A lot of PSPDFkit&#8217;s growth to date, in fact, has been by word of mouth, a strategy that has gotten it very far up to now. Its customers include Dropbox, DocuSign, SAP, IBM, Volkswagen, Fabasoft, Wolters Kluwer Deutschland, and the European Patent Office, among a number of others that it works with under NDA.</p>
<p>In many cases, not every company is happy to admit just how much of their user experience and technology have been built by third parties, and that&#8217;s the situation with where and how PSPDFkit is used, too, but the fact remains that it&#8217;s quietly huge: altogether, PSPDFkit&#8217;s tech, by way of its APIs and SDKs, is now approaching 1 billion users in 150 countries.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, this traction has also meant that PSPDFkit has had a lot of acquisition interest over the years. Large technology companies building productivity tools, working with developers already, and are already very active in mobile apps and cloud services have all knocked on PSPDFkit&#8217;s door. Although the startup is not disclosing its valuation, you can guess that, given its size and profitable status, with this latest round, it&#8217;s definitely become a more expensive buy. (And if all goes to plan, will become even more so.)</p>
<p>The story of PSPDFkit is an interesting one that mirrors a lot of how mobile development itself has grown up over the years.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Originally the company started out around 2011 as a framework and toolset created by Austrian engineer Peter Steinberger, who was already involved in the iOS developer community and could see a need in the market from a number of apps for document-manipulation features like e-signing, document editing, and document viewing. Apps were letting us turn a lot of things into virtual experiences, and paper was shaping up to be one of the first things to go.</p>
<p>That need turned out to be a classic use case for building that functionality and making it something that many others could access by way of SDKs and APIs: document manipulation tools &#8212; even something so basic as previewing a file that is contained in a cloud-based folder &#8212; are very hard to build from scratch, are not necessarily part of companies&#8217; core businesses, yet are nevertheless central to how they work.</p>
<p>Steinberger&#8217;s framework thus became one of the early examples of how SDKs and APIs could be used to integrate different services and functionality into other apps &#8212; a basic principle has now been applied to a whole host of other features: embeeded financial services, eg, neobanks; embedded payments, eg Stripe and others; embedded communications, eg, Twilio, Sinch, etc; and so on.</p>
<p>(The name PSPDFkit was a reference to Peter Steinberger&#8217;s initials; PDF because PDFs were, and largely remain, the company&#8217;s initial focus; and &#8220;kit&#8221; in reference to the SDK that it was.)</p>
<p>As mobile app creation and usage started to really take off, so did Steinberger&#8217;s framework, and soon Martin Schürrer joined him in building it. Rhyne &#8212; who was working in the U.S. as an attorney representing developers &#8212; then became their lawyer after meeting them at a developer event. Soon into that relationship, the three realized that not only was there a proper, growing business to be managed, but Steinberger and Schürrer had little interest in doing that. By 2014, Rhyne gave up practicing law and came on as a third co-founder, with Steinberger and Schürrer in Vienna, and Rhyne based out of North Carolina in the U.S.</p>
<p>With this round, Steinberger and Schürrer are stepping away from full-time roles but remain &#8220;significantly invested&#8221; in the business, while Rhyne is staying on as CEO.</p>
<p>Things evolved rapidly from there, in keeping with the meteoric rise of apps themselves.</p>
<p>Starting out on iOS, today PSPDFkit provides tools that can be used for building apps on Android and the web, using Flutter and React Native. The strategy is to work on building out a bigger platform to handle multiple, related functionality that developers might want to use related to documents, and perhaps the wider world of productivity.</p>
<p class="p1">Rhyne&#8217;s basic description of what PSPDFkit and its customers do today is &#8220;obsoleting paper.&#8221; But over time &#8212; not unlike how Stripe has progressed from its core feature, providing APIs to power payments, to a wider suite of services related to transactions &#8212; PSPDFkit sees an opportunity to do more, too, not least because the world&#8217;s expectations have also changed.</p>
<p class="p1">For example, Rhyne recalled how PSPDFkit put out a real time collaboration platform in 2015, &#8220;but we were like, &#8216;Man, it&#8217;s not getting traction, people don&#8217;t really want to use this.'&#8221; Then Covid-19 happened, he continued: &#8220;Now every single customer is saying, &#8216;This looks great. Yeah, we want to use that&#8230;&#8217; I think that we&#8217;re seeing a change in the way people interact with documents.&#8221;</p>
<p>That speaks of a lot of opportunity both for the startup, and for its investors.</p>
<p>“Software developers and engineers are on the cutting edge of work simply by the nature of their craft,” said Ryan Hinkle, MD at Insight Partners, in a statement. “How they work and collaborate should be on the cutting edge, too. With PSPDFKit’s software development kits and hosted solutions, the company is revolutionizing document processing for enterprises and the developers they task with keeping the company at the forefront of innovation. Insight is thrilled to play a role in the company’s growth journey.” Hinkle is joining the board with this round.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/pspdfkit-raises-116m-its-first-outside-money-now-nearly-1b-people-use-apps-powered-by-its-collaboration-signing-and-markup-tools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210586</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FCC proposes new rules to combat SIM swapping scams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/fcc-proposes-new-rules-to-combat-sim-swapping-scams/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/fcc-proposes-new-rules-to-combat-sim-swapping-scams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 11:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sim cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SIM swapping scams have been on the rise these past couple of years, but the FCC is seeking to create new rules that would help prevent SIM swapping scams and port-out fraud.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mariella Moon</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mariella Moon is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/pokemon-unite-has-arrived-on-android-and-ios/">&#8216;Pokémon Unite&#8217; has arrived on Android and iOS</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/17/google-reportedly-plans-to-add-free-channels-to-its-smart-tv-platform/">Google reportedly plans to add free channels to its smart TV platform</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">SIM swapping scams have been on the rise these past couple of years, and since most online services these days are tied to people&#8217;s phone numbers, the technique has the potential to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-28-cell-phone-hack-is-ruining-lives-identity-theft.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1">ruin victims&#8217; lives</a>. Now, the Federal Communications Commission is <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-proposes-rules-prevent-sim-swapping-and-port-out-fraud" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">seeking</a> to create new rules that would help prevent SIM swapping scams and port-out fraud, both of which are techniques designed to hijack people&#8217;s phone numbers and identities.</p>
<p>The commission said it has received numerous complaints from consumers &#8220;who have suffered significant distress, inconvenience and financial harm&#8221; as a result of both hijacking methods. SIM swapping is a technique wherein a bad actor convinces a wireless carrier to transfer a victim&#8217;s service to a phone they control. When a bad actor successfully transfers the victim&#8217;s service and number to another carrier, that&#8217;s called port-out fraud.</p>
<div id="max-player-injector" class="vmmi-si" data-maxi="0">
<div class="vdb_player">
<div><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">To make it harder for scammers to gain control of potential victims&#8217; phone numbers, the FCC wants to amend the Customer Proprietary Network Information (CPNI) and Local Number Portability rules. In particular, it wants to require providers to adopt more secure methods in authenticating a person&#8217;s identity before agreeing to transfer their service to a new phone or to another carrier. The commission also proposes a rule that would require providers to notify customers whenever a SIM switch or a port-out request is made on their accounts. </span></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>As part of the FCC&#8217;s rulemaking process, the public can now comment on these proposals. The commission still has to read those proposals and offer the public another chance to make their voice heard before it can decide whether to amend the aforementioned rules.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fcc-proposes-new-rules-sim-swapping-scams-093840753.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/fcc-proposes-new-rules-to-combat-sim-swapping-scams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211130</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SquadPal is a social app to help remote working teams gel</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/squadpal-is-a-social-app-to-help-remote-working-teams-gel/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/squadpal-is-a-social-app-to-help-remote-working-teams-gel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 10:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CapitalT VC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comms apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future of work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HouseParty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SquadPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211118</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The future of office work, post-COVID-19, is driving plenty of startup activity. Not just around core business needs like comms (Zoom, Slack et al) &#8212; but entrepreneurs are also competing to come up with the perfect tool to recreate the social serendipity of office life in order to make dispersed workers feel a bit more [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The future of office work, post-COVID-19, is driving plenty of startup activity. Not just around core business needs like comms (Zoom, Slack et al) &#8212; but entrepreneurs are also competing to come up with the perfect tool to recreate the social serendipity of office life in order to make dispersed workers feel a bit more connected.</p>
<p>This may actually be an impossible task. The chemistry of real life is a fickle wall-flower that&#8217;s hard to encapsulate in app-form (and a lot of office life was of course a total dirge). But that isn&#8217;t stopping people from trying. (The &#8216;Cambrian explosion&#8217; of dating apps, over the past decade, also suggests that hope for meaningful human connection at the convenient tap of an app springs eternal.)</p>
<p>To wit: Meet London-based <a href="https://www.squadpalapp.com">SquadPal</a>, a &#8220;social community&#8221; app that&#8217;s just raised a £400k pre-seed with a pitch offering a &#8216;chief happiness officer as a service&#8217;. Which does at least sounds a little bit different to all the &#8216;virtual watercooler&#8217; apps that quickly mushroomed into view as offices shut their doors last year.</p>
<p>SquadPal was also founded in 2020 (August) by Robinson Nouveau, Mehdi Benbrahim and Harshit Jain. Its trio of remote working co-founders have made a simple app for teams to silo some &#8216;fun&#8217; social interactions &#8212; be it a quiz, a game or a baking or &#8216;who has the cutest baby&#8217; competition &#8212; keeping that sort of non-work related yet team-building chatter out of more formal comms channels like Slack and Zoom. Or that&#8217;s the idea.</p>
<p>The aim is also to entice workers by offering a dedicated social app for workplace teams vs more ad hoc platforms that could be used for the same sort of stuff, like Houseparty.</p>
<p>In practice every company that&#8217;s already using a real-time messaging platform like Slack likely already has a &#8216;Watercooler&#8217; channel for &#8216;office banter&#8217; &#8212; but, hey, that doesn&#8217;t stop entrepreneurs dreaming.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SquadPal&#8217;s founders say their app provides a place where teammates can learn more about each other and share personal moments. So of course it features a central feed which shows the latest &#8220;activities&#8221; from the team. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here&#8217;s Nouveau, SquadPal&#8217;s CEO: &#8220;We are a Chief Happiness Officer as a Service helping remote teams fight the feeling of isolation and disconnect from their teams. We do this through a fun social community app including competitions, challenges and games. Our mission is to recreate the social life of remote teams online because being physically apart shouldn’t mean you can’t be virtually together.&#8221;</p>
<p>The team launched their app in February 2021, initially bootstrapping development. So far they&#8217;ve sign up 2,000 users from more than 500 companies.</p>
<p>Since launching the app the startup says it has <span style="font-weight: 400;">helped 72% of its active users to be &#8220;more engaged&#8221; at work. It also says 70% of users reported an improvement in their wellbeing at work. </span></p>
<p>Most of SquadPal&#8217;s current users are fully remote workers but it says it also wants to target hybrid workers and global teams working from different locations &#8212; reckoning there will be some 450 million employees working at least two days per week remotely by 2025.</p>
<p>Its roster of early investors include CapitalT VC plus angel investors such as serial angel Charlie Songhurst; PriceMatch co-founder Raphaël Theron; RLC Ventures Partner Jair Paula; Heroes co-founder Riccardo Bruni; Allplants co-founder Jonathan Petrides; Sonalytic co-founder and Spotify product director Martin Gould; and Foundrs &amp; Heights co-founder Dan Murray-Serter.</p>
<p>SquadPal says the pre-seed funds <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">will be put towards integrating the app within teams’ workplaces (Slack, Teams, Zoom etc) &#8212; so that it&#8217;s sitting in less of a silo. </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The startup also wants to add more curated activities and content for users to &#8220;find meaningful ways to connect while everyone is apart&#8221;. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/squadpal-is-a-social-app-to-help-remote-working-teams-gel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211118</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter ban in Nigeria to be lifted if platform sets up a local office and pays taxes, president says</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/twitter-ban-in-nigeria-to-be-lifted-if-platform-sets-up-a-local-office-and-pay-taxes-president-says/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/twitter-ban-in-nigeria-to-be-lifted-if-platform-sets-up-a-local-office-and-pay-taxes-president-says/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 08:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[independence day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social media ban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nigeria President Muhammadu Buhari announced on Friday that the ban on Twitter would be lifted, but only if the social media giant met certain conditions. The president disclosed this during his televised broadcast to Nigerians on the country&#8217;s 61st Independence Day anniversary. He acknowledged the fact that Twitter is used to disseminate information. Still, he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nigeria President Muhammadu Buhari announced on Friday that the ban on Twitter would </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be lifted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but only if the social media giant met certain conditions</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The president disclosed this during his televised broadcast to Nigerians on the country&#8217;s 61st Independence Day anniversary</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He acknowledged the fact that Twitter </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is used</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to disseminate information. Still, he warned about bad actors who misuse the platform to &#8220;organise, coordinate, and execute criminal activities, propagate fake news, and promote ethnic and religious sentiments</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hence, the reason why his government decided to suspend the social media platform&#8217;s operations in the country on June 5. He said this has allowed the government to put measures in place to address these challenges.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Gp9hjv7ACk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/nigeria-suspends-twitter-operations-says-platform-undermines-its-corporate-existence/">Nigeria suspends Twitter operations, says platform &#8216;undermines its corporate existence&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nigeria suspends Twitter operations, says platform &#8216;undermines its corporate existence&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/nigeria-suspends-twitter-operations-says-platform-undermines-its-corporate-existence/embed/#?secret=Gp9hjv7ACk" data-secret="Gp9hjv7ACk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One way it claims to be doing so is by engaging with the Twitter team. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In August, for instance, the nation&#8217;s information minister Lai Mohammed said Nigeria was in talks with Twitter to reinstate the company&#8217;s operations in the country</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He said ten requests had </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been made</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> but the government only reached an agreement with Twitter on seven &#8212; the other issues yet to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be sorted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> out include Twitter setting up a local office, paying tax </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">locally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and cooperating with the Nigerian government to regulate content and harmful tweets</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It seems nothing has changed since then. The president expressed a similar stance today but in a more nuanced manner.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to him, the committee he set up, alongside the nation&#8217;s technical team, have engaged Twitter to discuss five issues &#8212; national security and cohesion, registration, physical presence and representation, fair taxation, dispute resolution, and local content. If Twitter agrees to meet these requirements posed by the government, the ban will be lifted.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Following the extensive engagements, the issues are being addressed and I have directed that the suspension </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be lifted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> but only if the conditions </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are met</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to allow our citizens to continue the use of the platform for business and positive engagements,&#8221; he said</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In June, the Nigerian government <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/nigeria-suspends-twitter-operations-says-platform-undermines-its-corporate-existence/">suspended Twitter</a> after the company deleted a controversial post from the president threatening to punish regional secessionists</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Four months later, the country isn&#8217;t any closer to lifting the ban despite mounting pressure from the international community and several activists who have condemned the move, citing the government&#8217;s unnecessary attempt to stifle freedom of expression</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the Nigerian government has twice stated that it is working with Twitter to lift the ban, the social media platform has kept mum about said happenings</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><em>Update: According to a Twitter spokesperson: &#8220;We continue to engage with the Nigerian government and we are committed to charting a path forward to the restoration of Twitter for everyone in Nigeria. Discussions with the Nigerian government have been respectful and productive &#8212; we look forward to seeing the service restored very soon.&#8221;</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zVtW2GCJ5y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/trump-congratulates-nigeria-for-twitter-ban-says-more-countries-should-do-the-same/">Trump congratulates Nigeria for Twitter ban, says more countries should do the same</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Trump congratulates Nigeria for Twitter ban, says more countries should do the same&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/trump-congratulates-nigeria-for-twitter-ban-says-more-countries-should-do-the-same/embed/#?secret=zVtW2GCJ5y" data-secret="zVtW2GCJ5y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/twitter-ban-in-nigeria-to-be-lifted-if-platform-sets-up-a-local-office-and-pay-taxes-president-says/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SoftBank-backed Oyo files for $1.16 billion IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/softbank-backed-oyo-files-for-1-16-billion-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/softbank-backed-oyo-files-for-1-16-billion-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 05:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oyo is ready to explore the public markets. The eight-year-old Indian budget hotel giant has filed the paperworks (PDF) with the local market regulator for an initial public offering, in which it is seeking to raise about $1.16 billion. The Gurgaon-headquartered startup &#8212; which offers an operating system of sorts to help hoteliers accept digital bookings, payments, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Oyo is ready to explore the public markets. The eight-year-old Indian budget hotel giant has <a href="https://www.icicisecurities.com/Upload/ArticleAttachments/Oravel%20Stays%20Limited%20DRHP.pdf">filed the paperworks</a> (PDF) with the local market regulator for an initial public offering, in which it is seeking to raise about $1.16 billion.</p>
<p>The Gurgaon-headquartered startup &#8212; which offers an operating system of sorts to help hoteliers accept digital bookings, payments, determine the best pricing for a room, and integrates with third-party booking services &#8212; is seeking to raise about $942 million through sale of new shares, while the rest is set aside for sales of existing shares (secondary transaction).</p>
<p>SoftBank plans to sells stake worth over $175 million, Oyo said in the filing. The startup plans to deploy over $330 million to repay its debt. Oyo recently raised $660 million in debt.</p>
<p>The startup &#8212; which counts SoftBank, Airbnb, Lightspeed Venture Partners, Sequoia Capital India, and Microsoft among its investors and was most recently valyed at $9.6 billion &#8212; has not offered a ton of other details about what it is looking for from the retail investors, but here’s what we know: as we reported earlier this week, Oyo is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/indias-oyo-to-file-for-1-billion-ipo/">seeking a valuation of over $12 billion in the IPO</a>. And the startup’s young founder &#8212; Ritesh Agarwal &#8212; doesn’t plan to sell his shares in the public offering.</p>
<p>The filing today marks a major turnaround for Oyo that grew too ambitiously in international markets in recent years but corrected course by hitting brakes on some of those efforts.</p>
<p>Much like every other hospitality and travel firm, Oyo was also severely disrupted by the pandemic. At one point, the startup reported that its business was down by up to 60% as several nations enforced lockdowns as they scrambled to contain the spread of the virus.</p>
<p>The startup made a loss of $528 million on a total income of $600 million in the financial year that ended in March this year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But it has been showing signs of fast recovery in recent months as some of its key markets opened up in recent quarters. The startup said in the filing today that four markets &#8212; India, Indonesia, Malaysia, and Europe &#8212; account for about 90% of its overall revenue.</p>
<p>Oyo has also streamlined its relationship with hotels in recent quarters. The startup today doesn&#8217;t own any hotel of its own and instead works with over 157,000 partners and helps them operate hotels, resorts, and homes. It doesn&#8217;t promise any minimum guarantees to those partners.</p>
<p>The story of Oyo &#8212; in which currently SoftBank has over 45% ownership &#8212; starts with Agarwal, who left his rural town in search of a better education in Rajasthan. He often visited his friends in Delhi and stayed at their houses or rented cheap hotels. That’s when Agarwal, then in his late teens and a recent college dropout, spotted a budget hotel that was struggling to fill its rooms each night.</p>
<p>Agarwal then, he has said in the past conversations, convinced the hotelier to broker a deal to let him renovate the hotel and started marketing it to businesses in exchange for a cut of future commissions.</p>
<p>That deal immediately proved to be a success, which then propelled Agarwal to explore broadening his offering &#8212; now using technology &#8212; to focus on what were the neglected segments of the market.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2211100" style="width: 1510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2211100" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2211100 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-offering.jpg" alt="" width="1500" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-offering.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-offering.jpg?resize=150,64 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-offering.jpg?resize=300,129 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-offering.jpg?resize=768,329 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-offering.jpg?resize=680,291 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-offering.jpg?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2211100" class="wp-caption-text">Oyo&#8217;s offerings</p></div></p>
<p>That’s the beginning of Oyo, which immediately found success and soon enough attracted the attention of a fellowship run by the foundation of PayPal co-founder Peter Thiel.</p>
<p>Oyo first assumed the market leading position and then started to expand &#8212; beginning with Southeast Asia, Europe, China, and the U.S., to name a few markets. Its aggressive expansion bet has had a mixed success rate. It’s doing well in Europe and Southeast Asia, but making inroads in China and North America have proven to be more difficult than the startup likely assumed.</p>
<p>At the height of that expansion, Agarwal, 27, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/07/india-oyo-ritesh-agarwal-investment/">invested $700 million into the startup</a>. That year, he announced that he was planning to spend $2 billion through an entity called RA Hospitality Holdings to raise his stake in Oyo to 30%, from 10% prior to the $700 million investment. The filings show that now Ritesh and his other holdings companies own about 32 to 33% stake in Oyo.</p>
<p>Oyo said in the filing that its app has been downloaded more than 100 million times and 70% of its workforce lives in India. As of December 2019, it said in the filing, the startup viewed its total addressable market opportunity as serving 54 million short-stay storefronts.</p>
<p>&#8220;In India, Indonesia and Malaysia, OYO-powered hotel storefronts that joined the platform in 2018 and 2019 performed better than independent hotels of similar sizes in India, Indonesia and Malaysia respectively in 2019 on average. After 12 weeks of joining the OYO platform, OYO-powered hotel storefronts generated 1.5 to 1.9 times more revenue on average compared with the average revenue estimated at independent hotels of a similar size in India, Indonesia and Malaysia in 2019. In Europe, OYO-powered home storefronts earned an average of 2.4 times more revenue in 2019 compared with the average revenue estimated at an independently managed home in Europe in 2019,&#8221; it said in the filing.</p>
<p>Two interesting slides from the filing that offer an insight into Oyo&#8217;s business:</p>
<p><strong>Average revenue of OYO-powered hotels and comparable independent hotels pre-COVID (US$ &#8211; 2019).</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2211096" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-revenue.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="481" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-revenue.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-revenue.jpg?resize=150,70 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-revenue.jpg?resize=300,141 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-revenue.jpg?resize=768,361 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-revenue.jpg?resize=680,319 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-revenue.jpg?resize=1536,721 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-revenue.jpg?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><strong style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Oyo runs the second largest loyalty program in India among food, retail, hotel, and travel businesses.</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2211097" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-loyalty.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="399" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-loyalty.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-loyalty.jpg?resize=150,58 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-loyalty.jpg?resize=300,117 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-loyalty.jpg?resize=768,299 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-loyalty.jpg?resize=680,265 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/oyo-loyalty.jpg?resize=50,19 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><em>Catherine Shu contributed to this story.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/softbank-backed-oyo-files-for-1-16-billion-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210623</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>And that&#8217;s that, as the Zoom deal to buy Five9 is called off</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/and-thats-that-as-the-zoom-deal-to-buy-five9-is-called-off/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/and-thats-that-as-the-zoom-deal-to-buy-five9-is-called-off/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 01:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Five9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Talk about a roller coaster ride. Zoom, the video conferencing company that became everyone&#8217;s primary means of communication around work during the pandemic, will no longer be acquiring Five9, a maker of cloud-based customer-service software. Though the all-stock deal, announced in July, was expected to enable Zoom to tap into the lucrative contact center market, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Talk about a roller coaster ride.</p>
<p>Zoom, the video conferencing company that became everyone&#8217;s primary means of communication around work during the pandemic, will no longer be acquiring Five9, a maker of cloud-based customer-service software. Though the all-stock deal, announced in July, was expected to enable Zoom to tap into the lucrative contact center market, a few major hiccups along the way seemingly led to today&#8217;s decision.</p>
<p>First, Zoom&#8217;s shares, which moved in nearly a straight line toward the sky over the last couple of years, have more recently come under pressure, so the deal for Five9, which was valued at $14.7 billion in July, would have been considerably less today. (On the day that the deal was announced, Zoom&#8217;s shares were trading at around $360 each; they&#8217;re now trading at closer to $260 per share.)</p>
<p>It certainly didn&#8217;t help matters when Zoom last week disclosed that a U.S. Justice Department-led panel has been investigating the tie-up over concerns that it might create national security risks given Zoom&#8217;s ties to China.</p>
<p>Founder Eric Yuan is a naturalized American citizen who was born in China and moved to the U.S. as a 27-year-old in 1997. (Several years ago, we <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mzlObOyBZ9o">talked with Yuan</a> about overcoming numerous hurdles to do this.)</p>
<p>Zoom also said last year that it had mistakenly routed some meetings through servers in China and that it shut down the account of an activist who was using the platform to commemorate China’s Tiananmen Square crackdown. Afterward, the company, which has said previously that a sizable part of its development team is in China (as is the case with many multinational companies), announced it would not permit requests from the Chinese government to impact anyone outside of mainland China.</p>
<p>Still, the figurative nail the coffin might have been a recommendation two weeks ago by the proxy advisory firm Institutional Shareholder Service that Five9 shareholders vote against the acquisition over concerns about Zoom&#8217;s slowing growth.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That advice appears to have been heeded, with Five9 today issuing a news release that the merger plan had been “terminated by mutual agreement” between the two companies.</p>
<p>Zoom separately released an announcement of its own, downplaying the entire episode. Titled &#8220;<a href="https://blog.zoom.us/zoom-whats-next/">What&#8217;s next</a>,&#8221; Yuan writes of Five9 that it &#8220;presented an attractive means to bring to our customers an integrated contact center offering. That said,&#8221; he adds, &#8220;it was in no way foundational to the success of our platform nor was it the only way for us to offer our customers a compelling contact center solution.&#8221;</p>
<p>Either way, the development was expected evidently. As news emerged that the acquisition had been called off, <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">the share prices of both Zoom and Five9 barely budged.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/and-thats-that-as-the-zoom-deal-to-buy-five9-is-called-off/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211029</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Foxconn will build EVs for Lordstown Motors and Fisker at Ohio plant</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/foxconn-will-build-evs-for-lordstown-motors-and-fisker-at-ohio-plant/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/foxconn-will-build-evs-for-lordstown-motors-and-fisker-at-ohio-plant/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 23:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fisker Inc.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foxconn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lordstown Motors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Foxconn will build electric vehicles for Lordstown Motors as well as its other partner Fisker Inc. at a former GM factory in Ohio, under an agreement announced Thursday. Lordstown Motors, the beleaguered electric vehicle company that became publicly traded via a merger with a special purpose acquisition company, said Thursday it reached a nonbinding agreement [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Foxconn will build electric vehicles for Lordstown Motors as well as its other partner Fisker Inc. at a former GM factory in Ohio, under an agreement announced Thursday.</p>
<p>Lordstown Motors, the beleaguered electric vehicle company that became publicly traded via a merger with a special purpose acquisition company, said Thursday it reached a nonbinding agreement with Foxconn to sell its 6.2-million-square-foot factory. Lordstown purchased the factory in 2019 from General Motors.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, which has yet to close, Foxconn will pay $230 million for the facility. The deal excludes certain assets such as Lordstown&#8217;s hub motor assembly line, battery module and packing line assets and certain intellectual property rights. Foxconn will also buy $50 million of Lordstown common stock.</p>
<p>The companies said they will negotiate a contract manufacturing agreement for Foxconn to assemble Lordstown&#8217;s Endurance full-size pickup truck at the facility. Reaching a contract manufacturing agreement is <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">a condition to closing the facility purchase. </span>The parties have agreed to explore licensing arrangements for additional pickup truck programs.</p>
<p>The deal comes at a critical moment for Lordstown Motors, a cash-strapped startup turned SPAC that had a string of missteps earlier this year. In August, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/lordstown-motors-taps-former-icahn-exec-as-ceo-to-put-its-ev-truck-ambitions-back-on-track/">hired Daniel A. Ninivaggi</a>, a longtime automotive executive and former head of Carl C. Icahn’s holding company, as CEO and a board member. The appointment came after months of tumult at the company, including the resignation of its founder and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/lordstown-motors-ceo-and-cfo-resign-amidst-production-woes/">CEO Steve Burns. CFO Julio Rodriguez resigned</a> following a disappointing first-quarter earnings report that revealed the company was consuming more capital than expected and unable to reach previously <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/lordstown-motors-slashes-production-forecast-for-its-electric-pickup/">forecasted production numbers</a> for its electric Endurance pickup truck.</p>
<p>The goal of the partnership, the companies said in its announcement, is to present both Lordstown Motors and Foxconn with increased market opportunities in scalable electric vehicle production in North America. That includes Foxconn&#8217;s existing partnership with EV company Fisker Inc. (Lordstown and Fisker are separate companies and have no connection.)</p>
<p>In May, Fisker signed an agreement with Foxconn to co-develop and manufacture a new electric vehicle under a program called Project PEAR. Production on the Project PEAR car, which stands for Personal Electric Automotive Revolution, will be sold under the Fisker brand name in North America, Europe, China and India. Pre-production is expected tp begin in the U.S. by the end of 2023 and will then ramp up into the following year, Fisker told TechCrunch in an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/fisker-foxconn-ev-partnership-moving-faster-than-expected-ceo-henrik-fisker-says/">an August interview.</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Fisker didn’t reveal the U.S. manufacturing location. The final decision would be Foxconn’s, Fisker noted at the time.</p>
<p>Fisker issued a statement Thursday welcoming the news from Foxconn.</p>
<p>&#8220;Achieving key program objectives such as time to market, access to a well-developed supplier ecosystem and overall cost targets were all important factors in the decision to locate manufacturing in Ohio,&#8221; Henrik Fisker said in an emailed statement. &#8220;Since signing the agreement with Foxconn earlier this year, we have been working together intensively on all aspects of Project PEAR including design, engineering, supply chain and manufacturing. Fisker&#8217;s commitment to volume manufacturing in the United States takes another important step forward today with the signing of this agreement.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fisker also has another vehicle program in the works with a different contract manufacturer. The Fisker Ocean SUV will be assembled by automotive contract manufacturer Magna Steyr in Europe. The start of production is still on track to begin in November 2022, the company reiterated in its second-quarter earnings call. Deliveries will begin in Europe and the United States in late 2022, with a plan to reach production capacity of more than 5,000 vehicles per month during 2023. Deliveries to customers in China are also expected to begin in 2023.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/foxconn-will-build-evs-for-lordstown-motors-and-fisker-at-ohio-plant/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210994</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech giants brace for impact in India as new payments rule goes into effect</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/india-recurring-payments-rbi/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/india-recurring-payments-rbi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 23:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prime video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple, Sony, Google, Zoom, PayPal and several other tech companies as well as scores of banks have cautioned customers and partners in India to expect a surge in declined transactions as the world’s second-largest internet market’s central bank enforces a new directive for the way recurring payments are processed in the country. The Reserve Bank [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple, Sony, Google, Zoom, PayPal and several other tech companies as well as scores of banks have cautioned customers and partners in India to expect a surge in declined transactions as the world’s second-largest internet market’s central bank enforces a new directive for the way recurring payments are processed in the country.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India’s directive, which goes into effect on Friday, requires banks, financial institutions and payment gateways to obtain additional approval for auto-renewables transactions worth over 5,000 Indian rupees ($67) from users by conducting notifications, e-mandates and Additional Factors of Authentication (AFA). The directive impacts all such transactions for debit cards as well as credit cards.</p>
<p>The directive, which was<a href="https://www.rbi.org.in/Scripts/NotificationUser.aspx?Id=11668&amp;Mode=0"> first unveiled in 2019</a>, was scheduled to go into effect in April this year but was extended to September 30 after banks and other players said they were not fully prepared to comply.</p>
<p>India’s central bank was not amused by the way the industry handled its directive, saying in March that “any further delay in ensuring complete adherence to the framework beyond the extended timeline will attract stringent supervisory action.”</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India said in the original circular in 2019, that the framework was designed to serve as “a risk mitigant and customer facilitation measure,” adding that the issuer processing such transactions “shall send a pre-transaction notification to the customer, at least 24 hours prior to the actual charge by SMS or email, as per the customer’s preferences.”</p>
<p>Several companies have reminded their customers and in some cases, other business partners, about the new directive.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Apple reminded developers that due to the new directive, “some transactions that don’t meet these requirements will be declined by banks or card issuers.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>HDFC, the largest private bank in India, has posted the following message on its website: “Please note: Effective 1st Oct 2021, the Bank will NOT approve any Standing Instruction (e-Mandate for processing of recurring payments) given at Merchant Website / App, on HDFC Bank Credit card/Debit Card, unless it is as per RBI compliant process.” Several banks, including HDFC, Axis and Kotak have said this week that they will be complying with the new rule.</p>
<p>In May this year, Google stopped on-boarding new recurring payment customers on its Play Store. The company told developers that free trials and introductory pricing should be removed from the apps until &#8220;the ecosystem challenges are addressed.&#8221; YouTube has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/premium">moved</a> to support only a prepaid &#8212; pay as you go &#8212; payments acceptance model for its Premium service.</p>
<p>In the same month, Amazon said it was &#8220;<a href="https://www.amazon.in/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=pc_tc?nodeId=202042460&amp;tag=kp-web-inline-21&amp;SubscriptionId=AKIAJZ7ZVEW7WHEFIMWA&amp;ascsubtag=57752432">temporarily</a>&#8221; discontinuing new member sign-ups for Amazon Prime free trial until further notice. There hasn&#8217;t been any change to that notice since.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">After making payments simpler, we need to make recurring &amp; subscription payments easy <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/26a1.png" alt="⚡" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>It’s a pain to use any subscription product in India, not all cards work and random rules at banks <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f635-200d-1f4ab.png" alt="😵‍💫" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/tBrsoBOopx">pic.twitter.com/tBrsoBOopx</a></p>
<p>&mdash; pj (@BeingPractical) <a href="https://twitter.com/BeingPractical/status/1443432134945955840?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The directive doesn&#8217;t impact recurring payments made through UPI, a payments infrastructure built by a coalition of retail banks. Which explains why some firms &#8212; <a href="https://www.medianama.com/2021/09/223-netflix-upi-autopay-rbi-regulations/">including Netflix</a> &#8212; have added support for auto-pay on UPI in the country.</p>
<p>But its impact is likely to be far-reaching. A fintech founder told TechCrunch that the payments provider they use to advertise on Facebook and Google had informed them that their automatic-payments won&#8217;t be processed starting later this week, citing the central bank&#8217;s rule. The founder requested anonymity to discuss what he deemed to be sensitive.</p>
<p>The new rule is the latest in a series of guidelines the Indian central bank has proposed or enforced in recent years. As Pratik Bhakta <a href="https://the-captable.com/2021/09/fintech-innovators-brace-for-more-regulations-rbi/">outlines in a post on The CapTable</a>, the moves illustrate that though the regulator has encouraged the proliferation of fintech startups that are innovating for users, the RBI is closely watching whether any trend is attempting to hurt those consumers.</p>
<p>“Until legislation catches up, regulation has to adapt to ensure that the financial system absorbs digital innovation in a non-disruptive manner,” <a href="https://rbi.org.in/Scripts/BS_SpeechesView.aspx?Id=1129">said</a> RBI Deputy Governor T Rabi Sankar at a conference earlier this week. “We would only be able to reach a thriving and mature payments system if, over time, all stakeholders attach due importance to long-term improvements over short-term gains and internalise mature practices like informed consent and transparency of data usage.”</p>
<p>In emails to PlayStation Plus subscribers on Thursday, Sony said, “From 30 September 2021, you may see your credit and/or debit card payments for PlayStation Plus fail when trying to pay for a subscription on PlayStation Store.”</p>
<p>“This applies to both new subscription purchases and payment of recurring subscription fees. This means that any future PlayStation Plus subscription fees set up to be charged automatically may fail. If that happens, your PlayStation Plus subscription will come to an end.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/india-recurring-payments-rbi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210993</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What you should know about working with corporate venture investment committees</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/what-you-should-know-about-working-with-corporate-venture-investment-committees/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/what-you-should-know-about-working-with-corporate-venture-investment-committees/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 23:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate investment arms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate vc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate venture arms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital Firms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Brian Walsh demystifies the role of the corporate venture capital investment committee and shines a light on how entrepreneurs can navigate some of the hidden pitfalls.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Brian Walsh</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/WindVenturesvc">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bwalsh25/">Brian Walsh</a> is the head of <a href="https://www.windventures.vc/">WIND Ventures</a>, the venture capital arm of COPEC, a leading energy company in Central and South America and the U.S. WIND Ventures provides mobility, energy and retail startups and scaleups with access to Latin America.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/spacs-are-the-construct-vcs-need-to-fund-cleantech/">SPACs are the construct VCs need to fund clean tech</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/29/latin-americas-startup-ecosystem-is-not-immune-to-covid-19/">Latin American startup deals see major drop in COVID-19 era</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">With global corporate-venture-capital-backed (CVC) funding reaching $79 billion across 2,099 deals in the first half of 2021, according to<a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research/report/corporate-venture-capital-trends-h1-2021/"> CB Insights</a>, the chances are high that startups will find great opportunities with this growing investor set.</p>
<p>Entrepreneurs, however, are likely to discover that the investment process can be different for CVCs compared to private venture capital firms. While both types of investment firms tend to make decisions via an investment committee (IC), private VCs (inclusive of VCs with corporate backers that have an independent LPA structure) make up their ICs with firm partners and/or other venture-minded people.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			As CVCs become more active, entrepreneurs often don’t understand that the decision to invest, or not, doesn’t rest solely within a subgroup of the direct investment team or with venture-minded people. 					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>But for CVCs investing off a corporate balance sheet, the IC can include corporate-minded people, such as the CEO or business unit leaders, who generally tend to be detached from the venture mindset and the requirements for operating in the VC world. As such, entrepreneurs will realize that a successful CVC investment decision tends to have different requirements compared to a private VC firm&#8217;s decision.</p>
<p>So what do entrepreneurs seeking investment need to know about this relatively new but powerful participant in the funding process? I’ll do my best to demystify the role of the CVC IC and shine a light on how entrepreneurs can navigate some of the hidden pitfalls while taking advantage of the opportunities.</p>
<h2>The arbiters of investment</h2>
<p>While private VCs immerse themselves into the venture ecosystem, CVCs live in the middle of two very different worlds and mindsets: corporate and venture. The CVC must engage the venture ecosystem to attract deal flow while also driving opportunities that can be of strategic interest to the corporation.</p>
<p>To do this well, a CVC ideally should have a well-defined mandate and IC purpose statement — to deem investment opportunities as strategic, for example. A business unit leader or CEO who spends about an hour on a monthly IC session is nearly completely immersed within the corporate mindset while making a decision related to the venture world.<br />
<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/what-you-should-know-about-working-with-corporate-venture-investment-committees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210552</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Evil Geniuses CEO on the path toward esports ubiquity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/evil-geniuses-ceo-on-the-path-toward-esports-ubiquity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/evil-geniuses-ceo-on-the-path-toward-esports-ubiquity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 23:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evil Geniuses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nicole LaPointe Jameson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 Media and Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic brought a new class of gamers online for the very first time, and the gaming space has never been larger or more diverse. At the same time, while esports saw some viewership gains in the past year, it still had to deal with plenty of hurdles tied to pandemic restrictions on physical events. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The pandemic brought a new class of gamers online for the very first time, and the gaming space has never been larger or more diverse. At the same time, while esports saw some viewership gains in the past year, it still had to deal with plenty of hurdles tied to pandemic restrictions on physical events.</p>
<p>At TechCrunch Disrupt, we recently sat down with <a href="https://evilgeniuses.gg/">Evil Geniuses</a> CEO Nicole LaPointe Jameson who helms one of the oldest esports leagues around as one of the youngest CEOs in her class. We chatted about the challenges facing the esports industry to keep pace with a rapidly diversifying audience and the opportunities for building a league that can adjust to those shifts faster than others.</p>
<p>Evil Geniuses (EG) was founded in 1999 and has had a winding journey since. LaPointe Jameson got involved when the Chicago-based firm she worked for, Peak6 Investments, took over EG as part of an Amazon divestment following its acquisition of Twitch, which had previously owned Evil Geniuses. The capital injection came at a time when esports leagues were finally catching the attention of institutional investors who saw big opportunity in the space.</p>
<p>Years later, that potential is still there, but the path toward mainstream embrace has been more circuitous than many had hoped. Hard viewership numbers are hard to come by but signal a subindustry that&#8217;s growing more slowly than the overall industry it sits inside. Still, LaPointe Jameson believes the industry has plenty of room left for rising players to innovate and create new opportunities for the whole industry.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/evil-geniuses-ceo-on-the-path-toward-esports-ubiquity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210703</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Facebook releases internal research on Instagram&#8217;s mental health effects</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/daily-crunch-69/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/daily-crunch-69/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 22:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for September 30, 2021. It’s the last day of the third quarter! Yes, that means earnings season is coming, along with a whole bunch of venture capital data — more on that in a moment — but more importantly, how the <em>heck</em> is it Q4? Already?</p>
<p>From the TechCrunch side of things, cheap tickets to our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/">Sessions: SaaS</a> event are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/48-hours-left-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-sessions-saas-2021/">going away in short order</a>. So, snap ‘em up if you are coming. I’m hosting and even doing a panel or two. See you there! – <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gdmlWzYMuh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/48-hours-left-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-sessions-saas-2021/">48 hours left to save $100 on passes to TC Sessions: SaaS 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;48 hours left to save $100 on passes to TC Sessions: SaaS 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/48-hours-left-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-sessions-saas-2021/embed/#?secret=gdmlWzYMuh" data-secret="gdmlWzYMuh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/seeking-to-respin-instagrams-toxicity-for-teens-facebook-publishes-annotated-slide-decks/">Facebook spins own research:</a> </strong>The only way to get Facebook to release data and research concerning its own platform that hasn’t been filtered through its PR leviathan is to have it leak. Then Facebook <em>may</em> release it, but with a huge dose of its own spin. This, of course, is precisely the sort of transparency that the social giant is famous for and discussed before the Senate today.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/early-q3-indications-show-indias-startup-ecosystem-is-going-gangbusters/">India’s startup market on pace for staggering Q3:</a></strong> An early look into India’s rapidly expanding venture capital market indicates that the country could set fresh records in Q3. The India-China rivalry that we see in so many spheres now has a startup angle as well. We have even more on India in our startup notes!</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/alloy-raises-100m-at-a-1-35b-valuation-to-help-banks-and-fintechs-fight-fraud-with-its-api-based-platform/">Alloy raises $100M for anti-fraud work:</a> </strong>While we often write about fintech startups that feature consumers as their customer base, not every financial technology upstart wants to sell to you or me. Alloy is an example of a B2B fintech startup, focused on automating “onboarding identity decisions” and “transaction monitoring,” TechCrunch reports. The company is now worth $1.35 billion.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Before we start, TechCrunch’s <a href="https://twitter.com/bheater">Brian Heater</a> gets <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/actuator-6/">47 points for this headline</a>.</p>
<p>As promised above, let’s start our startup work with two stories from India:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/ola-electric-raises-200-million-at-3-billion-valuation/"><strong>Ola Electric raises $200M:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The Bangalore-based startup, which builds electric scooters, is part of the larger Ola empire, a huge startup in the Indian market that provides ride-hailing services in the country. Ola’s Electric business is now worth $3 billion, up from $1 billion two years ago.</li>
<li>And speaking of Indian startups now worth $3B, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/tiger-global-backs-india-ofbusiness-at-3-billion-valuation/"><strong>Tiger invests in OfBusiness:</strong></a> The $207 million Series F round doubles the value of OfBusiness in just two months, to a now tidy sum of $3 billion. What does the startup do? Per TechCrunch, it’s a “commerce startup that sells industrial goods and provides small businesses with credit.” Given how many SMBs there are in India, the startup shouldn’t run out of room to grow for some time.</li>
</ul>
<p>Next up, venture capital news:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/bgv-closes-fourth-fund-with-110m-aimed-at-immigrant-enterprise-ai-cross-border-startups/">BGV closes fourth fund worth $110M:</a> </strong>Benhamou Global Ventures, better known as BGV, has a fourth fund to invest from now, and it’s 60% bigger than its preceding investment vehicle. So far BGV has invested in 28 companies and expects that number to rise by more than a dozen with its new fund.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/these-two-former-corporate-vcs-just-raised-110-million-for-their-own-fund/">Counterpart Ventures also raises $110M, but for its first fund:</a></strong> What do you get when you take two former corporate venture capital investors and spin them out into their own fund? The backers of Counterpart are about to find out. The pair invested in Noom and DataRobot in their prior roles.</li>
</ul>
<p>And, finally, a venture round rundown:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/speedata-emerges-from-stealth-with-70m-and-groundbreaking-chip-technology-to-accelerate-big-data-analytics-processing/"><strong>Specialty chips are big business:</strong></a><strong> </strong>That’s the wager behind Speedata, which just came out of stealth and announced $70 million in financial backing. The fabless company is building what it describes as “the world’s first dedicated processor for optimizing cloud-based database and analytic workloads.” Given how big the data center market is, and how much demand there is for data science work, the company could be taking on a simply enormous market.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/mobile-gaming-company-voodoo-acquires-beach-bum/"><strong>Voodoo buys Beach Bum:</strong></a><strong> </strong>No, that’s not code or slang. That’s an accurate summation of my favorite bit of M&amp;A in some time. Per our own Romain Dillet, French mobile gaming company Voodoo is buying Israel-based Beach Bum, which “specialize[s] in tabletop and card games.” You can see how the latter could feed the former with ideas and IP. As a data point about how big the casual gaming market is, Voodoo claims 300 million MAUs, per its website. Casual gaming is <em>big</em>.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/forta-launches-with-23m-to-bring-better-security-to-smart-contracts/">Forta raises $23M for smart contract security:</a> </strong>As the blockchain economy (market?) grows, its security needs are expanding right along with it. And as smart contracts become an ever-more important function inside of the crypto world, their security needs are also rising. Forta, backed by a host of crypto-focused investors you have heard of, thinks that it has the solution to the matter.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/reachdesk-wraps-up-43m-to-expand-its-b2b-gifting-marketplace/">More capital for B2B gifting:</a></strong> On the back of corporate gifting startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/sendoso-nabs-100m-as-its-corporate-gifting-platform-passes-20000-customers/">Sendoso raising $100 million the other week</a>, Reachdesk has raised $43 million for its own efforts in the space. Corp gifting brings together e-commerce, sales tooling and IRL objects into a neat package.</li>
<li>And to close us off, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/accel-tiger-and-stripes-coo-back-mexico-city-based-higos-23m-raise-for-its-b2b-payments-platform/"><strong>Accel and Tiger team up to put $23M into Mexican B2B payments platform Higo</strong></a>. The company raised a far-smaller $3.3 million seed round just a half-year ago, making the Higo round another note on Mexico’s expanding startup market, a notably smaller deal from Tiger, and also, given how close it is landing to the company’s preceding investment, something of a very 2021 moment.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Scaling across Series A to C</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to find actionable, proven advice for scaling startups.</p>
<p>That’s because only 7% of the startups that raise seed rounds are able to grow their companies enough to land a Series C investment, according to a Dealroom study.</p>
<p>To create a framework for founders who are charting a path from $1 million to $25 million in annual revenue, Arthur Nobel, a principal at Knight Capital, conducted 47 interviews with founders and investors who&#8217;ve taken startups from Series A to C.</p>
<p>More than an overview, the article offers approaches for navigating the challenges of T2D3 (triple, triple, double, double, double) growth, specific hiring recommendations and other strategic insights.</p>
<p>As a bonus, the post also includes steps and visualizations you can use to create your own scaling roadmap.</p>
<p>&#8220;The takeaway is to initially figure out in which stage your company and departments are in and only do what is required for that stage,&#8221; writes Nobel.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1LhjpgV8u8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/scaling-across-series-a-to-c/">Scaling across Series A to C</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Scaling across Series A to C&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/scaling-across-series-a-to-c/embed/#?secret=1LhjpgV8u8" data-secret="1LhjpgV8u8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/tiktok-new-ad-products-invite-users-to-interact-with-taps-swipes-likes-and-more/">New ad products from TikTok:</a> </strong>Expect brands to have new ways to try to snag your attention on TikTok in the future, with the company working to bring “several new and interactive ad formats, ranging from clickable stickers to &#8216;Choose Your Own Adventure&#8217;-type ads to ‘super likes’ and more” to its social service. Whee.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/lordstown-motors-in-talks-to-sell-its-6-2m-square-foot-factory-to-taiwans-foxconn/">Lordstown may sell factory to Foxconn:</a></strong> Lordstown may sell a former GM plant it bought in 2019 to Foxconn. Lordstown is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/dogs-of-lordstown/">famous for not building EV trucks</a>, while Foxconn is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/29/18027032/foxconn-wisconsin-plant-jobs-deal-subsidy-governor-scott-walker">well known for not building factories in the United States</a>. So, call it a perfect pairing.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/facebook-messenger-releases-cross-app-group-chats-further-integrating-with-instagram/">Facebook brings Messenger closer to Instagram:</a></strong> Cross-app messaging between Facebook and Instagram is getting easier with <em>group</em> conversations now possible. The decision from Facebook to make Instagram worse to prop up its core app is a business decision that I suspect we’ll be chattin’ about for decades to come.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/spotify-rolls-out-podcast-polls-and-qas-to-creators-and-users-worldwide/">Spotify bolsters podcasting toolkit:</a> </strong>Music streaming service Spotify would like its users to consume more podcasts, both to improve its gross-margin profile and to give it pricing power in the future thanks to exclusive content. To that end, the company is rolling out podcasting tools including polls and Q&amp;A functionality to its global audience. The features were previously in beta.<strong><br />
</strong></li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants to help startups find the right expert for their needs. To do this, we’re building a shortlist of the top growth marketers. We’ve received great recommendations for growth marketers in the startup industry since we launched our survey.</p>
<p>We’re excited to read more responses as they come in! <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/daily-crunch-69/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210861</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NASA awards $253M to two companies developing electric propulsion tech for aircraft</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/nasa-awards-253m-to-two-companies-developing-electric-propulsion-tech-for-aircraft/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/nasa-awards-253m-to-two-companies-developing-electric-propulsion-tech-for-aircraft/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 22:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ge aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magnix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NASA has chosen two U.S. companies to develop electric propulsion technologies for aircraft, with the aim of introducing this tech to U.S. aviation fleets by 2035. The two companies, GE Aviation and MagniX, will conduct their work over the next five years. That includes ground and flight test demonstrations, as well as collaborations with other [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">NASA has chosen two U.S. companies to develop electric propulsion technologies for aircraft, with the aim of introducing this tech to U.S. aviation fleets by 2035.</p>
<p>The two companies, GE Aviation and MagniX, will conduct their work over the next five years. That includes ground and flight test demonstrations, as well as collaborations with other NASA projects focused on electric propulsion, data analysis and flight test instrumentation.</p>
<p>The awards, granted under the agency’s Electric Powertrain Flight Demonstration (EPFD) program, have a combined value of $253.4 million. Of that, $179 million was awarded to GE Aviation, with MagniX receiving $74.3 million.</p>
<p>“GE Aviation and MagniX will perform integrated megawatt-class powertrain system ground and flight demonstrations to validate their concepts, and project benefits for future [electrified aircraft propulsion] aircraft configurations,” NASA’s Gaudy Bezos-O’Connor, EPFD project manager explained in a statement. “These demonstrations will identify and retire technical barriers and integration risks. It will also help inform the development of standards and regulations for future EAP systems.”</p>
<p>The EPFD project is part of a larger NASA program called Integrated Aviation Systems, which conducts research and development to turn next-gen tech into real-world operational flight systems.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>There are many companies working on electric flight propulsion systems, but these are generally found in emerging air taxi markets, where the flights are shorter and the weight of batteries is mitigated by the overall small size of the aircraft. As <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/wright-tests-its-2-megawatt-electric-engines-for-passenger-planes/">TechCrunch’s Devin Coldewey explains</a>, needing to generate lift and the weight of batteries have been the “fundamental conundrum” that has held back electric planes.</p>
<p>Perhaps these public-private partnerships will finally crack the puzzle. The NASA project aims to develop tech for short-range and regional air travel, as well as narrow-body, single-aisle aircraft.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="w0AKZ03O2v"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/wright-tests-its-2-megawatt-electric-engines-for-passenger-planes/">Wright tests its 2-megawatt electric engines for passenger planes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wright tests its 2-megawatt electric engines for passenger planes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/wright-tests-its-2-megawatt-electric-engines-for-passenger-planes/embed/#?secret=w0AKZ03O2v" data-secret="w0AKZ03O2v" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/nasa-awards-253m-to-two-companies-developing-electric-propulsion-tech-for-aircraft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210967</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vlad Novakovski and Nicole Quinn to elucidate Series A fundraising</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/vlad-novakovski-and-nicole-quinn-to-elucidate-series-a-fundraising/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/vlad-novakovski-and-nicole-quinn-to-elucidate-series-a-fundraising/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 21:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nicole Quinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Live]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vlad Novakovski co-founded Lunchclub in 2017 as a way to improve professional networking. In 2020, the company made a large push toward videos (thanks, COVID) and eventually saw enough traction to raise a $24.2 million Series A at a valuation above $100 million. Nicole Quinn from Lightspeed Ventures lead the raise. We’re thrilled to have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Vlad Novakovski co-founded Lunchclub in 2017 as a way to improve professional networking. In 2020, the company made a large push toward videos (thanks, COVID) and eventually saw enough traction to raise a $24.2 million Series A at a valuation above $100 million. Nicole Quinn from Lightspeed Ventures lead the raise.</p>
<p>We’re thrilled to have both on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/check-out-the-amazing-speakers-joining-us-on-extra-cru-ahem-techcrunch-live/">TechCrunch Live</a> to help explain how to raise a Series A financing round. They’re sticking around the show to give feedback on pitch decks presented by selected startups.</p>
<p>TechCrunch Live also features the TCL Pitch-off, which gives folks in the audience the chance to raise their hand and pitch their startup to our guests, who will give their live feedback.</p>
<p>Nicole Quinn is a leader in venture capital and her portfolio is impressive, with such investments as Cameo, Zola, Goop, Calm, Haus Laboratories and others.</p>
<p>Vlad Novakovski co-founded Lunchclub in 2017 with Scott Wu and Hayley Leibson. In 2019 the company raised a $4 million seed round led by Andreessen Horowitz with other investments coming in from Quora’s co-founder, the Robinhood co-founders and Flexport’s co-founders. When the pandemic hit in early 2020, the company quickly turned focus to connecting professionals virtually.</p>
<p>Who reached out to whom? What did it take for Quinn to write the check to Novakovski and team? How do they work together now? <a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-live-with-lightspeed-venture-partners-and-lunchclub?ref=527261cda3f7">Join us on TechCrunch Live on Wednesday, October 6, at 12p PT / 3p ET to find out!</a></p>
<p>TechCrunch Live is 100% free to folks who attend live, but only TechCrunch+ members can access the content on-demand. If you’re not yet an TechCrunch+ member, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">sign up here</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/vlad-novakovski-and-nicole-quinn-to-elucidate-series-a-fundraising/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210859</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
