<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 15:41:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Looking Glass launches second-gen holographic displays</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/looking-glass-launches-second-gen-holographic-displays/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/looking-glass-launches-second-gen-holographic-displays/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Display]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holographic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[looking glass]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Brooklyn-based Looking glass today announced the release of a pair of second-gen holographic displays. Following up on late-last year’s release of the entry-level Portrait, the startup is offering new versions of the Looking Glass 4K and 8K systems, which sport 15.6- and 32-inch displays, respectively. In addition to sizes, there’s a pretty massive gulf in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Brooklyn-based Looking glass today announced the release of a pair of second-gen holographic displays. Following up on late-last year’s release of the entry-level Portrait, the startup is offering new versions of the Looking Glass 4K and 8K systems, which sport 15.6- and 32-inch displays, respectively.</p>
<p>In addition to sizes, there’s a pretty massive gulf in pricing here. Joining the $299 Portrait is the $3,000 4K and $17,500 8K. The pricing difference is all the more pronounced given that the tech essentially offers the same underlying technologies for producing and consuming 3D content.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176398" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176398" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2176398" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/4k___t-rex-by-Ashkan-Azarmi.gif" alt="" width="600" height="338" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176398" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Looking Glass</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Volume is a part of it,” CEO Shawn Frayne tells TechCrunch. “There are actually very few 8K displays out in the world at this size that folks are driving. While we expect the sale of that to be quite profound over the next few years, in the early phases we’re just not making the same scale as the Portrait.”</p>
<p>The company considers the Portrait a kind of ambassador for its technology &#8212; especially over the past year, when getting the systems in front of potential buyers was next to impossible. Having seen a number of Looking Glass’ older systems in person, I can attest to the fact that the effect really isn’t the same over Zoom. Looking Glass says it has sold 11,000 units and is shipping “thousands” a month as it works to fulfil demand and navigate global supply chain issues.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176400" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176400" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2176400" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/8k___medical.gif" alt="" width="600" height="338" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176400" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Looking Glass</p></div></p>
<p>“I think of it as their first opportunity to get their own holographic display without needing their boss’s approval,” said Frayne. &#8220;Someone is curious about it and they get it, and it lives up to or exceeds expectation and they go from there. The quality level is very high for the Portrait, and the bigger units are a bigger format version of that quality.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176397" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176397" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2176397" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Portrait_4k_8k___astronaut___t-rexby-Ashkan-Azarmi___Fruit-Bowlby-Jay-Howse.png" alt="" width="1024" height="595" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Portrait_4k_8k___astronaut___t-rexby-Ashkan-Azarmi___Fruit-Bowlby-Jay-Howse.png 5760w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Portrait_4k_8k___astronaut___t-rexby-Ashkan-Azarmi___Fruit-Bowlby-Jay-Howse.png?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Portrait_4k_8k___astronaut___t-rexby-Ashkan-Azarmi___Fruit-Bowlby-Jay-Howse.png?resize=300,174 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Portrait_4k_8k___astronaut___t-rexby-Ashkan-Azarmi___Fruit-Bowlby-Jay-Howse.png?resize=768,446 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Portrait_4k_8k___astronaut___t-rexby-Ashkan-Azarmi___Fruit-Bowlby-Jay-Howse.png?resize=680,395 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Portrait_4k_8k___astronaut___t-rexby-Ashkan-Azarmi___Fruit-Bowlby-Jay-Howse.png?resize=1536,893 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Portrait_4k_8k___astronaut___t-rexby-Ashkan-Azarmi___Fruit-Bowlby-Jay-Howse.png?resize=2048,1190 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Portrait_4k_8k___astronaut___t-rexby-Ashkan-Azarmi___Fruit-Bowlby-Jay-Howse.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176397" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Looking Glass</p></div></p>
<p>The new models will be replacing their predecessors, which were effectively developer units, rather than mainstream consumer products (though the company will continue to offer support). In addition to lower cost, the second-gen units are lighter and offer improved visual fidelity over their processors &#8212; particularly around the edges, where holographic displays can encounter issues.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RiITcVcbO3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/looking-glass-is-launching-3d-photo-software-for-its-holographic-tech/">Looking Glass is launching 3D photo software for its holographic tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Looking Glass is launching 3D photo software for its holographic tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/looking-glass-is-launching-3d-photo-software-for-its-holographic-tech/embed/#?secret=RiITcVcbO3" data-secret="RiITcVcbO3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/looking-glass-launches-second-gen-holographic-displays/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176393</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The TechCrunch List is dead. Long live commodity capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/the-techcrunch-list-is-dead-long-live-commodity-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/the-techcrunch-list-is-dead-long-live-commodity-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 14:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The TechCrunch List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s been almost exactly a year since we launched The TechCrunch List, a curated directory of venture capitalists designed to guide founders to the VCs most relevant to their startups. We had nearly 4,000 recommendations from founders — often with extensive documentation that in some cases exceeded 1000 words. From our initial edition to several [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s been almost exactly a year since <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/announcing-the-techcrunch-list/">we launched The TechCrunch List</a>, a curated directory of venture capitalists designed to guide founders to the VCs most relevant to their startups. We had nearly 4,000 recommendations from founders — often with extensive documentation that in some cases exceeded 1000 words. From our initial edition to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/the-techcrunch-list-update/">several extensive updates</a>, we ultimately selected 531 investors.</p>
<p>It was a great experiment used by hundreds of thousands of people with surprisingly deep engagement (people <i>really</i> love reading lists, apparently). Nonetheless, we are officially retiring the product today.</p>
<p>The reason is simple: the venture capital industry has radically changed over the past year, and the central thesis we used in constructing the list no longer applies.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>When we designed the list — which, to be clear, was never a ranking — we organized experienced investors across three main axes:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Specialization</b>: We believed that investor specialization mattered. We wanted to match biotech founders with biotech investors and ecommerce companies with ecommerce VCs. The bulk of our work reading through all those founder recommendations was identifying the brilliant investors in 31 different market categories who could offer differentiated strategic advice.</li>
<li><b>Stage</b>: We wanted to match founders with investors who would invest at the stage their companies were at, ranging from pre-seed to growth.</li>
<li><b>Geography</b>: We believed that local investors would have an edge over distant investors for founders, particularly at the earliest stages where regular counseling would be useful to reaching product-market fit.</li>
</ul>
<p>In other words, we took a very strong view that capital wasn’t a commodity, and that the right investor could radically change the trajectory of a founder’s ambitions.</p>
<p>When we started putting together the plans for The TechCrunch List in January 2020, the pandemic was just starting to spread around the world, and many of these assumptions still held true. However, as I think we have all seen, those assumptions have been completely upended over the past year.</p>
<p>The reality today is that capital has never been cheaper or more commodity. VCs invest rapidly, in all geographies, at all stages, in all industries, constantly, rapidly, and all the time.</p>
<p>I constantly heard this feedback over the past few months from both founders and investors. For founders, the focus on terms and price seem to consistently outrank nearly any other factor in building a relationship with an investor. Few founders would ever countenance lowering the valuations of their companies for a more experienced or specialized investor or an investor who was located locally. At the same price, these factors could differentiate one investor from another, but otherwise, price prevails, pretty much every single time.</p>
<p>Commensurately, VCs (and this applies most heavily at big funds of course) no longer care about any guidelines or theses around investing. Any stage, any geography, any market — if there is a deal to be done, they get it done and quickly. Tiger Global and SoftBank’s Vision Fund dominate this narrative, but there are at least a good dozen other firms that have similar styles these days. And given these are some of the largest firms by assets under management, they also just dominate the term sheets flying around the startup world.</p>
<p>If The TechCrunch List was about bringing signal to the noise of fundraising in order to save founders serious time and work, the reality is that the market today is just complete noise and frenetic chaos, and there truly isn’t much to be done to clarify that. The upshot is that VCs make decisions with more alacrity than ever before, so the good news is that the chaos should be short-lived for founders today.</p>
<p>So what’s next? We’ll continue experimenting with ways to help founders fundraise and find the best investors for them. That’s the premise of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/extracrunch/?tpcc=ecleftnav">Extra Crunch</a>, our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/">Early Stage events</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">the Extra Crunch stage at Disrupt</a> (which is coming up in just a few weeks — so <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/">buy your tickets</a> now!) as well as our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/extra-crunch-live/">Extra Crunch Live series</a> of discussions. Who knows, maybe we’ll introduce The TechCrunch List in another form in the future. But for today, it’s burned out and taking a nice, long, post-pandemic vacation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/the-techcrunch-list-is-dead-long-live-commodity-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176750</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investors don’t expect the US startup funding market to slow down</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/investors-dont-expect-the-us-startup-funding-market-to-slow-down/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/investors-dont-expect-the-us-startup-funding-market-to-slow-down/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 14:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costanoa Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MaC Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marlon Nichols]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valuation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanessa Larco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What’s driving the venture capital market in the United States to be as hot as it has proven to be? FOMO, plus the constituent belief that trying to time the market is a mistake.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Now in the opening weeks of the third quarter, The Exchange is taking a look back at the Q2 2021 venture capital market. Data indicate that it was incredibly active, with global and regional records shattered during the three-month period.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Per <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research/report/venture-trends-q2-2021">data from CB Insights</a>, for example, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/startups-have-never-had-it-so-good/">The Exchange reported</a> that global venture capital activity shot to $156 billion in the second quarter, up 157% from the year-ago Q2 result of just under $61 billion. More unicorns were born in the second quarter than any similar period to date, and valuations ticked higher.</p>
<p>The only data that seemingly didn’t come back in superlative fashion was round counts, which failed to set all-time highs in some cases. But the general vibe of Q2 venture capital data was clear: It’s a great time for startups looking to raise capital.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995210 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></span>To better understand what’s going on, we talked to investors from different regions to get a grip on how they view their market.</p>
<p>Today we’re discussing the U.S. startup world, including notes from Costanoa Ventures’ <a href="https://twitter.com/amyecheetham">Amy Cheetham</a>, MaC Venture Capital’s <a href="https://twitter.com/marloncnichols">Marlon Nichols</a>, NEA’s <a href="https://twitter.com/veelarco">Vanessa Larco</a>, and EY U.S. venture capital lead <a href="https://twitter.com/grabow">Jeff Grabow</a>.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why are investors writing so many checks? Let’s find out.</span></p>
<h2>A boom in venture-ready startups?</h2>
<p>Given the record capital deployed in the quarter, the fact that deal volume failed to reach all-time highs had us wondering <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">if the market lacked venture-backable startups.</span></p>
<p>If so, the lack of possible investments would help explain both rising deal size and resulting valuations. With lots of capital provided to venture investors themselves in recent quarters, a lack of startups that fit the venture model would force investors to compete with one another fiercely, possibly leading to larger rounds and higher prices.</p>
<p>That’s not the case. Instead, according to NEA&#8217;s Larco, “there are more than enough venture-ready startups to fund,&#8221; adding that “the pace of innovation across all industries and geographies has been astounding.”</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/investors-dont-expect-the-us-startup-funding-market-to-slow-down/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176692</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cadoo gets $1.5M to gamify fitness with betting challenges</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/cadoo-gets-1-5m-to-gamify-fitness-with-betting-challenges/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/cadoo-gets-1-5m-to-gamify-fitness-with-betting-challenges/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 14:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activity tracker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cadoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dorm Room Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DraftKings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthywage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[max altman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strava]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cadoo, a US-startup that&#8217;s gamifying fitness by turning it into a betting opportunity, using the prospect of winning (or losing) cold hard cash to motivate people to get off the couch, has collected $1.5 million in seed funds from Sam &#38; Max Altman’s Apollo VC and the student-focused Dorm Room Fund. The app itself has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.cadoo.io">Cadoo</a>, a US-startup that&#8217;s gamifying fitness by turning it into a betting opportunity, using the prospect of winning (or losing) cold hard cash to motivate people to get off the couch, has collected $1.5 million in seed funds from Sam &amp; Max Altman’s Apollo VC and the student-focused Dorm Room Fund.</p>
<p>The app itself has been around since 2018 but in March 2020 it launched a &#8220;challenge model&#8221; that lets users stake money to join a challenge related to a specific fitness goal &#8212; be it running 10 miles in 10 days, or walking three miles in three days.</p>
<p>Participants who achieve the challenge goal get their stake back and a pro-rata share of losers&#8217; staked entry fees.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A range of fitness levels are catered to by Cadoo&#8217;s challenges (&#8220;from daily steps to marathon training&#8221;), with some 50 public challenges hosted per week.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s also adding private challenges this month &#8212; which will enable users to host and configure fitness challenges for themselves/family and friends, or larger groups, such as companies, clubs, or schools.</span></p>
<p>Challenge-related activity is verified by <span class="il">the app</span> via API data from activity trackers and fitness apps. (Which hopefully means Cadoo is smart enough to detect if someone has attached their Fitbit to their dog&#8230; )</p>
<p>The app has support for a number of third party fitness services, including Strava, Fitbit and Apple Health.</p>
<p>CEO and founder <span style="font-weight: 400;">Colm Hayden describes the startup as &#8220;DraftKings for your own fitness goals&#8221;.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;Our audience consists of 25-50 year old fitness fanatics&#8217; who use <span class="il">Cadoo</span> to stay committed to their monthly/weekly fitness goals,&#8221; <span style="font-weight: 400;">he</span> told TechCrunch, adding: <span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;When people are serious about a goal they are trying to reach, they want intense motivation to back their ambitions.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>He says the app has attracted around 7,000 wager-loving users so far.</p>
<p>Cadoo&#8217;s business model is based on taking a fee from challenge losers before their entry fee stakes are distributed to challenge winners &#8212; which does potentially give the business an incentive to set harder challenges than users are able to complete.</p>
<p>But of course it&#8217;s up to users to pick which challenges to enter and thereby commit their hard earned cash to.</p>
<p>It also claims that 90% of users who sign up for Cadoo challenges successfully complete them.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hayden says it has future plans to expand monetization potential by offer</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ing winners fitness products &#8212; and taking a margin on those </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">products. And also by expanding into other types of verifiable goals, not just running/walking. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;We are working to build a motivation platform that enables anybody to reach their goals,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Financial incentives is an intense motivator, and 90% of users who sign up for Cadoo challenges reach their fitness goals. We are making Cadoo much bigger than just running goals, and in the future incentivizing almost any goal verifiable on the internet.&#8221;</p>
<p>While the app is US-based payments are processed by PayPal and <span style="font-weight: 400;">Hayden says it&#8217;s able to support participation internationally &#8212; at least </span>everywhere where PayPal is available.</p>
<p>Commenting on the seed raise in a statement, Apollo VC&#8217;s Altman brothers added: <span style="font-weight: 400;">“Cadoo makes it easy to motivate users to stay active with financial incentives. We believe the motivation industry that Cadoo is pioneering will be an important digital money use-case.”</span></p>
<p>Before the seed round, Cadoo says it had raised<span style="font-weight: 400;"> $350,000 via </span>an angel round from Tim Parsa’s Cloud Money Ventures Angel Syndicate, Wintech Ventures, and Daniel Gross&#8217;s Pioneer.</p>
<p>Of course gamification of health is nothing new &#8212; given the data-fuelled quantification and goal-based motivation that&#8217;s been going on around fitness for years, fuelled by wearables that make it trivially easy to track steps, distances, calories burned etc.</p>
<p>But injecting money into the mix adds another competitive layer that may be helpful for motivating a certain type of person to get or stay fit.</p>
<p>Cadoo isn&#8217;t the only fitness-focused startup to be taking this tack, either, though &#8212; with a number of apps that pay users to lose weight or otherwise be active (albeit, sometimes less directly by paying them in digital currency that can be exchanged for &#8216;rewards&#8217;). <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Others in the space include the likes of </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2009/09/14/tc50-healthywage-pays-you-to-get-in-better-shape/">HealthyWage</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> (a TC50 company we covered all the way back in 2009!); Runtopia and StepBet, to name a few.  </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="R8byTC9ijm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/01/the-future-of-sports-tech-heres-where-investors-are-placing-their-bets/">The future of sports tech: Here’s where investors are placing their bets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The future of sports tech: Here’s where investors are placing their bets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/01/the-future-of-sports-tech-heres-where-investors-are-placing-their-bets/embed/#?secret=R8byTC9ijm" data-secret="R8byTC9ijm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="n6C6MJQW5z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/fitness-wont-replace-the-gym-but-it-will-help-you-break-a-sweat/">It won’t replace the gym, but Fitness+ will help you break a sweat</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;It won’t replace the gym, but Fitness+ will help you break a sweat&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/fitness-wont-replace-the-gym-but-it-will-help-you-break-a-sweat/embed/#?secret=n6C6MJQW5z" data-secret="n6C6MJQW5z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/cadoo-gets-1-5m-to-gamify-fitness-with-betting-challenges/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176703</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marco Financial raises $82M in debt, equity seed round to support small Latin American exporters</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/marco-financial-raises-82m-seed-round-to-support-small-latin-american-exporters/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/marco-financial-raises-82m-seed-round-to-support-small-latin-american-exporters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 14:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arcadia Funds LLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cristóbal Silva Lombardi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jacob Shoihet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kayyak Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marco Financial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peter D. Spradling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176337</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Small and medium-sized businesses in Latin America finding it difficult to get the funds they need to export their goods to the United States is a gap Marco Financial is looking to bridge.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Small and medium-sized businesses in Latin America can find it difficult to get the funds they need to export their goods to the United States. It’s a gap <a href="https://www.marcofi.com/">Marco Financial</a> is looking to bridge through its tech-enabled risk assessment platform that can provide better insight on who should receive loans.</p>
<p>To continue its mission, the Miami-based trade finance company raised $7 million in seed funding and $75 million in a credit facility, led by Arcadia Funds LLC and Kayyak Ventures, to increase its credit line to $100 million. Marco was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/miami-based-marco-is-offering-revenue-based-lending-for-latin-american-companies/">backed last September by a small seed round</a> from Struck Capital and Antler and over $20 million in a credit facility underwritten by Arcadia Funds.</p>
<p>Additional investors in the newest seed round and expanded credit facility include Village Global VC, Flexport Ventures, Tresalia Capital, 342 Capital, Struck Capital, Antler LLC, Antler Elevate, Florida Funders and Fox Ventures. Strategic angel investors include Phil Bentley, CEO of Mitie, and Naman Budhdeo, co-founder and CEO of TripStack and FlightNetwork.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Jacob Shoihet, Marco’s co-founder and CEO, says not only is there a roughly $350 billion trade finance market to go after, but cited data learned from Javier Urrutia, director of Foreign Investments at PROCOLOMBIA, an organization that promotes foreign investment and nontraditional exports in Colombia, that for every 1% increase in export productivity, 500,000 new jobs can be created.</p>
<p>“For small and medium businesses in trade, this is important for companies creating a high level of job growth and lowering the poverty rate,” Shoihet told TechCrunch. “By making it easier for businesses to transcend the 30, 60, 90 and now even 120 days they wait to be paid for supplies, we can solve that gap and unlock billions in value so that companies can scale.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NNYVSNtKRv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/miami-based-marco-is-offering-revenue-based-lending-for-latin-american-companies/">Miami-based Marco Financial is launching a revenue-based lending service for Latin American SMEs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Miami-based Marco Financial is launching a revenue-based lending service for Latin American SMEs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/miami-based-marco-is-offering-revenue-based-lending-for-latin-american-companies/embed/#?secret=NNYVSNtKRv" data-secret="NNYVSNtKRv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Shoihet met his co-founder and COO Peter D. Spradling through the Antler accelerator, a Singapore- and New York-based early-stage investment and advisory services program that connects entrepreneurs and tech operators to launch new businesses. They started Marco in 2019 and now have offices in New York, Dallas and across Latin America.</p>
<p>Spradling was born in Uruguay and knows firsthand about the challenges of importing and exporting from working in his family’s slaughterhouse and later founding three of his own companies. In fact, one of his businesses imported e-cigarettes — his mother was a lifelong smoker, and he wanted to help her quit. He recalls pre-selling his inventory at a discount in order to get the money to import the goods.</p>
<p>“Banks don’t like risk, which means businesses spend most of their time trying to get financing rather than increasing sales,” Spradling told TechCrunch. “Banks in Latin America have a saying that ‘they lend money to people who don’t need it.’ Families with money can access the banks, but you can’t launch a business without capital, and many owners lack that access to banks.”</p>
<p>Marco’s factoring product enables new companies to get started without having to put up the significant amount of collateral that banks are asking. Banks typically look at financial statements for the past two years of the business and give a line of credit accordingly. Not needing as much collateral also enables more women in Latin America to become business owners because they often don’t have collateral, Spradling said.</p>
<p>In contrast, Marco reduces risk by basing its lines of credit on an analysis of the future potential of the business, thereby freeing up cash so that small and medium exporters can continue their operations and invest in their growth. The company is able to show what kind of financing can be obtained based on the amount of data customers provide. Marco also said it can reduce the loan origination process from over two months to one week and provide funding to approved exporters within 24 hours.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qTXbm9W76i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/how-tech-can-build-more-resilient-supply-chains/">How tech can build more resilient supply chains</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How tech can build more resilient supply chains&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/how-tech-can-build-more-resilient-supply-chains/embed/#?secret=qTXbm9W76i" data-secret="qTXbm9W76i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Cristóbal Silva Lombardi, general partner at Kayyak Ventures, told TechCrunch that Marco is providing an alternative for small and medium exporters to access capital that they previously had to get from friends and family.</p>
<p>In countries like Chile, electronic invoicing innovation has enabled the factoring industry to grow, and in turn, companies like Marco tend to become leaders in supply chain financing and shrink the high interest rates spread between small businesses and large firms.</p>
<p>“Marco wants to take that worldwide,” Silva Lombardi said. “There is a lot of value to tackle. Factoring is one of the corners in the financing market that hasn’t been tackled, and by using technology, Marco is building and creating value for the whole society. This is where venture capital firms should be putting their dollars — in companies where technology and talent unleash a lot of value.”</p>
<p>Since launching its product in January 2020, the company has processed thousands of invoices across 20 countries, amounting to more than $18 million.</p>
<p>However, it wasn’t easy in the beginning, according to Shoihet. Starting during the global pandemic, Marco initially had challenges accessing the market due to exports and supply chains being strained.</p>
<p>Today, Marco has found its groove and is lending as little as $25,000 per month and as much as $10 million, Shoihet said.</p>
<p>As such, the new funding will go toward simplifying cross-border payments, assessing risk and productizing ways to take unstructured data, processes and work to create a better experience for the customer. The company also said it aims to give large logistics providers the ability to finance exports on their own.</p>
<p>Marco was also able to attract new leadership, including Prajwal Manalwar, chief product officer, and Sabrina Teichman, chief growth officer. Manalwar worked for 13 years at PayPal, where he most recently was a product lead focused on debit card authorization rates and in-store payments. Teichman joins after 11 years with the U.S. government, most recently serving as managing director for the U.S. International Development Finance Corp.</p>
<p>“Now we can work on how to solve the problem at a larger scale by building infrastructure and information through the underwriting process and through partnerships from larger players in shipping, trade services and insurance — all incumbent industries that have clients with working capital,” Shoihet said. “By innovating the underwriting process, we can come to better conclusions and be the trade finance-as-a-service provider to clients in emerging markets.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="n44KRXor5F"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/startups-are-transforming-global-trade-in-the-covid-19-era/">Startups are transforming global trade in the COVID-19 era</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startups are transforming global trade in the COVID-19 era&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/startups-are-transforming-global-trade-in-the-covid-19-era/embed/#?secret=n44KRXor5F" data-secret="n44KRXor5F" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/marco-financial-raises-82m-seed-round-to-support-small-latin-american-exporters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176337</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ramp adds merchant &#8216;blocking&#8217; to corporate credit card</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/ramp-adds-merchant-blocking-to-corporate-credit-card/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/ramp-adds-merchant-blocking-to-corporate-credit-card/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 14:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Glyman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marqeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ramp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ask any employee and they’ll tell you one of their least favorite things to do is file expenses. And for companies, the process of managing corporate spend is one of their biggest challenges. Corporate credit cards help ease that pain, so it’s no surprise that the competition between startups in the space is heating up [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ask any employee and they’ll tell you one of their least favorite things to do is file expenses. And for companies, the process of managing corporate spend is one of their biggest challenges.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corporate credit cards help ease that pain, so it’s no surprise that the competition between startups in the space is heating up by the day. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the fastest growing players in the space is <a href="https://ramp.com/">Ramp</a>, a fintech company that earlier this year secured a $150 million debt facility with Goldman Sachs after having </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/ramp-raises-30m-as-the-battle-to-own-corporate-spend-heats-up/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised a $30 million Series B</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in late December 2020.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z5pTXxNMp2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/ramp-secures-150m-debt-line-from-goldman-sachs-as-the-corporate-spend-market-grows/">Ramp secures $150M debt line from Goldman Sachs as the corporate spend market grows</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ramp secures $150M debt line from Goldman Sachs as the corporate spend market grows&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/ramp-secures-150m-debt-line-from-goldman-sachs-as-the-corporate-spend-market-grows/embed/#?secret=Z5pTXxNMp2" data-secret="Z5pTXxNMp2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, the New York-based company is announcing a new feature that it says will give its corporate customers greater control and flexibility over the way their cards are used. Specifically, Ramp said it now offers its customers the option to approve or block merchants on the cards they offer to their employees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In an exclusive interview with TechCrunch, Ramp co-founder and CEO Eric Glyman </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">said the move was in response to customer demand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This was one of our most requested features, especially from companies with over 100 employees,” he told TechCrunch. “They said, ‘I can block a spam call. It’s crazy I can&#8217;t do this with my credit card.’ ”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176514" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176514" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2176514 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Merchant-Restrictions.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="448" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Merchant-Restrictions.jpg 2916w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Merchant-Restrictions.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Merchant-Restrictions.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Merchant-Restrictions.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Merchant-Restrictions.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Merchant-Restrictions.jpg?resize=1536,1011 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Merchant-Restrictions.jpg?resize=2048,1348 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Merchant-Restrictions.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176514" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Ramp</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the new feature, Ramp says companies “have complete control” over how their employees use their corporate cards, down to the vendor level. It allows companies to outline specifically who employees can spend with, which vendors can be charged on what card and how much they can charge. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, why is this a big deal? Glyman said this means that merchant-specific cards greatly reduce the risk from stolen or compromised cards. It also helps keep employees from inflating expenses or filing false reimbursement claims.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This gives security and control back to finance teams in a way that was never before possible,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also helps companies in their quest to save money by using corporate credit cards in the first place, Glyman added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“For example, they can restrict spending to businesses or companies that they have discounts or preferential pricing with,” he said. “It’s another layer of enforcement for finance teams.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The process was not an easy one since understanding and clustering unique identifiers to be able to identify merchants was “technically complex,” according to Glyman.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For its part, Ramp counts “thousands” of businesses as customers, with well into the tens of thousands of individuals using its cards.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2sOflCQqLO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/brex-ramp-tout-their-view-of-the-future-as-divvy-is-said-to-consider-a-sale-to-bill-com/">Brex, Ramp tout their view of the future as Divvy is said to consider a sale to Bill.com</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Brex, Ramp tout their view of the future as Divvy is said to consider a sale to Bill.com&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/brex-ramp-tout-their-view-of-the-future-as-divvy-is-said-to-consider-a-sale-to-bill-com/embed/#?secret=2sOflCQqLO" data-secret="2sOflCQqLO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re powering into nine figures monthly and over $1 billion in spend,” Glyman said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company must be doing something right.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since raising the credit line earlier this year, Ramp has seen continued growth, more than doubling volume over the past three months.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Glyman declined to reveal specific revenue figures, he said Ramp grew by more than 6,000% in 2020, compared to the year prior, and has grown over 1,000% over the past 12 months. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Customers are typically fast-growing startups as well as small businesses. Some of its more well-known startup customers include Ro, Sleep Eight, ClickUp, Marqeta, Candid, Better, Truebill and Nuggs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Ramp makes money mostly by interchange fees, Glyman said the two-year-old startup thinks of itself as a SaaS operator.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our long-term strategy is to develop great software,” he said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XgDmE6Jiob"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/as-corporate-cards-are-subsumed-into-software-airbase-posts-rapid-growth/">As corporate cards are subsumed into software, Airbase posts rapid growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As corporate cards are subsumed into software, Airbase posts rapid growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/as-corporate-cards-are-subsumed-into-software-airbase-posts-rapid-growth/embed/#?secret=XgDmE6Jiob" data-secret="XgDmE6Jiob" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/ramp-adds-merchant-blocking-to-corporate-credit-card/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176391</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Volkswagen&#8217;s new business strategy puts software and autonomous driving front and center</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/volkswagens-new-business-strategy-puts-software-and-autonomous-driving-front-and-center/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/volkswagens-new-business-strategy-puts-software-and-autonomous-driving-front-and-center/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 13:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argo AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volkswagen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vw]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Volkswagen will ramp up its software, mobility as a service and battery tech to stay competitive in the coming decades, as it and other automakers prepare for the largest transition in personal mobility since the invention of the car. Laying out the company strategy Tuesday, Chief Executive Officer Herbert Diess emphasized a top-to-bottom transformation in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Volkswagen will ramp up its software, mobility as a service and battery tech to stay competitive in the coming decades, as it and other automakers prepare for the largest transition in personal mobility since the invention of the car.</p>
<p>Laying out the company strategy Tuesday, Chief Executive Officer Herbert Diess emphasized a top-to-bottom transformation in everything from manufacturing to revenue streams. If revenue was historically driven by sales of internal combustion engine vehicles, Volkswagen CFO Arno Antlitz said the rest of the decade bring income derived not only from electric vehicle sales, but also software, autonomous driving and even ridesharing.</p>
<p>To that end, the company has been busy, planning six battery Gigafactories in Europe and an €800 million ($944 million) hardware platform research and development facility in West Berlin. The company’s also beefing up its in-house automotive software arm Cariad, which VW said could generate as much as €1.2 trillion ($1.4 trillion) in revenue by 2030, via subscriptions and other sales.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Volkswagen also has big plans for autonomous driving. The company wants to take a chunk of the market share from ridesharing and car rental, and it sees an integrated AV platform as the way to do it. Executives painted a vivid picture of customers being able to request a Volkswagen electric AV taxi or shuttle by the end of the decade, one that may not even include a steering wheel or driver’s seat, according to renderings shown during the presentation.</p>
<p>“Imagine that your grandmother or your eight-year-old son can hop in a Volkswagen cab to visit one another, whenever they want, without mom or dad behind the wheel,” Diess suggested. “You can use one of our mobility apps, and an ID Buzz will pick you up and your friends.”</p>
<p>Personal vehicles will be powered by Cariad, which the OEM said will have “level 4 readiness” by 2025. Shared mobility vehicles, like shuttles or taxis, will also be VW-owned and operated, and run on tech developed by AV company Argo AI. Volkswagen closed a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/01/self-driving-vehicle-startup-argo-ai-completes-2-6b-deal-with-volkswagen-expands-to-europe/">$2.6 billion investment</a> in the startup last June.</p>
<p>Europe’s largest automaker anticipates its investments in MaaS will pay off: the company expects annual revenues of over $70 billion in the five largest European markets alone by 2030, Christian Senger, CTO of Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles, said. The autonomous rideshare ID Buzz, which is being tested in a pilot project in Munich, will be rolled out as a commercial service in Hamburg in 2025, followed shortly by the U.S.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176708" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176708" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2176708" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-08.38.46.png" alt="" width="1024" height="572" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-08.38.46.png 2032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-08.38.46.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-08.38.46.png?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-08.38.46.png?resize=768,429 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-08.38.46.png?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-08.38.46.png?resize=1536,859 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-08.38.46.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176708" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.volkswagenag.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Volkswagen <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>In line with these estimates, the automaker anticipates BEV sales will account for 25% of sales by 2025 and 50% by 2030. ICE margins will likely come under increased pressure due to declining demand, tighter emissions regulations and comparative tax disadvantages, so Volkswagen plans to decrease its number of ICE models by 60% in Europe by 2030. Cost parity between ICE and BEV should be achieved within two to three years, Antlitz said, thanks to economies of scale and lower factory costs.</p>
<p>It’s an optimistic future, but one in which Volkswagen is fully confident: the company upped its profit target for 2025 to 8-9%, from 7-8%.</p>
<p>“Until 2030, the world of mobility will have seen the greatest transformation since the transition from horses to cars at the beginning of the 20th century,” Diess said. “The future of cars, the future of individual mobility will be bright.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ECNNhrKTL7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/rimac-automobili-founder-mate-rimac-shares-lessons-from-bootstrapping-an-ev-company/">Rimac Automobili founder Mate Rimac shares lessons from bootstrapping an EV company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rimac Automobili founder Mate Rimac shares lessons from bootstrapping an EV company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/rimac-automobili-founder-mate-rimac-shares-lessons-from-bootstrapping-an-ev-company/embed/#?secret=ECNNhrKTL7" data-secret="ECNNhrKTL7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/volkswagens-new-business-strategy-puts-software-and-autonomous-driving-front-and-center/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176696</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ring&#8217;s latest security updates are good, but still opt-in</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/ring-security-encryption-two-factor/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/ring-security-encryption-two-factor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 13:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Access Control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dark web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multi-factor authentication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Password]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175869</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ring, the video doorbell maker dubbed the &#8220;largest civilian surveillance network the U.S. has ever seen,&#8221; is rolling out new but long overdue security and privacy features. The Amazon-owned company&#8217;s reputation was bruised after a spate of account breaches in late 2019, in which hackers broke into Ring user accounts and harassed children in their own [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ring, the video doorbell maker dubbed the &#8220;<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/18/amazon-ring-largest-civilian-surveillance-network-us">largest civilian surveillance network the U.S. has ever seen,&#8221;</a> is rolling out new but long overdue security and privacy features.</p>
<p>The Amazon-owned company&#8217;s reputation was bruised after a spate of account breaches in late 2019, in which hackers broke into Ring user accounts and <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2019/12/12/she-installed-ring-camera-her-childrens-room-peace-mind-hacker-accessed-it-harassed-her-year-old-daughter/">harassed children in their own homes</a>. Then, taking advantage of Ring&#8217;s <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/epg4xm/amazon-ring-camera-security">weak security practices</a>, hackers had developed bespoke software to <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/3a88k5/how-hackers-are-breaking-into-ring-cameras">brute-force the passwords</a> on Ring accounts, which at this point were only protected by the user&#8217;s password. All the while, there were several caches of Ring user passwords floating around the dark web. Ring initially <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2020/1/17/21068703/amazon-ring-hacks-lawsuit-passwords">blamed its users</a> for using weak passwords (like &#8220;password&#8221; and &#8220;12345678,&#8221; which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/30/ring-security-control-center/">Ring allowed</a> users to set as passwords), but a couple of months later the company acknowledged its failings by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/ring-slightly-overhauls-security-and-privacy-but-its-still-not-enough/">rolling out</a> mandatory two-factor authentication by text message. It was a good start, aimed at making it more difficult — albeit only slightly — to curb the bulk of automated account hijacks.</p>
<p>But now Ring is going a step further by rolling out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/25/cybersecurity-101-guide-two-factor/">app-based two-factor authentication</a>, which many companies already offer (and have for some time) as it provides the far more secure delivery of two-factor codes using an encrypted connection, compared to text messages, which are susceptible to interception.</p>
<p>Ring is also enabling CAPTCHA in its apps to add another hurdle aimed at making automated login attempts more difficult by prompting users to prove they aren&#8217;t a robot.</p>
<p>Also announced is the launch of video end-to-end encryption, which Ring first rolled out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/ring-to-offer-opt-in-end-to-end-encryption-for-videos-beginning-later-this-year/">earlier this year</a> as a technical preview. One of Ring&#8217;s most flaunted (though highly controversial) features is allowing users to share video footage directly with more than 1,800 local police departments that are partnered with Ring. That said, police with a search warrant can always just <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/ring-police-warrants-neighbors/">demand the footage from Ring</a> instead. Video end-to-end encryption will mean that any video captured from a Ring device can only be accessed by the account owner — and not Ring, or any of its law enforcement partners.</p>
<p>Ring&#8217;s CTO Josh Roth said <a href="https://blog.ring.com/products-innovation/ring-announces-international-availability-of-video-end-to-end-encryption">in a blog post</a> that Ring believes that &#8220;our customers should control who sees their videos.&#8221; If that were true, Ring would have switched on end-to-end encryption to all users, giving every account owner privacy by default. But that would interfere with the company&#8217;s efforts to <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/technology/story/2021-06-17/ring-influencer-marketing-los-angeles-police-department">expand its police partnerships</a>, which in turn help to get Ring devices into the hands of local residents.</p>
<p>Compared to past security updates, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/ring-slightly-overhauls-security-and-privacy-but-its-still-not-enough/">didn&#8217;t go nearly far enough</a>, Ring&#8217;s new features make meaningful changes that give users the choice to make their accounts more secure and their data private. But the keyword there is &#8220;choice,&#8221; since users will have to opt-in to the new features. That isn&#8217;t unusual in itself; companies seldom force security changes on users fearing that it would add friction to the user experience, though recovering from an account hack because of poor security controls is undoubtedly worse.</p>
<p>Switching to app-based two-factor authentication is easy, just go to Ring&#8217;s <a href="https://account.ring.com/account/app/my-details">account settings</a> and switch from codes sent by text message to codes delivered by an authenticator app. We have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/25/cybersecurity-101-guide-two-factor/">a whole explainer</a> on why it&#8217;s important, why you should use an app, and which apps you might want to use.</p>
<p>But the biggest change Ring users can make is to <a href="https://account.ring.com/account/control-center/video-encryption/advanced-settings/end-to-end">switch on end-to-end encryption</a> on their accounts by going through the advanced settings of Ring&#8217;s control center. Switching on end-to-end encryption won&#8217;t limit what you can do with your account or stop you from sharing video footage with friends, family, or the police, but it will give you peace of mind knowing that you will have control of your data and what you do with it, and not Ring.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IGnNI5gpsv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/ring-police-warrants-neighbors/">Ring refuses to say how many users had video footage obtained by police</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ring refuses to say how many users had video footage obtained by police&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/ring-police-warrants-neighbors/embed/#?secret=IGnNI5gpsv" data-secret="IGnNI5gpsv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/ring-security-encryption-two-factor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175869</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amperity raises $100M on a $1B+ valuation to help company&#8217;s build better profiles of their customers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/amperity-raises-100m-on-a-1b-valuation-to-help-companys-build-better-profiles-of-their-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/amperity-raises-100m-on-a-1b-valuation-to-help-companys-build-better-profiles-of-their-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 13:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cookies and other third-party data sources are going the way of the dodo bird for many companies, regulators and platforms, and that&#8217;s giving a new emphasis on technology that will help companies better manage their customer data on their own steam. Today, one of the companies building tools for that end is announcing a big [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Cookies and other third-party data sources are going the way of the dodo bird for many companies, regulators and platforms, and that&#8217;s giving a new emphasis on technology that will help companies better manage their customer data on their own steam. Today, one of the companies building tools for that end is announcing a big round of funding, underscoring its growth.</p>
<p>Amperity, which provides a customer data platform for its businesses, has raised $100 million in funding at a valuation of over $1 billion. The startup typically works with large, consumer-focused enterprises along the lines of Starbucks, Wyndham Hotels &amp; Resorts, Patagonia and some 100 others, helping them to tap and organize their own data troves better to develop better profiles of their customers.</p>
<p>The Series D funding &#8212; led by HighSage Ventures with previous backers Tiger Global Management, Declaration Partners, Madrona Venture Group, and MaderaTechnology Partners also participating &#8212; brings the total raised by Amperity to $187 million and comes two years after the company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/15/amperity-series-c/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Series C of $50 million</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The last year of increased online activity and online shopping has put a much bigger focus on the data that companies are amassing about thier users and how they can better leverage that information to grow further. Amperity said that in 2020, annual recurring revenues were up 100%, partly on the back of that surge of interest in how to tap into customer data, not least because the older way of doing things has fallen out of favor.</p>
<p>Indeed, Kabir Shahani, the CEO who co-founded the company with CTO Derek Slager, believes that the trend away from third-party to first-party data has played and will play a much bigger role in Amperity&#8217;s growth longer term.</p>
<p>&#8220;Covid certainly &#8216;helped,'&#8221; he said, &#8220;but to me the story is less about that and more about how our idea has been validated.&#8221;</p>
<p>The idea  he and Slager had been thinking about was the dependency, and problems with, third-party cookies, an issue that has been lingering &#8220;for decades,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;When this idea started percolating, when we looked to start the company, we thought this must have already been solved. It was mind blowing that it hadn&#8217;t.&#8221; The reason why: data is in too many silos, and it&#8217;s not connected, which renders it impossible or at the least very challenging to use.</p>
<p>Amperity&#8217;s approach has been to build the connectivity to bring the data together out of its silos, and then to create ways to merge and make it useful. In that regard, it&#8217;s not unlike another company that also got some funding today, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/quantexa-raises-153m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Quantexa</a>, which originally build something similar to track fraud but is now also going after the customer data platform business as well.</p>
<p>As with Quantexa, Amperity has taken the approach of treating this like a big-data problem that AI can help solve.</p>
<p>&#8220;At the root of this is a hard computer science problem, all the disparate data runs off different keys,&#8221; he said. Some customer identifiers are based on phone numbers, some on physical addresses, some on email, and so on. &#8220;To connect all that you need one single key, but no one had done that before. So we thought, what if we tried to do that using machine learning?&#8221; They engaged &#8220;the world’s leading researcher in probabilistic data,&#8221; who built the models for Amperity, and that&#8217;s what powers the service today.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a massive market worth over $114 billion, so it&#8217;s no surprise to see investors like Tiger Global looking to get involved.</p>
<p>“<span class="il">Amperity</span> represents the future of how customer data can benefit both consumers and businesses by offering the most comprehensive AI-driven CDP on the market today,” said John Curtius, partner at Tiger Global Management. “The company’s technology is bringing outsized value to the biggest and most admired consumer brands in the world. Additionally, they continue to attract exceptional talent at all levels of the company to advance their mission, including the addition of Starbucks CEO Kevin Johnson to its board last year.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/amperity-raises-100m-on-a-1b-valuation-to-help-companys-build-better-profiles-of-their-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176687</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WebOps platform Pantheon raises $100M from SoftBank Vision Fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/webops-platform-pantheon-raises-100m-from-softbank-vision-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/webops-platform-pantheon-raises-100m-from-softbank-vision-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[as-a-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Club-Penguin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drupal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pantheon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redis labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serverless computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank Vision Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeWork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WebOps SaaS platform Pantheon, which started out as a Drupal and WordPress hosting service many years ago, today announced that it has raised a $100 million Series E round solely funded by the Softbank Vision Fund. With this round, Pantheon has now reached unicorn status, with a valuation of over $1 billion. Pantheon co-founder and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">WebOps SaaS platform <a href="https://pantheon.io/">Pantheon</a>, which started out as a Drupal and WordPress hosting service many years ago, today announced that it has raised a $100 million Series E round solely funded by the Softbank Vision Fund. With this round, Pantheon has now reached unicorn status, with a valuation of over $1 billion.</p>
<p>Pantheon co-founder and CEO Zack Rosen told me that the company wasn&#8217;t under any pressure to raise. &#8220;It really just helps us accelerate everything that we&#8217;re doing,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We didn&#8217;t need the funding. We had plenty of cash in the bank. We were planning to raise in a year or two years down the road. But we have a lot of conviction in and where this industry is going and our customers&#8217; needs are pretty apparent, so we just used this as an opportunity to pull things in by six months to a year and accelerate all the things that were already on our operational plans for the company.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176496" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screenshot-2021-07-12-165814.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176496" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2176496" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screenshot-2021-07-12-165814.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="108" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screenshot-2021-07-12-165814.jpg 1141w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screenshot-2021-07-12-165814.jpg?resize=150,54 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screenshot-2021-07-12-165814.jpg?resize=300,108 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screenshot-2021-07-12-165814.jpg?resize=768,276 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screenshot-2021-07-12-165814.jpg?resize=680,244 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screenshot-2021-07-12-165814.jpg?resize=50,18 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2176496" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Pantheon</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As Rosen noted, the role of company websites has changed quite a bit since Pantheon launched almost a dozen years ago. While originally, they were mostly about brand building and having a publishing channel, these days, they are directly tied to revenue. &#8220;The majority of buying decisions get made before anyone talks to a customer these days,&#8221; Rosen said. &#8220;All the research is getting done &#8212; hopefully &#8212; on your company&#8217;s website. Any link in an advertisement or link in an email is going to route that customer back to the website. That&#8217;s your most important digital product. And so marketers are really starting to think about it like that.&#8221;</p>
<p>So while hosting and publishing may be solved problems, driving revenue through a company&#8217;s website &#8212; and measuring that &#8212; is where Pantheon sees a lot of opportunities going forward. Though at the core of the company&#8217;s offering, of course, is still its serverless hosting platform and developers remain its core audience. But it&#8217;s the collaboration between the marketing teams and developers that is driving a lot of what the company is now investing in. &#8220;In order to deliver a best-in-class digital experience &#8212; and be able to iterate it every single day and work with designers and developers and website owners and project managers &#8212; you need a system of record for that work. You need a solid workflow for those teams,&#8221; Rosen noted.</p>
<p>Companies, he argues, are looking for a solid SaaS platform that provides them with those workflows, in addition to the high-performance hosting, CDNs and everything else that is now table stakes for hosting websites. &#8220;[Teams] want to stop thinking about this stuff,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They just want a partner &#8212; like any other SaaS application, whether it&#8217;s Stripe, Twilio or Salesforce. They just want it to work and not to worry about it. And then, once you have that taken care of, then you can move up into the things that really drive the outcomes these teams care about.&#8221;</p>
<p>As for raising from the SoftBank Vision Fund, which features the likes of ByteDance, Perch, Redis Labs, Slack and Arm among its investments (and, infamously, WeWork), Rosen said that Pantheon had its choice of firms, but at the end of the day, SoftBank&#8217;s team turned out to be &#8220;huge believers in this category,&#8221; he said, and could help Pantheon reach the scale it needs to define the WebOps category.</p>
<p>“Digital transformation has accelerated the movement to the cloud for essential business infrastructure. By automating workflows and do-it-yourself with its SaaS offering, we believe Pantheon’s leading platform is transforming how modern website experiences are created,” said Vikas Parekh, Partner at SoftBank Investment Advisers. “We are excited to partner with Zack and the Pantheon team to support their ambition of helping organizations embrace a new and better way of building websites that deliver results.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vlXXzDBiOD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/27/pantheon-bets-on-webops-as-it-charts-a-course-to-an-ipo/">Pantheon bets on WebOps as it charts a course to an IPO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pantheon bets on WebOps as it charts a course to an IPO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/27/pantheon-bets-on-webops-as-it-charts-a-course-to-an-ipo/embed/#?secret=vlXXzDBiOD" data-secret="vlXXzDBiOD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/webops-platform-pantheon-raises-100m-from-softbank-vision-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176463</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impact raises $150M at a $1.5B valuation as affiliate and other marketing partnerships come into their own</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/impact-raises-150m-at-a-1-5b-valuation-as-affiliate-and-other-marketing-partnerships-come-into-their-own/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/impact-raises-150m-at-a-1-5b-valuation-as-affiliate-and-other-marketing-partnerships-come-into-their-own/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176662</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Affiliate marketing may have started as a kind of side hustle for bloggers and others that were making the majority of their revenues through advertising or other channels, but with the rise of influencers and the huge profusion of spon-con on social media, the idea of leveraging a person&#8217;s own presence to make some money [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Affiliate marketing may have started as a kind of side hustle for bloggers and others that were making the majority of their revenues through advertising or other channels, but with the rise of influencers and the huge profusion of spon-con on social media, the idea of leveraging a person&#8217;s own presence to make some money and give a huge sales boost to a product, brand or service has taken on a life of its own. And to underscore that, today a company that&#8217;s built a marketplace to help connect people and companies in that larger set of relationships is announcing a big round of funding.</p>
<p><a href="https://impact.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Impact</a> &#8212; which has built a partnership management platform that lets brands engage people for influencer and affiliate marketing or wider business development; lets publishers also connect with brands and influencers; and provides the infrastructure both to track that content and collect revenues around it &#8212; has closed $150 million in funding on a $1.5 billion valuation.</p>
<p class="p1">Qatar Investment Authority (QIA) is leading this round, with Providence Public also participating. The company will be using the funds to continue expanding its partnership network as well as the kinds of tools it builds for brands, agencies and publishers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Impact runs what it calls a &#8220;partnership cloud&#8221; &#8212; somewhat akin to a &#8220;marketing cloud&#8221; &#8212; that it targets at what it terms the &#8220;partnership economy.&#8221; Those who use affiliate or influencer marketing to spread the word about their products; those who leverage their personalities or content to do that; and those platforms that house the content can all use Impact to engage with each other, and run their business operations within it.</p>
<p>&#8220;We started as a platform that was mostly used in a private marketplace setting,&#8221; said David A. Yovanno, Impact’s CEO, in an interview. &#8220;We were the first with a product and tech-led product in the affiliate space. We call this category partnerships but we didn’t come up with that term, our customers did after they started to use us in innovative ways.&#8221;</p>
<p>Impact has seen a big boom with the rise and increasing ubiquity of influencer marketing and spon-con. In the last year, the New York startup passed $100 million in annual recurring revenue, with its customers a list of some of the biggest names in the worlds of technology, retail and more, including Lenovo, Microsoft, Uber, eBay, Amex, CapitalOne, Disney, NBC&#8217;s Peacock, Walmart, Target, lots of D2C brands, and some other really huge tech companies that I&#8217;m not allowed to name&#8230; In all, its customer list has grown by 50% in the last year.</p>
<p>Spon-con and related marketing techniques have been on an upward trend for years, making gradually bigger dents in the 60% committment that brands typically dedicate to online advertising to get the word out. The last year of Covid-19 living has, perhaps unsurprisingly, worked as a particular boost, however: people spending a lot more time online, and much more time idling hours away on social media rather than engaging in the physical world, has led to a much bigger rush of brands leveraging that landscape to get their names in front of would-be buyers.</p>
<p>The snag in the market that Impact has been building to fix reminds me somewhat of the challenges in the digital music industry: initially, and frankly currently, it remains a challenge for rights owners in the world of music to accurately and efficiently track where and when music gets used, and then to collect revenues based on that, particularly when that music is used across the long tail of user-generated content.</p>
<p>A similar scenario exists in the spon-con world, especially when you consider how video clips are sampled and occasionally go viral, with those re-uses wander far from their origins in the process.</p>
<p>The play that Impact is providing here, therefore, is not just one of accounting and providing a marketplace for entities to discover and engage with one another, but potentially a big data play to track how and where content will be used and engaged with wherever that happens to be. If the space continues to grow as it look like it will, that means a bigger job and more investment needed to track the space.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/impact-raises-150m-at-a-1-5b-valuation-as-affiliate-and-other-marketing-partnerships-come-into-their-own/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176662</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ZoomInfo drops $575M on Chorus.ai as AI shakes up the sales market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/zoominfo-drops-575m-on-chorus-ai-as-ai-shakes-up-the-sales-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/zoominfo-drops-575m-on-chorus-ai-as-ai-shakes-up-the-sales-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chorus.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversational intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revenue intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zoominfo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ZoomInfo announced this morning it intends to acquire conversational sales intelligence tool Chorus.AI for $575 million. Shares of ZoomInfo are unchanged in pre-market trading following the news, per Yahoo Finance data. Sales intelligence, Chorus’s market, is a hot space that uses AI to &#8220;listen&#8221; to sales conversations to help improve interactions between salespeople and customers. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.zoominfo.com/">ZoomInfo</a> announced this morning it intends to acquire conversational sales intelligence tool Chorus.AI for $575 million. Shares of ZoomInfo are unchanged in pre-market trading following the news, per Yahoo Finance data.</p>
<p>Sales intelligence, Chorus’s market, is a hot space that uses AI to &#8220;listen&#8221; to sales conversations to help improve interactions between salespeople and customers. ZoomInfo is mostly known for providing information about customers, so the acquisition expands the acquiring company’s platform in a significant way.</p>
<p>The company sees an opportunity to bring together different parts of the sales process in a single platform by &#8220;combining ZoomInfo’s historic top-of-the-funnel strength with insights driven from the middle of the funnel in the customer conversations that Chorus captures,&#8221; it said in a release.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;With Chorus, the entire organization can make better decisions by surfacing insights and analytics that you would only get if you sat in on every sales or customer success call,&#8221; ZoomInfo CEO and founder Henry Schuck said<a href="https://blog.zoominfo.com/zoominfo-chorus/"> in a blog post</a> announcing the deal.</p>
<p>Ahead of the transaction, ZoomInfo was valued at just under $21 billion.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vAc33uC3zZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/13/chorus-ai-rings-up-33m-for-its-platform-that-analyses-sales-calls-to-close-more-deals/">Chorus.ai rings up $33M for its platform that analyses sales calls to close more deals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chorus.ai rings up $33M for its platform that analyses sales calls to close more deals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/13/chorus-ai-rings-up-33m-for-its-platform-that-analyses-sales-calls-to-close-more-deals/embed/#?secret=vAc33uC3zZ" data-secret="vAc33uC3zZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Chorus looks for what it calls &#8220;smart themes&#8221; in sales calls, which help managers steer sales teams towards the types of conversation and tone that is likely to drive more revenue. In fact, Chorus holds the largest patent portfolio related to conversational intelligence, according to the company.</p>
<p>Chorus was founded in 2015 and raised over $100 million along the way, <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/125617-96/company/profile#insights">according to Pitchbook data</a>. The most recent round was a $45 million Series C last year.</p>
<p><a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/focusing-on-relationships-chorus-ai-brings-in-45m-series-c-to-track-sales-conversations/">Crunchbase News reports</a> that at the time of its Series C round of funding, Chorus had “doubled its headcount to more than 100 employees and tripled its revenue over the past year.” That’s the sort of growth that venture capitalists covet, making the company’s 2020 funding round a non-surprise.</p>
<p>Notably PitchBook data indicates that the company’s final private valuation was around the $150 million mark; if accurate, it would imply that the company’s last private round was expensive in dilution terms. And that its investors did well in the exit, quickly more than trebling the capital that was last invested, with investors who put capital in earlier doing even better.</p>
<p>But we’re slightly skeptical of the company’s available valuation history given the growth that it claimed at the time of its Series C; it feels low. If that’s the case, the company’s exit multiple would decrease, making its final sale price slightly less impressive.</p>
<p>Of course a half-billion dollar exit is always material, even if venture capitalists in today’s red-hot, and expensive market are more interested in $1 billion exits and larger.</p>
<p>Chorus.ai will likely not be the final exit in the conversational intelligence space. Its rival Gong (often known by its URL, Gong.io) is one of the hotter startups in this space, having raised over $500 million. Its most recent raise was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/gong-going-gangbusters-grabs-250m-series-e-on-7-25b-valuation/">$250 million on a $7.25 billion valuation</a> last month.</p>
<p>The implication of the Chrous.ai exit and Gong’s enormous private valuation is that the application of AI to audio data in a sales environment is incredibly useful, given the number of customers the two companies’ aggregate valuation implies.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2NDkrDsjEP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/gong-going-gangbusters-grabs-250m-series-e-on-7-25b-valuation/">Gong going gangbusters, grabs $250M Series E on $7.25B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gong going gangbusters, grabs $250M Series E on $7.25B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/gong-going-gangbusters-grabs-250m-series-e-on-7-25b-valuation/embed/#?secret=2NDkrDsjEP" data-secret="2NDkrDsjEP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/zoominfo-drops-575m-on-chorus-ai-as-ai-shakes-up-the-sales-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176668</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Perch acquires Web Deals Direct for $100M+ to boost to its Amazon roll-up play</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/perch-acquires-web-deals-direct-for-100m-to-boost-to-its-amazon-roll-up-play/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/perch-acquires-web-deals-direct-for-100m-to-boost-to-its-amazon-roll-up-play/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roll up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web deals direct]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the heels of raising $775 million earlier this year, Perch has made a big acquisition that will bring on a number of new brands and operations infrastructure to enhance its position in the race to roll up smaller merchants that sell and fulfill sales through Amazon. The company has acquired Web Deals Direct, an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On the heels of <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/softbanks-vision-fund-2-leads-775m-investment-in-perch-sets-new-record-for-fastest-company-to-achieve-profitable-unicorn-status-in-the-us-301299324.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raising $775 million</a> earlier this year, <a href="http://perchhq.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Perch</a> has made a big acquisition that will bring on a number of new brands and operations infrastructure to enhance its position in the race to roll up smaller merchants that sell and fulfill sales through Amazon. The company has acquired <a href="https://webdealsdirect.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Web Deals Direct</a>, an Amazon seller that owns 30 brands of its own pulling in $80 million in revenue annually and also operates its own warehouse.</p>
<p>Terms of the deal are not being disclosed but I understand from sources that it was a nine-figure deal valued between $100 million and $200 million.</p>
<p>There are millions of merchants currently on Amazon&#8217;s marketplace, leveraging the e-commerce giant&#8217;s storefront, search tools, fulfillment infrastructure, payment tools, warehouses and delivery network to sell products to buyers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Companies like Perch compete against the likes of Elevate Brands (which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elevate-brands-banks-250m-to-roll-up-third-party-merchants-selling-on-amazons-marketplace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">yesterday announced $250 million in funding</a>), Thrasio, Heyday, SellerX, Branded, Razor Group and many others that are seizing an opportunity to snap up and roll up the more successful of these to bring better economies of scale into the model, while also building technology to better measure and leverage sales analytics and more.</p>
<p>While these companies are, essentially, acting as marketplace consolidators, this latest acquisition is significant because, in a sense, it underscores an interesting shift towards a consolidation of the consolidators themselves.</p>
<p>WDD&#8217;s categories span home goods, sports, arts and crafts, pet supplies and office products, and Perch&#8217;s VP of acquisitions, <span class="il">Nate</span> Jackson, said Perch was interested in them because they are one of the more successful Amazon merchants. In a market where visibility is based on how well engaged previous buyers are with your products, WDD has picked up some 110,000 reviews and 2.3 million customers.</p>
<p>For WDD the idea is that joining Perch will give it more reach in terms of targeting more customers, and to bring it better analytics leveraging insights and sales from Perch&#8217;s other brands, which currently number at around 70 and cover the same categories.</p>
<p>&#8220;We took our business from zero to $80 million in sales in 5 short years,” said Adam Feinberg, CEO of Web Deals Direct, in a statement. “But, with Perch, who are proven eCommerce operators, we think the possibilities of growth in the next 5 years are just as exciting. I’ve been so impressed with the caliber of their team, and I trust their long-term vision to steward our business into the next phase of growth. This was a complex deal, but Perch has made the process fair and transparent. I want to thank all of the great Web Deals Direct team members for the organization we’ve built together; our employees could not be in better hands with Perch.”</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also a signal of what the next steps might be for these roll-up companies, with Perch gaining a 230,000 square foot warehouse in California and now looking to get more warehouse space on the East Coast. While Amazon might still be an important storefront for visibility, it&#8217;s a sign of how these companies may be looking at taking on more of the process themselves on the fulfillment side to grow margins.</p>
<p>“This deal marks a major milestone for Perch,” said Perch founder and CEO, Chris Bell, in a statement. “The complexity and size of the business is a testament to the excellent organization Adam and the entire team at Web Deals Direct have built, and it is a pleasure to work with such inspirational entrepreneurs.”</p>
<p>This is not a completely new area for Perch, and perhaps the writing has always been on the wall that it would eventually bring more fulfillment into its own e-commerce operations to lessen some of the reliance on Amazon.</p>
<p>Before founding Perch, Bell and Perch&#8217;s COO designed and built the Wayfair Delivery Network for online furniture company Wayfair &#8212; a service that handled 3 million &#8220;heavy bulky orders&#8221; annually, and did so with a view to speeding up the turnaround time, turning what typically takes a month to deliver into a two-day process. That will be some of what the team now hopes to bring to Perch, it seems.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/perch-acquires-web-deals-direct-for-100m-to-boost-to-its-amazon-roll-up-play/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176636</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Programming robots to put jackets on people is harder than it looks</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/programming-robots-to-put-jackets-on-people-is-harder-than-it-looks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/programming-robots-to-put-jackets-on-people-is-harder-than-it-looks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSAIL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT CSAIL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If there’s one thing we’ve learned from some of our favorite YouTube shitty robots, it’s that human-robot interaction can be a tricky business. Developing methods to get rigid robotic arms to perform delicate tasks around soft human bodies is easier said than done. This week, a team at MIT’s CSAIL department is showcasing its work [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If there’s one thing we’ve learned from some of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/video/making-sh-with-simone-giertz-this-is-an-adventure-inc/">our favorite YouTube shitty robots</a>, it’s that human-robot interaction can be a tricky business. Developing methods to get rigid robotic arms to perform delicate tasks around soft human bodies is easier said than done.</p>
<p>This week, a team at MIT’s CSAIL department is <a href="https://www.csail.mit.edu/news/getting-dressed-help-robots">showcasing its work using robotic arms to help people get dressed</a>. The promise of such technology is clear: helping people with mobility issues perform tasks that many of us take for granted.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-9JrDMBg2HE?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Among the biggest hurdles is creating algorithms that are able to navigate around the human form efficiently, without hurting the person it&#8217;s trying to help. Preprogrammed modes can run into all sorts of variables, including shapes and human reactions. Overreacting to variables, on the other hand, can effectively freeze the robot, unsure of the best route to take.</p>
<p>So, the team set out to develop a system that could adapt to different scenarios and learn as it goes.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176438" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176438" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2176438" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_5614.png" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_5614.png 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_5614.png?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_5614.png?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_5614.png?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_5614.png?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_5614.png?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_5614.png?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_5614.png?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176438" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> MIT CSAIL</p></div></p>
<p>“To provide a theoretical guarantee of human safety, the team&#8217;s algorithm reasons about the uncertainty in the human model. Instead of having a single, default model where the robot only understands one potential reaction, the team gave the machine an understanding of many possible models, to more closely mimic how a human can understand other humans,” MIT writes in a blog post. As the robot gathers more data, it will reduce uncertainty and refine those models.”</p>
<p>The team says it will also be researching how human subjects react to these sorts of tasks.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nf0BLgMRWp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/cables-could-help-soft-robots-transform-into-harder-structures/">Cables could help soft robots transform into harder structures</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cables could help soft robots transform into harder structures&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/cables-could-help-soft-robots-transform-into-harder-structures/embed/#?secret=nf0BLgMRWp" data-secret="nf0BLgMRWp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/programming-robots-to-put-jackets-on-people-is-harder-than-it-looks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176436</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arctic Wolf secures $150M at Series F, tripling its valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/arctic-wolf-series-f/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/arctic-wolf-series-f/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Viking Global Investors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176016</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Arctic Wolf, a managed cybersecurity company that offers &#8220;security operations-as-a-concierge&#8221; service, has raised $150 million at Series F. This round was led by Viking Global Investors, Owl Rock, and other existing investors, and lands less than a year after the company’s last round of investment when it became the first managed detection and response (MDR) [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Arctic Wolf, a managed cybersecurity company that offers &#8220;security operations-as-a-concierge&#8221; service, has raised $150 million at Series F.</p>
<p>This round was led by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/viking-global-investors/">Viking Global Investors</a>, Owl Rock, and other existing investors, and lands less than a year after the company’s last round of investment when it became the first managed detection and response (MDR) companies to secure a valuation of over $1 billion. This latest round brings its total amount of funding raised to date to just shy of $500 million, and sees the company’s valuation soar from $1.3 billion to $4.3 billion.</p>
<p>“This is a recognition on our part, and our investors’ part, of the challenge that our industry is facing,” Arctic Wolf CEO Brian NeSmith told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>As a result of this challenging <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/cybersecurity/">cybersecurity</a> landscape, fueled by pandemic turbulence and a mass shift to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/remote-work/">remote working</a>, Arctic Wolf has seen impressive growth over the last 12 months. The company, which provides round-the-clock security monitoring for small and mid-sized organizations through its cloud security operations platform, saw its revenues double on rapid platform adoption growth, with nearly 60% of its 3,000 customers using at least three of its security operations solutions. This, the company claims, makes it fastest-growing company at scale in the fastest-growing area of the cybersecurity market.</p>
<p>The company’s headcount has also increased dramatically: the company onboard approximately 400 employees over the past 12 months and plans to add 500 new roles in the coming year.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The newly-raised funds will be used to keep its momentum going, NeSmith said, and to step up its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ma/">mergers and acquisitions</a> strategy. Arctic Wolf has made three acquisitions since it was founded 2012 — including cybersecurity vulnerability assessment startup RootSecure in 2018 — and it&#8217;s planning to increase this number significantly over the next 12 months.</p>
<p>“We’ve got letters of intent for a couple more, and I expect that over the next year we’ll probably do between 5 and 10 acquisitions,” said NeSmith.</p>
<p>With Series F funding under its belt, Arctic Wolf is now starting to think about its exit strategy. NeSmith tells TechCrunch that while the company is weighing up its options, an IPO is likely the next logical move for the company.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>“I think ultimately the exit is IPO. That’s the most likely outcome,” he says. “Frankly, from some of the companies I’ve seen IPO over the last 3-6 months, we could be a public company today. We’re a little more measured, so we want to realize that not being public is an end point, you’re just changing the way you run the company.”</p>
<p><b>Read more:</b></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/microsoft-to-acquire-riskiq/">Microsoft confirms it’s buying cybersecurity startup RiskIQ</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/zerofox-acquires-dark-web-threat-intelligence-company-vigilante/">ZeroFox acquires dark web threat intelligence company Vigilante</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/barracuda-enters-xdr-market-with-skout-cybersecurity-acquisition/">Barracuda acquires Skout Cybersecurity to enter the XDR market</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/noname-security-closes-60m-series-b-to-eliminate-api-flaws/">Noname Security closes $60M Series B to eliminate API flaws</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/zero-trust-unicorn-illumio-closes-225m-series-f-led-by-thoma-brava/">Zero trust unicorn Illumio closes $225M Series F led by Thoma Bravo</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/arctic-wolf-series-f/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176016</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Female Founders Fund closes third fund with $57M for female founders</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/female-founder-fund-closes-third-fund-with-57m-for-female-bipoc-founders/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/female-founder-fund-closes-third-fund-with-57m-for-female-bipoc-founders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anne wojcicki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anu Duggal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Female Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pivotal Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Susan Wojcicki]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Female Founders Fund announced Tuesday the closing of its Fund III after raising $57 million to create what it considers “the largest fund for seed capital specifically for female founders.”]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://femalefoundersfund.com/">Female Founders Fund</a> announced Tuesday the closing of its Fund III after raising $57 million to create what the seven-year-old New York-based early-stage fund considers “the largest fund for seed capital specifically for female founders.”</p>
<p>The oversubscribed fund is backed by institutional investors including Goldman Sachs, Cambridge Associates, Melinda French Gates’ Pivotal Ventures, Twitter, Plexo Capital and the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation. It also includes investments from 23andMe founder Anne Wojcicki, YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki and Houseparty co-founder Sima Sistani.</p>
<p>“I firmly believe we are missing out on transformational ideas by not putting resources behind women,” said Melinda French Gates, founder of Pivotal Ventures, in a statement. “I’ve invested in the Female Founders Fund because we need women founders and funders at the table if we want to build a more prosperous and inclusive economy for everyone. New and innovative ideas come from everywhere; we can&#8217;t keep looking in the same old packages.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Fund III brings FFF’s total assets under management to over $95 million since it was formed in 2014 to invest in female-founded technology companies and lifestyle brands. The third fund’s portfolio is already 70% invested in BIPOC founders, which stands for Black, Indigenous and people of color, Anu Duggal, founding partner of Female Founders Fund, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>FFF began raising its third fund in 2020, making its first close just before the global pandemic locked everything down. That didn’t slow down Duggal’s ability to meet potential investors, which she said was done from her kitchen table.</p>
<p>“It was an incredible testament to how fast so much can be done without the flights and in-person meetings, which does take a bunch of time,” she said. “I think investors felt the same because March through June was preoccupied with making sure portfolio companies were in a good spot.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="g56cOlkmgw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/anu-duggal-on-covid-19-promoting-diversity-and-building-a-fund/">Anu Duggal on COVID-19, promoting diversity and building a fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Anu Duggal on COVID-19, promoting diversity and building a fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/anu-duggal-on-covid-19-promoting-diversity-and-building-a-fund/embed/#?secret=g56cOlkmgw" data-secret="g56cOlkmgw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The new fund is a continuation of FFF’s existing strategy — essentially doubling down on investing in female, women of color and LGBTQ+ founders who are building companies at the seed stage. The biggest differentiator with the third fund is that FFF will be able to increase its check sizes to between $750,000 to $1 million, Duggal said. Half of the fund will go to follow-on funding.</p>
<p>While fundraising over the past 18 months, Duggal said she was inspired by the momentum of female-led companies going public, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/bumble-ipo-could-raise-more-than-1b-for-dating-service/">Bumble</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/23andme-set-to-go-public-via-a-virgin-group-spac-merger/">23andMe</a> and Figs, which also drove investor backing of the new fund, she added.</p>
<p>Fund III’s fundraising goal is in line with the transition from FFF’s previous funds: Fund I was $6 million and Fund II was $25 million. So far, FFF has invested in more than 50 female-led companies nationwide.</p>
<p>To date, FFF has invested in seven companies from Fund III, including a few that haven’t been announced yet or are in stealth mode. Duggal expects to be able to invest in 25 companies from this fund.</p>
<p>Many of the companies are pre-launch, so there aren’t early successes quite yet, but one of the first investments was in an at-home blood test created by one of Facebook’s female engineers, she said. FFF was able to bring in Anne Wojcicki as an angel investor.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1Bq28HH1c3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/despite-gains-gender-diversity-in-vc-funding-struggled-in-2020/">Despite gains, gender diversity in VC funding struggled in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Despite gains, gender diversity in VC funding struggled in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/despite-gains-gender-diversity-in-vc-funding-struggled-in-2020/embed/#?secret=1Bq28HH1c3" data-secret="1Bq28HH1c3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“One of our themes is consumerization of digital health, and this is a great example,” Duggal said. “It can be annoying to have to go get blood drawn, and this is putting the experience and the data in the hands of the consumer.”</p>
<p>The Female Founders Fund is also looking at startups focused on the development of the workplace — tools for employees, small businesses and creators. Most everyone had to adjust to a pandemic working lifestyle, and the firm doesn’t see that ending soon.</p>
<p>Two newer areas of focus are climate change and education. Within education, FFF sees a trend in opportunities for technology to enable senior citizens to remain mentally engaged through continuing education. The firm is also looking at the climate market for technology to replace plastic food containers, refillable solutions, alternatives to meat and ways to record carbon usages on a daily basis.</p>
<p>“From day one, we have been committed to building the largest and most powerful network of female operators in technology,” Duggal added. “We are happy with the support we have received from Anne Wojcicki and Susan Wojcicki, Houseparty and some of our founders, as well as Melinda French Gates. This shows that we are developing something that is unique.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ClP9bnthEE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/the-artemis-fund-focuses-on-women-founders-in-underserved-communities/">The Artemis Fund focuses on women founders in underserved communities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Artemis Fund focuses on women founders in underserved communities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/the-artemis-fund-focuses-on-women-founders-in-underserved-communities/embed/#?secret=ClP9bnthEE" data-secret="ClP9bnthEE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/female-founder-fund-closes-third-fund-with-57m-for-female-bipoc-founders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176342</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Micromobility operator Veo raises $16M to fund U.S. expansion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/micromobility-operator-veo-raises-16m-to-fund-u-s-expansion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/micromobility-operator-veo-raises-16m-to-fund-u-s-expansion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autotech Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-scooter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scooter sharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Series A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shared micromobility operator Veo has raised $16 million in new funding as the company ramps up its expansion plans in the United States. The Series A funding round, which follows permit awards in Santa Monica, San Diego and New York, will be used to expand Veo&#8217;s fleet and focus on developing city and community partnerships. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Shared micromobility operator Veo has raised $16 million in new funding as the company ramps up its expansion plans in the United States. The Series A funding round, which follows permit awards in Santa Monica, San Diego and New York, will be used to expand Veo&#8217;s fleet and focus on developing city and community partnerships.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Veo, which was founded in 2017,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has sought venture funding a bit later in the game than other micromobility companies. </span><a href="https://veo-mobility.medium.com/sorry-boys-the-first-profitable-micromobility-company-was-veo-not-lime-97b6b279243f?source=user_profile---------4----------------------------"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Veo’s co-founder and CEO Candice Xie</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has been vocal about creating a sustainable business model that’s profitable on its own before seeking external funding, which the company says it’s done. But as Veo expands its footprint, it needs the additional funds to purchase the vehicles necessary to deploy in new markets, according to the company. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We want to make sure we have very high-quality vehicles as well because vehicle depreciation cost is a huge factor in unit economics, and we have a very good control of that,” Edwin Tan, co-founder and president of Veo, told TechCrunch. “By leveraging our design and supply chain, we want to show that we can continue to develop high quality, long-lasting vehicles.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7h6uIJbssm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/bird-lime-and-veoride-selected-for-nyc-e-scooter-pilot/">Bird, Lime and Veo selected for NYC e-scooter pilot</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bird, Lime and Veo selected for NYC e-scooter pilot&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/bird-lime-and-veoride-selected-for-nyc-e-scooter-pilot/embed/#?secret=7h6uIJbssm" data-secret="7h6uIJbssm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company, which has always designed and manufactured its own electric scooters and bikes rather than partnering with a manufacturer, recently rolled out its <a href="https://veo-mobility.medium.com/innovating-our-way-to-safer-streets-with-the-veo-astro-4-ea6188dc7b17">newest Astro 4</a>, which Tan said can last about three years. Veo&#8217;s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">previous vehicle generation can last two years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">New features on the vehicle can help greatly reduce operational costs and help users get more for their money, said Tan. The Astro 4 is the first shared e-scooter with turn signals, according to Veo. It will also feature a new lighting feature that asks passerby to “Please pick me up” on the bottom of the board if knocked over — an effort to alert people with disabilities to the presence of the scooter while solving the public nuisance problem. A brighter headlight, decklight and taillight have also been added along with and other features like improved suspension and IoT will be helpful in keeping costs down, Tan said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are expanding out R&amp;D budget,” said Tan. “We want to make sure we can create new technology or a new product that can solve for new form factors. We believe this industry is still very early, and think we can create more form factors and really change how people move around with different vehicles. That unmet demand is really important for us.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Veo averages one new vehicle each year, according to Tan. The company plans to launch a new vehicle in the first quarter of 2022 that will solve for the “winter problem” and overcome the seasonality of rides. The company said it already has a solution for that but isn’t ready to share more details. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Veo also wants to address the needs of people who don’t feel safe or comfortable riding a stand-up kick scooter or a bike. Veo&#8217;s Cosmo model, which is a sit-down scooter design, is an example of the company&#8217;s attempt to meet that demand. Veo plans to offer additional models that are accessible to a wider range of people, a move that aligns with requests from cities. </span></p>
<p>The funding round was led by Autotech Ventures, with participation from UP Partners, FJ Labs and Interplay Ventures.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fcYoeLKAda"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/25/candice-xie-has-a-plan-for-building-a-sustainable-scooter-company-and-its-working/">Veo CEO Candice Xie has a plan for building a sustainable scooter company, and it&#8217;s working</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Veo CEO Candice Xie has a plan for building a sustainable scooter company, and it&#8217;s working&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/25/candice-xie-has-a-plan-for-building-a-sustainable-scooter-company-and-its-working/embed/#?secret=fcYoeLKAda" data-secret="fcYoeLKAda" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/micromobility-operator-veo-raises-16m-to-fund-u-s-expansion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176477</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Product-led sales startup Endgame raises over $17M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/product-led-sales-startup-endgame-raises-over-17m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/product-led-sales-startup-endgame-raises-over-17m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Bilmes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Endgame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gainsight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kara nortman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liquid 2 ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menlo ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Naomi Ionita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nick Mehta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unusual Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upfront ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Endgame, enabling software companies to turn customer observations into go-to-market strategies, raised a total of $17 million raised in back-to-back seed and Series A funding rounds.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.endgame.io/">Endgame</a>, enabling software companies to turn customer observations into go-to-market strategies, announced Tuesday it raised a total of $17 million in back-to-back seed and Series A funding rounds.</p>
<p>The $12.25 million Series A was led by Menlo Ventures, while the $5 million seed round was led by Upfront Ventures. Also participating in the round are a group of investors including Todd and Rahul’s Fund, Liquid 2 Ventures and Gainsight CEO Nick Mehta.</p>
<p>Los Angeles-based Endgame was founded in 2020 and provides a self-service look at what’s happening in a software trial so that a sales team can prioritize accounts based on user behavior signals and act on them faster without having to be a data scientist or engineer.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Company CEO Alex Bilmes told TechCrunch that the concepts of product-led sales and product-led growth have taken over the sale of software. Today’s customers sign up for a trial, and if they like it, they invite their friends to try it.</p>
<p>However, at a certain point, some sales pressure is needed to close the deal. That’s where Endgame comes in: It shows who is doing what, and what features are being used — data that is typically opaque to sales and revenue teams.</p>
<p>Traditional customer relationship management systems are designed to be user-driven, meaning the sales rep is responsible for adding notes. It’s simpler if a rep only has a few accounts, but across tens of millions of users, Endgame analyzes the data and identifies which accounts are most likely to convert, who are the users to engage, what makes a good customer and how to take action with the right people.</p>
<p>Endgame is not competing against other companies so much as in-house developers that are cobbling a bunch of apps together in efforts to create a system that works for them, Bilmes said.</p>
<p>“Most of this is solved with do-it-yourself,” he added. “I have built Endgame a number of times at other companies using databases and other piece-meals to put together something so I could mash data from lots of places and build subscriptive views for revenue teams. We compete with those data scientists and internal teams stitching together horizontal tools.”</p>
<p>Endgame is pre-revenue and is already catering to a group of beta customers like Figma, Loom, Airtable, Clubhouse, Mode, Retool and Algolia that are looking for a dedicated software platform to capture product-led value.</p>
<p>Bilmes said the customer relationship management market, both huge and fast-growing at 35% annually, is expected to reach $114 billion by 2027. To meet demand, he intends to use the new funds to continue hiring aggressively. He has already tripled the size of the team to nine in the past few months, and expects to double that in the coming year. In addition, funds will go toward R&amp;D and to further define the product-led sales landscape.</p>
<p>Growth over the next year will be customer-focused as Endgame works to get into the hands of the right customers and making it as accessible as possible for people to begin doing product-led motions.</p>
<p>“Our efforts are product-focused,” Bilmes said. “We’ve seen more demand than we can possibly hope to fill given the problem is so real for so many.”</p>
<p>As part of the investment, Upfront Ventures Partner Kara Nortman and Menlo Ventures Partner Naomi Ionita will join Endgame’s board of directors. Sandhya Hegde, partner at Unusual Ventures, which also participated in both rounds, joins as a board observer to create an all-women investor board.</p>
<p>When Endgame was raising its seed fund, it wanted to work with Nortman, who has expertise in applying consumer concepts to enterprise, Bilmes said. When it came to the Series A, Bilmes said he felt Ionita was the perfect partner due to her similar background to Bilmes and expertise in teaching salespeople how to engage.</p>
<p>Ionita told TechCrunch she learned about Endgame from Nortman, with whom she has invested in other startups. The company understands the pain point and is also providing something self-serve that gives the “why and how.”</p>
<p>“This intelligence doesn’t exist, and I know that because I lived it — building in-house or seeing companies flying blind,” she added. “Alex just gets this, and I see Endgame being the system of record and intelligence for bridging self-serve. They will be the final bridge that needs to exist between product teams and product-facing sales reps for which accounts to address and why.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iOts9CnLrK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/should-your-saas-startup-embrace-a-bottom-up-gtm-strategy/">Should your SaaS startup embrace a bottom-up GTM strategy?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Should your SaaS startup embrace a bottom-up GTM strategy?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/should-your-saas-startup-embrace-a-bottom-up-gtm-strategy/embed/#?secret=iOts9CnLrK" data-secret="iOts9CnLrK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/product-led-sales-startup-endgame-raises-over-17m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176357</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remote raises $150M on a $1B+ valuation to manage payroll and more for organizations&#8217; global workforces</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/remote-raises-150m-on-a-1b-valuation-to-manage-payroll-and-more-for-organizations-global-workforces/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/remote-raises-150m-on-a-1b-valuation-to-manage-payroll-and-more-for-organizations-global-workforces/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 11:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future of work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Remote]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote.com]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For many of us, going to work these days no longer means going into a specific office like it used to; and today one of the startups that&#8217;s built a platform to help cater for that new, bigger world of employment &#8212; wherever talent might be &#8212; is announcing a major round of funding on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For many of us, going to work these days no longer means going into a specific office like it used to; and today one of the startups that&#8217;s built a platform to help cater for that new, bigger world of employment &#8212; wherever talent might be &#8212; is announcing a major round of funding on the back of strong demand for its tools.</p>
<p><a href="https://remote.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Remote</a>, which provides tools to manage onboarding, payroll, benefits and other services for tech and other knowledge workers located in remote countries &#8212; be they contractors or full-time employees &#8212; has raised $150 million. Job van der Voort, the Dutch-based CEO and co-founder of New York-based Remote, confirmed in an interview that funding values Remote at over $1 billion.</p>
<p>Accel is leading this Series B, with participation also from previous investors Sequoia, Index Ventures, Two Sigma, General Catalyst and Day One Ventures.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding will be used in a couple of areas. First and foremost, it will go towards expanding its business to more markets. The startup has been built from the ground up in a fully-integrated way, and in contrast to a number of others that it competes with in providing Employer of Record services, Remote fully owns all of its infrastructure. It now provides its HR services, as fully-operational legal entities, for 50 countries has a target of growing that to 80 by the end of this year. The platform is also set to be enhanced with more tools around areas like benefits, equity incentive planning, visa and immigration support and employee relocation.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are doubling down on our approach,&#8221; Van der Voort said. &#8220;We try to fully own the entire stack: entity, operations, experts in house, payroll, benefits and visa and immigration &#8212; all of the items that come up most often. We want to to build infrastructure products, foundational products because those have a higher level of quality and ultimately a lower price.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition, Remote will be using the funding to continue building more tools and partnerships to integrate with other providers of services in what is a very fragmented human resources market. Two of these are being announced today to coincide with the funding news: Remote has launched a Global Employee API that HR platforms that focus on domestic payroll can integrate to provide their own international offering powered by Remote. HR platform <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/rippling-nabs-145m-at-a-1-35b-valuation-to-build-out-its-all-in-one-platform-for-employee-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rippling</a> (Parker Conrad&#8217;s latest act) is one of its first customers. And Remote is also getting cosier with other parts of the HR chain of services: applicant tracking system Greenhouse now integrating with it to help with the onboarding process for new hires.</p>
<p>$150 million at a $1 billion+ valuation is a very, very sizable Series B, even by today&#8217;s flush-market standards, but it comes after a bumper year for the company, and in particular since November last year when it raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/remote-raises-35m-to-help-orgs-with-global-workforce-payroll-benefits-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Series A of $35 million</a>. In the last nine months, customer numbers have grown seven-fold, with users on the platform increasing 10 times. Most interestingly, perhaps, is that Remote&#8217;s revenues &#8212; it&#8217;s packages start at $149 per month but go up from there &#8212; have increased by a much bigger amount: 65x, the company said. That basically points to the fact that engagement from those users &#8212; how much they are leaning on Remote&#8217;s tech &#8212; has skyrocketed.</p>
<p>Although there are a lot of competitors in the same space as Remote &#8212; they include a number of more local players alongside a pretty big range of startups like Oyster (which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/oyster-an-hr-platform-for-distributed-workforces-snaps-up-50m-on-a-475m-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced $50 million in funding in June</a>), Deel, which is <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-21/payroll-startup-deel-raises-funds-at-1-25-billion-valuation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">now valued at $1.25 billion</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/turing-nabs-32m-more-for-an-ai-based-platform-to-source-and-manage-engineers-remotely/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Turing</a>; Papaya Global (now also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/papaya-global-raises-100m-more-at-a-1b-valuation-for-tools-to-hire-pay-and-manage-distributed-workforces/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">valued at over $1 billion</a>); and many more &#8212; the opportunity they are collectively tackling is a massive one that, if anything, appears to be growing.</p>
<p>Hiring internationally has always been a costly, time-consuming and organizationally-challenged endeavor, so much so that many companies have opted not to do it at all, or to reserve it for very unique cases. That paradigm has drastically shifted in recent years, however.</p>
<p>Even before Covid-19 hit, there was a shortage of talent, resulting in a competitive struggle for good people, in company&#8217;s home markets, which encouraged companies to look further afield when hiring. Then, once looking further afield, those employers had to give consideration to employing those people remotely &#8212; that is, letting them work from afar &#8212; because the process of relocating them had also become more expensive and harder to work through.</p>
<p>Then Covid-19 happened, and everyone, including people working in a company&#8217;s HQ, started to work remotely, changing the goalposts yet again on what is expected by workers, and what organizations are willing to consider when bringing a new person on board, or managing someone it already knows, just from a much farther distance.</p>
<p>While a lot of that has played out in the idea of relocating to different cities in the same country &#8212; Miami and Austin getting a big wave of Silicon Valley &#8220;expats&#8221; being two examples of that &#8212; it seems just a short leap to consider that now that sourcing and managing is taking on a much more international provide. A lot of new hires, as well as existing employees who are possibly not from the US to begin with, or simply want to see another part of the world, are now also a part of the mix. That is where companies like Remote are coming in and lowering the barriers to entry by making it as easy to hire and manage a person abroad as it is in your own city.</p>
<p>“Remote is at the center of a profound shift in the way that companies hire,&#8221; said Miles Clements, a partner at Accel, in a statement. &#8220;Their new Global Employee API opens up access to Remote’s robust global employment infrastructure and knowledge map, and will help any HR provider expand internationally at a speed impossible before. Remote’s future vision as a financial services provider will consolidate complicated processes into one trusted platform, and we’re excited to partner with the global leader in the quickly emerging category of remote work.”</p>
<p>And it&#8217;s interesting to see it now partnering with the likes of Rippling. It was a no-brainer that as the latter company matured and grew, that it would have to consider how to handle the international component. Using an API from Remote is an example of how the model that has played out in communications (led by companies like Twilio and Sinch) and fintech (hello, Stripe), also has an analogue in HR, with Remote taking the charge on that.</p>
<p>And to be clear, for now Remote has no plans to build a product that it would sell directly to individuals.</p>
<p>&#8220;Individuals are reaching out to us, saying, &#8216;I found this job and can you help me and make sure I get paid?&#8217; That&#8217;s been interesting,&#8221; Van der Voort said. &#8220;We thought about [building a product for them] but we have so much to do with employers first.&#8221; One thing that&#8217;s heartening in Remote&#8217;s approach is that it wouldn&#8217;t want to provide this service unless it could completely follow through on it, which in the case of an individual would mean &#8220;vetting every major employer,&#8221; he said, which is too big a task for it right now.</p>
<p>In the meantime, Remote itself has walked the walk when it comes to remote working. Originally co-founded by two European transplants to San Francisco, the pair had first-hand experience of the paradoxical pains and opportunities of being in an organization that uses remote workforces.</p>
<p>Van der Voort had been the VP of product for GitLab, which he scaled from 5 to 450 employees working remotely (it’s now a customer of Remote’s); and before co-founding Remote CTO Marcelo Lebre had been VP of engineering for Unbabel — another startup focused on reducing international barriers, this time between how companies and global customers communicate.</p>
<p>Today, not only is the CEO based out of Amsterdam in The Netherlands and CTO in Lisbon, Portugal, but New York-based Remote itself has grown to 220 from 50 employees, and this wider group has also been working remotely across 47 countries since November 2020.</p>
<p>&#8220;The world is looking very different today,&#8221; Van der Voort said. &#8220;The biggest change for us has been the size of the organization. We&#8217;ve gone from 50 to more than 200 employees, and I haven’t met any of them! We have tried to follow our values of bringing opportunity everywhere so we hire everywhere as we solve that for our customers, too.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/remote-raises-150m-on-a-1b-valuation-to-manage-payroll-and-more-for-organizations-global-workforces/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176581</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google fined $592M in France for breaching antitrust order to negotiate copyright fees for news snippets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 11:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyright law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Le Monde]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Showcase]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[France has hit Google with a fine of half a billion euros after finding major breaches in how it negotiated with publishers to remunerate them for reuse of their content &#8212; as is required under a pan-EU reform of digital copyright law which extended neighbouring rights to news snippets. The size of the fine is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">France has hit Google with a fine of half a billion euros after finding major breaches in how it negotiated with publishers to remunerate them for reuse of their content &#8212; as is required under a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/european-parliament-votes-for-controversial-copyright-reform/">pan-EU reform of digital copyright law</a> which extended neighbouring rights to news snippets.</p>
<p>The size of the fine is notable as it&#8217;s over half of the entire <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/google-to-pay-out-1b-to-publishers-to-license-content-for-new-google-news-showcase/">$1BN news licensing pot that Google announced last October</a> &#8212; when it said it would be paying news publishers “to create and curate high-quality content” to appear on its platforms.</p>
<p>At the time, the move that looked intended to shrink Google&#8217;s exposure to legal mandates to pay publishers for content reuse by pushing them to accept commercial terms which give it broad rights to &#8216;showcase&#8217; their content.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>France&#8217;s watchdog has now called out &#8212; and sanctioned &#8212; the practice.</p>
<p>The half a billion euro penalty is also notable for being considerably more than Google had already agreed to pay French publishers, according to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-google-france-copyright-exclusive-idUSKBN2AC27N">Reuters</a> &#8212; which reported, back in February, that the tech giant had inked a deal with a group of 121 publishers to pay them just $76M over three years.</p>
<p>France&#8217;s competition authority <a href="https://www.autoritedelaconcurrence.fr/fr/article/remuneration-des-droits-voisins-lautorite-sanctionne-google-hauteur-de-500-millions-deuros">said today</a> that it&#8217;s applying the sanction of €500 million ($592M) against the tech giant for failing to comply with a number of injunctions related to its earlier, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/09/frances-competition-watchdog-orders-google-to-pay-for-news-reuse/">April 2020 decision</a> &#8212; when the watchdog ordered Google to negotiate in good faith with publishers to remunerate them for displaying their protected content.</p>
<p>Initially, Google sought to evade the neighbouring news right by stopping displaying snippets of content alongside links it showed in Google News in France. But the watchdog found that was likely to be an abuse of its dominant position &#8212; and ordered Google to stop circumventing the law and negotiate with publishers to pay for the reuse in good faith.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="r5bx5CKu02"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/09/frances-competition-watchdog-orders-google-to-pay-for-news-reuse/">France&#8217;s competition watchdog orders Google to pay for news reuse</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;France&#8217;s competition watchdog orders Google to pay for news reuse&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/09/frances-competition-watchdog-orders-google-to-pay-for-news-reuse/embed/#?secret=r5bx5CKu02" data-secret="r5bx5CKu02" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The<em> Autorité de la Concurrence</em> is not happy with how Google has gone about this, though.</p>
<p>A number of publishers complained to it that the negotiations were not carried out in good faith and that Google did not provide them with key information necessary to inform payments.</p>
<p>The Syndicate of magazine press publishers (SEPM), the Alliance de Presse d&#8217;Information Générale (APIG) and Agence France Presse (AFP) made complaints in August/September 2020 &#8212; kicking off the investigation by the watchdog and today&#8217;s announcement of a major penalty.</p>
<p>Further fines &#8212; of up to €900,000 per day &#8212; could be headed Google&#8217;s way if it continues to breach the watchdog&#8217;s injunctions and fails to supply publishers with all the required information within a new two-month deadline.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.autoritedelaconcurrence.fr/fr/communiques-de-presse/remuneration-des-droits-voisins-lautorite-sanctionne-google-hauteur-de-500">press release</a> detailing its investigation, the <em>Autorité </em>said Google sought to unilaterally impose its global news licensing product, aka &#8216;Showcase&#8217;, under a partnership the tech giant calls Publisher Curated News &#8212; in negotiations with publishers &#8212; pushing for the legal neighbouring right to be incorporated as &#8220;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">an ancillary component with no separate financial valuation&#8221;.</span></p>
<p>Publishers requests to break out copyright remuneration negotiations were denied, per the watchdog&#8217;s investigation.</p>
<p>It also found Google &#8220;unjustifiably&#8221; reduced the scope of negotiations with regard to the scope of income derived from the display of protected news content &#8212; with Google telling publishers that only advertising income from Google Search pages posting news content should be taken into account in determining the level of remuneration due.</p>
<p>The authority found this exclusion of income from other Google services and all indirect income related to this content to be in breach of the copyright law and its earlier compliance order.</p>
<p>Google also &#8220;deliberately circumscribed&#8221; the scope of the law on neighboring rights by excluding titles that do not have a Political and General Information certificate &#8212; which the watchdog couched as a &#8220;bad faith&#8221; interpretation of the code on intellectual property.</p>
<p>It also found the tech giant sought to exclude press agencies from renumeration related to their content when used by third party publishers &#8212; highlighting that as another breach of its April 2020 decision, by further noting: &#8220;The French legislator has been very explicit on the need to include press agencies.&#8221;</p>
<p>In another finding, it said Google had only provided publishers with &#8220;partial&#8221; and &#8220;insufficient&#8221; information for a &#8220;transparency assessment of renumeration due&#8221;; and further accused the tech giant of delaying until just a few days before the injunction deadline to provide it &#8212; so of being &#8220;late&#8221; too.</p>
<p>The authority&#8217;s investigation highlights compliance problems with another injunction &#8212; related to an obligation of neutrality in how protected content is presented on Google&#8217;s platforms &#8212; with the watchdog writing on that: &#8220;The strategy put in place by Google has thus strongly encouraged publishers to accept the contractual conditions of the <em>Showcase</em> service and to renounce negotiations relating specifically to the current uses of protected content, which was the subject of the Injunctions, under penalty of seeing their exposure and their remuneration degraded compared to their competitors who would have accepted the proposed terms. Google cannot therefore claim to have taken the necessary measures to prevent its negotiations from affecting the presentation of protected content in its services.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another injunction sought to prevent Google from seeking to leverage its dominance by offsetting remunerations paid to publishers for the neighbouring rights.</p>
<p>On this the watchdog also took issue with its approach &#8212; noting that its Showcase product requires publishers to make not just snippets of their content available for display on Google&#8217;s platforms but &#8220;large extracts&#8221; and even whole articles.</p>
<p>It also found that Google linked participation in the <em>Showcase</em> program to subscription to another service called <em>Subscribe with Google</em> (SwG) &#8212; enabling it to link negotiation on neighboring rights with the subscription of new services that could financially benefit its business.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MUKLVkgHz9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/google-inks-agreement-in-france-on-paying-publishers-for-news-reuse/">Google inks agreement in France on paying publishers for news reuse</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google inks agreement in France on paying publishers for news reuse&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/google-inks-agreement-in-france-on-paying-publishers-for-news-reuse/embed/#?secret=MUKLVkgHz9" data-secret="MUKLVkgHz9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Under a subhead which denounces what it found as &#8220;extremely serious practices&#8221;, the authority goes on to accuse Google of &#8220;a deliberate, elaborate and systematic strategy of non-compliance&#8221; &#8212; and of continuing an already years-long &#8220;opposition strategy&#8221; to the principle of neighbouring rights; and then, after they&#8217;d been baked into EU and French law, seeking to &#8220;minimize the concrete scope of those rights as much as possible&#8221;.</p>
<p>Google has, the authority asserts, sought to use a global strategy to close down publishers&#8217; ability to negotiate for remuneration for their content reuse at a national level &#8212; using its Showcase product as a cloak for &#8220;avoiding or limiting as much as possible&#8221; payments to publishers; and, simultaneously, seeking to use negotiations on neighboring rights as an opportunity to obtain access to new content by press publishers that could allow it to collect additional income, such as from subscriptions to press titles.</p>
<p>&#8220;The sanction of 500 million euros takes into account the exceptional seriousness of the breaches observed and that the behavior of Google has further delayed the proper application of the law on neighboring rights, which aimed to better take into account the value of content from publishers and news agencies included on the platforms. The Authority will be extremely vigilant about the correct application of its decision, as non-execution can now lead to periodic penalty payments,&#8221; added the watchdog&#8217;s president, Isabelle de Silva, in a statement (which we&#8217;ve translated from French).</p>
<p>The half a billion euro fine and the warning to Google that its practices will attract daily fines if it persists in ignoring the injunctions put the tech giant on notice that the detail of commercial deals won&#8217;t be allowed to fly under the radar in France.</p>
<p>Any more attempts to shape a self-serving version of &#8216;compliance&#8217; are likely to attract further sanction from the watchdog &#8212; which also recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/france-fines-google-268m-for-adtech-abuses-and-gets-interoperability-commitments/">applied a number of interoperability requirements</a> on Google&#8217;s ad business (and slapped it with a $268M fine), also acting on complaints from publishers.</p>
<p>While anything Google agrees to in France on the neighbouring rights issue is likely to set the bar for what it can achieve with commercial deals elsewhere &#8212; at least in other EU markets, where the copyright extension also applies (once it&#8217;s been transposed into a Member State&#8217;s national law).</p>
<p>In a statement responding to the authority&#8217;s sanction, Google expressed disappointment with the outcome of the investigation &#8212; claiming to have acted in good faith throughout negotiations with publishers:</p>
<blockquote><p>“We are very disappointed with this decision &#8212; we have acted in good faith throughout the entire process. The fine ignores our efforts to reach an agreement, and the reality of how news works on our platforms. To date, Google is the only company to have announced agreements on neighbouring rights. We are also about to finalize an agreement with AFP that includes a global licensing agreement, as well as the remuneration of their neighbouring rights for their press publications.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The tech giant went on to suggest that the authority&#8217;s decision is &#8220;primarily&#8221; related to negotiations in France which took place between May and September 2020, further claiming it has continued to engage with publishers and press agencies since then to find &#8220;solutions&#8221;.</p>
<p>By way of example it pointed to a January 2021 framework agreement inked with the Alliance de la Presse d’Information Générale &#8212; which it claims covers every IPG title (Information de Presse Générale) in a &#8220;transparent and non-discriminatory way&#8221;. It also pointed to agreements it has inked with other publications in the market, including Le Monde, Courrier International, L&#8217;Obs, Le Figaro, Libération, and L’Express.</p>
<p>Google also reiterated its confident it can sign a global licensing agreement with Agence France Presse &#8212; which it said it also wants to include remuneration of neighbouring rights for press publications from the agency.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our objective remains the same: We want to turn the page with a definitive agreement,&#8221; it added, saying it would take the French Competition Authority’s &#8220;feedback into consideration and adapt our offers&#8221; and that: &#8220;We are already engaging with press publishers and agencies beyond IPG, by covering publications that are recognised by the CPPAP as &#8216;online press services&#8217;, and we reiterate our offer to have an independent third party in a position to evaluate our offers and allow us to base our discussions on facts.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other major fines for Google in France in recent years include the aforementioned <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/france-fines-google-268m-for-adtech-abuses-and-gets-interoperability-commitments/">$268M for adtech abuses</a> last month; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/france-fines-google-120m-and-amazon-42m-for-dropping-tracking-cookies-without-consent/">$120 for dropping tracking cookies without consent</a> back in December; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/20/france-slaps-google-with-166m-antitrust-fine-for-opaque-and-inconsistent-ad-rules/">$166M in December 2019</a> for opaque and inconsistent ad rules; and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/french-data-protection-watchdog-fines-google-57-million-under-the-gdpr/">$57M for privacy violations</a> in January 2019.</p>
<p>Beyond the EU, Australia <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/after-facebooks-news-flex-australia-passes-bargaining-code-for-platforms-and-publishers/">recently passed a law</a> which requires tech giants, Google and Facebook, to enter mandatory arbitration with publishers for reuse of their content if they fail to agree commercial terms on their own.</p>
<p>Its law has attracted considerable attention worldwide as legislators grapple with how to rein in powerful tech platforms and ensure the sustainability of traditional news businesses whose revenues have been hit by the Internet-driven shift to digital publishing.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/uks-digital-markets-unit-starts-work-on-pro-competition-reforms/">UK&#8217;s Competition and Markets Authority</a> has, for example, described Australia&#8217;s backstop of mandatory arbitration if commercial negotiations fail as a “sensible” approach &#8212; at at time when the government is working on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/the-uks-plan-to-tackle-big-tech-wont-be-one-sized-fits-all/">shaping an ex ante regulation regime</a> to enable competition authorities to pro-actively tackle abuses by platforms with strategic market power.</p>
<p>Ahead of Australia&#8217;s law being passed, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/google-threatens-to-close-its-search-engine-in-australia-as-it-lobbies-against-digital-news-code/">Google had warned that it might have to close its services in the country</a> if legislators went ahead and also suggested the quality could degrade or that it may have to start to charge for products. In the event, it did not shut up shop down under.</p>
<p>The tech giant was also an active lobbyist against the EU&#8217;s plan to extend digital copyright to cover snippets of news content &#8212; and, as recently as <a href="https://blog.google/perspectives/richard-gingras/how-google-invests-news/">2019</a>, it was vowing never to pay for news.</p>
<p>A few years later it announced the $1BN pot to pay publishers to licence content. But Google&#8217;s eventual bill for its ad business piggybacking upon others&#8217; journalism may be rather larger than that.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7tWNg7QmMx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/google-to-pay-out-1b-to-publishers-to-license-content-for-new-google-news-showcase/">Google to pay out $1B to publishers to license content for new Google News Showcase</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google to pay out $1B to publishers to license content for new Google News Showcase&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/google-to-pay-out-1b-to-publishers-to-license-content-for-new-google-news-showcase/embed/#?secret=7tWNg7QmMx" data-secret="7tWNg7QmMx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7vCHx6GVjC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/after-facebooks-news-flex-australia-passes-bargaining-code-for-platforms-and-publishers/">After Facebook&#8217;s news flex, Australia passes bargaining code for platforms and publishers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;After Facebook&#8217;s news flex, Australia passes bargaining code for platforms and publishers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/after-facebooks-news-flex-australia-passes-bargaining-code-for-platforms-and-publishers/embed/#?secret=7vCHx6GVjC" data-secret="7vCHx6GVjC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yKRGJvUymY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/google-threatens-to-close-its-search-engine-in-australia-as-it-lobbies-against-digital-news-code/">Google threatens to close its search engine in Australia as it lobbies against digital news code</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google threatens to close its search engine in Australia as it lobbies against digital news code&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/google-threatens-to-close-its-search-engine-in-australia-as-it-lobbies-against-digital-news-code/embed/#?secret=yKRGJvUymY" data-secret="yKRGJvUymY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176580</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
