<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 20:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Home services platform Porch acquires four companies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/home-services-platform-porch-acquires-four-companies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/home-services-platform-porch-acquires-four-companies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 21:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arizona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contractor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ing group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance broker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north carolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[porch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Carolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virginia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Only a few weeks after its SPAC IPO, Porch today announced that it has made four acquisitions, worth a total of $122 million. The most important here is probably the acquisition of Homeowners of America for $100 million, which gets Porch deeper into the home insurance space. In addition, Porch is also acquiring mover marketing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Only a few weeks <a href="https://therealdeal.com/national/2020/12/24/porch-valuation-soars-to-1b-after-ipo/">after its SPAC IPO</a>, Porch today announced that it has made four acquisitions, worth a total of $122 million. The most important here is probably the acquisition of <a href="https://hoaic.com/">Homeowners of America</a> for $100 million, which gets Porch deeper into the home insurance space. In addition, Porch is also acquiring mover marketing and data platform <a href="https://v12data.com/v12-data/">V12</a> for $22 million, as well as home inspection service <a href="https://www.palm-tech.com/">Palm-Tech</a> and <a href="https://iroofing.org/">iRoofing</a>, a SaaS application for roofing contractors. Porch did not disclose the acquisition prices for the latter two companies.</p>
<p>You may still think of Porch as a marketplace for home improvement and repair services &#8212; and that&#8217;s what it started out as when it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/06/05/home-improvement-and-repair-marketplace-porch-raises-6-3m-from-sv-angel-jeff-skoll-and-others/">launched</a> about seven years ago. Yet while it still offers those services, a couple of years after its 2013 launch, the company <a href="https://porchgroup.com/story">pivoted</a> to building what it now calls a &#8220;vertical software platform for the home.&#8221; Through a number of acquisitions, the Porch Group now includes Porch.com, as well as services like HireAHelper, Inspection Support Network for home inspectors, Kandela for providing services around moving and an insurance broker in the form of the Elite Insurance Group. In some form or another, Porch&#8217;s tools are now used &#8212; either directly or indirectly &#8212; by two-thirds of U.S. homebuyers every month.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096738" style="width: 354px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096738" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2096738" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png" alt="" width="344" height="250" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png 979w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png?resize=150,109 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png?resize=300,218 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png?resize=768,559 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png?resize=680,495 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 344px) 100vw, 344px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2096738" class="wp-caption-text">Porch founder and CEO Matt Ehrlichman. Image Credits: Porch</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As Porch founder and CEO Matt Ehrlichman told me, he had originally planned to take his company public through a traditional IPO. He noted that going the increasingly popular SPAC route, though, allowed him to push his timeline up by a year, which in turn now enables the company to make the acquisitions it announced today.</p>
<p>&#8220;In total, we had a $323 million fundraise that allows us now to not only be a public company with public currency, but to be very well capitalized. And picking up that year allows us to be able to go and pursue acquisitions that we think make really good fits for Porch,&#8221; Ehrlichman told me. While Porch&#8217;s guidance for its 2021 revenue was previously $120 million, it&#8217;s now updating that guidance to $170 million based on these acquisitions. That would mean Porch would grow its revenue by about 134% year-over-year between 2020 and 2021.</p>
<p>As the company had previously laid out in its public documents, the plan for 2021 was always to get deeper into insurance. Indeed, as Ehrlichman noted, Porch these days tends to think of itself as a vertical software company that layers insurtech on top of its services in order to be able to create a recurring revenue stream. And because Porch offers such a wide range of services already, its customer acquisition costs are essentially zero for these services.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096726" style="width: 367px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096726" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2096726" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png" alt="" width="357" height="85" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png 600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png?resize=150,36 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png?resize=300,72 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png?resize=50,12 50w" sizes="(max-width: 357px) 100vw, 357px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2096726" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Homeowners of America</p></div></p>
<p>Porch was already a licensed insurance brokerage. With Homeowners of America, it is acquiring a company that is both an insurance carrier as well as a managing general agent..</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re able to capture all of the economic value from the consumer as we help them get insurance set up with their new home and we can really control that experience to delight them. As we wrap all the technology we&#8217;ve invested in around that experience we can make it super simple and instant to be able to get the right insurance at the right price for your new home. And because we have all of this data about the home that nobody else has &#8212; from the inspection we know if the roof is old, we know if the hot water system is gonna break soon and all the appliances &#8212; we know all of this data and so it just gives us a really big advantage in insurance.&#8221;</p>
<p>Data, indeed, is what a lot of these acquisitions are about. Because Porch knows so much about so many customers, it is able to provide the companies it acquires with access to relevant data, which in turn helps them offer additional services and make smarter decisions.</p>
<p>Homeowners of America is currently operating in six states (Texas, Arizona, North Carolina, South Carolina, Virginia and Georgia) and licensed in 31. It has a network of more than 800 agencies so far and Porch expects to expand the company&#8217;s network and geographic reach in the coming months. &#8220;Because we have [customer acquisition cost]-free demand all across the country, one of the opportunities for us is simply just to expand that across the nation,&#8221; Ehrlichman explained.</p>
<p>As for V12, Porch&#8217;s focus is on that company&#8217;s mover marketing and data platform. The acquisition should help it reach its medium-term goal of building a $200 million revenue stream in this area. V12 offers services across multiple verticals, though, including in the automotive space, and will continue to do so. The platform&#8217;s overall focus is to help brands identify the right time to reach out to a given consumer &#8212; maybe before they decide to buy a new car or move. With Porch&#8217;s existing data layered on top of V12&#8217;s existing capabilities, the company expects that it will be able to expand these features and it will also allow Porch to not offer mover marketing but what Ehrlichman called &#8220;pro-mover&#8221; services, as well.</p>
<p>&#8220;V12 anchors what we call our marketing software division. A key focus of that is mover marketing. That&#8217;s where it&#8217;s going to have, long term, tremendous differentiation. But there are a number of other things that they&#8217;re working on that are going to have really nice growth vectors, and they&#8217;ll continue to push those,&#8221; said Ehrlichman.</p>
<p>As for the two smaller acquisitions of iRoofing and Palm-Tech, these are more akin to some of the previous acquisitions the company made in the contractor and inspection verticals. Like with those previous acquisitions, the plan is to help them grow faster, in part through integrating them into the overall Porch group&#8217;s family of products.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our business is and continues to be highly recurring or reoccurring in nature,&#8221; said <span class="il">Porch</span> CFO Marty Heimbigner. &#8220;Nearly all of our revenues, including that of these new acquisitions, is consistent and predictable. This repeat revenue is also high margin with less than 20% cost of revenue and is expected to grow more than 30% per year on our platform. So, we believe these deals are highly accretive for our shareholders.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/home-services-platform-porch-acquires-four-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096660</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiger Global is raising a new $3.75 billion venture fund, one year after closing its last</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tiger-global-is-raising-a-new-3-75-billion-venture-fund-one-year-after-closing-its-last/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tiger-global-is-raising-a-new-3-75-billion-venture-fund-one-year-after-closing-its-last/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 20:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Credit Karma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kustomer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lee Fixel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peloton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postmates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snowflake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sumo logic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096546</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[According to a recent letter sent to its investors, Tiger Global Management, the New York-based investing powerhouse, is raising a new $3.75 billion venture fund called Tiger Private Investment Partners XIV that it expects to close in March. The fund is Tiger Global&#8217;s 13th venture fund, despite its title &#8212; the partners might be superstitious [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">According to a recent letter sent to its investors, <a href="https://www.tigerglobal.com/home">Tiger Global Management</a>, the New York-based investing powerhouse, is raising a new $3.75 billion venture fund called Tiger Private Investment Partners XIV that it expects to close in March.</p>
<p>The fund is Tiger Global&#8217;s 13th venture fund, despite its title &#8212; the partners might be superstitious &#8212; and it comes hot on the heels of the firm&#8217;s 12th venture fund, closed exactly a year ago, also with $3.75 billion in capital commitments.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for the firm declined to comment on the letter or Tiger Global&#8217;s broader fundraising strategy when reached this morning.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s a lot of capital to target, even amid a sea of enormous new venture vehicles. New Enterprise Associates closed its newest fund with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/11/nea-venture-capitals-quiet-giant-closes-on-3-6-billion/">$3.6 billion</a> last year. Lightspeed Venture Partners soon after announced <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/lightspeed-boosts-three-funds-with-4b/">$4 billion</a> across three funds. Andreessen Horowitz, the youngest of the three firms, announced in November it had closed a pair of funds totaling <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/a16z-is-now-managing-16-5-billion-after-announcing-two-new-funds/">$4.5 billion</a>.</p>
<p>At the same time, Tiger Global has seemingly has a strong case to potential limited partners. Last year alone, numerous of its portfolio companies either went public or was acquired.</p>
<p>Yatsen Holding, the nearly five-year-old parent company of China-based <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-cosmetics-perfectdiary/all-girls-buy-it-in-china-perfect-diary-gives-cosmetics-world-a-makeover-with-live-streams-low-prices-idUSKBN25M0BP">cosmetics giant</a> Perfect Diary, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-perfect-diary-ipo/perfect-diary-parents-shares-soar-in-u-s-debut-idUSKBN27Z2NK">went public</a> in November and is now valued at $14 billion. (Tiger Global&#8217;s ownership stake didn&#8217;t merit a mention on the company&#8217;s <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1819580/000119312520282237/d57580df1.htm#rom57580_16">regulatory filing</a>.)</p>
<p>Tiger Global also quietly <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1640147/000162827920000112/filename4.htm">invested</a> in the cloud-based data warehousing outfit Snowflake and, while again, it didn&#8217;t have a big enough stake to be included in the company&#8217;s <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1640147/000162828020013010/snowflakes-1.htm#ia73499eb79a34ddeaa563501d30356b0_106">S-1</a>, even a tiny ownership percentage would be valuable, given that Snowflake is now valued at $85 billion.</p>
<p>And Tiger Global backed Root insurance, a nearly six-year-old, Columbus, Oh.-based insurance company that went public in November and currently boasts a market cap of $5.3 billion. Tiger owned 10.3% sailing into the offering.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WhmMxVIgOg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/3-lessons-from-roots-ipo-pricing/">3 lessons from Root&#8217;s IPO pricing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 lessons from Root&#8217;s IPO pricing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/3-lessons-from-roots-ipo-pricing/embed/#?secret=WhmMxVIgOg" data-secret="WhmMxVIgOg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As for M&amp;A, Tiger Global saw at least three of its companies swallowed by bigger tech companies during 2020, including Postmates&#8217;s all-stock sale to Uber for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/uber-officially-completes-postmates-acquisition/">$2.65 billion</a>; Credit Karma&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/24/intuit-credit-karma/">$7 billion</a> sale in cash and stock to Intuit; and the sale of Kustomer, which focused on customer service platforms and chatbots, for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/facebook-confirms-it-has-acquired-kustomer-sources-say-for-1b/">$1 billion</a> to Facebook.</p>
<p>Tiger Global, whose roots are in hedge fund management, launched its private equity business in 2003, spearheaded by Chase Coleman, who&#8217;d previously worked for hedge-fund pioneer Julian Robertson at Tiger Management; Scott Shleifer, who joined the firm in 2002 after spending three years with the Blackstone Group; and, soon after, Lee Fixel, who joined the firm in 2006.</p>
<p>Shleifer focused on China; Fixel focused on India, and the rest of the firm&#8217;s support team (it now has 22 investing professionals on staff) helped find deals in Brazil and Russia  before beginning to focus more aggressively on opportunities in the U.S.</p>
<p>Every investing decision was eventually made by each of the three. Fixel left in 2019 to launch his own investment firm, <a href="https://addition.com/">Addition</a>. Now Shleifer and Coleman are the firm&#8217;s sole decision-makers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cbGFxXLGw3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/14/lee-fixel-is-leaving-tiger-global/">Lee Fixel is leaving Tiger Global</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lee Fixel is leaving Tiger Global&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/14/lee-fixel-is-leaving-tiger-global/embed/#?secret=cbGFxXLGw3" data-secret="cbGFxXLGw3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Whether the firm replaces Fixel is an open question. Tiger Global is known for grooming investors within its operations rather than hiring outsiders, so a new top lieutenant would almost surely come from its current team.</p>
<p>In the meantime, the firm&#8217;s private equity arm &#8212; which has written everything from Series A checks (Warby Parker) to checks in the multiple hundreds of millions of dollars &#8212; is currently managing assets of $30 million, compared with the $49 billion that Tiger Global is managing more broadly.</p>
<p>A year ago, Tiger Global, which employs 100 people altogether, was reportedly managing <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/tiger-global-raises-3-75-billion-venture-fund-11579887013">$36.2 billion</a> in assets.</p>
<p>According to the outfit&#8217;s investor letter, the firm&#8217;s gross internal rate of return across its 12 previous funds is 32%, while its net IRR is 24%.</p>
<p>Tiger Global&#8217;s investors include a mix of sovereign wealth funds, foundations, endowments, pensions, and its own employees, who are collectively believed to be the firm&#8217;s biggest investors at this point.</p>
<p>Some of Tiger Global&#8217;s biggest wins to date have include a $200 million bet on the e-commerce giant JD.com that produced a $5 billion for the firm. According to the WSJ, it also cleared more than $1 billion on the Chinese online-services platform Meituan Dianping, which went public in 2018.</p>
<p>Tiger Global also reportedly reaped <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-05-09/tiger-global-is-said-to-reap-3-billion-from-flipkart-investment">$3 billion</a> from majority sale of India&#8217;s Flipkart to Walmart in 2018,  though the Indian government has more recently been <a href="https://www.livemint.com/news/india/tiger-global-moves-delhi-high-court-against-flipkart-tax-ruling-11600702202999.html">trying to recover $1.9 billion</a> from the firm, claiming it has outstanding tax dues on the sale of its share in the company.</p>
<p>Not last, Tiger Global owned nearly 20% of the connected fitness company Peloton at the time of its 2019 IPO (a deal that Fixel reportedly <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexkonrad/2020/07/01/lee-fixel-raises-1-billion-fund-addition/?sh=7f5c48eb19a1">brought to the table</a>, along with Flipkart).</p>
<p>Peloton, valued by private investors at $4 billion before doubling immediately in value as a publicly traded company, now boasts a market cap of $48.6 billion.</p>
<p>Tiger Global has invested its current fund in roughly 50 companies over the last 12 months. Among its newest bets is <a href="https://blend.com/">Blend</a>, an eight-year-old, San Francisco-based digital lending platform that yesterday announced <a href="https://finledger.com/2021/01/13/blend-raises-300-million-series-g-at-3-3-billion-valuation/">$300 million in Series G funding</a>, including from Coatue, at a post-money valuation of $3.3 billion.</p>
<p>It also led the newly announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/checkout-com-raises-450-million-and-reaches-15-billion-valuation/">$450 million Series C round</a> for Checkout.com, an eight-year-old, London-based online payments platform that is now valued at $15 billion. And it wrote a follow-on check to Cockroach Labs, the nearly six-year-old, New York-based distributed SQL database that just raised<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/cockroach-labs-scores-160m-series-e-on-2b-valuation/"> $160 million in Series E funding</a> at a $2 billion valuation, just eight months after raising an $86.6 million Series D round.</p>
<p>Another of its newest, biggest bets centers on the online education platform Zuowebang, in China. Back in June, Tiger Global co-led a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-zuoyebang-fundraiisng/chinese-online-tutor-zuoyebang-raises-750-million-in-fresh-round-idUSKBN240093">$750 million Series E round</a> in the company.</p>
<p>Last month, it was back again, co-leading a <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/china-online-education-startup-draws-061425152.html">$1.6 billion round</a> in the distance-learning company.</p>
<p><em>Pictured: Scott Shleifer, managing director of Tiger Global Management LLC, right, speaks with an attendee during the UJA-Federation of New York Wall Street Dinner in New York, on Wednesday, Dec. 14, 2011. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tiger-global-is-raising-a-new-3-75-billion-venture-fund-one-year-after-closing-its-last/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096546</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2020 was one of the warmest years in history and indicates mounting risks of climate change</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/2020-was-one-of-the-warmest-years-in-history-and-indicates-mounting-risks-of-climate-change/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/2020-was-one-of-the-warmest-years-in-history-and-indicates-mounting-risks-of-climate-change/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 20:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Director]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[katharine hayhoe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Washington Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[us government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington DC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s official. 2020 was one of the warmest years on record either edging out or coming in just behind 2016 for the warmest year in recorded history according to data from US government agencies. The National Aeronautics and Space Administration had the year just tied with 2016, while the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration put [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s official. 2020 was one of the warmest years on record either edging out or coming in just behind 2016 for the warmest year in recorded history according to data from US government agencies.</p>
<p>The National Aeronautics and Space Administration had the year just tied with 2016, while the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration put the figure just behind 2016&#8217;s totals.</p>
<p>No matter the ranking, the big picture for the climate isn&#8217;t pretty according to scientists from NASA&#8217;s <a href="https://www.giss.nasa.gov/">Goddard Institute for Space Studies</a> (GISS) in New York and the Washington, DC-based NOAA.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The last seven years have been the warmest seven years on record, typifying the ongoing and dramatic warming trend,” said GISS Director <a href="https://www.giss.nasa.gov/staff/gschmidt/">Gavin Schmidt</a>, in a statement. “Whether one year is a record or not is not really that important – the important things are long-term trends. With these trends, and as the human impact on the climate increases, we have to expect that records will continue to be broken.”</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a dire message for the nation considering the cost of last year&#8217;s record-breaking <a href="https://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/billions/"> 22 weather and climate disasters.</a> At least 262 people died and scores more were injured by climate-related disasters, according to the NOAA.</p>
<p>And the combination of wildfires, droughts, heatwaves, tornados, tropical cyclones, and severe weather events like hail storms in Texas and the derecho that wrecked the Midwest cost the nation $95 billion.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2034047" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2034047" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2034047" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg" alt="Homes are engulfed in flames in Vacaville, California during the LNU Lightning Complex fire on August 19, 2020." width="1024" height="618" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg 2630w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=300,181 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=768,464 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=680,411 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=1536,927 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=2048,1237 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2034047" class="wp-caption-text">Homes are engulfed in flames in Vacaville, California during the LNU Lightning Complex fire on August 19, 2020. &#8211; As of the late hours of August 18,2020 the Hennessey fire has merged with at least 7 fires and is now called the LNU Lightning Complex fires. Dozens of fires are burning out of control throughout Northern California as fire resources are spread thin. (Photo by JOSH EDELSON/AFP via Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<p>Both organizations track temperature trends to get some sort of picture of the impact that human activities &#8212; specifically greenhouse gas emissions &#8212; have on the planet. The image that comes into focus is that human activity has already contributed to increasing Earth&#8217;s average temperature by more than 2 degrees Fahrenheit since the industrial age took hold in the late 19th century.</p>
<p>Most troubling to scientists is that this year&#8217;s near record-setting temperatures happened without a boost from the climatic weather phenomenon known as El Niño, which is a large-scale ocean-atmosphere climate interaction linked to a periodic warming.</p>
<p>“The previous record warm year, 2016, received a significant boost from a strong El Niño. The lack of a similar assist from El Niño this year is evidence that the background climate continues to warm due to greenhouse gases,” Schmidt said, in a statement.</p>
<p>The warming trends the word is experiencing are most pronounced in the Arctic, according to NASA. There, temperatures have warmed three times as a fast as the rest of the globe over the past 30 years, Schmidt said. The loss of Arctic sea ice &#8212; whose annual minimum area is declining by about 13 percent per decade &#8212; makes the region less reflective, which means more sunlight is being absorbed by oceans, causing temperatures to climb even more.</p>
<p>These accelerating effects of climate change could be perilous for the world at large, Katharine Hayhoe, a professor at Texas Tech University <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/interactive/2021/2020-tied-for-hottest-year-on-record/">wrote in an email to The Washington Post</a>.</p>
<p class=" font--body font-copy color-gray-darkest pb-md mw-md ma-auto pr-sm pl-sm ">&#8220;What keeps us climate scientists up in the dead of night is wondering what we don’t know about the self-reinforcing or vicious cycles in the Earth’s climate system,&#8221; Hayhoe wrote. &#8220;The further and faster we push it beyond anything experienced in the history of human civilization on this planet, the greater the risk of serious and even dangerous consequences. And this year, we’ve seen that in spades&#8230; It’s no longer a question of when the impacts of climate change will manifest themselves: They are already here and now. The only question remaining is how much worse it will get.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/2020-was-one-of-the-warmest-years-in-history-and-indicates-mounting-risks-of-climate-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096697</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 consumer hardware VCs share their 2021 investment strategies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Construct Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consumer Electronics Show]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyril Ebersweiler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayna grayson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ggv capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hans tung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lux capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rob coneybeer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shasta ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearable devices]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Tesla is arguably the most interesting connected consumer hardware company since Apple exploded in scale with the success of the iPhone."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Consumer hardware has always been a tough market to crack, but the COVID-19 crisis made it even harder.</p>
<p>TechCrunch surveyed five key investors who touch different aspects of the consumer electronics industry, based on our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/the-techcrunch-list/?verticals=576769646">TechCrunch List</a> of top VCs recommended by founders, along with other sources.</p>
<p>We asked these investors the same six questions, and each provided similar thoughts, but different approaches:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ggvc.com/ggv_employee/hans-tung/">Hans Tung</a>, managing partner, GGV Capital</li>
<li>Dayna Grayson, co-founder and general partner, <a href="https://www.constructcap.com">Construct Capital</a></li>
<li><a href="https://sosv.com/team/cyril-ebersweiler/">Cyril Ebersweiler</a>, general partner, SOSV</li>
<li><a href="https://luxcapital.com/team/bilal-zuberi/">Bilal Zuberi</a>, partner, Lux Capital</li>
<li><a href="https://www.shasta.vc/bio/rob-coneybeer/">Rob Coneybeer</a>, managing director, Shasta Ventures</li>
</ul>
<p>Despite the pandemic, each identified bright spots in the consumer electronic world. One thing is clear, investors are generally bullish on at-home fitness startups. Multiple respondents cited Peloton, Tonal and Mirror as recent highlights in consumer electronics.</p>
<p>Said Shasta Venture&#8217;s Rob Coneybeer, &#8220;With all due respect to my friends at Nest (where Shasta was a Series A investor), Tonal is the most exciting consumer connected hardware company I’ve ever been involved with.&#8221;</p>
<p>Besides asking about the trends and opportunities they&#8217;re pursuing in 2021, the investors we spoke to also identified other investors, founders and companies who are leaders in consumer hardware and shared how they&#8217;ve reshaped their investment strategies during the pandemic. Their responses have been edited for space and clarity.</p>
<hr />
<h2>Hans Tung, GGV Capital</h2>
<p><strong>Which consumer hardware sector shows the most promise for explosive growth?</strong></p>
<p>For consumer hardware, offering end users a differentiated experience is extremely important. Social interactions, gamification and high-quality PGC (professionally generated content) such as with Peloton, Xiaomi and Tonal is a must to drive growth. It’s also easy to see how the acceleration of the digital economy created by COVID-19 will also drive growth for hardware.</p>
<p>First, services improved by the speed and reliability of 5G such as live streaming, gaming, cloud computing, etc. will create opportunity for new mobile devices and global mass market consumers will continue to demand high-quality, low-cost hardware. For example, Arevo is experimenting with “hardware as a service” with a 3D printing facility in Vietnam.</p>
<p>For enterprise hardware, security, reliability and fast updates are key competitive advantages. Also as a result of 5G… manufacturing automation and industrial applications. Finally IoT for health and safety may find its sweet spot thanks to COVID-19 with new wearables that track sleep, fitness and overall wellness.</p>
<p><strong>How did COVID-19 change consumer hardware and your investment strategy?</strong></p>
<p>One opportunity for consumer hardware companies to consider as a result of COVID-19 is how they engage with their customers. They should think of themselves more like e-commerce companies, where user experience, ongoing engagement with the consumer and iteration based on market feedback rule the day. While Peloton had this approach well before COVID, it has built a $46 billion company thinking about their products in this way.</p>
<p>For example, some consumers felt the bike was too expensive so instead of responding with a low-end product, the company partnered with Affirm to make their hardware more affordable with pay-as-you-go plans. A Peloton bike is not a one-and-done purchase; there is constant interaction between users, and the company that drives more satisfaction in the hardware adds more value in the business.</p>
<p><strong>Entering 2021, in what way is hardware still hard?</strong></p>
<p>Hardware is still hard because it takes more to iterate fast. The outcome for competitors relative to speed-to-market can be dramatic. For example, every year I look at future generation of EVs with lots of innovations and cool features from existing OEMs but see very few of these making it to market compared to Tesla and other pure players that are cranking out vehicles. Their speed of execution is impressive.</p>
<p><strong>Who are some leaders in consumer hardware &#8212; founders, companies, investors?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>John Foley, founder and CEO of <a href="https://www.onepeloton.com/">Peloton</a>. John and the Peloton team have cracked the code on the integration of community experience and hardware.</li>
<li>Sonny Vu, founder of Misfit and founder/CEO of <a href="http://www.arevo.com">Arevo</a>, maker of ultrastrong, lightweight continuous carbon fiber products on demand. Experienced founder and team with 3D printing manufacturing know-how at scale are now able to offer breakthrough consumer and industrial products at competitive prices.</li>
<li>Manu Jain, head of <a href="https://www.mi.com/">Xiaomi</a>’s business in India where Xiaomi is the #1-selling smart phone. He built the Indian operation from the ground up; had zero dollar marketing budget for the first three years; and localized manufacturing for all Xiaomi phones sold in India.</li>
<li>Jim Xiao, founder and CEO of <a href="http://www.bymason.com">Mason</a>, a rising star who is creating &#8220;mobile infrastructure as a service.&#8221;</li>
<li>Irving Fain, founder and CEO of <a href="http://www.boweryfarming.com">Bowery Farming</a>. Irving and his team are on a mission to reimagine modern farming.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is there anything else you would like to share with TechCrunch readers?</strong></p>
<p>Worry less about trends and build products that resonate with customers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Dayna Grayson, Construct Capital<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096389</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>iSpot expands its ad measurement platform by acquiring Ace Metrix</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/ispot-acquires-ace-metrix/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/ispot-acquires-ace-metrix/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ace metrix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iSpot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leapfrog ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palomar ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wpp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[iSpot.tv announced today that it has acquired Ace Metrix, a deal that brings two TV and video ad measurement companies together. iSpot founder and CEO Sean Muller said that the companies have complementary solutions. After all, he said, &#8220;In simple terms, there are only two reasons why brands buy advertising — one is to deliver business [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.ispot.tv">iSpot.tv</a> announced today that it has acquired <a href="https://www.acemetrix.com">Ace Metrix</a>, a deal that brings two TV and video ad measurement companies together.</p>
<p>iSpot founder and CEO Sean Muller said that the companies have complementary solutions. After all, he said, &#8220;In simple terms, there are only two reasons why brands buy advertising — one is to deliver business results and the other is to build brand recognition, likability and impact.&#8221;</p>
<p>The existing iSpot platform excels in the first area, Muller said, measuring the reach and conversation rates of ads that run on both TV and streaming. Ace Metrix, on the other hand, measures how an ad affects consumer sentiment — so by bringing the two companies together, it can offer &#8220;a complete solution in one platform.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Muller added that measuring the brand impact of an ad has become even more important as marketers try to navigate a constantly changing news landscape (to put it mildly).</p>
<p>&#8220;Brands are being forced to have a say in politics and all sorts of things,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Understanding the way your messages are being perceived is crucially important &#8230; When you invest in a piece of creative, it becomes even more important to ensure that your message is on point and triggers the right emotions.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kYXonmjow6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/05/19/ispot-series-b/">iSpot.tv Raises $21.9M To Track The Online Impact Of TV Advertising</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;iSpot.tv Raises $21.9M To Track The Online Impact Of TV Advertising&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2015/05/19/ispot-series-b/embed/#?secret=kYXonmjow6" data-secret="kYXonmjow6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Ace Metrix had raised $25 million in funding from investors including Hummer Winblad Venture Partners, WPP, Palomar Ventures and Leapfrog Ventures, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/ace-metrix">according to Crunchbase.</a></p>
<p>The financial terms of the acquisition were not disclosed, but iSpot says Ace&#8217;s 45 employees will all be joining the company, bringing total headcount to 240, with Ace CEO Peter Daboll becoming iSpot&#8217;s chief strategy officer. Ace will also maintain its office in Los Angeles (iSpot is headquartered in Bellevue, Washington).</p>
<p>Muller also noted that Ace had annualized SaaS revenues &#8220;north of the double digit millions&#8221; and that it was cashflow positive. The combined company has annual contracts with more than 500 brands.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re integrating the companies together very quickly — it&#8217;s already underway,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We&#8217;re going to be one company, one vision and so the Ace products become part of the iSpot product suite. But we will maintain the Ace name for those products.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oB1GelG4Dk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/breaking-down-the-specs-of-a-successful-video-ad/">Breaking down the specs of a successful video ad</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Breaking down the specs of a successful video ad&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/breaking-down-the-specs-of-a-successful-video-ad/embed/#?secret=oB1GelG4Dk" data-secret="oB1GelG4Dk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/ispot-acquires-ace-metrix/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096698</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This new module keeps Philips Hue bulbs connected even when the wall switch gets flipped</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/this-new-module-keeps-philips-hue-bulbs-connected-even-when-the-wall-switch-gets-flipped/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/this-new-module-keeps-philips-hue-bulbs-connected-even-when-the-wall-switch-gets-flipped/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philips hue]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Philips Hue bulbs are pretty great, but they have a mortal enemy: the humble light switch. If you&#8217;ve got a Hue bulb tied to a standard light switch, flipping that switch means the Hue bulb loses power completely&#8230; along with any fancy tricks like controlling the bulb through your phone or a voice assistant. A [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Philips Hue bulbs are pretty great, but they have a mortal enemy: the humble light switch. If you&#8217;ve got a Hue bulb tied to a standard light switch, flipping that switch means the Hue bulb loses power completely&#8230; along with any fancy tricks like controlling the bulb through your phone or a voice assistant.</p>
<p>A few solutions for this exist, but mostly involve swapping out the switch in question for something with a bit more smarts. This morning Signify (the company previously known as Philips Lighting) announced an official solution that works with your existing switches, albeit with a caveat or two.</p>
<p>Called the &#8220;wall switch module&#8221;, it&#8217;s expected to ship later this year — Spring if you&#8217;re in Europe, or Summer if you&#8217;re in North America. Once wired up, it turns your existing light switch into something more like a Hue controller, allowing it to toggle between different light presets rather than simply cutting power.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At $40 each (or $70 for a 2-pack), it&#8217;s&#8230; not cheap. Add in the fact that it&#8217;s powered by a battery (presumably to remove the need for a neutral wire and simplify installation) with an estimated lifespan of ~5 years, this probably isn&#8217;t something you want to implement house-wide. But for a single light switch or two, it seems like a decent solution.</p>
<p><strong>The company also announced a few new Hue accessories, in case you&#8217;re looking to expand your collection: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A revised version of its portable dimmer switch, which will ship in February and cost $25. The seperate on/off buttons are becoming a single toggle, and a &#8220;Hue&#8221; button is being added to let you trigger a specific lighting scene.</li>
<li>A new light bar, the Philips Hue Amarant, which is meant to live outside and be mounted on the ground or an overhang. It&#8217;ll ship in March in North America, and cost $170 each (though you&#8217;ll also need an outdoor Hue power supply box, which will add $60-$70 bucks to the price if you don&#8217;t have one already.)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/this-new-module-keeps-philips-hue-bulbs-connected-even-when-the-wall-switch-gets-flipped/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096674</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medium acquires social book reading app Glose</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/medium-acquires-social-book-reading-app-glose/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/medium-acquires-social-book-reading-app-glose/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medium]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Medium is acquiring Paris-based startup Glose for an undisclosed amount. Glose has been building iOS, Android and web apps that let you buy, download and read books on your devices. The company has turned reading into a multiplayer experience as you can build a bookshelf, share notes with your followers and start conversations in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://medium.com">Medium</a> is <a href="https://blog.medium.com/medium-acquires-social-ebook-platform-glose-cf2e94485d8">acquiring</a> Paris-based startup <a href="https://glose.com/what-is-glose">Glose</a> for an undisclosed amount. Glose has been building iOS, Android and web apps that let you buy, download and read books on your devices.</p>
<p>The company has turned reading into a multiplayer experience as you can build a bookshelf, share notes with your followers and start conversations in the margins. Sure, there are social platforms that let you talk about books, such as Goodreads. But Glose&#8217;s differentiating point is that the social features are intrinsically linked with the reading features — those aren&#8217;t two separate platforms. There are also some gamification features that help you stay motivated as you read difficult books —&nbsp;you get streak rewards for instance.</p>
<p>In many ways, Glose’s one-tap highlighting and commenting features are reminiscent of Medium’s features on this front. You can highlight text in any reading app on your phone or tablet but you can’t do much with it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>More recently, Glose has launched a separate service called <a href="https://glose.education">Glose Education</a>. As the name suggests, that version is tailored for universities and high schools. Teachers can hand out assignments and you can read a book as a group.</p>
<p>Over 1 million people have used Glose and 25 universities have signed up to Glose Education, including Stanford and Columbia University.</p>
<p>But Glose isn’t just a software play. The company has also put together a comprehensive book store. The company has partnered with 20,000 publishers so that you can buy ebooks directly from the app.</p>
<p>And if you are studying Virginia Wolf this semester, Glose also provides hundreds of thousands of public domain books for free. Glose also supports audio books.</p>
<p>This is by far the most interesting part as Medium now plans to expand beyond articles and blogs. While Glose is sticking around for now, Medium also plans to integrate ebooks and audio books to its service.</p>
<p>It’s a smart move as many prolific bloggers are also book writers. Right now, they write a blog post on Medium and link to a third-party site if you want to buy their books. Having the ability to host everything written by an author is a better experience for both content creators and readers.</p>
<p>“We’re impressed not only by Glose&#39;s reading products and technology, but also by their experience in partnering with book authors and publishers,&quot; Medium CEO Ev Williams said in a statement. “Books are a means of exploring an idea, a way to go deeper. The vast majority of the world’s ideas are stored in books and journals, yet are hardly searchable nor shareable. With Glose, we want to improve that experience within Medium’s large network of engaged readers and writers. We look forward to working with the Glose team on partnering with publishers to help authors reach more readers.&quot;</p>
<p>The Glose team will remain in Paris, which means that Medium is opening its first office outside of the U.S. Glose will continue to honor its partnerships with authors, publishers, schools and institutions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KQX5QjVKqx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/11/13/glose-is-a-new-ebook-reader-to-turn-reading-into-a-social-experience/">Glose Is A New Ebook Reader That Turns Reading Into A Social Experience</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Glose Is A New Ebook Reader That Turns Reading Into A Social Experience&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/11/13/glose-is-a-new-ebook-reader-to-turn-reading-into-a-social-experience/embed/#?secret=KQX5QjVKqx" data-secret="KQX5QjVKqx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/medium-acquires-social-book-reading-app-glose/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096643</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Confusion over WhatsApp&#8217;s new T&#038;Cs triggers privacy warning from Italy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 18:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU data protection law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tcs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096467</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Confusion over an update to Facebook-owned chat platform WhatsApp&#8217;s terms and conditions has triggered an intervention by Italy&#8217;s data protection agency. The Italian GPDP said today it has contacted the European Data Protection Board (EDPB) to raise concerns about a lack of clear information over what&#8217;s changing under the incoming T&#38;Cs. In recent weeks WhatsApp [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Confusion over an update to Facebook-owned chat platform WhatsApp&#8217;s terms and conditions has triggered an intervention by Italy&#8217;s data protection agency.</p>
<p>The Italian GPDP said today it has contacted the European Data Protection Board (EDPB) to raise concerns about a lack of clear information over what&#8217;s changing under the incoming T&amp;Cs.</p>
<p>In recent weeks WhatsApp has been alerting users they must accept new T&amp;Cs in order to keep using the service after February 8.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A similar alert over updated terms has also triggered concerns in India &#8212; where a petition was filed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/whatsapp-faces-legal-challenge-over-privacy-in-its-biggest-market/">today</a> in the Delhi High Court alleging the new terms are a violation of users&#8217; fundamental rights to privacy and pose a threat to national security.</p>
<p>In a notification on its <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9519943">website</a> the Italian agency writes that it believes it is not possible for WhatsApp users to understand the changes that are being introduced under the new terms, nor to &#8220;clearly understand which data processing will actually be carried out by the messaging service after February 8&#8221;.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096622" style="width: 428px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096622" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2096622" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png?w=418" alt="" width="418" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png 737w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png?resize=92,150 92w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png?resize=185,300 185w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png?resize=418,680 418w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png?resize=31,50 31w" sizes="(max-width: 418px) 100vw, 418px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2096622" class="wp-caption-text">Screengrab of the T&amp;Cs alert being shown to WhatsApp users in Europe (Image credit: TechCrunch)</p></div></p>
<p>For consent to be a valid legal basis for processing personal data under EU law the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) requires that users are properly informed of each specific use and given a free choice over whether their data is processed for each purpose.</p>
<p>The Italian agency adds that it reserves the right to intervene &#8220;as a matter of urgency&#8221; in order to protect users and enforce EU laws on the protection of personal data.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve reached out to the EDPB with questions about the GPDP&#8217;s intervention. The steering body&#8217;s role is typically to act as a liaison between EU DPAs. But it also issues guidance on the interpretation of EU law and can step in to cast the deciding vote in cases where there is disagreement on cross-border EU investigations.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JEoO50GzAe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/e2e-encrypted-email-providers-also-see-sign-ups-surge-as-chat-app-users-flock-to-signal-and-telegram-in-search-of-privacy/">E2E encrypted email providers also see sign-ups surge as chat app users flock to Signal and Telegram in search of privacy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;E2E encrypted email providers also see sign-ups surge as chat app users flock to Signal and Telegram in search of privacy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/e2e-encrypted-email-providers-also-see-sign-ups-surge-as-chat-app-users-flock-to-signal-and-telegram-in-search-of-privacy/embed/#?secret=JEoO50GzAe" data-secret="JEoO50GzAe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://www.euronews.com/2021/01/11/turkey-investigates-whatsapp-and-facebook-over-data-privacy-update">Earlier this week</a> Turkish antitrust authorities also announced they are investigating WhatsApp&#8217;s updated T&amp;Cs &#8212; objecting to what they claimed are differences in how much data will be shared with Facebook under the new terms in Europe and outside.</p>
<p>While, on Monday, Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission &#8212; which is WhatsApp&#8217;s lead data regulator in the EU &#8212; told us the messaging app has given it a commitment EU users are not affected by any broader change to data-sharing practices. So Facebook&#8217;s lead regulator in the EU has not raised any objections to the new WhatsApp T&amp;Cs.</p>
<p>WhatsApp itself has also claimed there are no changes at all to its data sharing practices anywhere in the world under this update.</p>
<p>Clearly there&#8217;s been a communications failure somewhere along the chain &#8212; which makes the Italian objection to a lack of clarity in the wording of the new T&amp;Cs seem reasonable.</p>
<p>Reached for comment on the GDPD&#8217;s intervention, a WhatsApp spokesperson told us:</p>
<blockquote><p>We are reviewing the Garante&#8217;s announcement regarding WhatsApp&#8217;s Privacy Policy update. We want to be clear that the policy update does not affect the privacy of your messages with friends or family in any way or require Italian users to agree to new data-sharing practices with Facebook. Instead, this update provides further transparency about how we collect and use data, as well as clarifying changes related to messaging a business on WhatsApp, which is optional. We remain committed to providing everyone in Italy with private end-to-end encrypted messaging.</p></blockquote>
<p>How exactly the Italian agency could intervene over the WhatsApp T&amp;Cs is an interesting question. (And, indeed, we&#8217;ve reached out to the GPDP with questions.)</p>
<p>The GDPR&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism means cross-border complaints get funnelled through a lead data supervisor where a company has its main regional base (Ireland in WhatsApp&#8217;s case). But as noted above, Ireland has &#8212; thus far &#8212; said it doesn&#8217;t have a problem with WhatsApp&#8217;s updated T&amp;Cs.</p>
<p>However under the GDPR, other DPAs do have powers to act off their own bat when they believe there is a pressing risk to users&#8217; data.</p>
<p>Such as, in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/02/google-ordered-to-halt-human-review-of-voice-ai-recordings-over-privacy-risks/">2019</a>, when the Hamburg DPA ordered Google to stop manual reviews of snippets of Google Assistant users&#8217; audio (which it had been reviewing as part of a grading program).</p>
<p>In that case Hamburg informed Google of its intention to use the GDPR&#8217;s Article 66 powers &#8212; which allows a national agency to order data processing to stop if it believes there is “an urgent need to act in order to protect the rights and freedoms of data subjects” &#8212; which immediately led to Google suspending human reviews across Europe.</p>
<p>The tech giant later amended how the program operates. The Hamburg DPA didn&#8217;t even need to <em>use</em> Article 66 &#8212; just the mere threat of the order to stop processing was enough.</p>
<p>Some 1.5 years later and there are signs many EU data protection agencies &#8212; outside a couple of key jurisdictions which oversee the lion&#8217;s share of big tech &#8212; are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/20/further-delay-to-gdpr-enforcement-of-2018-twitter-breach/">becoming frustrated</a> by perceived regulatory inaction against big tech.</p>
<p>So there may be an increased willingness among these agencies to resort to creative procedures of their own to protect citizens&#8217; data. (And it&#8217;s certainly interesting to note that France&#8217;s CNIL recently slapped <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/france-fines-google-120m-and-amazon-42m-for-dropping-tracking-cookies-without-consent/">Amazon and Google with big fines over cookie consents</a> &#8212; acting under the ePrivacy Directive, which does not include a GDPR-style one-stop-shop mechanism.)</p>
<p>In related news this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/facebooks-eu-us-data-transfers-face-their-final-countdown/">week</a>, an opinion by an advisor to the EU&#8217;s top court also appears to be responding to concern at GDPR enforcement bottlenecks.</p>
<p>In the opinion <a href="https://curia.europa.eu/jcms/upload/docs/application/pdf/2021-01/cp210001en.pdf">Advocate General Bobek takes the view</a> that the law allows national DPAs to bring their own proceedings in certain situations &#8212; including in order to adopt “urgent measures” or to intervene “following the lead data protection authority having decided not to handle a case”.</p>
<p>The CJEU ruling on that case is still pending but the court tends to align with the position of its advisors so it seems likely we&#8217;ll see data protection enforcement activity increasing across the board from EU DPAs in the coming years, rather than being stuck waiting for a few DPAs to issue all the major decisions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="R2NboKXYmr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/">GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/embed/#?secret=R2NboKXYmr" data-secret="R2NboKXYmr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096467</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond Meat shares soar after inking deal with Taco Bell on new menu items</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/beyond-meat-shares-soar-after-inking-deal-with-taco-bell-on-new-menu-items/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/beyond-meat-shares-soar-after-inking-deal-with-taco-bell-on-new-menu-items/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 18:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beyond Meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fast food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taco bell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yum brands]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shares of Beyond Meat are soaring on news that the company will be working with Taco Bell on new menu items. The company&#8217;s stock was up $17.13, or 13.67%, to $142.48 and climbing in midday trading after Taco Bell announced that it would embrace Beyond Meat to come up with new menu items due to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Shares of <a href="https://www.beyondmeat.com/">Beyond Meat</a> are soaring on news that the company will be working with Taco Bell on new menu items.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s stock <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=beyond+meat+shares&amp;rlz=1C5GCEA_enUS896US897&amp;oq=beyond+meat+shares&amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j0l8.1953j0j7&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8">was up $17.13, or 13.67%, to $142.48 and climbing</a> in midday trading after Taco Bell announced that it would embrace Beyond Meat to come up with new menu items due to be tested in the next year.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2096617" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Unsaved-Preview-Document-4.png" alt="" width="1024" height="762" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Unsaved-Preview-Document-4.png 1392w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Unsaved-Preview-Document-4.png?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Unsaved-Preview-Document-4.png?resize=300,223 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Unsaved-Preview-Document-4.png?resize=768,572 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Unsaved-Preview-Document-4.png?resize=680,506 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Unsaved-Preview-Document-4.png?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The decision from Taco Bell, a subsidiary of Yum Brands,<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/06/19/taco-bell-will-not-be-adding-fake-meat-from-beyond-meat-to-its-menu.html"> is a departure from the Mexican fast food chain&#8217;s commitment to go it alone</a> as it developed new vegetarian menu items.</p>
<p>“We’ve looked. We’ve met with Beyond, we’ve met with Impossible — our head of innovation knows everybody, and they all know her,” Julie Felss Masino, Taco Bell’s president of North American operations, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/06/19/taco-bell-will-not-be-adding-fake-meat-from-beyond-meat-to-its-menu.html">told CNBC back in 2019</a>. “But I think what we’re proud of is that we’ve been doing vegetarian for 57 years.”</p>
<p>Now the company wants más alternative proteins from the Southern California alternative protein provider. &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">We have long been a leader in the vegetarian space, but this year, we have more meatless options in store that vegetarians, veggie-curious and even meat-eaters will love,&#8221; said Liz Matthews, Taco Bell&#8217;s Global Chief Food Innovation Officer. </span></p>
<p>Taco Bell boasts that it already has over 30 vegetarian ingredients on the U.S. menu, but its lack of protein alternatives was noticeable as many of its competitors embraced the meat substitute craze.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/beyond-meat-shares-soar-after-inking-deal-with-taco-bell-on-new-menu-items/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096565</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swimm raises $5.7M to help teams document their code</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/swimm-raises-5-7m-to-help-teams-document-their-code/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/swimm-raises-5-7m-to-help-teams-document-their-code/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 18:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[documentation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[information]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pitango]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Most developers don&#8217;t enjoy writing documentation for their code and that makes life quite a bit harder when a new team member tries to get started on working on a company&#8217;s codebase. And even when there are documentation or in-line comments in the source code, that&#8217;s often not updated and over time, that information becomes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Most developers don&#8217;t enjoy writing documentation for their code and that makes life quite a bit harder when a new team member tries to get started on working on a company&#8217;s codebase. And even when there are documentation or in-line comments in the source code, that&#8217;s often not updated and over time, that information becomes close to irrelevant. <a href="https://swimm.io/">Swimm</a>, which today announced that it has raised a $5.7 million seed round, aims to automate as much of this process as possible after the initial documentation has been written by automatically updating it as changes are made.</p>
<p>The funding round was led by Pitango First, with TAU Ventures, Axon Ventures and Fundfire also investing in this round, together with a group of angel investors that include the founder of developer platform Snyk.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096535" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_linkedIn@3x.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096535" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2096535" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_linkedIn@3x.png" alt="" width="1024" height="536" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_linkedIn@3x.png 3600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_linkedIn@3x.png?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_linkedIn@3x.png?resize=300,157 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_linkedIn@3x.png?resize=768,402 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_linkedIn@3x.png?resize=680,356 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_linkedIn@3x.png?resize=1536,804 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_linkedIn@3x.png?resize=2048,1072 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_linkedIn@3x.png?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2096535" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Swimm</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Swimm&#8217;s marketing mostly focuses on helping teams speed up onboarding, but it&#8217;s probably a useful tool for any team. Using Swimm, you can create the standard &#8212; but auto-updated &#8212; documentation, but also walkthroughs and tutorials. Using its code browser, you can also easily find all of the documentation that relates to a given file.</p>
<p>The nifty part here is that while the tool can&#8217;t write the documentation for you, Swimm will automatically update any code examples in the documentation for you &#8212; or alert you when there is a major change that needs a manual update. Ideally, this will reduce the drift between the codebase and documentation.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096561" style="width: 358px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/plans-scroll-4x.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096561" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2096561" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/plans-scroll-4x.png?w=680" alt="" width="348" height="261" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/plans-scroll-4x.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/plans-scroll-4x.png?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/plans-scroll-4x.png?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/plans-scroll-4x.png?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/plans-scroll-4x.png?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/plans-scroll-4x.png?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/plans-scroll-4x.png?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 348px) 100vw, 348px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2096561" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Swimm</p></div></p>
<p>The founding team, Oren Toledano (CEO), Omer Rosenbaum (CTO), Gilad Navot (Chief Product Officer) and Tom Ahi Dror (Chief Business Officer), started working on this problem based on their experience while running <a href="https://www.itc.tech/">Israel Tech Challenge</a>, a coding bootcamp inspired by the training program used by the Israeli Defence Forces&#8217; 8200 Intelligence Unit.</p>
<p>&#8220;We met with many companies in Israel and in the US to understand the engineering onboarding process,&#8221; Toledano told me. &#8220;And we felt that it was kind of broken &#8212; and many times, we heard the sentence: &#8216;we throw them to the water, and they either sink or swim.'&#8221; (That&#8217;s also why the company is called Swimm). Companies, he argues, often don&#8217;t have a way to train new employees on their code base, simply because it&#8217;s impossible for them to do so effectively without good documentation.</p>
<p>&#8220;The larger the company is, the more scattered the knowledge on the code base is &#8212; and a lot of this knowledge leaves the company when developers leave,&#8221; he noted.</p>
<p>With Swimm, a company could ideally not just offer those new hires access to tutorials that are based on the current code base, but also an easier entryway to start working on the production codebase as well.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096582" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096582" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2096582" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/new-swimm_ig-product@3x.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2096582" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Swimm</p></div></p>
<p>One thing that&#8217;s worth noting here is that developers run Swimm locally on a developer&#8217;s machine. In part, that&#8217;s because this approach reduces the security risks since no code is ever sent to Swimm&#8217;s servers. Indeed, the Swimm team tells me that some of its early customers are security companies. It also makes it easier for new users to get started with Swimm.</p>
<p>Toledano tells me that while the team mostly focused on building the core of the product and working with its early design partners (and its first set of paying customers), the plan for the next few months is to bring on more users after launching the product&#8217;s beta.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;Software development is now at the core of every modern business. <span class="il">Swimm</span> provides a structured, contextual and transparent way to improve developer productivity,&#8221; said Yair Cassuto, a partner at Pitango First who is joining <span class="il">Swimm</span>&#8216;s board. &#8220;<span class="il">Swimm</span>’s solution allows for rapid and insightful onboarding on any codebase. This applies across the developer life cycle: from onboarding to project transitions, adopting new open source capabilities and even offboarding.&#8221;                        <wbr></wbr>                                                           <wbr></wbr></p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/G88Dc4z_RWE?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/swimm-raises-5-7m-to-help-teams-document-their-code/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096498</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nuclear fusion tech developer General Fusion now has Shopify and Amazon founders backing it</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/nuclear-fusion-tech-developer-general-fusion-now-has-shopify-and-amazon-founders-backing-it/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/nuclear-fusion-tech-developer-general-fusion-now-has-shopify-and-amazon-founders-backing-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 17:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakthrough Energy Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fusion power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuclear fusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plasma physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a brief announcement today, the Canadian nuclear fusion technology developer General Fusion announced that the investment firm created by Shopify founder Tobias Lütke has joined the company&#8217;s cap table. The size of the investment made by Lütke&#8217;s Thistledown Capital was not disclosed, but with the addition, General Fusion has the founders of the two [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a brief announcement today, the Canadian nuclear fusion technology developer <a href="https://generalfusion.com/">General Fusion</a> announced that the investment firm created by Shopify founder Tobias Lütke has joined the company&#8217;s cap table.</p>
<p>The size of the investment made by Lütke&#8217;s Thistledown Capital was not disclosed, but with the addition, General Fusion has the founders of the two biggest e-commerce companies in the Western world on its cap table.</p>
<p>Jeff Bezos, the founder and chief executive of Amazon, first invested in the company nearly a decade ago and General Fusion has been steadily raising cash since that time. In 2019, the company hauled in $100 million. That capital commitment is part of a haul totaling at least, $192 million, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/general-fusion">according to Crunchbase</a> although the real figure is likely higher.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Indeed, General Fusion <a href="https://generalfusion.com/2020/07/general-fusion-brings-in-more-large-global-investors/">kept adding cash</a> throughout 2020 as it looked to develop its demonstration fusion reactor.</p>
<p>General Fusion&#8217;s process is based on technology called magnetized target fusion (MTF), first proposed by the U.S. Naval Research Lab and developed in the 1970s.</p>
<p>The process involves creating a magnetically confined moderately warm plasma of around 100 eV (roughly 50 times the photon energy of visible light) in a flux conserver (a shell that preserves the magnetic field). By rapidly compressing the flux conserver and the magnetic field inside of it surrounding the plasma, the plasma is superheated to a temperature that can initiate a fast fusion burn and create a fusion reaction, <a href="https://generalfusion.com/2017/06/tokamak-compression-experiments-general-fusion-cap-congress/">according to a 2017 description of the technology</a> from General Fusion&#8217;s chief science officer and founder, Michel Laberge.</p>
<p>The company uses a roughly three-meter sphere filled with molten lead-lithium that&#8217;s pumped to form a cavity. A pulse of magnetically confined plasma fuel is then injected into the cavity. Then, around the sphere, pistons create a pressure wave into the middle of the sphere, compressing the plasma to fusion conditions.</p>
<p>Neutrons escaping from the fusion reaction are captured in the liquid metal, and the heat from that metal generates electricity via a steam turbine. A heat exchanger steam turbine produces the power and the steam is recycled to run the pistons.</p>
<p>In recent years, both General Fusion and its main North American competitor <a href="https://cfs.energy/">Commonwealth Fusion Systems</a> have made strides in getting their small-scale nuclear fusion technology ready for commercialization.</p>
<p>In the past, the wry joke about fusion technologies was that they were always 10 years away, but now companies are looking at a four-year horizon to bring fusion to initial markets, if not the masses.</p>
<p>For its part, Commonwealth Fusion Systems is in the process of building a 10-ton magnet that has the magnetic force equivalent to 20 MRI machines. “After we get the magnet to work, we’ll be building a machine that will generate more power than it takes to run. We see that as the Kitty Hawk moment [for fusion],” said Bob Mumgaard, the chief executive of Commonwealth Fusion <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/with-84-million-in-new-cash-commonwealth-fusion-is-on-track-for-a-demonstration-fusion-reactor-by-2025/">in an interview last year</a>.</p>
<p>Other startup companies are also racing to bring technologies to market and hit the 2025 timeline like the United Kingdom’s <a href="https://www.tokamakenergy.co.uk/">Tokamak Energy</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EOTsOUgxdP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/with-84-million-in-new-cash-commonwealth-fusion-is-on-track-for-a-demonstration-fusion-reactor-by-2025/">With $84 million in new cash, Commonwealth Fusion is on track for a demonstration fusion reactor by 2025</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With $84 million in new cash, Commonwealth Fusion is on track for a demonstration fusion reactor by 2025&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/with-84-million-in-new-cash-commonwealth-fusion-is-on-track-for-a-demonstration-fusion-reactor-by-2025/embed/#?secret=EOTsOUgxdP" data-secret="EOTsOUgxdP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Like General Fusion, Commonwealth also has deep-pocketed backers including the Bill Gates-backed sustainable-technology-focused investor, Breakthrough Energy Ventures. In all, those investors have committed over $200 million to the company, which formally launched in 2018.</p>
<p>As these companies begin readying their technologies for market, governments are laying the groundwork to make it easier for them to commercialize.</p>
<p>At the end of last year, the Trump administration <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/133/text?r=1&amp;s=3">signed the COVID relief and omnibus appropriations bill</a> that included an amendment to support the development of fusion energy in the U.S.</p>
<p>The new amendment directed the Department of Energy to carry out a fusion energy sciences research and development program; authorized DOE programs in inertial fusion energy and alternative concepts to find new ways forward for fusion power; reauthorized the INFUSE program to create public-private partnerships between national labs and fusion developers; and created a milestone-based development program to support companies not just through R&amp;D, but into the construction of full-scale systems.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s this milestone program that was a cornerstone of the policy work that the Fusion Industry Association wanted to see in the U.S., according to a December statement from the organization.</p>
<p>By unlocking $325 million in financing over a five-year period, the U.S. government will actually double its research with matching contributions from the fusion industry. These demonstration facilities could go a long way toward accelerating the deployment of fusion technologies.</p>
<p>Founded in 2019, Thistledown Capital was formed to invest in tech that can decarbonize industry. The firm, based in Ottawa, has already backed CarbonCure, a technology that captures carbon dioxide from the air.</p>
<p>“<span class="il">General</span> <span class="il">Fusion</span> has a strong record of attracting funding support from some of the world’s most influential technology leaders,” said Greg Twinney, CFO, <span class="il">General</span> <span class="il">Fusion, in a statement.</span> “<span class="il">Fusion</span> is planet-saving technology, and we are proud to support the mission of Thistledown Capital in its pursuit for a greener tomorrow.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/nuclear-fusion-tech-developer-general-fusion-now-has-shopify-and-amazon-founders-backing-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096384</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blue Origin successfully launches and lands key crew capsule test in first mission of 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/blue-origin-successfully-launches-and-lands-key-crew-capsule-test-in-first-mission-of-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/blue-origin-successfully-launches-and-lands-key-crew-capsule-test-in-first-mission-of-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 17:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new shepard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blue Origin launched its first mission of 2021, flying its New Shepard rocket in West Texas to a medium height of just over 350,000 feet. This is the first flight for this particular booster, and for the capsule it carried, which was equipped with a range of new passenger safety, control and comfort systems that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Blue Origin launched its first mission of 2021, flying its New Shepard rocket in West Texas to a medium height of just over 350,000 feet. This is the first flight for this particular booster, and for the capsule it carried, which was equipped with a range of new passenger safety, control and comfort systems that Blue Origin was testing during flight for the first time. Also on board was a life-sized test dummy called &#8216;Mannequin Skywalker&#8217; that recorded information during the flight and landing that the Blue Origin will now review.</p>
<p>Based on the video stream and commentary from the company, this looks like a very successful test, including a takeoff, booster separation, controlled landing burn and touchdown – and a parachute-aided landing back on terra firma for the crew capsule. The mission didn&#8217;t carry any real passengers, although there were 50,000 postcards on board from school kids globally that have now officially been to space (past the Karman line) which will be returned to those students via Blue Origin&#8217;s non-profit &#8216;Club for the Future.&#8217;</p>
<p>This is essentially what the mission will look like once Blue Origin actually begins to fly paying private astronauts to suborbital space as well; while we don&#8217;t have a timeline for when that&#8217;ll happen, today&#8217;s launch included key tests of a crew alert system that will provide anyone onboard with crucial mission information, as well as a new soft lining on the wall for protection during the weightless portion of the flight, as well as for sound and vibration dampening for the comfort of those on board. This capsule was also equipped with a carbon dioxide scrubber, which will be used to provide safe atmosphere for those within the capsule during the course of the flight.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2096542" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blue-origin-ns14-landing.gif" alt="" width="1000" height="560" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/blue-origin-successfully-launches-and-lands-key-crew-capsule-test-in-first-mission-of-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096525</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thimble teaches kids STEM skills with robotics kits combined with live Zoom classes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/thimble-teaches-kids-stem-skills-with-robotics-kits-combined-with-live-zoom-classes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/thimble-teaches-kids-stem-skills-with-robotics-kits-combined-with-live-zoom-classes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 17:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STEM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teacher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thimble]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096472</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Parents with kids stuck learning at home during the pandemic have had to look for alternative activities to promote the hands-on learning experiences kids are missing out on due to attending class virtually. The New York-based educational technology startup Thimble aims to help address this problem by offering a subscription service for STEM-based projects that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Parents with kids stuck learning at home during the pandemic have had to look for alternative activities to promote the hands-on learning experiences kids are missing out on due to attending class virtually. The New York-based educational technology startup <a href="https://thimble.io/">Thimble</a> aims to help address this problem by offering a subscription service for STEM-based projects that allow kids to make robotics, electronics and other tech using a combination of kits shipped to the home and live online instruction.</p>
<p>Thimble began back in 2016 as Kickstarter project when it raised $300,000 in 45 days to develop its STEM-based robotics and programming kits. The next year, it then began selling its kits to schools, largely in New York, for use in the classroom or in after-school programs. Over the years that followed, Thimble scaled its customer base to include around 250 schools across New York, Pennsylvania, and California, who would buy the kits and gain access to teacher training.</p>
<p>But the COVID-19 pandemic changed the course of Thimble&#8217;s business.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;A lot of schools were in panic mode. They were not sure what was happening, and so their spending was frozen for some time,&#8221; explains Thimble co-founder and CEO Oscar Pedroso, whose background is in education. &#8220;Even our top customers that I would call, they would just give [say], &#8216;hey, this is not a good time. We think we&#8217;re going to be closing schools down.&#8221;</p>
<p>Pedroso realized that the company would have to quickly pivot to begin selling directly to parents instead.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096509" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096509" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2096509" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set4.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="529" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set4.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set4.jpg?resize=150,117 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set4.jpg?resize=300,233 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set4.jpg?resize=768,598 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set4.jpg?resize=680,529 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set4.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2096509" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Thimble</p></div></p>
<p>Around April, it made the shift &#8212; effectively entering the B2C market for the first time.</p>
<p>The company today offers parents a subscription that allows them to receive up to 15 different STEM-focused project kits and a curriculum that includes live instruction from an educator. One kit is shipped out over the course of three months, though an accelerated program is available that ships with more frequency.</p>
<p>The first kit is basic electronics where kids learn how to build simple circuits, like a doorbell, kitchen timer and a music composer, for example. The kit is designed so kids can experience &#8220;quick wins&#8221; to keep their attention and whet their appetite for more projects. This leads into future kits like those offering a Wi-Fi robot, a little drone, an LED compass that lights up, and a synthesizer that lets kids become their own D.J.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096505" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096505" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2096505" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set8-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="529" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set8-1.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set8-1.jpg?resize=150,117 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set8-1.jpg?resize=300,233 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set8-1.jpg?resize=768,598 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set8-1.jpg?resize=680,529 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set8-1.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2096505" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Thimble</p></div></p>
<p>While any family can use the kits to help kids experience hands-on electronics and robotics, Pedroso says that about 70% of subscribers are those where the child already has a knack for doing these sorts of projects. The remaining 30% are those where the parents are looking to introduce the concepts of robotics and programming, to see if the kids show an interest. Around 40% of the students are girls.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://thimble.io/subscriptions/">subscription</a> is more expensive than some DIY projects at $59.99/per month (or $47.99/mo if paid annually), but this is because it includes live instruction in the form of weekly 1-hour Zoom classes. Thimble has part-time employees who are not just able to understand teach the material, but can do so in a way that appeals to children &#8212; by being passionate, energetic and capable of jumping in to help if they sense a child is having an issue or getting frustrated. Two of the five teachers are women. One instructor is bilingual and teaches some classes in Spanish.</p>
<p>During class, one teacher instructs while a second helps moderate the chat room and answer the questions that kids ask in there.</p>
<p>The live classes will have around 15-20 students each, but Thimble additionally offers a <a href="https://thimble.io/subscriptions-3/">package</a> for small groups that reduces class size. These could be used by homeschool &#8220;pods&#8221; or other groups.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096508" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096508" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2096508" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set5.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="529" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set5.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set5.jpg?resize=150,117 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set5.jpg?resize=300,233 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set5.jpg?resize=768,598 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set5.jpg?resize=680,529 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/creator-set5.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2096508" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Thimble</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We started hearing from pods and then micro-schools,&#8221; notes Pedroso. &#8220;Those were parents who were connected to other parents, and wanted their kids to be part of the same class. They generally required a little bit more attention and wanted some things a little more customized,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>These subscriptions are more expensive at $250/month, but the cost is shared among the group of parents, which brings the price down on per-household basis. Around 10% of the total customer base is on this plan, as most customers are individual families.</p>
<p>Thimble also works with several community programs and nonprofits in select markets that help to subsidize the cost of the kits to make the subscriptions more affordable. These are announced, as available, through schools, newsletters, and other marketing efforts.</p>
<p>Since pivoting to subscriptions, Thimble has re-established a customer base and now has 1,110 paid customers. Some, however, are grandfathered in to an earlier price point, so Thimble needs to scale the business further.</p>
<p>In addition to the Kickstarter, Thimble has raised funds and worked on the business over the year with the help of multiple accelerators, including LearnLaunch in Boston, Halcyon in D.C., and Telluride Venture Accelerator in Colorado.</p>
<p>The startup, co-founded by Joel Cilli in Pittsburgh, is now around 60% closed on its seed round of $1 million, but isn&#8217;t announcing details of that at this time.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/thimble-teaches-kids-stem-skills-with-robotics-kits-combined-with-live-zoom-classes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096472</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mosaic raises $18.5M Series A from GC to rebuild the CFO software stack</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/mosaic-raises-18-5m-series-a-from-gc-to-rebuild-the-cfo-software-stack/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/mosaic-raises-18-5m-series-a-from-gc-to-rebuild-the-cfo-software-stack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CFO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mosaic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2095960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CFOs are the supposed omniscient owners of a company. While the CEO sets strategy, messages, and builds culture, the CFO needs to know everything that it is going on in an organization. Where is revenue coming from, and when will it arrive? How much will new headcount cost, and when do those expenses need to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">CFOs are the supposed omniscient owners of a company. While the CEO sets strategy, messages, and builds culture, the CFO needs to know everything that it is going on in an organization. Where is revenue coming from, and when will it arrive? How much will new headcount cost, and when do those expenses need to be paid? How can cash flows be managed, and what debt products might help smooth out any discontinuities?</p>
<p>As companies have migrated to the cloud, these questions have gotten harder to answer as other departments started avoiding the ERP as a centralized system-of-record. Worse, CFOs are expected to be more strategic than ever about finance, but can struggle to deliver important forecasts and projections given the lack of availability of key data. CMOs have gotten a whole new software stack to run marketing in the past decade, so why not CFOs?</p>
<p>For three Palantir alums, the hope is that CFOs will turn to their new startup called <a href="https://www.mosaic.tech">Mosaic</a>. Mosaic is a “strategic finance platform” that is designed to ingest data from all sorts of systems in the alphabet soup of enterprise IT — ERPs, HRISs, CRMs, etc. — and then provide CFOs and their teams with strategic planning tools to be able to predict and forecast with better accuracy and with speed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company was founded in April 2019 by Bijan Moallemi, Brian Campbell and Joe Garafalo, who worked together at Palantir in the company’s finance team for more than 15 years collectively. While there, they saw the company grow from a small organization with a bit more than one hundred people to an organization with thousands of employees, more than <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/leaked-palantir-s-1-shows-company-has-125-customers-after-17-years/">one hundred customers as we saw last year with Palantir’s IPO</a>, and incoming revenue from more than a dozen countries.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096252" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096252" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2096252" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Founders.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="340" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Founders.jpg 4005w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Founders.jpg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Founders.jpg?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Founders.jpg?resize=768,384 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Founders.jpg?resize=680,340 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Founders.jpg?resize=1536,767 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Founders.jpg?resize=2048,1023 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Founders.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2096252" class="wp-caption-text">Mosaic founders Bijan Moallemi, Brian Campbell and Joseph Garafalo. Photos via Mosaic.</p></div></p>
<p>Strategically handling finance was critical for Palantir’s success, but the existing tools in its stack couldn’t keep up with the company’s needs. So Palantir ended up building its own. We were “not just cranking away in Excel, which is really the default tool in the toolkit for CFOs, but actually building a technical team that was writing code, [and] building tools to really give speed, access, trust, and visibility across the organization,” Moallemi, who is CEO of Mosaic, described.</p>
<p>Most organizations can’t spare their technical talent to the CFO’s office, and so as the three co-founders left Palantir to other pastures as heads of finance — Moallemi to edtech startup Piazza, Campbell to litigation management startup Everlaw and Garafalo to blockchain startup Axoni — they continued to percolate on how finance could be improved. They came together to do for all companies what they saw at Palantir: build a great software foundation for the CFO’s office. “Probably the biggest advancements to the office of the CFO over the last 10 years has been moving from kind of desktop-based Excel to cloud-based Google Sheets,” Moallemi said.</p>
<p>So what is Mosaic trying to do to rebuild the CFO software stack? It wants to build a platform that is a gateway to connecting the entire company to discuss finance in a more collaborative fashion. So while Mosaic focuses on reporting and planning, the mainstays of the finance office, it wants to open those dashboards and forecasts wider into the company so more people can have insight into what’s going on and also give feedback to the CFO.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096254" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096254" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2096254" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Screenshot.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="425" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Screenshot.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Screenshot.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Screenshot.png?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Screenshot.png?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Screenshot.png?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Screenshot.png?resize=1536,960 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Screenshot.png?resize=2048,1280 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Mosaic-Screenshot.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2096254" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot of Mosaic&#8217;s planning function. Photo via Mosaic.</p></div></p>
<p>There are a handful of companies like publicly-traded Anaplan that have entered this space in the last decade. Moallemi says incumbents have a couple of key challenges that Mosaic hopes to overcome. First is onboarding, which can take months for some of these companies as consultants integrate the software into a company’s workflow. Second is that these tools often require dedicated, full-time staff to stay operational. Third is that these tools are basically non-visible to anyone outside the CFO office. Mosaic wants to be ready to integrate immediately, widely distributed within orgs, and require minimal upkeep to be useful.</p>
<p>“Everyone wants to be strategic, but it&#8217;s so tough to do because 80% of your time is pulling data from these disparate systems, cleaning it, mapping it, updating your Excel files, and maybe 20% of [your time] is actually taking a step back and understanding what the data is telling you,” Moallemi said.</p>
<p>That’s perhaps why it’s target customers are Series B and C-funded companies, who no doubt have much of their data already located in easily-accessible databases. The company started with smaller companies and Moallemi said “We&#8217;ve been slowly inching our way up there over the last 12 months or so working with larger, more complex customers.” The company has grown to 30 employees and has revenues in the seven figures (without a sales org according to Moallemi), although the startup didn’t want to be more specific than that.</p>
<p>With all that growth and excitement, the company is attracting investor attention. Today, the company announced that it raised $18.5 million of Series A financing led by Trevor Oelschig of General Catalyst, who has led other enterprise SaaS deals into startups like Fivetran, Contentful, and Loom. That round closed at the end of last year.</p>
<p>Mosaic previously raised a $2.5 million seed investment led by Ross Fubini of XYZ Ventures in mid-2019, who was formerly an investor at Village Global. Fubini said by email that he was intrigued by the company because the founders had a “shared pain” at Palantir over the state of software for CFOs, and “they had all experienced this deep frustration with the tools they needed to do their jobs.”</p>
<p>Other investors in the Series A included Felicis Ventures, plus XYZ and Village Global.</p>
<p>Along with the financing, the company also announced the creation of an advisory board that includes the current or former CFOs from nine tech companies, including Palantir, Dropbox, and Shopify.</p>
<p>Many functions of business have had a complete transformation in software. Now, Mosaic hopes, it’s the CFO’s time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/mosaic-raises-18-5m-series-a-from-gc-to-rebuild-the-cfo-software-stack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2095960</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Poshmark prices IPO above range as public markets continue to YOLO startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/poshmark-prices-ipo-above-range-as-public-markets-continue-to-yolo-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/poshmark-prices-ipo-above-range-as-public-markets-continue-to-yolo-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 16:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poshmark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Poshmark priced its IPO at $42 per share last night, comfortably ahead of its $35 to $39 range that already greatly boosted the company's valuation.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Here we are again. Again.</p>
<p>Yes, it&#8217;s another morning in which we have to discuss a venture-backed technology company going public at a price above its IPO range.</p>
<p>This time it&#8217;s Poshmark, which <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/poshmark-inc-announces-pricing-of-initial-public-offering-301208035.html">priced its IPO</a> at $42 per share last night, comfortably ahead of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/at-35-to-39-per-share-poshmarks-ipo-could-5x-its-last-private-valuation/">its $35 to $39 range</a> that already greatly boosted the company&#8217;s valuation. The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/unpacking-poshmarks-ipo-filing/">consumer-to-consumer used fashion marketplace</a> sold 6.6 million shares at its IPO price, raising a gross $277.2 million before other possible shares are sold.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>According to <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/poshmark/company_financials">Crunchbase data</a>, that&#8217;s the biggest round Poshmark has raised in its history.</p>
<p>The company was able to so greatly boost its valuation in the process that the resulting dilution is minute. This is the late-2020, early-2021 IPO market in action: Pick a private company, boost its worth greatly in its public offering when comparing to its last private valuation, send it to trade and watch its worth &#8212; usually &#8212; soar.</p>
<p>Then venture capitalists get to complain that Wall Street is underpricing their children while, from where I sit, it always appears that the VCs who put the last money into the company before its public offering tend to do even better than the bankers.</p>
<p>A useful question to ask: Who is underpricing whom?</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995212 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>But this morning we have some work to do. First, what are Poshmark&#8217;s final simple and diluted valuations, what revenue multiples does it sport today, and, what do we think its final pricing means for public markets in general?</p>
<p>A hint: Nothing that follows is bearish.</p>
<h2>Poshmark&#8217;s IPO pricing</h2>
<p>There are a few ways to consider Poshmark&#8217;s value. One is to use its simple share count, a figure that doesn&#8217;t include vested-yet-unexercised stock options and RSUs. Another is to include those shares.</p>
<p>Here are the resulting valuations:<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/poshmark-prices-ipo-above-range-as-public-markets-continue-to-yolo-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096386</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech and health companies including Microsoft and Salesforce team up on digital COVID-19 vaccination records</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tech-and-health-companies-including-microsoft-and-salesforce-team-up-on-digital-covid-19-vaccination-records/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tech-and-health-companies-including-microsoft-and-salesforce-team-up-on-digital-covid-19-vaccination-records/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 16:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthvana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mayo Clinic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[standards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccination]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new cross-industry initiative is seeking to establish a standard for digital vaccination records that can be used universally to identify COVID-19 vaccination status for individuals, in a way that can be both secure via encryption and traceable and verifiable for trustworthiness regarding their contents. The so-called &#8220;Vaccination Credential Initiative&#8221; includes a range of big-name [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A new cross-industry initiative is <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210114005294/en/Broad-Coalition-of-Health-and-Technology-Industry-Leaders-Announce-Vaccination-Credential-Initiative-to-Accelerate-Digital-Access-to-COVID-19-Vaccination-Records">seeking to establish a standard</a> for digital vaccination records that can be used universally to identify COVID-19 vaccination status for individuals, in a way that can be both secure via encryption and traceable and verifiable for trustworthiness regarding their contents. The so-called &#8220;Vaccination Credential Initiative&#8221; includes a range of big-name companies from both the healthcare and the tech industry, including Microsoft, Oracle, Salesforce and Epic, as well as the Mayo Clinic, Safe Health, Change Healthcare and the CARIN Alliance to name a few.</p>
<p>The effort is beginning with existing, recognized standards already in use in digital healthcare programs, like the SMART Health Cards specification, which adheres to HL7 FHIR (Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources) which is a standard created for use in digital health records to make them interoperable between providers. The final product that the initiative aims to establish is an &#8220;encrypted digital copy of their immunization credentials to store in a digital wallet of their choice,&#8221; with a backup available as a printed QR code that includes W3C-standards verifiable credentials for individuals who don&#8217;t own or prefer not to use smartphones.</p>
<p>Vaccination credentials aren&#8217;t a new thing &#8212; they&#8217;ve existed in some form or another since the 1700s. But their use and history is also mired in controversy and accusations of inequity, since this is human beings we&#8217;re dealing with. And already with COVID-19, there are efforts underway to make access to certain geographies dependent upon negative COVID-19 test results (though such results don&#8217;t actually guarantee that an individual doesn&#8217;t actually have COVID-19 or won&#8217;t transfer it to others).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A recent initiative by LA County specifically also is already providing digital immunization records to individuals via a partnership with Healthvana, facilitated by Apple&#8217;s Wallet technology. But Healthvana&#8217;s CEO and founder was explicit in telling me that that isn&#8217;t about providing a proof of immunity for use in deterring an individual&#8217;s social or geographic access. Instead, it&#8217;s about informing and supporting patients for optimal care outcomes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aGRMq6UoKS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/healthvanas-digital-covid-19-vaccination-records-are-about-communication-not-passports-for-the-immune/">Healthvana&#8217;s digital COVID-19 vaccination records are about communication, not passports for the immune</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Healthvana&#8217;s digital COVID-19 vaccination records are about communication, not passports for the immune&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/healthvanas-digital-covid-19-vaccination-records-are-about-communication-not-passports-for-the-immune/embed/#?secret=aGRMq6UoKS" data-secret="aGRMq6UoKS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It sounds like this initiative is much more about using a COVID-19 immunization record as a literal passport of sorts. It&#8217;s right in the name of the initiative, for once (&#8220;Credential&#8221; is pretty explicit). The companies involved also at least seem cognizant of the potential pitfalls of such a program, as MITRE&#8217;s chief digital health physician Dr. Brian Anderson said that &#8220;we are working to ensure that underserved populations have access to this verification,&#8221; and added that &#8220;just as COVID-19 does not discriminate based on socio-economic status, we must ensure that convenient access to records crosses the digital divide.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other quotes from Oracle and Salesforce, and additional member leaders, confirm that the effort is focused on fostering a reopening of social and economic activity, including &#8220;resuming travel,&#8221; get[ting] back to public life,&#8221; and &#8220;get[ting] concerts and sporting events going again.&#8221; Safe Health also says that they&#8217;ll help facilitate a &#8220;privacy-preserving health status verification&#8221; solution that is at least in part &#8220;blockchain-enabled.&#8221;</p>
<p>Given the urgency of solutions that can lead to a safe re-opening, and a way to keep tabs on the massive, global vaccination program that&#8217;s already underway, it makes sense that a modern approach would include a digital version of historic vaccination record systems. But such an approach, while it leverages new conveniences and modes made possible by smartphones and the internet, also opens itself up to new potential pitfalls and risks that will no doubt be highly scrutinized, particularly by public interest groups focused on privacy and equitable treatment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tech-and-health-companies-including-microsoft-and-salesforce-team-up-on-digital-covid-19-vaccination-records/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096482</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plaid CEO touts new &#8216;clarity&#8217; after failed Visa acquisition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/plaid-ceo-touts-new-clarity-after-failed-visa-acquisition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/plaid-ceo-touts-new-clarity-after-failed-visa-acquisition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 16:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plaid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zach Perret]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[According to Plaid CEO Zach Perret, the COVID-19 pandemic triggered a "sea change" in consumer behavior.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Yesterday, we spoke with Plaid CEO and co-founder <a href="https://twitter.com/zachperret">Zach Perret</a> after news broke that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/visa-will-not-acquire-plaid-after-running-into-regulatory-wall/">Visa no longer plans to buy his company for $5.3 billion</a>.</p>
<p>The deal was heralded in early 2020 as a sign of the growing importance of fintech startups. Then it failed to close, eventually <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/doj-files-antitrust-lawsuit-challenging-visas-5-3-billion-acquisition-of-plaid/">running into a lawsuit from the U.S. Department of Justice</a>. A few months later, the acquisition was dropped.</p>
<p>Sentiment in the market changed since the transaction was announced. As TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/venture-capitalists-react-to-visa-plaid-deal-meltdown/">reported yesterday</a>, there&#8217;s a good deal of optimism to be found amongst investors and others that Plaid will eventually be worth more than the price at which the Visa deal valued it.</p>
<p>What follows is a summary of our conversation with Perret, digging into a number of topics we felt most were pressing in the wake of Plaid&#8217;s unshackling.</p>
<h2>Now what?</h2>
<p>First and upfront: It does not appear that Plaid is racing to the public markets via a blank-check company, or SPAC, a question several readers asked on Twitter. Our impression from our chat regarding near-term liquidity via the public markets is that those with their hopes up have them up a few years too early.</p>
<p>TechCrunch asked Perret how it feels to be free from his erstwhile corporate boss.</p>
<p>He said that the last few years have been a &#8220;roller coaster,&#8221; adding that when they made the choice to sell, it made sense at the time from mission and delivery perspectives — Visa wanted to accomplish similar things and could give his company access to a wide network of potential customers.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/plaid-ceo-touts-new-clarity-after-failed-visa-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096046</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WhatsApp faces legal challenge over privacy in its biggest market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/whatsapp-faces-legal-challenge-over-privacy-in-its-biggest-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/whatsapp-faces-legal-challenge-over-privacy-in-its-biggest-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 15:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paytm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WhatsApp is facing a legal challenge in India, its biggest market, after a petition was filed Thursday before Delhi High Court over the upcoming change in the Facebook-owned app’s data-sharing policy. The petition alleges the new terms that WhatsApp requires its roughly 450 million users in the country to accept is a violation of their [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">WhatsApp is facing a legal challenge in India, its biggest market, after a petition was filed Thursday before Delhi High Court over the upcoming change in the Facebook-owned app’s data-sharing policy.</p>
<p>The petition alleges the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/signal-brian-acton-talks-about-exploding-growth-monetization-and-whatsapp-data-sharing-outrage/">new terms</a> that WhatsApp requires its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/youtube-and-whatsapp-inch-closer-to-half-a-billion-users-in-india/">roughly 450 million users</a> in the country to accept is a violation of their fundamental rights to privacy and poses a threat to national security.</p>
<p>Through an in-app alert, WhatsApp has asked users in recent days to agree to new terms of conditions that grants the app the consent to share with Facebook some personal data about them, such as their phone number and location.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Users will have to agree to these terms by February 8 if they wish to continue using the app, the alert said. The change has been mischaracterized by many as their personal communication being compromised, which WhatsApp <a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/general/security-and-privacy/answering-your-questions-about-whatsapps-privacy-policy">clarified</a> this week was not the case.</p>
<p>The Facebook-owned service, which serves <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/12/whatsapp-hits-2-billion-users-up-from-1-5-billion-2-years-ago/">over 2 billion users worldwide</a>, said private conversations between people remain just as private as before. Facebook has also bought front-page newspaper ads in several leading Indian dailies this week to explain the change, which it first outlined last year.</p>
<p>The petitioner said the new terms grant WhatsApp a “360-degree profile into a person’s online activity” without any “government oversight.”</p>
<p>&#8220;WhatsApp has made a mockery out of our fundamental right to privacy while discharging a public function in India, besides jeopardizing the National Security of the country by sharing, transmitting and storing the users data in some [other] country and that data, in turn, will be governed by the laws of that foreign country,&#8221; the petition, which is expected to be heard Friday, reads.</p>
<p>Several high-profile startup founders and executives in India have also criticized WhatsApp’s new data-sharing policy. Vijay Shekhar Sharma, founder and chief executive of India’s most valuable startup Paytm, accused WhatsApp of operating with double standards, pointing to how the new change was not affecting the app’s users in Europe.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">How long we will be taken for granted by such blatant double standards ?<br />Self claimed ad claiming respect of our privacy v/s   actual policy.</p>
<p>For India <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f1ee-1f1f3.png" alt="🇮🇳" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />                For Europe <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f1ea-1f1fa.png" alt="🇪🇺" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/bT45XwvsO1">pic.twitter.com/bT45XwvsO1</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Vijay Shekhar Sharma (@vijayshekhar) <a href="https://twitter.com/vijayshekhar/status/1349186007007023104?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 13, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The outrage over the new change has resulted in tens of millions of users exploring other communication apps such as Signal and Telegram in recent days. In an interview with TechCrunch earlier this week, Signal co-founder and chairman executive Brian Acton said “the smallest of events helped trigger the largest of outcomes. We’re also excited that we are having conversations about online privacy and digital safety and people are turning to Signal as the answer to those questions.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PSLeXzJUOD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/signal-brian-acton-talks-about-exploding-growth-monetization-and-whatsapp-data-sharing-outrage/">Signal’s Brian Acton talks about exploding growth, monetization and WhatsApp data-sharing outrage</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Signal’s Brian Acton talks about exploding growth, monetization and WhatsApp data-sharing outrage&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/signal-brian-acton-talks-about-exploding-growth-monetization-and-whatsapp-data-sharing-outrage/embed/#?secret=PSLeXzJUOD" data-secret="PSLeXzJUOD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/whatsapp-faces-legal-challenge-over-privacy-in-its-biggest-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096465</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harness snags $85M Series C on $1.7B valuation as revenue grows 3x</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/harness-snags-85m-series-c-on-1-7b-valuation-as-revenue-grows-3x/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/harness-snags-85m-series-c-on-1-7b-valuation-as-revenue-grows-3x/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 15:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alkeon Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jyoti bansal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Harness, the startup that wants to create a suite of engineering tools to give every company the kind of technological reach that the biggest companies have, announced an $85 million Series C today on a $1.7 billion valuation. Today&#8217;s round comes after 2019&#8217;s $60 million Series B, which had a $500 million valuation, showing a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://harness.io/">Harness</a>, the startup that wants to create a suite of engineering tools to give every company the kind of technological reach that the biggest companies have, announced an $85 million Series C today on a $1.7 billion valuation.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s round comes after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/23/harness-hauls-in-60m-series-b-investment-on-500m-valuation/">2019&#8217;s $60 million Series B</a>, which had a $500 million valuation, showing a company rapidly increasing in value. For a company that launched just three years ago, this is a fairly remarkable trajectory.</p>
<p>Alkeon Capital led the round with help from new investors Battery Ventures, Citi Ventures, Norwest Venture Partners, Sorenson Capital and Thomvest Ventures. The startup also revealed a previously unannounced $30 million B-1 round raised after the $60 million round, bringing the total raised to date to $195 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Company founder and CEO Jyoti Bansal previously founded AppDynamics, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/24/cisco-snaps-up-appdynamics-for-3-7b-right-before-its-ipo/">he sold to Cisco in 2017</a> for $3.7 billion. With his track record, investors came looking for him this round. It didn&#8217;t hurt that revenue grew almost 3x last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;The business is doing very well, so the investor community has been proactively reaching out and trying to invest in us. We were not actually planning to raise a round until later this year. We had enough capital to get through that, but there were a lot of people wanting to invest,&#8221; Bansal told me.</p>
<p>In fact, he said there is so much investor interest that he could have raised twice as much, but didn&#8217;t feel a need to take on that much capital at this time. &#8220;Overall, the investor community sees the value in developer tools and the DevOps market. There are so many big public companies now in that space that have gone out in the last three to five years and that has definitely created even more validation of this space,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Bansal says that he started the company with the goal of making every company as good as Google or Facebook when it comes to engineering efficiency. Since most companies lack the engineering resources of these large companies, that&#8217;s a tall task, but one he thinks he can solve through software.</p>
<p>The company started by building a continuous delivery module. A cloud cost-efficiency module followed. Last year the company bought <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/harness-makes-first-acquisition-snagging-open-source-ci-company-drone-io/">open-source continuous integration company Drone.io</a> and they are working on building that into the platform now, with it currently in beta. There are additional modules on the product roadmap coming this year, according to Bansal.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZazmUwM7nF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/harness-makes-first-acquisition-snagging-open-source-ci-company-drone-io/">Harness makes first acquisition, snagging open-source CI company Drone.io</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Harness makes first acquisition, snagging open-source CI company Drone.io&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/harness-makes-first-acquisition-snagging-open-source-ci-company-drone-io/embed/#?secret=ZazmUwM7nF" data-secret="ZazmUwM7nF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As the company continued to grow revenue and build out the platform in 2020, it also added a slew of new employees, growing from 200 to 300 during the pandemic. Bansal says that he has plans to add another 200 by the end of this year. Harness has a reputation of being a good place to work, recently <a href="https://www.adweek.com/media/glassdoor-releases-best-places-to-work-in-2021-lists/">landing on Glassdoor&#8217;s best companies list</a>.</p>
<p>As an experienced entrepreneur, Bansal takes building a diverse company with a welcoming culture very seriously. &#8220;Yes, you have to provide equal opportunity and make sure that you are open to hiring people from diverse backgrounds, but you have to be more proactive about it in the sense that you have to make sure that your company environment and company culture feels very welcoming to everyone,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been a difficult time building a company during the pandemic, adding so many new employees, and finding a way to make everyone feel welcome and included. Bansal says he has actually seen productivity increase during the pandemic, but now has to guard against employee burnout.</p>
<p>He says that people didn&#8217;t know how to draw boundaries when working at home. One thing he did was introduce a program to give everyone one Friday a month off to recharge. The company also recently announced it would be a &#8220;work from anywhere&#8221; company post-COVID, but Bansal still plans on having regional offices where people can meet when needed.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="55tI49Zp6G"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/23/harness-hauls-in-60m-series-b-investment-on-500m-valuation/">Harness hauls in $60M Series B investment on $500M valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Harness hauls in $60M Series B investment on $500M valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/23/harness-hauls-in-60m-series-b-investment-on-500m-valuation/embed/#?secret=55tI49Zp6G" data-secret="55tI49Zp6G" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/harness-snags-85m-series-c-on-1-7b-valuation-as-revenue-grows-3x/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096435</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Samsung answers Apple with the $199 Galaxy Buds Pro</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/samsung-answers-apple-with-the-199-galaxy-buds-pro/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/samsung-answers-apple-with-the-199-galaxy-buds-pro/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[samsung galaxy buds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless earbuds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even before the leaks, we all saw the Galaxy Buds Pro coming. It was a given that the company was planning to deliver its own take on Apple’s AirPods Pro, with improved sound quality and active noise canceling. The real secret weapon here, however, may be the price. This morning’s S21 announcement found Samsung dropping [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Even before the leaks, we all saw the Galaxy Buds Pro coming. It was a given that the company was planning to deliver its own take on Apple’s AirPods Pro, with improved sound quality and active noise canceling. The real secret weapon here, however, may be the price.</p>
<p>This morning’s S21 announcement found Samsung dropping $200 off the price of its flagship smartphone, and here the Galaxy Buds come in at $50 cheaper than the AirPods’ asking price. It’s not clearance-bin pricing exactly, but $199 is a pretty reasonable starting price. And Samsung’s earbud track record is a pretty good indication that the headphones will be solid.</p>
<p>The buds get a stated five hours of on-board battery life. That bumps up to eight hours with active noise canceling and Bixby Voice off &#8212; one of those things I can fairly easily live without. The case bumps things up to 18 and 28 hours, respectively. Pretty impressive claims for a quite small case.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2096162" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096162" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2096162 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/01_galaxybudspro_handson_violet_201230054208.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/01_galaxybudspro_handson_violet_201230054208.jpg 3258w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/01_galaxybudspro_handson_violet_201230054208.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/01_galaxybudspro_handson_violet_201230054208.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/01_galaxybudspro_handson_violet_201230054208.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/01_galaxybudspro_handson_violet_201230054208.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/01_galaxybudspro_handson_violet_201230054208.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/01_galaxybudspro_handson_violet_201230054208.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/01_galaxybudspro_handson_violet_201230054208.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2096162" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Samsung</p></div></p>
<p>The buds’ design improves on the Galaxy Buds Live’s bean design, trading it for something a bit more ergonomic that’s designed to reduce the contact area between the device and the ear. Per Samsung’s claims, the ANC is capable of reducing ambient sound up to 99%. You can tweak the settings from there. They sport an 11 mm woofer and 6.5 mm tweeter, along with three microphones for calls.</p>
<p>There are a couple of features specifically for Samsung devices, including auto switching between phones and tablets, as well as Dolby head tracking and microphone capabilities for video recording on the Galaxy S21.</p>
<p>The buds are available in three colors and go up for order today. They’ll hit retail tomorrow.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ces-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/samsung-answers-apple-with-the-199-galaxy-buds-pro/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096204</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
