<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 14:14:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Apple said to be planning new 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pros with MagSafe and Apple processors</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/apple-said-to-be-planning-new-14-and-16-inch-macbook-pros-with-magsafe-and-apple-processors/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/apple-said-to-be-planning-new-14-and-16-inch-macbook-pros-with-magsafe-and-apple-processors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 14:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple keyboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macintosh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magsafe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oled]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Jobs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[touch bar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096981</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has planned new upgraded MacBook Pros for launch &#8220;later this year&#8221; according to a new report from Bloomberg. These new models would come in both 14-inch and 16-inch sizes, with new and improved Apple Silicon processors like those that Apple debuted on the new MacBook Air and 13-inch MacBook Pro model late last year. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple has planned new upgraded MacBook Pros for launch &#8220;later this year&#8221; according to a<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-15/apple-macbook-pros-with-magsafe-return-in-the-works?sref=gni836kR"> new report from Bloomberg</a>. These new models would come in both 14-inch and 16-inch sizes, with new and improved Apple Silicon processors like those that Apple debuted on the new MacBook Air and 13-inch MacBook Pro model late last year. They would also see the return of Apple&#8217;s MagSafe charger, a magnetic dedicated charging port that would replace USB-C for power, and they could potentially do away with the Touch Bar, the small strip of OLED display built in to the keyboard on modern MacBook Pros.</p>
<p>Bloomberg&#8217;s report suggests that these MacBook Pro models will have processors with more cores and better graphics capabilities than the existing M1 chips that power Apple&#8217;s current notebooks with in-house silicon, and that they&#8217;ll also have displays with brighter panels that offer higher contrast. Physically, they&#8217;ll resemble existing notebooks, according to the report&#8217;s sources, but they&#8217;ll see the return of MagSafe, the dedicated magnetic charging interface that Apple used prior to switching power delivery over to USB-C on its laptops.</p>
<p>MagSafe had the advantage of easily disconnecting in case of anyone accidentally tripping across the power cord while plugged in, without yanking the computer with it. It also meant that it kept all data ports free for accessories. Bloomberg says that the revitalized MagSafe for new notebooks will also offer faster charging vs. USB-C, in addition to those other benefits.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As for the Touch Bar, it has been a topic of debate since its introduction. Pro users in particular seem to dislike the interface option, especially because it replaces a row of dedicated physical keys that could be useful in professional workflows. The report claims that Apple has &#8220;tested versions that remove the Touch Bar,&#8221; so it seems less clear that Apple will finally unring that particular bell, but I personally know a lot of people who would be excited if that does come to pass.</p>
<p>Finally, Bloomberg says Apple is also planning a new redesigned MacBook Air. That was updated most recently just a couple of months ago, and the report says it&#8217;ll only follow &#8220;long after&#8221; these new MacBook Pros, so it seems unlikely to arrive in 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/apple-said-to-be-planning-new-14-and-16-inch-macbook-pros-with-magsafe-and-apple-processors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096981</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Want a job in tech? Flockjay pitches its sales training service as an on-ramp to tech careers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/backed-by-marc-benioff-flockjay-pitches-its-sales-training-service-as-an-onramp-to-tech-careers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/backed-by-marc-benioff-flockjay-pitches-its-sales-training-service-as-an-onramp-to-tech-careers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 14:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cleo Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coatue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flockjay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harvard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[impact america fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new jersey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul Buchheit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Willerer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096978</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Most people don&#8217;t even know that a job in tech sales is even a possibility,&#8221; says Shaan Hathiramani, the founder and chief executive of Flockjay, a company offering a tech sales training curriculum to the masses. Hathiramani sees his startup as an onramp to the tech industry for legions of workers who have the skillsets [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;Most people don&#8217;t even know that a job in tech sales is even a possibility,&#8221; says Shaan Hathiramani, the founder and chief executive of <a href="https://flockjay.com/">Flockjay</a>, a company offering a tech sales training curriculum to the masses.</p>
<p>Hathiramani sees his startup as an onramp to the tech industry for legions of workers who have the skillsets to work in tech, but lack the network to see themselves in the business. Just like coding bootcamps have enabled thousands to get jobs as programmers in the tech business, Flockjay can get talented people who had never considered a job in tech into the industry.</p>
<p>The company, which had previously raised $3 million from investors including Serena Williams and Will Smith, along with tech industry luminaries like Microsoft chairman John Thompson; Airtable head of sales Liat Bycel; Gmail inventor Paul Buchheit; and former Netflix CPO Tom Willerer, has just raised new capital to expand its business in a time when accelerated onramps to new jobs have never been more important.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The healthcare response to the ongoing COVID-19 epidemic, which has closed businesses and torn through the American economy. The unemployment rate in the country sits at 6.4% and the nation lost 140,000 jobs again in December &#8212; with all of those job losses coming from women.</p>
<p>A former financier with the multi-billion dollar investment firm, Citadel, Hathiramani sees Flockjay, and the business of tech sales as a way for a number of people to transform their lives.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We provide a premier sales academy,&#8221; Hathiramani said. &#8220;It costs zero dollars if you take the course and don’t get a job and costs 10% of your income for the first year if you do get a job. That nets out to 6 or 7K.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>A few hundred students have gone through the program so far, Hathiramani said, and the goal is to train 1,000 people over the course of 2021. The average income of a student before they go through Flockjay&#8217;s training program is $30,000 to $35,000 typically, Hathiramani said.</p>
<p>Upon graduation, those students can expect to make between $75,000 and $85,000, he said.</p>
<p>Increasing access among those students who have not necessarily been exposed to the tech world is critical for what Hathiramani wants to do with his sales bootcamp.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096986" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096986" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2096986" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg 1112w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/shaan-2.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2096986" class="wp-caption-text">Flockjay founder Shaan Hathiramani. Image Credit: Flockjay</p></div></p>
<p>The entrepreneur said roughly 40% of students don&#8217;t have a four-year college degree; half of the students identify as female or non-binary, and half of the company&#8217;s students identify as Black or<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2020/08/17/latinx-not-preferred-term-among-hispanics-survey-says/"> hispanic</a>. About 80% of the company&#8217;s students find a job within the first six months of graduation.</p>
<p>These are students like Elise Cox, a former Bojangles&#8217; manager and Flockjay graduate, who moved from Georgia to Denver to be a sales tech representative for Gusto. Tripling her salary from $13 an hour in the food service industry to a salaried position with wages and benefits.</p>
<p>“I enjoy being able to generate revenue for the company,” Cox, a 41-year-old grandmother, whose five-year plans include a sales leadership role, <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90410678/fockjay-serena-williams-backed-tech-academy-raises-3m">told Fast Company two years ago</a>. “The revenue is the lifeblood of the company and being part of the team gives me sense of fulfillment.”</p>
<p>Partnerships with <a href="https://opportunityatwork.org/">Opportunity@Work</a>, <a href="https://www.hiddengeniusproject.org/">Hidden Genius Project</a>, <a href="https://www.peninsulabridge.org/">Peninsula Bridge</a>, and TechHire Oakland, help to ensure a diverse pool of applicants and a more diverse workforce for the tech industry &#8212; <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/12/six-years-into-diversity-reports-big-tech-has-made-little-progress.html">where diversity is still a huge problem</a>.</p>
<p>As Hathiramani looks to take his company from training a couple of hundred students to over a thousand, the founder has raised new cash from previous investors including Lightspeed, Coatue, and Y Combinator, and new investors like eVentures, Salesforce Ventures, along with the Impact America Fund, Cleo Capital and Gabrielle Union.</p>
<p>For the New Jersey-born entrepreneur, Flockjay was a way to give back to a community that he knew intimately. After his family settled in New Jersey after immigrating to the United States, Hathiramani went first to Horace Mann on a scholarship and then attended Harvard before getting his job at Citadel.</p>
<p>Even while he was working at the pinnacle of the financial services world he started non-profits like the Big Shoulders Fund and taught financial literacy.</p>
<p>After a while, he moved to the Bay Area to begin plotting a way to merge his twin interests in education and financial inclusion.</p>
<p>&#8220;That led to me spending a year helping startups for free and trying to understand their problems with hiring and training&#8221; said Hathiramani. &#8220;It helped me surface this economic waste in plain sight. There were all these people talking to customers and they were spending three months on the job learning the job and they didn&#8217;t want to do the job or they weren&#8217;t very good at it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tech salesforces were a point of entry in the system that almost anyone could access, if they could get in through the door, Hathiramani said. Flockjay wants to be the key to opening the door.</p>
<p>So, the company now has $11 million in new funding to bring its sales training bootcamp to a larger audience. Hathiramani also wants to make the bootcamp model more of a community with continuous development after a student completes the program. &#8220;I view education as a membership and not a transaction,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We focus on continuous learning and continuous up-skilling.&#8221;</p>
<p>Part of that is the flywheel of building up networks in a manner similar to YCombinator, the accelerator program from which Flockjay graduated in 2019.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We went through YC to learn&#8230; how they manufacture the privilege in the world that they have afforded,&#8221; said Hathiramani. &#8220;How do you take some of that and provide it to someone who is starting their careers in tech. You get better at your job the more connections you have. As we accelerate the alumni piece… they can draw on other alums that they’re selling into.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/backed-by-marc-benioff-flockjay-pitches-its-sales-training-service-as-an-onramp-to-tech-careers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096978</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon&#8217;s newest product lets companies build their own Alexa assistant for cars, apps and video games</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/amazons-newest-product-lets-companies-build-their-own-alexa-assistant/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/amazons-newest-product-lets-companies-build-their-own-alexa-assistant/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 13:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon is selling access to the underlying technology stack of Alexa to let companies — starting with Fiat Chrysler Automobiles — build their own intelligent assistants with unique voices, skills and wake words. The new Alexa Custom Assistant product, which was announced Friday, can coexist and cooperate with the Alexa assistant. Theoretically, this means an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon is selling access to the underlying technology stack of Alexa to let companies — starting with Fiat Chrysler Automobiles — build their own intelligent assistants with unique voices, skills and wake words.</p>
<p>The new Alexa Custom Assistant product, which was announced Friday, can coexist and cooperate with the Alexa assistant. Theoretically, this means an automaker could choose to use the custom assistant to interact with drivers on specific products and services tied to the vehicle as well as integrate the Alexa voice assistant for other needs. For instance, if a driver asks Alexa to roll down a car window, the request will be routed to the brand&#8217;s assistant, Amazon explained. If a customer asks the brand&#8217;s assistant to play an audio book, the request will be routed to Alexa.</p>
<p>Yes, that means your next car could have two Alexas.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here&#8217;s a video showing how it works.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/tmuGQjZcn2w?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Fiat Chrysler Automobiles will be the first Alexa Custom Assistant customer. An FCA-branded intelligent assistant is being built for integration in select vehicle models, according to Amazon.</p>
<p>Amazon&#8217;s pitch isn&#8217;t just to automakers, however. The e-commerce giant said it can be used to build intelligent assistants into mobile applications, smart properties, video games and consumer electronics. The Alexa Custom Assistant is based on the Alexa technology stack. The custom wake words are created with the same process used for developing the Alexa wake word. Amazon will give companies access to Alexa&#8217;s voice science experts to help guide them through the recording process and develop the voice using advanced machine learning algorithms. Developers also have access to Alexa&#8217;s pre-built capabilities such as communications, local search, traffic, and navigation, to further accelerate time to market.</p>
<p>The aim of this new product, Amazon says, is to give companies an efficient and cost-effective way of delivering an intelligent assistant to its customers. The path of building an intelligent AI-based assistant is complex, typically involves long development cycles, and requires resources to build it from scratch and maintain over time, Amazon argues.</p>
<p>Of course, it&#8217;s also another way to ensure Alexa is in more devices, even if it goes by another name.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/amazons-newest-product-lets-companies-build-their-own-alexa-assistant/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096964</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A security researcher commandeered a country&#8217;s expired top-level domain to save it from hackers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/congo-comandeered/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/congo-comandeered/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 12:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Democratic Republic of Congo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Detectify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domain name registry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top level domain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096824</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In mid-October, a little-known but critically important domain name for one country&#8217;s internet space began to expire. The domain — scpt-network.com — was one of two nameservers for the .cd country code top-level domain, assigned to the Democratic Republic of Congo. If it fell into the wrong hands, an attacker could redirect millions of unknowing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In mid-October, a little-known but critically important domain name for one country&#8217;s internet space began to expire.</p>
<p>The domain — <code>scpt-network.com</code> — was one of two nameservers for the <code>.cd</code> country code top-level domain, assigned to the Democratic Republic of Congo. If it fell into the wrong hands, an attacker could redirect millions of unknowing internet users to rogue websites of their choosing.</p>
<p>Clearly, a domain of such importance wasn&#8217;t supposed to expire; someone in the Congolese government probably forgot to pay for its renewal. Luckily, expired domains don&#8217;t disappear immediately. Instead, the clock started on a grace period for its government owners to buy back the domain before it was sold to someone else.</p>
<p>By chance, Fredrik Almroth, a security researcher and co-founder of cybersecurity startup Detectify, was already looking at nameservers of country code top-level domains (or ccTLDs), the two-letter suffixes at the end of regional web addresses, like <code>.fr</code> for France or <code>.uk</code> for the United Kingdom. When he found this critical domain name was about to expire, Almroth began to monitor it, assuming someone in the Congolese government would pay to reclaim the domain.</p>
<p>But nobody ever did.</p>
<p>By the end of December, the clock was almost up and the domain was about to fall off the internet. Within minutes of the domain becoming available, Almroth quickly snapped it up to prevent anyone else from taking it over — because, as he told TechCrunch, &#8220;the implications are kind of huge.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s rare but not unheard of for a top-level domain to expire.</p>
<p>In 2017, security researcher Matthew Bryant <a href="https://thehackerblog.com/the-io-error-taking-control-of-all-io-domains-with-a-targeted-registration/index.html">took over</a> the nameservers of the <code>.io</code> top-level domain, assigned to the British Indian Ocean Territory. But malicious hackers have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/17/sea-turtle-talos-dns-hijack/">also shown interest</a> in targeting top-level domains hack into companies and governments that use the same country-based domain suffix.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--callout block--right" >
		<h4 class="block--callout__title">Read more on TechCrunch</h4>
		
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/17/sea-turtle-talos-dns-hijack/">A new state-backed hacker group is hijacking government domains at a phenomenal pace</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/ring-neighbors-exposed-locations-addresses/">Amazon’s Ring Neighbors app exposed users’ precise locations and home addresses</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/nso-fleming-data-location/">NSO used real people’s location data to pitch its contact-tracing tech, researchers say</a></li>
<li>Got a tip? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/securedrop">Get in touch</a>.</li>
</ul>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Taking over a nameserver is not supposed to be an easy task because they are a vital part of how the internet works.</p>
<p>Every time you visit a website your device relies on a nameserver to convert a web address in your browser to the machine-readable address that tells your device where on the internet to find the site you&#8217;re looking for. Some liken nameservers to the phone directory of the internet. Sometimes your browser looks no further than its own cache for the answer, and sometimes it has to ask the nearest nameserver for the answer. But the nameservers that control top-level domains are considered authoritative and know where to look without having to ask another nameserver.</p>
<p>With control of an authoritative nameserver, malicious hackers could run man-in-the-middle attacks to silently intercept and redirect internet users going to legitimate sites to malicious webpages.</p>
<p>These kinds of attacks have been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/17/sea-turtle-talos-dns-hijack/">used in sophisticated espionage campaigns</a> aimed at cloning websites to trick victims into handing over their passwords, which hackers use to get access to company networks to steal information.</p>
<p>Worse, Almroth said with control of the nameserver it was possible to obtain valid SSL (HTTPS) certificates, allowing for an attacker to intercept encrypted web traffic or any email mailbox for any <code>.cd</code> domain, he said. To the untrained eye, a successful attacker could redirect victims to a spoofed website and they would be none the wiser.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you can abuse the validation schemes used to issue certificates, you can undermine the SSL of any domain under <code>.cd</code> as well,&#8221; Almroth said. &#8220;The capabilities of being in such a privileged position is scary.&#8221;</p>
<p>Almroth ended up sitting on the domain for about a week as he tried to figure out a way to hand it back. By this point the domain had been inactive for two months already and nothing had catastrophically broken. At most, websites with a <code>.cd</code> domain might have taken slightly longer to load.</p>
<p>Since the remaining nameserver was running normally, Almroth kept the domain offline so that whenever an internet user tried to access a domain that relied on the nameserver under his control, it would automatically timeout and pass the request to the remaining nameserver.</p>
<p>In the end, the Congolese government didn&#8217;t bother asking for the domain back. It spun up an entirely new but similarly named domain — <code>scpt-network.net</code> — to replace the one now in Almroth&#8217;s possession.</p>
<p>We reached out to the Congolese authorities for comment but did not hear back.</p>
<p>ICANN, the international non-profit organization responsible for internet address allocation, said country code top-level domains are operated by their respective countries and its role is &#8220;very limited,&#8221; a spokesperson said.</p>
<p>For its part, ICANN encouraged countries to follow best practices and <a href="https://www.icann.org/resources/pages/dnssec-what-is-it-why-important-2019-03-05-en">to use DNSSEC</a>, a cryptographically more secure technology that makes it nearly impossible to serve up spoofed websites. One network security engineer who asked not to be named as they were not authorized to speak to the media questioned whether DNSSEC would be effective at all against a top-level domain hijack.</p>
<p>At least in this case, it&#8217;s nothing a calendar reminder can&#8217;t solve.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="C6s6EiqQGE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/17/sea-turtle-talos-dns-hijack/">A new state-backed hacker group is hijacking government domains at a phenomenal pace</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A new state-backed hacker group is hijacking government domains at a phenomenal pace&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/17/sea-turtle-talos-dns-hijack/embed/#?secret=C6s6EiqQGE" data-secret="C6s6EiqQGE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/congo-comandeered/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096824</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Twitter is handling the 2021 US presidential transition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/how-twitter-is-handling-the-2021-us-presidential-transition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/how-twitter-is-handling-the-2021-us-presidential-transition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 11:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[election integrity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter has set out its plans for US Inauguration Day 2021, next Wednesday, January 20, when president-elect Joe Biden will be sworn into office as the 46th US president and vice president-elect Kamala Harris will become VP. &#8220;This year, multiple challenging circumstances will require that most people experience this historic ceremony virtually,&#8221; the social media [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter has set out its plans for US Inauguration Day 2021, next Wednesday, January 20, when president-elect Joe Biden will be sworn into office as the 46th US president and vice president-elect Kamala Harris will become VP.</p>
<p>&#8220;This year, multiple challenging circumstances will require that most people experience this historic ceremony virtually,&#8221; the social media firm writes in a <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2021/inauguration-2021.html">blog post</a> detailing how it will handle the transition of power on its platform as the Trump administration departs office.</p>
<p>&#8220;As Twitter will serve as both a venue for people to watch and talk about this political event, and play a key role in facilitating the transfer of official government communication channels, we want to be transparent and clear about what people should expect to see on the platform.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The inauguration will of course be livestreamed via Twitter by multiple accounts (such as news outlets), as well as the official inauguration accounts, <a class="has-hover-card" href="https://twitter.com/jccic">@JCCIC</a> and <a class="has-hover-card" href="https://twitter.com/BidenInaugural">@BidenInaugural</a>.</p>
<p>Twitter will also be streaming the ceremony via its <a href="https://twitter.com/explore/tabs/us-elections-2020">US Elections Hub</a>, where it says it will share curated Moments, Lists and accounts to follow as well.</p>
<p>Once sworn into office, Biden and Harris will gain control of the @POTUS and @VP Twitter accounts. Other accounts that will transition to the new administration on the day include @WhiteHouse, @FLOTUS and @PressSec.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Twitter has also confirmed that Harris&#8217; husband, Douglas Emhoff, will use a new official account &#8212; called <a href="https://twitter.com/SecondGentleman">@SecondGentleman</a>. (It&#8217;s not clear why not &#8216;SGOTUS&#8217;; aside from, well, the unloveliness of the acronym.) </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gJfr14LhX6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/trump-banned-from-twitter/">Twitter permanently bans President Trump</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter permanently bans President Trump&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/trump-banned-from-twitter/embed/#?secret=gJfr14LhX6" data-secret="gJfr14LhX6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As it did when president Obama left office, Twitter will transfer the current institutional accounts of the Trump administration to the <a href="https://www.archives.gov/">National Archives and Records Administration </a>(Nara) &#8212; meaning the outgoing administration&#8217;s tweets and account history will remain publicly available (with account usernames updated to reflect their archived status, e.g. @POTUS will be archived as @POTUS45).</p>
<p>However Trump&#8217;s personal account, which he frequently used as a political cudgel, yelling in ALL CAPS and/or spewing his customary self-pitying tweets, has already been wiped from public view after Twitter took the decision to permanently ban him <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/trump-banned-from-twitter/">last week</a> for repeat violations of its rules of conduct. So there&#8217;s likely to be a major gap in Nara&#8217;s Trump archive.</p>
<p>Since <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/trump-will-face-different-twitter-rules-when-he-leaves-office-11608642198">late last year</a> we&#8217;ve known the transitioning @POTUS and institutional accounts will not automatically retain followers from the prior administration. But Twitter still hasn&#8217;t confirmed why.</p>
<p>Today it just reiterated that the current (33.3M) followers of @POTUS and the other official accounts will receive a notification about the archival process which will include the &#8220;option&#8221; to follow the new holders of the accounts.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s another notable change from 2017 when Trump inherited the ~14M followers of president Obama&#8217;s @POTUS. Biden will instead have to start his presidential tweeting from scratch.</p>
<p>Given the chaotic events in the US capital last week, when supporters of the outgoing president broke through police lines to cause mayhem on the hill and in the House, there&#8217;s every reason for tech platforms to approach the 2021 transition with trepidation, lest their tools get used to livestream another historic insurrection (or worse).</p>
<p>Since then Trump has also continued to maintain his false claim that the election was stolen through voter fraud.</p>
<p>Although he avoided any new direct reference to this big lie when he circumvented <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/trump-banned-from-twitter/">Twitter&#8217;s ban</a> on his personal account earlier this week, by <a href="https://twitter.com/WhiteHouse/status/1349492130578919425">posting a new video of himself speaking</a> on the official @WhiteHouse account.</p>
<p>In the video he decried the &#8220;incursion at the US capital&#8221;, as he put it; claimed that he &#8220;unequivocally condemns the violence that we saw last week&#8221;; and called for unity. But Twitter has put tight limits on what Trump can say on its platform without having his posts removed (as well limiting him to the official @POTUS channel). So he remains on a very tight speech leash.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wravivlpiI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/why-twitter-banned-president-trump/">Why Twitter says it banned President Trump</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Twitter says it banned President Trump&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/why-twitter-banned-president-trump/embed/#?secret=wravivlpiI" data-secret="wravivlpiI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In the video Trump limits his verbal attacks to a few remarks &#8212; about what he describes as &#8220;the unprecedented assault on free speech we have seen in recent days&#8221; &#8212; dubbing tech platforms&#8217; censorship &#8220;wrong&#8221; and &#8220;dangerous&#8221;, and adding that &#8220;what is needed now is for us to listen to one another, not to silence one another&#8221;.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a lot going on here but it should not escape notice that Trump&#8217;s seeming contrition and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/is-trump-back-on-twitter/">quasi-concession</a> and his <em>very-last-minute</em> calls for unity have only come when he actively feels power draining away from him.</p>
<p>Most notably, his call for unity has only come after<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> powerful tech platforms acted to shut off his hate-megaphone &#8212; ending the years of special dispensation they granted Trump to ride roughshod over democratic convention and tear up the civic rulebook. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">It&#8217;s very interesting to speculate how different the 2021 US inauguration might look and feel if platforms like Twitter had consistently enforced their rules against Trump from the get-go. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Instead we&#8217;re stuck in all sorts of lockdown, counting the days til Biden takes office &#8212; and above all hoping for a smooth transition of power.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">So Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey is quite right when he <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1349510771928010753">said</a> this week that Twitter has failed in its mission to &#8220;promote healthy conversation&#8221;. His company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/10/18/gamergate-tactics/">ignored warnings about online toxicity for years</a>. Trump is, in no small part, the divisive product of that. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">That said, having to ban an account has real and significant ramifications. While there are clear and obvious exceptions, I feel a ban is a failure of ours ultimately to promote healthy conversation. And a time for us to reflect on our operations and the environment around us.</p>
<p>&mdash; jack (@jack) <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1349510771928010753?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 14, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In a brief section of Twitter&#8217;s transition handling blog post, entitled &#8220;protecting the public conversation&#8221;, the company refers back to a <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2021/protecting--the-conversation-following-the-riots-in-washington--.html">post</a> from earlier this week where it set out steps it&#8217;s taking to try to prevent its platform from being used to &#8220;incite violence, organize attacks, and share deliberately misleading information about the election outcome&#8221; in the coming days.</p>
<p>These measures include permanently suspending ~70,000 accounts it said were primarily dedicated to sharing content related to the QAnon conspiracy theory; aggressively beefing up its civic integrity policy; and applying interaction limits on labeled tweets plus blocking violative keywords from appearing in Trends and search.</p>
<p>&#8220;These efforts, including our open lines of communication with law enforcement, will continue through the inauguration and will adapt as needed if circumstances change in real-time,&#8221; it adds, preparing for the possibility of more unrest.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5swpwkfHOt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/europe-seizes-on-social-medias-purging-of-trump-to-bang-the-drum-for-regulation/">Europe seizes on social media&#8217;s purging of Trump to bang the drum for regulation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe seizes on social media&#8217;s purging of Trump to bang the drum for regulation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/europe-seizes-on-social-medias-purging-of-trump-to-bang-the-drum-for-regulation/embed/#?secret=5swpwkfHOt" data-secret="5swpwkfHOt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/how-twitter-is-handling-the-2021-us-presidential-transition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096917</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneWeb has now raised $1.4B, with $400M from SoftBank and Hughes, to help fund its first satellite fleet</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/oneweb-picks-up-1-4b-more-from-softbank-and-hughes-to-help-fund-its-first-satellite-fleet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/oneweb-picks-up-1-4b-more-from-softbank-and-hughes-to-help-fund-its-first-satellite-fleet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 10:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096927</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a troubled year that saw broadband satellite operator OneWeb file for bankruptcy, get rescue finance from the UK government and Bharti, and then emerge out of that with a launch of part of its fleet last month, the London-based company today announced that it&#8217;s closed $1.4 billion in funding &#8212; money that it says [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After a troubled year that saw broadband satellite operator <a href="https://www.oneweb.world/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OneWeb</a> file for<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/27/oneweb-to-file-for-bankruptcy-as-effort-to-securing-funding-including-from-investor-softbank-falls-through/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> bankruptcy</a>, get rescue finance from the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/03/the-uk-government-to-acquire-satellite-company-oneweb-in-deal-funded-in-part-by-indias-bharti-global/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">UK government</a> and Bharti, and then emerge out of that with a launch of part of its fleet <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/oneweb-launches-36-satellites-to-join-its-global-broadband-constellation-on-orbit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">last month</a>, the London-based company today announced that it&#8217;s closed $1.4 billion in funding &#8212; money that it says will be enough to (finally) get the rest of its first-generation fleet of 648 satellites off the ground.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The 36 new satellites OneWeb launched in December brought the total number in orbit to 110 satellites. This means there are still more than 500 left to launch in the first generation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The company is continuing to whittle down its ambitions. Earlier this week, OneWeb <a href="https://www.oneweb.world/media-center/oneweb-streamlines-constellation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announced</a> that it had &#8220;streamlined its constellation&#8221; and as a result was reducing the request it was making to the U.S. regulators for licenses. Originally OneWeb had applied to the FCC for market access for </span>47,884 satellites; now the figure is down to 6,372.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>SoftBank Group Corp. and Hughes Network Systems are providing the financing, the company said. The news comes about a month after OneWeb launched 36 satellites, its third launch to put more of its fleet into orbit. At the time, its executive chairman <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/98e57ccc-8ecf-4a6a-afa9-1c8366043b56" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sunil Bharti Mittal said</a> that it was on track to raise $400 million<del> &#8212; so this represents a more-than threefold increase on that amount.</del> This appears to confirm that.</p>
<p>“OneWeb’s mission is to connect everyone, everywhere. We have made rapid progress to re-start the business since emerging from Chapter 11 in November,&#8221; said Neil Masterson, CEO of OneWeb, in a statement. &#8220;We welcome the investments by SoftBank and Hughes as further proof of progress towards delivering our goal.”</p>
<p>A spokesperson for the company has confirmed to me that the company is not disclosing its valuation. Adding in this round, it looks like the company has raised around $4.5 billion to date, although the bankruptcy meant a significant recapitalization and revaluation of the business and that figure includes funding from before it was restructured.</p>
<p>SoftBank and Hughes are both past backers and partners in OneWeb, so this is something of an insurance policy to make sure that its previous investment doesn&#8217;t go completely to waste. (At least some of it has already been written down: SoftBank years ago <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/13/softbank-expects-24-billion-in-losses-from-vision-fund-wework-and-oneweb-investments/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted an eye-watering loss of $24 billion</a> due in part to that OneWeb bet.)</p>
<p>Hughes, meanwhile, invests via its parent company EchoStar and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/07/oneweb-is-a-step-closer-to-bringing-its-global-satellite-based-internet-services-to-earth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">inked a deal with the company way back in 2017</a> to build the terrestrial infrastructure that would work with OneWeb&#8217;s satellites. Deals, building and rollouts in the world of satellite technology play out over a number of years, and often face delays, so being three years out &#8212; or even more &#8212; on seeing any fruits from that deal is not hugely surprising.</p>
<p>OneWeb acknowledged the long-time connection between the investors and confirmed that the ground network is still being built by Hughes.</p>
<p>“We are delighted to welcome the investment from SoftBank and Hughes. Both are deeply familiar with our business, share our vision for the future, and their commitment allows us to capitalise on the significant growth opportunity ahead for OneWeb,&#8221; said Mittal in a statement. &#8220;We gain from their experience and capabilities, as we deliver a unique LEO network for the world.”</p>
<p>Originally, Hughes had planned for the first services to start running in 2019 &#8212; although that was when OneWeb and its fleet of LEO (low-earth orbit) satellites was still a very shiny idea, backed by $1.7 billion in venture funding.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s original idea was always great but (no pun intended) also something of a moonshot: LEO satellites have already been proven to be a strong and useful complement to terrestrial networks for providing broadband connectivity to more remote areas that couldn&#8217;t be reached in other ways. The idea with OneWeb was to make that service something useful and used by a much bigger group of on-the-ground users, with <a href="https://www.oneweb.world/technology" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the promise</a> being 400Mbps for everyone.</p>
<p>While broadband usage has certainly exploded in the interim, what OneWeb perhaps didn&#8217;t bank on was that those building non-satellite systems for providing connectivity would also be progressing in their network advances; nor how long it might take, or the financing needed, to get its fleet off the ground on the timelines it was promising.</p>
<p>These days, OneWeb says that growing ubiquity of 5G, Internet of Things and connectivity needs overall still present a strong use case for its approach &#8212; which it says &#8220;<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">includes a network of global gateway stations and a range of user terminals for different customer markets capable of delivering affordable, fast, high-bandwidth and low-latency communications services.&#8221; </span></p>
<p>Secretary of State, BEIS, The Rt. Hon. Kwasi Kwarteng, said in a statement: “Our investment in OneWeb is part of our continued commitment to the UK’s space sector, putting Britain at the forefront of the latest technological advances. Today’s investment brings the company one step closer to delivering its mission to provide global broadband connectivity for people, businesses and governments, while potentially unlocking new research, development and manufacturing opportunities in the UK.”</p>
<p>SoftBank is getting a seat on OneWeb&#8217;s board with this deal.</p>
<p>“We are excited to support OneWeb as it increases capacity and accelerates towards commercialisation,&#8221; said Masayoshi Son, Representative Director, Corporate Officer, Chairman &amp; CEO of SoftBank, in a statement. &#8220;We are thrilled to continue our partnership with Bharti, the UK Government and Hughes to help OneWeb deliver on its mission to transform internet access around the world.”</p>
<p>Pradman Kaul, President of Hughes, added: “OneWeb continues to inspire the industry and attract the best players in the business to come together to bring its LEO constellation to fruition. The investments made today by Hughes and SoftBank will help realise the full potential of OneWeb in connecting enterprise, government and mobility customers, especially with multi-transport services that complement our own geostationary offerings in meeting and accelerating demand for broadband around the world.”</p>
<p><em>Updated to clarify that the $1.4 billion includes $400 million announced today, plus previous funding.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/oneweb-picks-up-1-4b-more-from-softbank-and-hughes-to-help-fund-its-first-satellite-fleet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096927</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump Administration adds Xiaomi to military blacklist</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/xiaomi-us-blacklist/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/xiaomi-us-blacklist/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 05:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chinese smartphone maker Xiaomi is the latest to be added to the Trump Administration&#8217;s military blacklist. On Thursday, the Department of Defense added nine more companies to its list of alleged Chinese military companies, including Xiaomi. Xiaomi was the world&#8217;s third-largest smartphone maker as of Q3 last year, coming ahead of Apple and trailing behind [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chinese smartphone maker Xiaomi is the latest to be added to the Trump Administration&#8217;s military blacklist. On Thursday, the Department of Defense <a href="https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Releases/Release/Article/2472464/dod-releases-list-of-additional-companies-in-accordance-with-section-1237-of-fy/">added</a> nine more companies to its list of alleged Chinese military companies, including Xiaomi.</p>
<p>Xiaomi was the world&#8217;s third-largest smartphone maker as of Q3 last year, coming ahead of Apple and trailing behind Samsung and Huawei, according to market researcher <a href="https://www.idc.com/promo/smartphone-market-share/vendor">IDC</a>.</p>
<p>In November, President Donald Trump <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/29/the-trump-administration-will-add-smic-chinas-largest-chipmaker-to-its-defense-blacklist-report/">signed an executive order</a>, which was set to take effect in January, to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/executive-order-addressing-threat-securities-investments-finance-communist-chinese-military-companies/">bar investment</a> in companies designated as supporting efforts of China&#8217;s military, intelligence and security apparatuses. Huawei, China&#8217;s major chipmaker <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/29/the-trump-administration-will-add-smic-chinas-largest-chipmaker-to-its-defense-blacklist-report/">SMIC</a>, and the country&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/nyse-reverses-plans-to-delist-chinas-three-big-telcos/">three largest telecoms operators</a> are among the targets of the list.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The military blacklist is different from the Commerce Department&#8217;s entity list, which famously cuts <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/19/us-commerce-department-adds-46-huawei-affiliates-to-entity-list/">Huawei</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/dji-added-to-commerce-department-entity-list/">DJI</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/07/eight-chinese-tech-firms-placed-on-u-s-entity-list-for-their-role-in-human-rights-violations-against-muslim-minority-groups/">SenseTime</a> and other Chinese tech firms off their U.S. suppliers over national security concerns.</p>
<p>Xiaomi &#8220;confirms that it is not owned, controlled or affiliated with the Chinese military, and is not a &#8216;Communist Chinese Military Company&#8217; defined under the NDAA [National Defense Authorization Act]. The company will take appropriate course of actions to protect the interests of the company and its shareholders,&#8221; a Xiaomi spokesperson said in a statement.</p>
<p>Like the entity list, the U.S. government&#8217;s military blacklist has caused confusion around compliance. In response to the sanctions on China Mobile, China Unicom and China Telecom, the New York Stock Exchange made three moves. It first announced to delist the three Chinese telcos, then decided not to after consultation with regulators, but eventually reversed its reversal and<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/the-nyse-will-delist-three-chinese-telecoms-after-all/"> said it would delist them</a>, after all, upon further evaluation.</p>
<p>&#8220;The company is reviewing the potential consequences of this to develop a fuller understanding of its impact on the group. The company will make further announcements as and when appropriate,&#8221; the Xiaomi representative said.</p>
<p>Xiaomi is listed in Hong Kong, and the executive order could force American investors to divest their holdings in the phone maker, whose shares tumbled more than 11% to $29 apiece on the blacklist announcement.</p>
<p>While Xiaomi&#8217;s operations and technology access are unaffected in the latest round of U.S. government assault, a supply chain ban could become a sword of Damocles. The Chinese phone maker has been working closely with Qualcomm and was notably<a href="https://www.engadget.com/xiaomi-mi-11-snapdragon-888-221003638.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAC8x6DK3flg35_l1wvr7GMdm-ngC9WiFtxFHwzBJQCu_9L7CIAXGajm2elon3TKKfpjZIN8hnQ9o3QKf0NJ-LNy8B2wz6YEzEcap2bfX0uMiX5knzFIcL_2tHkMnDuMLBsYjCTkoZyFIT0LPJB_3H-tPP4KoST9jrkYDRZ_14Nd-"> the first to get</a> the high-end Snapdragon 888 chips. To evade restrictions imposed by the entity list, Huawei <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/huawei-sells-budget-phone-unit-honor-to-government-distribution-partners/">spun out its budget phone unit Honor</a> in a bid to save its supply chain. It remains to be seen how Joe Biden will tackle Trump-era policies towards Chinese tech giants.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/xiaomi-us-blacklist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096907</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A theory about the current IPO market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/a-theory-about-the-current-ipo-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/a-theory-about-the-current-ipo-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 23:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poshmark]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096743</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lots of demand, little supply, boom goes the price.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As expected, shares of Poshmark exploded this morning, blasting over 130% higher in afternoon trading <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/poshmark-prices-ipo-above-range-as-public-markets-continue-to-yolo-startups/">from the company&#8217;s above-range IPO price of $42</a>. The enormous and noisy debut of Poshmark comes a day after Affirm, another IPO, was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/wall-street-hugs-affirm-as-it-starts-life-as-a-public-company/">treated similarly by the public markets</a>.</p>
<p>Both explosive debuts were preceded <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/the-ipo-market-looks-hot-as-airbnb-and-c3-ai-raise-price-targets/">by huge December debuts from C3.ai, Doordash and Airbnb</a>. It seems today that any venture-backed company that can claim some sort of tech mantle is being treated to a strong IPO pricing run and a huge first-day result.</p>
<p>This is, of course, annoying to some people. Namely, certain elements of the venture capital community who would prefer to keep all outsized gains in their own pockets. But, no matter. You might be wondering what is going on. Let&#8217;s talk about it.</p>
<h2 class="c-mrkdwn__pre" data-stringify-type="pre">Here&#8217;s how you get a big first-day IPO pop</h2>
<p>TechCrunch has covered the IPO window as closely as we can over the last few years. And the late-stage venture capital markets, along with the changing value of tech stocks and the huge boom in consumer (retail) investing.</p>
<p>Based on my participation in as much of that reporting as I could take part in here&#8217;s how you get a 130% first-day IPO pop in a company that has actually been around long enough for investors to math-out reasonable growth and profit expectations for the future:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Exist in a climate of near-zero interest rates.</strong> This leads to super-cheap money, bonds being shit and no one wanting to hold cash. Lots of dollars go into more speculative assets, like stocks. And lots of money goes into exotic investments, <a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/articles/us-vc-fundraising-hits-record-69b-in-2020-after-a16z-closes-two-mega-funds#:~:text=US%20venture%20capital%20funds%20have,%244.5%20billion%20in%20commitments%20Friday.">like venture capital funds</a>.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/a-theory-about-the-current-ipo-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096743</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Samsung unveils Galaxy S21 line</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/daily-crunch-samsung-unveils-galaxy-s21-line/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/daily-crunch-samsung-unveils-galaxy-s21-line/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 23:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096831</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Samsung lowers prices with its latest Galaxy S phones, Google completes its Fitbit acquisition and Beyond Meat is coming to Taco Bell. This is your Daily Crunch for January 14, 2021. The big story: Samsung unveils Galaxy S21 line Samsung&#8217;s new line of phones includes the S21, S21+ and S21 Ultra, priced at $799, $999 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Samsung lowers prices with its latest Galaxy S phones, Google completes its Fitbit acquisition and Beyond Meat is coming to Taco Bell. This is your Daily Crunch for January 14, 2021.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Samsung unveils Galaxy S21 line</strong></p>
<p>Samsung&#8217;s new line of phones includes the S21, S21+ and S21 Ultra, priced at $799, $999 and $1,119 respectively, an across-the-board price cut of $200. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/samsungs-galaxy-s21-line-arrives-with-camera-bumps-price-drops-and-s-pen-compatibility/">Brian Heater writes</a> that the Ultra, in particular, &#8220;has one very important trick up its sleeve&#8221; — namely compatibility with the S Pen.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>All three phones are available for pre-order now and start shipping on January 29.</p>
<p>In addition, Samsung announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/samsung-answers-apple-with-the-199-galaxy-buds-pro/">the Galaxy Buds Pro</a>, which cost $199 and come with a stated five hours of battery life. And it&#8217;s launching a Bluetooth locator, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/samsung-unveils-its-newest-tile-competitor-the-galaxy-smarttag/">dubbed the Galaxy SmartTag</a>.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/googles-fitbit-acquisition-is-official/">Google’s Fitbit acquisition is official</a> — This follows regulatory scrutiny on both sides of the pond.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/ring-neighbors-exposed-locations-addresses/">Amazon’s Ring Neighbors app exposed users’ precise locations and home addresses</a> — The bug made it possible to retrieve the location data on users who posted to the app.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/beyond-meat-shares-soar-after-inking-deal-with-taco-bell-on-new-menu-items/">Beyond Meat shares soar after inking deal with Taco Bell on new menu items</a> — Taco Bell announced that it would work with Beyond Meat to come up with new menu items due to be tested in the next year.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/medium-acquires-social-book-reading-app-glose/">Medium acquires social book reading app Glose</a> — Glose has been building iOS, Android and web apps that let you buy, download and read books on your devices.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tiger-global-is-raising-a-new-3-75-billion-venture-fund-one-year-after-closing-its-last/">Tiger Global is raising a new $3.75B venture fund, one year after closing its last</a> — Despite being named Tiger Private Investment Partners XIV, this is actually the firm&#8217;s thirteenth fund.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/carbyne-raises-25m-for-a-next-generation-platform-to-improve-emergency-911-responses/">Carbyne raises $25M for a next-generation platform to improve emergency 911 responses</a> — The Israeli startup aims to help emergency services get more complete information about callers, and to provide additional telemedicine services.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/">Five consumer hardware VCs share their 2021 investment strategies</a> — Investors are generally bullish on at-home fitness startups.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/poshmark-prices-ipo-above-range-as-public-markets-continue-to-yolo-startups/">Poshmark prices IPO above range as public markets continue to YOLO startups</a> — This is the late-2020, early-2021 IPO market in action.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/12-flexible-vcs-who-operate-where-equity-meets-revenue-share/">Twelve ‘flexible VCs’ who operate where equity meets revenue share</a> — Founders seeking non-dilutive funding: start here.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tech-and-health-companies-including-microsoft-and-salesforce-team-up-on-digital-covid-19-vaccination-records/">Tech and health companies including Microsoft and Salesforce team up on digital COVID-19 vaccination records</a> — The so-called “Vaccination Credential Initiative” includes a range of big-name companies from both the healthcare and tech industries.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/2020-was-one-of-the-warmest-years-in-history-and-indicates-mounting-risks-of-climate-change/">2020 was one of the warmest years in history and indicates mounting risks of climate change</a> — 2020 either edged out or came in just behind 2016 as the warmest year in recorded history, according to data from U.S. government agencies.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/daily-crunch-samsung-unveils-galaxy-s21-line/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096831</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The end of Plaid-Visa, and Palantir&#8217;s growing startup mafia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/the-end-of-plaid-visa-and-palantirs-growing-startup-mafia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/the-end-of-plaid-visa-and-palantirs-growing-startup-mafia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 22:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bakkt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuvia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plaid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supercharger ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[talkspace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture-capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This week we &#8212; Natasha and Danny and Alex and Grace &#8212; had a lot to get through, as the news volume in early 2021 has been rapid and serious. Sadly this means that some early-stage rounds missed the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/c1a7a791-30d6-453e-9ec4-677d49391bc3?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture-capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This week we &#8212; <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/DannyCrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall">Grace</a> &#8212; had a lot to get through, as the news volume in early 2021 has been rapid and serious. Sadly this means that some early-stage rounds missed the cut, though we did make sure to have some Series A material in the show.</p>
<p>So, what did the assembled crew get to? Here&#8217;s your cheat sheet:</p>
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/venture-capitalists-react-to-visa-plaid-deal-meltdown/?tpcc=ECTW2020">demise of the Plaid-Visa deal</a>, our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/plaid-ceo-touts-new-clarity-after-failed-visa-acquisition/">chat with the CEO of the fintech unicorn</a> and what the failed transaction <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/will-startup-valuations-change-given-rising-antitrust-concerns/">could mean</a> for startup valuations more broadly.</li>
<li>Why the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/two-year-old-nuvia-sells-to-qualcomm-for-1-4-billion/">$1.4 billion Nuvia exit to Qualcomm</a> is impressive in scale and puzzling. This topic also gave Danny a chance to talk about chips, his favorite thing.</li>
<li>Auto-insurance rates can often depend on highly variable demographic data like marital status, income and education. Loop is a new seed-stage startup that wants to make the process more equitable.<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/loop-launches-out-of-stealth-to-make-auto-insurance-more-equitable/"> It landed millions this week,</a> underscoring a broader insurtech wave.</li>
<li>SuperCharger Ventures pivoted its fintech accelerator <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/inside-supercharger-ventures-debut-virtual-edtech-accelerator/">into an edtech accelerator</a>! We discuss why the shift and its surprising focus on B2B makes a ton of sense.</li>
<li>Crypto&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/cryptos-lose-ground-as-bitcoin-falls-23-ether-29-in-last-24-hours/">going up and down</a>, ahead of the anticipated Coinbase IPO and the known Bakkt SPAC. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/2021-a-spac-odyssey/">More on that here</a>.</li>
<li>Sticking to the SPAC front, SoFi joined the list of companies using blank-check companies to approach the public markets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>As <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-talkspace-m-a-hudson-executive/online-therapy-provider-talkspace-to-go-public-via-1-4-billion-spac-deal-idUSKBN29I1A2">is Talkspace</a>, the tele-therapy startup that you&#8217;ve heard of.</li>
<li>Then there was SoftBank, of course, which has its own SPAC in the market now, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/20/softbank-will-reportedly-file-for-a-spac-on-monday/">confirming earlier reports.</a> Which makes perfect sense.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are so many SPACs and bits of IPO news and funding rounds to pick through and cover that we&#8217;re already straining the time limits of the show to even cover half of the material. This week that meant that we excised a chunk of the show to a forthcoming Saturday episode that is focused on e-commerce.</p>
<p>So, we will talk to you again soon!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts.</i></p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/the-end-of-plaid-visa-and-palantirs-growing-startup-mafia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096663</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Capsule raises $2 million for its collaborative video platform aimed at brands</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/capsule-raises-2-million-for-its-video-qa-platform-aimed-at-brands/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/capsule-raises-2-million-for-its-video-qa-platform-aimed-at-brands/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 22:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Array Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Capsule video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Capsule, a video Q&#38;A platform aimed at brands, emerged last year in direct response to the challenges companies were facing in terms of reaching consumers during the pandemic. Now, the business has closed on $2 million in pre-seed funding. The round was led by Array Ventures and included participation from Bloomberg Beta and other angels. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://capsule.video/">Capsule</a>, a video Q&amp;A platform aimed at brands, emerged last year in direct response to the challenges companies were facing in terms of reaching consumers during the pandemic. Now, the business has closed on $2 million in pre-seed funding. The round was led by Array Ventures and included participation from Bloomberg Beta and other angels.</p>
<p>The startup was founded by the same team that originally created the animated GIF capture tool and social network <a href="https://phhhoto.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Phhhoto</a>, which eventually lost out to Instagram’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/22/instagram-boomerang/?_ga=2.127143629.1347273196.1592833498-1783005191.1582664406">clone</a>, Boomerang. Phhhoto shut down in 2017 and the team pivoted to work on an experiential marketing business, <a href="https://hypno.com/">Hypno.</a> The new company had been working with brands that hosted live events and experiences as a way to connect with customers. Hypno would offer them things like photo booths and other camera platforms that allowed for interactivity.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic essentially killed Hypno&#8217;s business as live events dried up. However, the brands Hypno had worked with still had the same needs &#8212; they just had to go about reaching their customers in a different way.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2096765" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096765" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2096765" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/capsule-frame.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/capsule-frame.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/capsule-frame.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/capsule-frame.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/capsule-frame.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/capsule-frame.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/capsule-frame.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/capsule-frame.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2096765" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Capsule</p></div></p>
<p>That&#8217;s how Capsule came to exist. Launched last year, the startup offers a full platform for hosting Q&amp;A sessions, where the brand starts with a template that they then customize to match their campaign by changing the logo, colors, buttons, background and URLs &#8212; sort of a like a Squarespace for the video Q&amp;A format.</p>
<p>The brand will then write their questions and prompts for consumers to answer, in the form of short video responses. This Q&amp;A URL is distributed however the company chooses &#8212; like on social media, for example. A new feature also allows a &#8220;capsule&#8221; to be embedded on the website.</p>
<p>The consumers&#8217; responses to the Q&amp;A are curated for the final video product. What makes the technology even more interesting is how Capsule assembles this footage.</p>
<p>Capsule instantly and automatically processes the video, adding elements like music and graphics, pre-roll or post-roll, which makes the resulting video appear professionally edited. The startup does this by using its own JavaScript-based programming language that automates mixing of things like color, audio, graphics and dynamic type. All the customer has to do is select the kind of video they want &#8212; like one with an energetic feel or a more somber one, for instance.</p>
<p>Today, Capsule has grown its library to about 20 base templates. But each of these can be edited by changing colors, styles and even the music &#8212; including either from direct uploads or from thousands of royalty-free tracks Capsule provides.</p>
<p><div style="width: 1920px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-2096700-1" width="1920" height="1080" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Product-Video.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Product-Video.mp4">https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Product-Video.mp4</a></video></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>According to Capsule co-founder Champ Bennett, the platform&#8217;s flexibility has led to a wide range of use cases. Though the company&#8217;s first customers had come from the live events space that Hypno had catered to, new customers soon began to adopt the product.</p>
<p>&#8220;What we immediately started to hear from both our existing customers and then, suddenly, a bunch of new customers that were coming our way, is that the platform was useful in so many different contexts,&#8221; he explains. &#8220;For example, UGC [user-generated content] campaigns or generating social content to promote a business, or awareness, or product reviews and testimonials, or even creators who just wanted a faster way to make content that looked and felt a little bit more professional,&#8221; Bennett says.</p>
<p>At launch, Capsule was used by companies like Netflix and organizations like OkayAfrica. It&#8217;s since landed contracts with hundreds of customers, including teams inside larger organizations like Google, Samsung, Salesforce, Deloitte and The Wall Street Journal, along with other small-to-medium businesses, like <a href="https://thyroidawareness.capsule.video/">Paloma Health</a>. The USO has also used Capsule.</p>
<p>These brands and others are especially hungry for tools that help them create original, short-form video content, which is becoming a key way businesses are marketing their products and services. Capsule notes that studies have <a href="https://databox.com/videos-vs-images-in-facebook-ads">indicated</a> video click-through rates are two-three times higher than static images and 95% of businesses are <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/state-of-video-marketing-new-data">reporting</a> an increase in their video spend year-over-year.</p>
<p>The pandemic had accelerated the existing demand for video content, but brands faced challenges in terms of video being difficult to scale.</p>
<p>&#8220;Increasingly, brands have started to kind of hack the way that they can create video,&#8221; says Bennett. &#8220;And one of the ways they&#8217;re doing that is by tapping into different creators within their organizations &#8212; whether it&#8217;s employees or founders or partners or influencers or fans of the brand or whatever it is &#8212; then activating them to create content on their behalf,&#8221; he continues. &#8220;We call this community-generated content, which is sort of like an iteration on user-generated content. It&#8217;s this idea that content can come from anywhere.&#8221;</p>
<p>Capsule says it wanted to work with Array Ventures GP Shruti Gandhi, who has an engineering background, because she very deeply understood the core technology. She introduced the team to Bloomberg Beta in New York, which also immediately understood what Capsule was building, Bennett says.</p>
<p>With the additional funds, Capsule will be hiring a product designer and will be developing new collaboration features, like the ability to upvote content.</p>
<p>Longer-term, the company believes its platform will enable more people to get involved with video creation.</p>
<p>&#8220;It turns out that there are so many different people within businesses who are capable of creating video content. They just don&#8217;t have the technical know-how to do it. They&#8217;re not video editors,&#8221; Bennett says. &#8220;So what we&#8217;re really doing is untapping this creative potential that exists inside of businesses everywhere, small and large.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/capsule-raises-2-million-for-its-video-qa-platform-aimed-at-brands/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096700</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>12 &#8216;flexible VCs&#8217; who operate where equity meets revenue share</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/12-flexible-vcs-who-operate-where-equity-meets-revenue-share/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/12-flexible-vcs-who-operate-where-equity-meets-revenue-share/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 21:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Collab Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colorado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa monica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seed money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tennessee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A dozen active investors who offer funding via revenue-based, compensation-based and blended-return streams.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">David Teten</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dteten">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		David Teten is founder of <a href="https://versatilevc.com/">Versatile VC</a> and writes periodically at <a href="https://teten.com/">teten.com</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/dteten">@dteten</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/flexible-vc-a-new-model-for-startups-targeting-profitability/">Flexible VC: A new model for startups targeting profitability</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/10/in-the-future-everyone-will-be-famous-for-15-followers/">In the future, everyone will be famous for 15 followers</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jamie Finney</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jamie Finney is a founding partner at <a href="https://www.greatercolorado.vc/">Greater Colorado Venture Fund</a>, where he <a href="https://www.greatercolorado.vc/blog">blogs about his work</a> on VC and small communities. 
	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/flexible-vc-a-new-model-for-startups-targeting-profitability/">Flexible VC: A new model for startups targeting profitability</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Previously, we introduced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/flexible-vc-a-new-model-for-startups-targeting-profitability/">the concept of flexible VC</a>: structures that allow founders to access immediate risk capital while preserving exit and ownership optionality. We list here all the active flexible VCs we have identified, broken into these categories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Revenue-based</li>
<li>Compensation-based</li>
<li>Blended-return streams</li>
</ul>
<h2>Revenue-based flexible VCs</h2>
<p><em>These investors are paid back primarily based on a percentage of revenues.</em></p>
<h3>Capacity Capital</h3>
<p>Chattanooga, TN-based <a href="https://capacity.is/capital/">Capacity Capital</a> was launched in 2020 with a primary focus on the southeastern U.S. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jdbragdon/">Jonathan Bragdon</a>, its CEO, describes Capacity as “a team of founders-turned-funders making non-dilutive, founder-aligned investments of $50,000-$300,000 in post-startup, post-revenue businesses planning to 2x revenues in 12-24 months. Investments are typically in exchange for a capped, single-digit revenue share and a right to equity under certain circumstances.</p>
<p>If the company sells or raises enough capital, the investment converts into an agreed-upon percentage of equity. If the company grows without raising additional equity funding, founders redeem most of the equity right, based on a pre-agreed return amount. With a portfolio that includes food, tech and services, the fund is industry-agnostic and focused on the overlooked and underrepresented with high-margin business models.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jonathan sometimes refers to their investments as &#8220;micro-mezzanine” because “mezz is typically structured as a contractual periodic payment, with some equity-like upside, but subordinate to other debt … so most lenders look at it like equity. But, it is typically shorter term with fewer control mechanisms than equity (i.e., not VC). I wanted [a term for] something similar (between debt and equity) but on an extremely small scale.”</p>
<p>In addition to a fund, the overall <a href="https://capacity.is/">Capacity</a> organization provides direct mentorship, consulting and connects founders to a broad network of talent, diverse forms of capital and existing resources focused on the post-startup stage of growth. The founders, LPs and venture partners have a long history in local startup ecosystems in the Southeast including <a href="https://launchtn.org/">LaunchTN</a>, <a href="https://colab.co/">The Company Lab</a>, <a href="https://costarters.co/">CO.STARTERS</a> and several other regional funds and resources.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NfVOvxX8Y3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/flexible-vc-a-new-model-for-startups-targeting-profitability/">Flexible VC: A new model for startups targeting profitability</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Flexible VC: A new model for startups targeting profitability&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/flexible-vc-a-new-model-for-startups-targeting-profitability/embed/#?secret=NfVOvxX8Y3" data-secret="NfVOvxX8Y3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Greater Colorado Venture Fund</h3>
<p><strong><a href="http://greatercolorado.vc">Greater Colorado Venture Fund</a></strong> (GCVF) is a $17 million seed fund that invests in high-growth startups in rural Colorado using equity and flexible VC structuring.</p>
<p>A typical GCVF flexible VC investment is $100,000-$250,000 for up to 10% ownership, of which 9% is redeemable, with a sub-10% revenue share and 12-month-plus holiday period. GCVF specializes in providing critical support to founders based in small communities, while connecting them to an unfair network well-beyond their small-town headquarters.</p>
<p>GCVF is pioneering the future of venture capital and high-growth startups for all small communities. With Colorado as an ideal pilot community, the GCVF team (which includes Jamie Finney, a co-author of this article) has helped grow multiple staple initiatives in the rural Colorado startup ecosystem, including <a href="https://westslopestartupweek.com/">West Slope Startup Week</a>, <a href="https://www.tellurideva.com/">Telluride Venture Accelerator</a>, <a href="https://startupcolorado.org/">Startup Colorado</a>, <a href="https://energizecolorado.com/gap-fund/">Energize Colorado Gap Fund</a> and the <a href="https://www.greatercolorado.vc/gcps-2020">Greater Colorado Pitch Series</a>.</p>
<p>Recognizing the need for creative investment structures in their Colorado market, they co-founded the <a href="https://www.wregistration.com/ehome/index.php?eventid=499665&amp;tabid=1000440&amp;">Alternative Capital Summit</a>, creating the first community of flexible VCs and alternative startup investors.</p>
<p>They share their learnings on flexible VC and pioneering rural startup ecosystems on the <a href="https://www.greatercolorado.vc/blog">GCVF blog</a>.</p>
<h3><strong><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/12-flexible-vcs-who-operate-where-equity-meets-revenue-share/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Home services platform Porch acquires four companies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/home-services-platform-porch-acquires-four-companies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/home-services-platform-porch-acquires-four-companies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 21:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arizona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contractor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ing group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance broker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north carolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[porch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Carolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virginia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Only a few weeks after its SPAC IPO, Porch today announced that it has made four acquisitions, worth a total of $122 million. The most important here is probably the acquisition of Homeowners of America for $100 million, which gets Porch deeper into the home insurance space. In addition, Porch is also acquiring mover marketing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Only a few weeks <a href="https://therealdeal.com/national/2020/12/24/porch-valuation-soars-to-1b-after-ipo/">after its SPAC IPO</a>, Porch today announced that it has made four acquisitions, worth a total of $122 million. The most important here is probably the acquisition of <a href="https://hoaic.com/">Homeowners of America</a> for $100 million, which gets Porch deeper into the home insurance space. In addition, Porch is also acquiring mover marketing and data platform <a href="https://v12data.com/v12-data/">V12</a> for $22 million, as well as home inspection service <a href="https://www.palm-tech.com/">Palm-Tech</a> and <a href="https://iroofing.org/">iRoofing</a>, a SaaS application for roofing contractors. Porch did not disclose the acquisition prices for the latter two companies.</p>
<p>You may still think of Porch as a marketplace for home improvement and repair services &#8212; and that&#8217;s what it started out as when it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/06/05/home-improvement-and-repair-marketplace-porch-raises-6-3m-from-sv-angel-jeff-skoll-and-others/">launched</a> about seven years ago. Yet while it still offers those services, a couple of years after its 2013 launch, the company <a href="https://porchgroup.com/story">pivoted</a> to building what it now calls a &#8220;vertical software platform for the home.&#8221; Through a number of acquisitions, the Porch Group now includes Porch.com, as well as services like HireAHelper, Inspection Support Network for home inspectors, Kandela for providing services around moving and an insurance broker in the form of the Elite Insurance Group. In some form or another, Porch&#8217;s tools are now used &#8212; either directly or indirectly &#8212; by two-thirds of U.S. homebuyers every month.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096738" style="width: 354px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096738" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2096738" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png" alt="" width="344" height="250" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png 979w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png?resize=150,109 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png?resize=300,218 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png?resize=768,559 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png?resize=680,495 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2020-12-16-at-1.13.55-PM-1.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 344px) 100vw, 344px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2096738" class="wp-caption-text">Porch founder and CEO Matt Ehrlichman. Image Credits: Porch</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As Porch founder and CEO Matt Ehrlichman told me, he had originally planned to take his company public through a traditional IPO. He noted that going the increasingly popular SPAC route, though, allowed him to push his timeline up by a year, which in turn now enables the company to make the acquisitions it announced today.</p>
<p>&#8220;In total, we had a $323 million fundraise that allows us now to not only be a public company with public currency, but to be very well capitalized. And picking up that year allows us to be able to go and pursue acquisitions that we think make really good fits for Porch,&#8221; Ehrlichman told me. While Porch&#8217;s guidance for its 2021 revenue was previously $120 million, it&#8217;s now updating that guidance to $170 million based on these acquisitions. That would mean Porch would grow its revenue by about 134% year-over-year between 2020 and 2021.</p>
<p>As the company had previously laid out in its public documents, the plan for 2021 was always to get deeper into insurance. Indeed, as Ehrlichman noted, Porch these days tends to think of itself as a vertical software company that layers insurtech on top of its services in order to be able to create a recurring revenue stream. And because Porch offers such a wide range of services already, its customer acquisition costs are essentially zero for these services.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096726" style="width: 367px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096726" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2096726" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png" alt="" width="357" height="85" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png 600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png?resize=150,36 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png?resize=300,72 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Homeowners-of-America-Insurance-Company-logo-.png?resize=50,12 50w" sizes="(max-width: 357px) 100vw, 357px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2096726" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Homeowners of America</p></div></p>
<p>Porch was already a licensed insurance brokerage. With Homeowners of America, it is acquiring a company that is both an insurance carrier as well as a managing general agent..</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re able to capture all of the economic value from the consumer as we help them get insurance set up with their new home and we can really control that experience to delight them. As we wrap all the technology we&#8217;ve invested in around that experience we can make it super simple and instant to be able to get the right insurance at the right price for your new home. And because we have all of this data about the home that nobody else has &#8212; from the inspection we know if the roof is old, we know if the hot water system is gonna break soon and all the appliances &#8212; we know all of this data and so it just gives us a really big advantage in insurance.&#8221;</p>
<p>Data, indeed, is what a lot of these acquisitions are about. Because Porch knows so much about so many customers, it is able to provide the companies it acquires with access to relevant data, which in turn helps them offer additional services and make smarter decisions.</p>
<p>Homeowners of America is currently operating in six states (Texas, Arizona, North Carolina, South Carolina, Virginia and Georgia) and licensed in 31. It has a network of more than 800 agencies so far and Porch expects to expand the company&#8217;s network and geographic reach in the coming months. &#8220;Because we have [customer acquisition cost]-free demand all across the country, one of the opportunities for us is simply just to expand that across the nation,&#8221; Ehrlichman explained.</p>
<p>As for V12, Porch&#8217;s focus is on that company&#8217;s mover marketing and data platform. The acquisition should help it reach its medium-term goal of building a $200 million revenue stream in this area. V12 offers services across multiple verticals, though, including in the automotive space, and will continue to do so. The platform&#8217;s overall focus is to help brands identify the right time to reach out to a given consumer &#8212; maybe before they decide to buy a new car or move. With Porch&#8217;s existing data layered on top of V12&#8217;s existing capabilities, the company expects that it will be able to expand these features and it will also allow Porch to not offer mover marketing but what Ehrlichman called &#8220;pro-mover&#8221; services, as well.</p>
<p>&#8220;V12 anchors what we call our marketing software division. A key focus of that is mover marketing. That&#8217;s where it&#8217;s going to have, long term, tremendous differentiation. But there are a number of other things that they&#8217;re working on that are going to have really nice growth vectors, and they&#8217;ll continue to push those,&#8221; said Ehrlichman.</p>
<p>As for the two smaller acquisitions of iRoofing and Palm-Tech, these are more akin to some of the previous acquisitions the company made in the contractor and inspection verticals. Like with those previous acquisitions, the plan is to help them grow faster, in part through integrating them into the overall Porch group&#8217;s family of products.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our business is and continues to be highly recurring or reoccurring in nature,&#8221; said <span class="il">Porch</span> CFO Marty Heimbigner. &#8220;Nearly all of our revenues, including that of these new acquisitions, is consistent and predictable. This repeat revenue is also high margin with less than 20% cost of revenue and is expected to grow more than 30% per year on our platform. So, we believe these deals are highly accretive for our shareholders.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/home-services-platform-porch-acquires-four-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096660</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exclusive: Tiger Global is raising a new $3.75 billion venture fund, one year after closing its last</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tiger-global-is-raising-a-new-3-75-billion-venture-fund-one-year-after-closing-its-last/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tiger-global-is-raising-a-new-3-75-billion-venture-fund-one-year-after-closing-its-last/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 20:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Credit Karma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kustomer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lee Fixel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peloton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postmates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snowflake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sumo logic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096546</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[According to a recent letter sent to its investors, Tiger Global Management, the New York-based investing powerhouse, is raising a new $3.75 billion venture fund called Tiger Private Investment Partners XIV that it expects to close in March. The fund is Tiger Global&#8217;s thirteenth venture fund, despite its title &#8212; the partners might be superstitious [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">According to a recent letter sent to its investors, <a href="https://www.tigerglobal.com/home">Tiger Global Management</a>, the New York-based investing powerhouse, is raising a new $3.75 billion venture fund called Tiger Private Investment Partners XIV that it expects to close in March.</p>
<p>The fund is Tiger Global&#8217;s thirteenth venture fund, despite its title &#8212; the partners might be superstitious &#8212; and it comes hot on the heels of the firm&#8217;s twelfth venture fund, closed exactly a year ago, also with $3.75 billion in capital commitments.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for the firm declined to comment on the letter or Tiger Global&#8217;s broader fundraising strategy when reached this morning.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s a lot of capital to target, even amid a sea of enormous new venture vehicles. New Enterprise Associates closed its newest fund with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/11/nea-venture-capitals-quiet-giant-closes-on-3-6-billion/">$3.6 billion</a> last year. Lightspeed Venture Partners soon after announced <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/lightspeed-boosts-three-funds-with-4b/">$4 billion</a> across three funds. Andreessen Horowitz, the youngest of the three firms, announced in November it had closed a pair of funds totaling <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/a16z-is-now-managing-16-5-billion-after-announcing-two-new-funds/">$4.5 billion</a>.</p>
<p>At the same time, Tiger Global seemingly has a strong case to present potential limited partners. Last year alone, numerous of its portfolio companies either went public or were acquired.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qSAMOS4a1s"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/a16z-is-now-managing-16-5-billion-after-announcing-two-new-funds/">A16z is now managing $16.5 billion, after announcing two new funds</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A16z is now managing $16.5 billion, after announcing two new funds&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/a16z-is-now-managing-16-5-billion-after-announcing-two-new-funds/embed/#?secret=qSAMOS4a1s" data-secret="qSAMOS4a1s" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Yatsen Holding, the nearly five-year-old parent company of China-based <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-cosmetics-perfectdiary/all-girls-buy-it-in-china-perfect-diary-gives-cosmetics-world-a-makeover-with-live-streams-low-prices-idUSKBN25M0BP">cosmetics giant</a> Perfect Diary, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-perfect-diary-ipo/perfect-diary-parents-shares-soar-in-u-s-debut-idUSKBN27Z2NK">went public</a> in November and is now valued at $14 billion. (Tiger Global&#8217;s ownership stake didn&#8217;t merit a mention on the company&#8217;s <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1819580/000119312520282237/d57580df1.htm#rom57580_16">regulatory filing</a>.)</p>
<p>Tiger Global also quietly <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1640147/000162827920000112/filename4.htm">invested</a> in the cloud-based data warehousing outfit Snowflake and, while again, it didn&#8217;t have a big enough stake to be included in the company&#8217;s <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1640147/000162828020013010/snowflakes-1.htm#ia73499eb79a34ddeaa563501d30356b0_106">S-1</a>, even a tiny ownership percentage would be valuable, given that Snowflake is now valued at $85 billion.</p>
<p>And Tiger Global backed Root insurance, a nearly six-year-old, Columbus, Ohio-based insurance company that <a href="https://www.insurancejournal.com/news/national/2020/10/28/588450.htm">went public</a> in November and currently boasts a market cap of $5.3 billion. Tiger owned 10.3% sailing into the offering.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WhmMxVIgOg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/3-lessons-from-roots-ipo-pricing/">3 lessons from Root&#8217;s IPO pricing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 lessons from Root&#8217;s IPO pricing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/3-lessons-from-roots-ipo-pricing/embed/#?secret=WhmMxVIgOg" data-secret="WhmMxVIgOg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As for M&amp;A, Tiger Global saw at least three of its companies swallowed by bigger tech companies during 2020, including Postmates&#8217;s all-stock sale to Uber for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/uber-officially-completes-postmates-acquisition/">$2.65 billion</a>; Credit Karma&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/24/intuit-credit-karma/">$7 billion</a> sale in cash and stock to Intuit; and the sale of Kustomer, which focused on customer service platforms and chatbots, for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/facebook-confirms-it-has-acquired-kustomer-sources-say-for-1b/">$1 billion</a> to Facebook.</p>
<p>Tiger Global, whose roots are in hedge fund management, launched its private equity business in 2003, spearheaded by Chase Coleman, who&#8217;d previously worked for hedge-fund pioneer Julian Robertson at Tiger Management; and Scott Shleifer, who joined the firm in 2002 after spending three years with the Blackstone Group. Lee Fixel, who would become a key contributor in the business, joined in 2006.</p>
<p>Shleifer focused on China, Fixel focused on India and the rest of the firm&#8217;s support team (it now has 22 investing professionals on staff) helped find deals in Brazil and Russia before beginning to focus more aggressively on opportunities in the U.S.</p>
<p>Every investing decision was eventually made by each of the three. Fixel left in 2019 to launch his own investment firm, <a href="https://addition.com/">Addition</a>. Now Shleifer and Coleman are the firm&#8217;s sole decision-makers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cbGFxXLGw3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/14/lee-fixel-is-leaving-tiger-global/">Lee Fixel is leaving Tiger Global</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lee Fixel is leaving Tiger Global&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/14/lee-fixel-is-leaving-tiger-global/embed/#?secret=cbGFxXLGw3" data-secret="cbGFxXLGw3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Whether the firm eventually replaces Fixel is an open question, though it doesn&#8217;t appear to be the plan. Tiger Global is known for grooming investors within its operations rather than hiring outsiders, so a new top lieutenant would almost surely come from its current team.</p>
<p>In the meantime, the firm&#8217;s private equity arm &#8212; which has written everything from Series A checks (Warby Parker) to checks in the multiple hundreds of millions of dollars &#8212; is currently managing assets of $30 million, compared with the $49 billion that Tiger is managing more broadly.</p>
<p>A year ago, Tiger Global, which employs 100 people altogether, was reportedly managing <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/tiger-global-raises-3-75-billion-venture-fund-11579887013">$36.2 billion</a> in assets.</p>
<p>According to the outfit&#8217;s investor letter, the firm&#8217;s gross internal rate of return across its 12 previous funds is 32%, while its net IRR is 24%.</p>
<p>Tiger Global&#8217;s investors include a mix of sovereign wealth funds, foundations, endowments, pensions and its own employees, who are collectively believed to be the firm&#8217;s biggest investors at this point.</p>
<p>Some of Tiger Global&#8217;s biggest wins to date have included a $200 million bet on the e-commerce giant JD.com that produced a $5 billion for the firm. According to the WSJ, it also cleared more than $1 billion on the Chinese online-services platform Meituan, which went public in 2018.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5lPnInKC1P"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/checkout-com-raises-450-million-and-reaches-15-billion-valuation/">Checkout.com raises $450 million and reaches $15 billion valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Checkout.com raises $450 million and reaches $15 billion valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/checkout-com-raises-450-million-and-reaches-15-billion-valuation/embed/#?secret=5lPnInKC1P" data-secret="5lPnInKC1P" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Tiger Global also reportedly reaped <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-05-09/tiger-global-is-said-to-reap-3-billion-from-flipkart-investment">$3 billion</a> from majority sale of India&#8217;s Flipkart to Walmart in 2018,  though the Indian government has more recently been <a href="https://www.livemint.com/news/india/tiger-global-moves-delhi-high-court-against-flipkart-tax-ruling-11600702202999.html">trying to recover $1.9 billion</a> from the firm, claiming it has outstanding tax due on the sale of its share in the company.</p>
<p>One outcome that might surprise even Tiger Global&#8217;s investors ties to the connected fitness company Peloton, 20% of which the firm owned at the time of Peloton&#8217;s  2019 IPO (a deal that Fixel reportedly <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexkonrad/2020/07/01/lee-fixel-raises-1-billion-fund-addition/?sh=7f5c48eb19a1">brought to the table</a>, along with Flipkart). By adding new users throughout the pandemic, Peloton &#8212; which was valued by private investors at $4 billion and doubled in value immediately as a publicly traded company &#8212; now boasts a market cap of $48.6 billion.</p>
<p>Tiger Global has invested its current fund in roughly 50 companies over the last 12 months.</p>
<p>Among its newest bets is <a href="https://blend.com/">Blend</a>, an eight-year-old, San Francisco-based digital lending platform that yesterday announced <a href="https://finledger.com/2021/01/13/blend-raises-300-million-series-g-at-3-3-billion-valuation/">$300 million in Series G funding</a>, including from Coatue, at a post-money valuation of $3.3 billion.</p>
<p>It also led the newly announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/checkout-com-raises-450-million-and-reaches-15-billion-valuation/">$450 million Series C round</a> for Checkout.com, an eight-year-old, London-based online payments platform that is now valued at $15 billion. And it wrote a follow-on check to Cockroach Labs, the nearly six-year-old, New York-based distributed SQL database that just raised<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/cockroach-labs-scores-160m-series-e-on-2b-valuation/"> $160 million in Series E funding</a> at a $2 billion valuation, just eight months after raising an $86.6 million Series D round.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VStIZZp7UR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/cockroach-labs-scores-160m-series-e-on-2b-valuation/">Cockroach Labs scores $160M Series E on $2B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cockroach Labs scores $160M Series E on $2B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/cockroach-labs-scores-160m-series-e-on-2b-valuation/embed/#?secret=VStIZZp7UR" data-secret="VStIZZp7UR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Another of its newest, biggest bets centers on the online education platform Zuowebang, in China. Back in June, Tiger Global co-led a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-zuoyebang-fundraiisng/chinese-online-tutor-zuoyebang-raises-750-million-in-fresh-round-idUSKBN240093">$750 million Series E round</a> in the company.</p>
<p>Last month, it was back again, co-leading a <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/china-online-education-startup-draws-061425152.html">$1.6 billion round</a> in the distance-learning company.</p>
<p><em>Pictured: Scott Shleifer, managing director of Tiger Global Management LLC, right, speaks with an attendee during the UJA-Federation of New York Wall Street Dinner in New York, on Wednesday, Dec. 14, 2011. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tiger-global-is-raising-a-new-3-75-billion-venture-fund-one-year-after-closing-its-last/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096546</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2020 was one of the warmest years in history and indicates mounting risks of climate change</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/2020-was-one-of-the-warmest-years-in-history-and-indicates-mounting-risks-of-climate-change/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/2020-was-one-of-the-warmest-years-in-history-and-indicates-mounting-risks-of-climate-change/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 20:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[katharine hayhoe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Washington Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[us government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington DC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s official. 2020 was one of the warmest years on record, either edging out or coming in just behind 2016 for the warmest year in recorded history according to data from U.S. government agencies (The National Aeronautics and Space Administration had the year just tied with 2016, while the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration put [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s official. 2020 was one of the warmest years on record, either edging out or coming in just behind 2016 for the warmest year in recorded history according to data from U.S. government agencies (The National Aeronautics and Space Administration had the year just tied with 2016, while the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration put the figure just behind 2016&#8217;s totals).</p>
<p>No matter the ranking, the big picture for the climate isn&#8217;t pretty, according to scientists from NASA&#8217;s <a href="https://www.giss.nasa.gov/">Goddard Institute for Space Studies</a> (GISS) in New York and the Washington, DC-based NOAA.</p>
<p>“The last seven years have been the warmest seven years on record, typifying the ongoing and dramatic warming trend,” said GISS Director <a href="https://www.giss.nasa.gov/staff/gschmidt/">Gavin Schmidt</a>, in a statement. “Whether one year is a record or not is not really that important – the important things are long-term trends. With these trends, and as the human impact on the climate increases, we have to expect that records will continue to be broken.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wUYGIJi7XB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/bill-gates-just-released-a-plan-for-us-leadership-on-climate-change-including-35b-in-funding/">Bill Gates just released a plan for US leadership on climate change, including $35B in funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bill Gates just released a plan for US leadership on climate change, including $35B in funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/bill-gates-just-released-a-plan-for-us-leadership-on-climate-change-including-35b-in-funding/embed/#?secret=wUYGIJi7XB" data-secret="wUYGIJi7XB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That&#8217;s a dire message for the nation considering the cost of last year&#8217;s record-breaking <a href="https://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/billions/"> 22 weather and climate disasters.</a> At least 262 people died and scores more were injured by climate-related disasters, according to the NOAA.</p>
<p>And the combination of wildfires, droughts, heatwaves, tornados, tropical cyclones and severe weather events like hail storms in Texas and the derecho that wrecked the Midwest cost the nation $95 billion.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2034047" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2034047" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2034047" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg" alt="Homes are engulfed in flames in Vacaville, California during the LNU Lightning Complex fire on August 19, 2020." width="1024" height="618" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg 2630w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=300,181 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=768,464 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=680,411 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=1536,927 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=2048,1237 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1228105407.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2034047" class="wp-caption-text">Homes are engulfed in flames in Vacaville, California during the LNU Lightning Complex fire on August 19, 2020. As of the late hours of August 18, 2020 the Hennessey fire has merged with at least 7 fires and is now called the LNU Lightning Complex fires. Dozens of fires are burning out of control throughout Northern California as fire resources are spread thin. (Photo by JOSH EDELSON/AFP via Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<p>Both organizations track temperature trends to get some sort of picture of the impact that human activities &#8212; specifically greenhouse gas emissions &#8212; have on the planet. The image that comes into focus is that human activity has already contributed to increasing Earth&#8217;s average temperature by more than 2 degrees Fahrenheit since the industrial age took hold in the late 19th century.</p>
<p>Most troubling to scientists is that this year&#8217;s near record-setting temperatures happened without a boost from the climatic weather phenomenon known as El Niño, which is a large-scale ocean-atmosphere climate interaction linked to a periodic warming.</p>
<p>“The previous record warm year, 2016, received a significant boost from a strong El Niño. The lack of a similar assist from El Niño this year is evidence that the background climate continues to warm due to greenhouse gases,” Schmidt said, in a statement.</p>
<p>The warming trends the word is experiencing are most pronounced in the Arctic, according to NASA. There, temperatures have warmed three times as a fast as the rest of the globe over the past 30 years, Schmidt said. The loss of Arctic sea ice &#8212; whose annual minimum area is declining by about 13% per decade &#8212; makes the region less reflective, which means more sunlight is being absorbed by oceans, causing temperatures to climb even more.</p>
<p>These accelerating effects of climate change could be perilous for the world at large, Katharine Hayhoe, a professor at Texas Tech University <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/interactive/2021/2020-tied-for-hottest-year-on-record/">wrote in an email to The Washington Post</a>.</p>
<p class=" font--body font-copy color-gray-darkest pb-md mw-md ma-auto pr-sm pl-sm ">&#8220;What keeps us climate scientists up in the dead of night is wondering what we don’t know about the self-reinforcing or vicious cycles in the Earth’s climate system,&#8221; Hayhoe wrote. &#8220;The further and faster we push it beyond anything experienced in the history of human civilization on this planet, the greater the risk of serious and even dangerous consequences. And this year, we’ve seen that in spades&#8230; It’s no longer a question of when the impacts of climate change will manifest themselves: They are already here and now. The only question remaining is how much worse it will get.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Mx0IzINULF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/carbon-dioxide-emissions-are-set-to-hit-a-record-high-this-year-its-not-fine-but-not-hopeless/">Carbon dioxide emissions are set to hit a record high this year (it&#8217;s not fine, but not hopeless)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Carbon dioxide emissions are set to hit a record high this year (it&#8217;s not fine, but not hopeless)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/carbon-dioxide-emissions-are-set-to-hit-a-record-high-this-year-its-not-fine-but-not-hopeless/embed/#?secret=Mx0IzINULF" data-secret="Mx0IzINULF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/2020-was-one-of-the-warmest-years-in-history-and-indicates-mounting-risks-of-climate-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096697</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 consumer hardware VCs share their 2021 investment strategies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Construct Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consumer Electronics Show]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyril Ebersweiler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayna grayson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ggv capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hans tung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lux capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rob coneybeer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shasta ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearable devices]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Tesla is arguably the most interesting connected consumer hardware company since Apple exploded in scale with the success of the iPhone."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Consumer hardware has always been a tough market to crack, but the COVID-19 crisis made it even harder.</p>
<p>TechCrunch surveyed five key investors who touch different aspects of the consumer electronics industry, based on our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/the-techcrunch-list/?verticals=576769646">TechCrunch List</a> of top VCs recommended by founders, along with other sources.</p>
<p>We asked these investors the same six questions, and each provided similar thoughts, but different approaches:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ggvc.com/ggv_employee/hans-tung/">Hans Tung</a>, managing partner, GGV Capital</li>
<li>Dayna Grayson, co-founder and general partner, <a href="https://www.constructcap.com">Construct Capital</a></li>
<li><a href="https://sosv.com/team/cyril-ebersweiler/">Cyril Ebersweiler</a>, general partner, SOSV</li>
<li><a href="https://luxcapital.com/team/bilal-zuberi/">Bilal Zuberi</a>, partner, Lux Capital</li>
<li><a href="https://www.shasta.vc/bio/rob-coneybeer/">Rob Coneybeer</a>, managing director, Shasta Ventures</li>
</ul>
<p>Despite the pandemic, each identified bright spots in the consumer electronic world. One thing is clear, investors are generally bullish on at-home fitness startups. Multiple respondents cited Peloton, Tonal and Mirror as recent highlights in consumer electronics.</p>
<p>Said Shasta Venture&#8217;s Rob Coneybeer, &#8220;With all due respect to my friends at Nest (where Shasta was a Series A investor), Tonal is the most exciting consumer connected hardware company I’ve ever been involved with.&#8221;</p>
<p>Besides asking about the trends and opportunities they&#8217;re pursuing in 2021, the investors we spoke to also identified other investors, founders and companies who are leaders in consumer hardware and shared how they&#8217;ve reshaped their investment strategies during the pandemic. Their responses have been edited for space and clarity.</p>
<hr />
<h2>Hans Tung, GGV Capital</h2>
<p><strong>Which consumer hardware sector shows the most promise for explosive growth?</strong></p>
<p>For consumer hardware, offering end users a differentiated experience is extremely important. Social interactions, gamification and high-quality PGC (professionally generated content) such as with Peloton, Xiaomi and Tonal is a must to drive growth. It’s also easy to see how the acceleration of the digital economy created by COVID-19 will also drive growth for hardware.</p>
<p>First, services improved by the speed and reliability of 5G such as live streaming, gaming, cloud computing, etc. will create opportunity for new mobile devices and global mass market consumers will continue to demand high-quality, low-cost hardware. For example, Arevo is experimenting with “hardware as a service” with a 3D printing facility in Vietnam.</p>
<p>For enterprise hardware, security, reliability and fast updates are key competitive advantages. Also as a result of 5G… manufacturing automation and industrial applications. Finally IoT for health and safety may find its sweet spot thanks to COVID-19 with new wearables that track sleep, fitness and overall wellness.</p>
<p><strong>How did COVID-19 change consumer hardware and your investment strategy?</strong></p>
<p>One opportunity for consumer hardware companies to consider as a result of COVID-19 is how they engage with their customers. They should think of themselves more like e-commerce companies, where user experience, ongoing engagement with the consumer and iteration based on market feedback rule the day. While Peloton had this approach well before COVID, it has built a $46 billion company thinking about their products in this way.</p>
<p>For example, some consumers felt the bike was too expensive so instead of responding with a low-end product, the company partnered with Affirm to make their hardware more affordable with pay-as-you-go plans. A Peloton bike is not a one-and-done purchase; there is constant interaction between users, and the company that drives more satisfaction in the hardware adds more value in the business.</p>
<p><strong>Entering 2021, in what way is hardware still hard?</strong></p>
<p>Hardware is still hard because it takes more to iterate fast. The outcome for competitors relative to speed-to-market can be dramatic. For example, every year I look at future generation of EVs with lots of innovations and cool features from existing OEMs but see very few of these making it to market compared to Tesla and other pure players that are cranking out vehicles. Their speed of execution is impressive.</p>
<p><strong>Who are some leaders in consumer hardware &#8212; founders, companies, investors?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>John Foley, founder and CEO of <a href="https://www.onepeloton.com/">Peloton</a>. John and the Peloton team have cracked the code on the integration of community experience and hardware.</li>
<li>Sonny Vu, founder of Misfit and founder/CEO of <a href="http://www.arevo.com">Arevo</a>, maker of ultrastrong, lightweight continuous carbon fiber products on demand. Experienced founder and team with 3D printing manufacturing know-how at scale are now able to offer breakthrough consumer and industrial products at competitive prices.</li>
<li>Manu Jain, head of <a href="https://www.mi.com/">Xiaomi</a>’s business in India where Xiaomi is the #1-selling smart phone. He built the Indian operation from the ground up; had zero dollar marketing budget for the first three years; and localized manufacturing for all Xiaomi phones sold in India.</li>
<li>Jim Xiao, founder and CEO of <a href="http://www.bymason.com">Mason</a>, a rising star who is creating &#8220;mobile infrastructure as a service.&#8221;</li>
<li>Irving Fain, founder and CEO of <a href="http://www.boweryfarming.com">Bowery Farming</a>. Irving and his team are on a mission to reimagine modern farming.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is there anything else you would like to share with TechCrunch readers?</strong></p>
<p>Worry less about trends and build products that resonate with customers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Dayna Grayson, Construct Capital<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096389</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>iSpot expands its ad measurement platform by acquiring Ace Metrix</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/ispot-acquires-ace-metrix/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/ispot-acquires-ace-metrix/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ace metrix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iSpot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leapfrog ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palomar ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wpp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ISpot.tv announced today that it has acquired Ace Metrix, a deal that brings two TV and video ad measurement companies together. ISpot founder and CEO Sean Muller said that the companies have complementary solutions. After all, he said, &#8220;In simple terms, there are only two reasons why brands buy advertising — one is to deliver business [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.ispot.tv">ISpot.tv</a> announced today that it has acquired <a href="https://www.acemetrix.com">Ace Metrix</a>, a deal that brings two TV and video ad measurement companies together.</p>
<p>ISpot founder and CEO Sean Muller said that the companies have complementary solutions. After all, he said, &#8220;In simple terms, there are only two reasons why brands buy advertising — one is to deliver business results and the other is to build brand recognition, likability and impact.&#8221;</p>
<p>The existing iSpot platform excels in the first area, Muller said, measuring the reach and conversation rates of ads that run on both TV and streaming. Ace Metrix, on the other hand, measures how an ad affects consumer sentiment — so by bringing the two companies together, it can offer &#8220;a complete solution in one platform.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Muller added that measuring the brand impact of an ad has become even more important as marketers try to navigate a constantly changing news landscape (to put it mildly).</p>
<p>&#8220;Brands are being forced to have a say in politics and all sorts of things,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Understanding the way your messages are being perceived is crucially important &#8230; When you invest in a piece of creative, it becomes even more important to ensure that your message is on point and triggers the right emotions.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kYXonmjow6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/05/19/ispot-series-b/">iSpot.tv Raises $21.9M To Track The Online Impact Of TV Advertising</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;iSpot.tv Raises $21.9M To Track The Online Impact Of TV Advertising&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2015/05/19/ispot-series-b/embed/#?secret=kYXonmjow6" data-secret="kYXonmjow6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Ace Metrix had raised $25 million in funding from investors including Hummer Winblad Venture Partners, WPP, Palomar Ventures and Leapfrog Ventures, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/ace-metrix">according to Crunchbase.</a></p>
<p>The financial terms of the acquisition were not disclosed, but iSpot says Ace&#8217;s 45 employees will all be joining the company, bringing total headcount to 240, with Ace CEO Peter Daboll becoming iSpot&#8217;s chief strategy officer. Ace will also maintain its office in Los Angeles (iSpot is headquartered in Bellevue, Washington).</p>
<p>Muller also noted that Ace had annualized SaaS revenues &#8220;north of the double digit millions&#8221; and that it was cashflow positive. The combined company has annual contracts with more than 500 brands.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re integrating the companies together very quickly — it&#8217;s already underway,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We&#8217;re going to be one company, one vision and so the Ace products become part of the iSpot product suite. But we will maintain the Ace name for those products.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oB1GelG4Dk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/breaking-down-the-specs-of-a-successful-video-ad/">Breaking down the specs of a successful video ad</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Breaking down the specs of a successful video ad&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/breaking-down-the-specs-of-a-successful-video-ad/embed/#?secret=oB1GelG4Dk" data-secret="oB1GelG4Dk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/ispot-acquires-ace-metrix/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096698</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This new module keeps Philips Hue bulbs connected even when the wall switch gets flipped</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/this-new-module-keeps-philips-hue-bulbs-connected-even-when-the-wall-switch-gets-flipped/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/this-new-module-keeps-philips-hue-bulbs-connected-even-when-the-wall-switch-gets-flipped/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philips hue]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Philips Hue bulbs are pretty great, but they have a mortal enemy: the humble light switch. If you&#8217;ve got a Hue bulb tied to a standard light switch, flipping that switch means the Hue bulb loses power completely&#8230; along with any fancy tricks like controlling the bulb through your phone or a voice assistant. A [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Philips Hue bulbs are pretty great, but they have a mortal enemy: the humble light switch. If you&#8217;ve got a Hue bulb tied to a standard light switch, flipping that switch means the Hue bulb loses power completely&#8230; along with any fancy tricks like controlling the bulb through your phone or a voice assistant.</p>
<p>A few solutions for this exist, but mostly involve swapping out the switch in question for something with a bit more smarts. This morning Signify (the company previously known as Philips Lighting) announced an official solution that works with your existing switches, albeit with a caveat or two.</p>
<p>Called the &#8220;wall switch module,&#8221; it&#8217;s expected to ship later this year — spring if you&#8217;re in Europe, or summer if you&#8217;re in North America. Once wired up, it turns your existing light switch into something more like a Hue controller, allowing it to toggle between different light presets rather than simply cutting power.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At $40 each (or $70 for a two-pack), it&#8217;s&#8230; not cheap. Add in the fact that it&#8217;s powered by a battery (presumably to remove the need for a neutral wire and simplify installation) with an estimated lifespan of ~five years, this probably isn&#8217;t something you want to implement house-wide. But for a single light switch or two, it seems like a decent solution.</p>
<p><strong>The company also announced a few new Hue accessories, in case you&#8217;re looking to expand your collection: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A revised version of its portable dimmer switch, which will ship in February and cost $25. The separate on/off buttons are becoming a single toggle, and a &#8220;Hue&#8221; button is being added to let you trigger a specific lighting scene.</li>
<li>A new light bar, the Philips Hue Amarant, which is meant to live outside and be mounted on the ground or an overhang. It&#8217;ll ship in March in North America, and cost $170 each (though you&#8217;ll also need an outdoor Hue power supply box, which will add $60-$70 to the price if you don&#8217;t have one already.)</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8TY06cONbP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/philips-hues-new-play-gradient-lightstrip-promises-a-big-upgrade-for-home-entertainment-spaces/">Philips Hue&#8217;s new Play gradient lightstrip promises a big upgrade for home entertainment spaces</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Philips Hue&#8217;s new Play gradient lightstrip promises a big upgrade for home entertainment spaces&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/philips-hues-new-play-gradient-lightstrip-promises-a-big-upgrade-for-home-entertainment-spaces/embed/#?secret=8TY06cONbP" data-secret="8TY06cONbP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/this-new-module-keeps-philips-hue-bulbs-connected-even-when-the-wall-switch-gets-flipped/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096674</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medium acquires social book reading app Glose</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/medium-acquires-social-book-reading-app-glose/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/medium-acquires-social-book-reading-app-glose/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medium]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Medium is acquiring Paris-based startup Glose for an undisclosed amount. Glose has been building iOS, Android and web apps that let you buy, download and read books on your devices. The company has turned reading into a multiplayer experience, as you can build a bookshelf, share notes with your followers and start conversations in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://medium.com">Medium</a> is <a href="https://blog.medium.com/medium-acquires-social-ebook-platform-glose-cf2e94485d8">acquiring</a> Paris-based startup <a href="https://glose.com/what-is-glose">Glose</a> for an undisclosed amount. Glose has been building iOS, Android and web apps that let you buy, download and read books on your devices.</p>
<p>The company has turned reading into a multiplayer experience, as you can build a bookshelf, share notes with your followers and start conversations in the margins. Sure, there are social platforms that let you talk about books, such as Goodreads. But Glose&#8217;s differentiating point is that the social features are intrinsically linked with the reading features — those aren&#8217;t two separate platforms. There are also some gamification features that help you stay motivated as you read difficult books — you get streak rewards for instance.</p>
<p>In many ways, Glose’s one-tap highlighting and commenting features are reminiscent of Medium’s features on this front. You can highlight text in any reading app on your phone or tablet but you can’t do much with it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>More recently, Glose has launched a separate service called <a href="https://glose.education">Glose Education</a>. As the name suggests, that version is tailored for universities and high schools. Teachers can hand out assignments and you can read a book as a group.</p>
<p>More than 1 million people have used Glose and 25 universities have signed up to Glose Education, including Stanford and Columbia University.</p>
<p>But Glose isn’t just a software play. The company has also put together a comprehensive bookstore. The company has partnered with 20,000 publishers so that you can buy e-books directly from the app.</p>
<p>And if you are studying Virginia Wolf this semester, Glose also provides hundreds of thousands of public domain books for free. Glose also supports audio books.</p>
<p>This is by far the most interesting part, as Medium now plans to expand beyond articles and blogs. While Glose is sticking around for now, Medium also plans to integrate e-books and audio books to its service.</p>
<p>It’s a smart move, as many prolific bloggers are also book writers. Right now, they write a blog post on Medium and link to a third-party site if you want to buy their books. Having the ability to host everything written by an author is a better experience for both content creators and readers.</p>
<p>“We’re impressed not only by Glose&#8217;s reading products and technology, but also by their experience in partnering with book authors and publishers,&#8221; Medium CEO Ev Williams said in a statement. “Books are a means of exploring an idea, a way to go deeper. The vast majority of the world’s ideas are stored in books and journals, yet are hardly searchable nor shareable. With Glose, we want to improve that experience within Medium’s large network of engaged readers and writers. We look forward to working with the Glose team on partnering with publishers to help authors reach more readers.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Glose team will remain in Paris, which means that Medium is opening its first office outside of the U.S. Glose will continue to honor its partnerships with authors, publishers, schools and institutions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KQX5QjVKqx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/11/13/glose-is-a-new-ebook-reader-to-turn-reading-into-a-social-experience/">Glose Is A New Ebook Reader That Turns Reading Into A Social Experience</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Glose Is A New Ebook Reader That Turns Reading Into A Social Experience&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/11/13/glose-is-a-new-ebook-reader-to-turn-reading-into-a-social-experience/embed/#?secret=KQX5QjVKqx" data-secret="KQX5QjVKqx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/medium-acquires-social-book-reading-app-glose/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096643</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Confusion over WhatsApp&#8217;s new T&#038;Cs triggers privacy warning from Italy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 18:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU data protection law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tcs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2096467</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Confusion over an update to Facebook-owned chat platform WhatsApp&#8217;s terms and conditions has triggered an intervention by Italy&#8217;s data protection agency. The Italian GPDP said today it has contacted the European Data Protection Board (EDPB) to raise concerns about a lack of clear information over what&#8217;s changing under the incoming T&#38;Cs. In recent weeks WhatsApp [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Confusion over an update to Facebook-owned chat platform WhatsApp&#8217;s terms and conditions has triggered an intervention by Italy&#8217;s data protection agency.</p>
<p>The Italian GPDP said today it has contacted the European Data Protection Board (EDPB) to raise concerns about a lack of clear information over what&#8217;s changing under the incoming T&amp;Cs.</p>
<p>In recent weeks WhatsApp has been alerting users they must accept new T&amp;Cs in order to keep using the service after February 8.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A similar alert over updated terms has also triggered concerns in India &#8212; where a petition was filed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/whatsapp-faces-legal-challenge-over-privacy-in-its-biggest-market/">today</a> in the Delhi High Court alleging the new terms are a violation of users&#8217; fundamental rights to privacy and pose a threat to national security.</p>
<p>In a notification on its <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9519943">website</a> the Italian agency writes that it believes it is not possible for WhatsApp users to understand the changes that are being introduced under the new terms, nor to &#8220;clearly understand which data processing will actually be carried out by the messaging service after February 8.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2096622" style="width: 428px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2096622" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2096622" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png?w=418" alt="" width="418" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png 737w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png?resize=92,150 92w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png?resize=185,300 185w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png?resize=418,680 418w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3399.png?resize=31,50 31w" sizes="(max-width: 418px) 100vw, 418px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2096622" class="wp-caption-text">Screengrab of the T&amp;Cs alert being shown to WhatsApp users in Europe. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch.</p></div></p>
<p>For consent to be a valid legal basis for processing personal data under EU law the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) requires that users are properly informed of each specific use and given a free choice over whether their data is processed for each purpose.</p>
<p>The Italian agency adds that it reserves the right to intervene &#8220;as a matter of urgency&#8221; in order to protect users and enforce EU laws on the protection of personal data.</p>
<p>We reached out to the EDPB with questions about the GPDP&#8217;s intervention. The steering body&#8217;s role is typically to act as a liaison between EU DPAs. But it also issues guidance on the interpretation of EU law and can step in to cast the deciding vote in cases where there is disagreement on cross-border EU investigations.</p>
<p>It told us there was &#8220;an exchange of views&#8221; on the topic at yesterday&#8217;s plenary meeting.</p>
<p>&#8220;The matter will most likely be further discussed at a later date,&#8221; it added. &#8220;Please note that SAs [supervisory authorities] regularly exchange information on cases within the context of the one-Stop-Shop.</p>
<p>&#8220;The EDPB has played its role in promoting cooperation between SAs, and will continue to facilitate such exchanges between authorities, in order to ensure a consistent application of data protection law across the EU in accordance with its mandate.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JEoO50GzAe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/e2e-encrypted-email-providers-also-see-sign-ups-surge-as-chat-app-users-flock-to-signal-and-telegram-in-search-of-privacy/">E2E encrypted email providers also see sign-ups surge as chat app users flock to Signal and Telegram in search of privacy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;E2E encrypted email providers also see sign-ups surge as chat app users flock to Signal and Telegram in search of privacy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/e2e-encrypted-email-providers-also-see-sign-ups-surge-as-chat-app-users-flock-to-signal-and-telegram-in-search-of-privacy/embed/#?secret=JEoO50GzAe" data-secret="JEoO50GzAe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://www.euronews.com/2021/01/11/turkey-investigates-whatsapp-and-facebook-over-data-privacy-update">Earlier this week</a> Turkish antitrust authorities also announced they are investigating WhatsApp&#8217;s updated T&amp;Cs &#8212; objecting to what they claimed are differences in how much data will be shared with Facebook under the new terms in Europe and outside.</p>
<p>While on Monday, Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission &#8212; which is WhatsApp&#8217;s lead data regulator in the EU &#8212; told us the messaging app has given it a commitment EU users are not affected by any broader change to data-sharing practices. So Facebook&#8217;s lead regulator in the EU has not raised any objections to the new WhatsApp T&amp;Cs.</p>
<p>WhatsApp itself has also claimed there are no changes at all to its data sharing practices anywhere in the world under this update.</p>
<p>Clearly there&#8217;s been a communications failure somewhere along the chain &#8212; which makes the Italian objection to a lack of clarity in the wording of the new T&amp;Cs seem reasonable.</p>
<p>Reached for comment on the GDPD&#8217;s intervention, a WhatsApp spokesperson told us:</p>
<blockquote><p>We are reviewing the Garante&#8217;s announcement regarding WhatsApp&#8217;s Privacy Policy update. We want to be clear that the policy update does not affect the privacy of your messages with friends or family in any way or require Italian users to agree to new data-sharing practices with Facebook. Instead, this update provides further transparency about how we collect and use data, as well as clarifying changes related to messaging a business on WhatsApp, which is optional. We remain committed to providing everyone in Italy with private end-to-end encrypted messaging.</p></blockquote>
<p>How exactly the Italian agency could intervene over the WhatsApp T&amp;Cs is an interesting question. (And, indeed, we&#8217;ve reached out to the GPDP with questions.)</p>
<p>The GDPR&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism means cross-border complaints get funneled through a lead data supervisor where a company has its main regional base (Ireland in WhatsApp&#8217;s case). But as noted above, Ireland has &#8212; thus far &#8212; said it doesn&#8217;t have a problem with WhatsApp&#8217;s updated T&amp;Cs.</p>
<p>However under the GDPR, other DPAs do have powers to act off their own bat when they believe there is a pressing risk to users&#8217; data.</p>
<p>Such as, in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/02/google-ordered-to-halt-human-review-of-voice-ai-recordings-over-privacy-risks/">2019</a>, when the Hamburg DPA ordered Google to stop manual reviews of snippets of Google Assistant users&#8217; audio (which it had been reviewing as part of a grading program).</p>
<p>In that case Hamburg informed Google of its intention to use the GDPR&#8217;s Article 66 powers &#8212; which allows a national agency to order data processing to stop if it believes there is “an urgent need to act in order to protect the rights and freedoms of data subjects” &#8212; which immediately led to Google suspending human reviews across Europe.</p>
<p>The tech giant later amended how the program operates. The Hamburg DPA didn&#8217;t even need to <em>use</em> Article 66 &#8212; just the mere threat of the order to stop processing was enough.</p>
<p>Some 1.5 years later and there are signs many EU data protection agencies &#8212; outside a couple of key jurisdictions that oversee the lion&#8217;s share of big tech &#8212; are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/20/further-delay-to-gdpr-enforcement-of-2018-twitter-breach/">becoming frustrated</a> by perceived regulatory inaction against big tech.</p>
<p>So there may be an increased willingness among these agencies to resort to creative procedures of their own to protect citizens&#8217; data. (And it&#8217;s certainly interesting to note that France&#8217;s CNIL recently slapped <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/france-fines-google-120m-and-amazon-42m-for-dropping-tracking-cookies-without-consent/">Amazon and Google with big fines over cookie consents</a> &#8212; acting under the ePrivacy Directive, which does not include a GDPR-style one-stop-shop mechanism.)</p>
<p>In related news this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/facebooks-eu-us-data-transfers-face-their-final-countdown/">week</a>, an opinion by an advisor to the EU&#8217;s top court also appears to be responding to concern at GDPR enforcement bottlenecks.</p>
<p>In the opinion <a href="https://curia.europa.eu/jcms/upload/docs/application/pdf/2021-01/cp210001en.pdf">Advocate General Bobek takes the view</a> that the law allows national DPAs to bring their own proceedings in certain situations &#8212; including in order to adopt “urgent measures” or to intervene “following the lead data protection authority having decided not to handle a case.”</p>
<p>The CJEU ruling on that case is still pending but the court tends to align with the position of its advisors so it seems likely we&#8217;ll see data protection enforcement activity increasing across the board from EU DPAs in the coming years, rather than being stuck waiting for a few DPAs to issue all the major decisions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="R2NboKXYmr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/">GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/embed/#?secret=R2NboKXYmr" data-secret="R2NboKXYmr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em><br />
This report was updated with comment from the EDPB</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2096467</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
