<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 20:37:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Announcing the agenda for TC Early Stage &#8211; Operations &#038; Fundraising</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/announcing-the-agenda-for-tc-early-stage-operations-fundraising/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/announcing-the-agenda-for-tc-early-stage-operations-fundraising/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Smith]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 20:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122408</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As an early-stage founder, how do you identify the right investors? Or know how to hire the best possible team to set up your company for growth? Should you bootstrap, and if so, how do you do it successfully? How do you nail virtual pitch meetings? What about product market fit? Board construction and good [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As an early-stage founder, how do you identify the right investors? Or know how to hire the best possible team to set up your company for growth? Should you bootstrap, and if so, how do you do it successfully? How do you nail virtual pitch meetings? What about product market fit? Board construction and good governance? How do you make sound financial decisions both for your company and yourself?</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">You’ve got questions. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=agendapost">TechCrunch Early Stage</a> will have answers for you on April 1 &amp; 2.</p>
<p>At the virtual event, we’re bringing together some of the most seasoned operators in the fields of legal, recruiting, product, data security, and sales to help you find your way through a tactical quagmire to the bright light of success at the end of the tunnel.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Of course, the show will cover more than operational challenges. We also have many, many sessions around fundraising, from how to think about raising your Series A to how to get an investors attention.<br />
If you’re in the midst of building a company, this show is worth making time for. Plus, audience members will be able to ask their own questions to our expert speakers in each and every breakout session.</p>
<h3>Finding Your Product Market Fit with Sean Lane (Olive AI)</h3>
<p>Olive AI founder and CEO is no stranger to the pivot. Hear how he practiced patience in the search for product market fit, how he knew it when he finally found it, and tactics he used to build on it.</p>
<h3>How to Get an Investor&#8217;s Attention with Marlon Nichols (MacVenture Partners)</h3>
<p>Marlon Nichols is an expert in early-stage investments, having invested in countless successful ventures such as Gimlet Media, MongoDB, Thrive Market, PlayVS, Fair, Wonderschool and Finesse. Right now, there is more seed stage fundraising than ever before, and Marlon will speak on how to get noticed by investors, how to grow your business and how to survive in the crowded, competitive space of tech startups. He will provide insights on how to network, craft a great pitch and target the best investors for your success.</p>
<h3>How to Nail Your Virtual Pitch Meeting with Melissa Bradley (Ureeka)</h3>
<p>The rules of the pitch meeting have changed. Instead of traveling across the country, wasting time in planes, trains and automobiles, founders can take upwards of 30 meetings in a day from the comfort of their home. Entrepreneur and VC Melissa Bradley will outline how to make the most of that half hour on Zoom and lock in the next one.</p>
<h3>10 Things NOT To Do When You Are Starting a Company with Leah Solivan (Fuel Capital)</h3>
<p>With voices across the internet giving their two-cents on how to run a great business. Fuel Capital&#8217;s Leah Solivan, who was CEO at TaskRabbit for 8 years, will share a list of things that a founder should NOT do. Avoid the pitfalls that could break your momentum, or worst case, your company and ask Solivan your own questions.</p>
<h3>How To Get Into An Accelerator with Neal Sales-Griffin (Techstars)</h3>
<p>Accelerators provide an incredible launch pad for early stage startups, offering a built-in network, accessible advisors, and of course, capital. But first, you&#8217;ve got to be accepted. Hear Techstars Neal Sales-Griffin outline how to get into an accelerator and make the most of the experience.</p>
<h3>4 Things To Think About Before Raising a Series A with Bucky Moore (Kleiner Perkins)</h3>
<p>Founders looking to raise Series A capital know that it&#8217;s an entirely different ball game than seed stage funding. Hear Kleiner Perkins partner Bucky Moore outline the most important ways to mentally prepare for heading into Series A fundraising.</p>
<h3>How to Build Your Early Team for Future Growth with Sarah Smith (Bain Capital Ventures)</h3>
<p>More than your investors, or even you as a founder, your early employees will have a tremendous influence on the trajectory of your company. You hire them, and often times, they hire everyone else. Hear Bain Capital Ventures partner Sarah Smith talk through how to recruit a top-notch early team that sets your startup up for future growth.</p>
<h3>Contracts, Cap Tables and other Legal Questions with Dawn Belt (Fenwick)</h3>
<p>No matter the industry, your startup requires legal help. Whether it&#8217;s building out the cap table, writing up contracts, understanding the laws around hiring or simply feeling secure with a TOS. Whatever the question, Fenwick &amp; West partner Dawn Belt has the answer.</p>
<h3>Finance for Founders with Alexa von Tobel (Inspired Capital)</h3>
<p>As a founder, you not only have to master your company&#8217;s finances, you also have to tackle your own personal finances. Managing your money as a founder comes with a unique set of questions (see: QSBS). Leveraging her expertise from LearnVest and as a Certified Financial Planner<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, Alexa will share financial planning best practices so founders can remove this layer of stress from the pressure of building a business.</p>
<h3>Leadership Culture and Good Governance with David Easton (Generation Investment Management)</h3>
<p>David Easton is a growth-stage partner at Generation Investment Management with portfolio companies that include Asana, Andela, Gusto, and Docusign, among others. Easton will talk through how to choose your board and foster a leadership culture that keeps sustainable, good governance top of mind.</p>
<h3>Building and Leading a Sales Team with Ryan Azus (Zoom)</h3>
<p>Contrary to popular opinion, even the very best products don&#8217;t sell themselves. Salespeople do. Hear from Zoom&#8217;s Chief Revenue Officer, at the helm of the company&#8217;s sales team during the biggest period of growth of any software company ever, lay out how to build a stellar sales team.</p>
<h3>The All-22 View with Eghosa Omoigui (EchoVC Partners)</h3>
<p>Improving line of sight and dynamic field of play aperture is rarely discussed but hugely important. Great founders, operators and investors have an understanding of playbooks on both sides of the ball. We&#8217;ll talk through learnings and some ideas on how to build muscle memory and skillsets so that founders never lose perspective when it&#8217;s time to make a big decision.</p>
<p>And we&#8217;ll also have some great sessions from our partners too!</p>
<h3>Creating and Protecting IP Value in Connection with VC Financings brought to you by <a href="http://www.perkinscoie.com/">Perkins Coie</a></h3>
<p>How do venture capital investors value formal Intellectual Property (IP) rights in connection with a decision to fund a technology or life sciences start-up? How do they conduct IP due diligence? How do investors and founders, post-funding, ensure their start-ups are pursuing an IP strategy that optimizes exit valuation for all? Perkins Coie partners Michael Glenn (Patent Prosecution) and Matt Oshinsky (Emerging Companies Venture Capital) will be joined alongside a seasoned venture capitalist to discuss these and other questions regarding safeguarding IP rights and maximizing the value of all technology development activities.</p>
<h3>Scientist Entrepreneurs &#8211; Scaling Breakout Engineering Biology Companies brought to you by <a href="https://www.mayfield.com/">Mayfield</a></h3>
<p>Biology as technology will re-invent trillion dollar industries and enhance human and planetary evolution. In this session, two early-stage investors and company builders, Arvind Gupta and Ursheet Parikh, will be in conversation with a leading author and seed investor Po Bronson, Managing Director of IndieBio. They will share their playbook on scaling start-ups touching upon three seminal areas which influence trajectory – fundraising, hiring, and product design. Their insights will draw on their experience with companies including ingredients-as-service leader Geltor which raised a $91 million Series B in 2020, CRISPR platform Mammoth Biosciences whose dream team includes co-founder Nobel Laureate Jennifer Doudna, and Endpoint Health, started by the founding team of GeneWEAVE (acquired by Roche) and former YC Bio Partner Diego Rey, which is designing a new class of therapeutic products that focus on hospital conditions that kill as many people as cancer.</p>
<h3>Using Fast Feedback to Make Higher-Confidence Decisions and Accelerate the Dev Process brought to you by <a href="https://www.usertesting.com/">UserTesting</a></h3>
<p>We&#8217;ll discuss how to use fast feedback methodologies to make high-confidence product decisions based on objective customer data in real time, without slowing the dev process. Quickly diagnose problems, settle disputes, reduce the risk of rework, and iterate faster. This session will include real-world case studies.</p>
<h3>An M&amp;A Playbook for Startup Founders: Lessons from Google and Microsoft brought to you by <a href="http://www.meruscap.com/">Merus Capital</a></h3>
<p>One of the most important decisions a founding team can make is when to consider selling the company to a strategic buyer. In this session, learn the tactics for approaching acquirors, avoiding common pitfalls and maximizing the likelihood of achieving an eye-popping valuation. Hear from Sean Dempsey, founding partner of Merus Capital who spent 10 years leading acquisitions for Google and Microsoft, and Dave Sobota, VP of Corporate Development at Instacart and former M&amp;A leader at Google.</p>
<h3>Why Founders should adopt OKRs now? brought to you by <a href="https://dell.to/TechCrunch">Dell for Entrepreneurs</a></h3>
<p>Execution is key to a start-up&#8217;s survival and growth especially when it comes to fast-moving software and technology products. Being in the tricky intersection of investors, customers and employees, a founder needs to balance priorities, align teams and create a visionary product that works. Moreover, in this age of hyper feedback loops and changing business models, the founder has to be agile enough to absorb and quickly react to changes in the product roadmap and consumer needs. OKRs &#8211; a toolkit used majorly by engineering and product teams is more than relevant now for founders of all kinds to embrace. Join the session to learn the history of OKRs, what they are about, and witness case studies of successful real-life adoption.</p>
<h3>Naming &amp; Protecting Your Company’s Intellectual Property brought to you by <a href="http://www.brainbase.com/">Brainbase</a></h3>
<p>You have an idea for a game-changing product or service – what do you call it? Once you’ve picked a name, how do you make sure nobody else is using it? Is the domain and Twitter handle available? Brainbase makes it easy for anyone to file a trademark without a lawyer, and instantly own your brand across all channels. In this session, Brainbase co-founder and CEO Nate Cavanaugh will explain the importance of owning your company’s trademark, both for brand protection and for fundraising due diligence.</p>
<h3>Nailing the little things: How startups can achieve operational excellence from &#8220;Day one&#8221; brought to you by <a href="https://www.bcapgroup.com/">B Capital Group</a></h3>
<p>The early days of launching a company can be a whirlwind for founding teams as unexpected challenges and opportunities require flexibility, agility and speed. But implementing a few key operating best practices and processes early can be a crucial part of a startup&#8217;s success or failure when it prepares for rapid growth. Join partners from B Capital Group, a multi-stage global investor, to learn about the most important things you can do to set your startup up for success early in your journey, and what will be most important to investors as you raise your Seed, A and B funding rounds. Speakers include Howard Morgan, Chairman of B Capital Group and co-founder of First Round Capital, and Partners Karen Page (formerly of Box) and Gabe Greenbaum (formerly of Pritzker Group).</p>
<p>This year, we’ve <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/announcing-the-tc-early-stage-pitch-off/">added a pitch-off</a> on day 2 of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=agendapost">TC Early Stage</a>, showcasing interesting startups from a variety of sectors. All-star judges will give their feedback live. You don’t want to miss it! And if you&#8217;re interested in pitching, you can still <a href="https://tc692057.typeform.com/to/jNejpAvG">apply to pitch by tomorrow, March 9</a>.</p>
<p>Of course, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=quorapost&amp;display=true">TC Early Stage</a> dual event ticket holders will get access to both events (April 1-2 and July 8-9) and have access to 2x the content that comes out of the event live or on demand. Plus, you can take advantage of additional savings with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=quorapost&amp;display=true">Early Bird pricing</a> on dual event tickets until March 26!</p>
<p>Mercenary CEOs know all too well that this is about the most bang you can get for your buck. Period. Grab <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=quorapost&amp;display=true">get your ticket now and save up to $100</a>!</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/announcing-the-agenda-for-tc-early-stage-operations-fundraising/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122408</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>From electric charging to supply chain management, InMotion Ventures preps Jaguar for a sustainable future</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/from-electric-charging-to-supply-chain-management-inmotion-ventures-preps-jaguar-for-a-sustainable-future/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/from-electric-charging-to-supply-chain-management-inmotion-ventures-preps-jaguar-for-a-sustainable-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 19:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inmotion Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jaguar Land Rover]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sebastian Peck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Obviously, we venture beyond electrification into autonomous vehicles and connectivity. There will be a lot of value creation once OEMs are able to surface their APIs."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Since <a href="https://www.inmotionventures.com/">InMotion Ventures</a>, the independent investment and incubation initiative set up by <a href="https://www.jaguarlandrover.com/">Jaguar Land Rover</a>, launched in 2016 the firm has focused on backing companies across the mobility space broadly. Its 15 active investments run the gamut from autonomous vehicles, to car insurance tech, to ride-sharing, and travel planning, but increasingly the firm is focusing its efforts on vehicle electrification and sustainable supply chains.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			As the mobility market moves to embrace electrification, InMotion wants to make sure its portfolio is in the mix.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>That&#8217;s evident from its most recent investment in <a href="https://www.circulor.com/">Circulor</a>, a company that monitors supply chains from raw material inputs to finished outputs with an eye toward sustainable sourcing.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">As an OEM nowadays it’s increasingly important to have increasing transparency and visibility into how all of those materials have been sourced,&#8221; said the firm&#8217;s managing director, Sebastian Peck. Circulor already has a strong footprint in the automotive industry, Peck said, and is working with a major oil company on tracing the share of recycled plastics that have come from that provider. &#8220;It has applications across any industry.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Jaguar Land Rover is also using Circulor&#8217;s technology to track a material that&#8217;s being used in the interior of one of the company&#8217;s vehicles, Peck said. The stealthy project hasn&#8217;t been publicly revealed yet, but the company has worked with a university and supplier to trace the material from its point of origin to the finished product.</p>
<p>Sustainable supply chains aren&#8217;t the only priorities Peck laid out in a recent interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>As the mobility market moves to embrace electrification, InMotion wants to make sure its portfolio is in the mix and Peck said it would be looking to make investments in a number of different areas around electric vehicles and batteries.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We have looked at a number of companies who are developing new battery chemistries. We haven’t made an investment yet,&#8221; Peck said. &#8220;We don’t have a deep enough insight into the IP portfolios of the big battery suppliers to really be able to reliably benchmark those new chemistries. We have not had enough conviction to make an investment or back a particular company. From a value chain it is two or three steps away from us. It’s a space we’re looking at.&#8221;<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/from-electric-charging-to-supply-chain-management-inmotion-ventures-preps-jaguar-for-a-sustainable-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121522</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cosi raises €20M for its &#8216;full-stack&#8217; approach to short-term rentals</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/cosi-raises-e20m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/cosi-raises-e20m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 18:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cosi group]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cosi Group, a Berlin-based startup offering an alternative to boutique hotels and managed short-stay apartments, is disclosing €20 million in new investment. Backing the round is Vienna-based Soravia, a leading real estate group in German-speaking countries. Existing investors Cherry Ventures, e.ventures, Kreos Capital and Bremke followed on, along with a number of individual investors. They [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.cosi-group.com/">Cosi Group</a>, a Berlin-based startup offering an alternative to boutique hotels and managed short-stay apartments, is disclosing €20 million in new investment.</p>
<p>Backing the round is Vienna-based Soravia, a leading real estate group in German-speaking countries. Existing investors Cherry Ventures, e.ventures, Kreos Capital and Bremke followed on, along with a number of individual investors. They are described as including the founders of Flixbus, Travelperk, Comtravo and Cosi&#8217;s own founders.</p>
<p>Cosi says it will use the fresh capital to accelerate international expansion in Europe, implement a new brand and launch a &#8220;new strategic business unit&#8221; soon.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iAvqWbzAFw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/21/cosi/">Cosi raises €5M for its &#8216;full-stack&#8217; hospitality alternative to boutique hotels</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cosi raises €5M for its &#8216;full-stack&#8217; hospitality alternative to boutique hotels&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/21/cosi/embed/#?secret=iAvqWbzAFw" data-secret="iAvqWbzAFw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Originally described as a tech-enabled or “full-stack” hospitality service that competes with well-run boutique hotels or traditional local managed apartments, the company signs long-term leases with property owners, and then furnishes those apartments itself to “control” the interior design experience. It claims to have digitised, and where possible, automated its processes in order to scale and maintain quality of service throughout the guest journey, from initial contact to loyalty.</p>
<p>Christian Gaiser, CEO of Cosi, tells me the startup has not only been able to mitigate the pandemic &#8212; which has seen major restrictions in travel, including countries going into full lockdown &#8212; but actually thrive. That&#8217;s because Cosi was able to tap &#8220;new demand channels&#8221; that aren&#8217;t reliant on holiday travel or short business trips.</p>
<p>Described as &#8220;midstay&#8221; (guests that stay for one month or longer), examples include people who arrive in a city and need a home for one or two months until they find a longer-term apartment, citizens who need to get away from shared apartments (perhaps to be less at risk or to work from home), or families who are building or renovating a house that faces construction delays due to the pandemic.</p>
<p>&#8220;Thus, we were able to reach over 90% occupancy and managed to operate our locations on a cash-flow-positive scale,&#8221; adds the Cosi CEO. &#8220;Lesson learned for us: Even when almost all your demand channels dry out, you still can do a lot if you focus on what you can control. We simply activated new demand channels.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition, he says the pandemic has accelerated a shift in demand preferences, seeing &#8220;big hotel bunkers&#8221; become less popular versus individual apartment style accommodations.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Cosi has also seen a &#8220;massive boost in supply,&#8221; with lots of takeover opportunities in the hotel space, especially for underperforming hotel properties. And since office space demand has contracted dramatically, the company is receiving offers to convert office space for use as midstay accommodation.</p>
<p>&#8220;On the back of our strong COVID performance, we&#8217;ve built a lot of trust among the real estate community and receive more and more offers,&#8221; says Gaiser. &#8220;Prices for supply have fallen sometimes dramatically, depending on the city, due to these factors&#8221;.</p>
<p>To that end, Cosi currently has 750 units under contract, with 1,500 more under negotiation.</p>
<p>Adds the Cosi CEO: &#8220;Now is exactly the right timing to double down on Cosi&#8217;s growth from a long-term perspective. When everyone is scared/shocked, you can win big if you have a clear plan. Our investors bought into this plan, as we have demonstrated that our business model is resilient and we also have the capacity to navigate the ship both in good but also in rough waters.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BYafrQt6TC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/corporate-sustainability-initiatives-may-open-doors-for-carbon-offset-startups/">Corporate sustainability initiatives may open doors for carbon offset startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Corporate sustainability initiatives may open doors for carbon offset startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/corporate-sustainability-initiatives-may-open-doors-for-carbon-offset-startups/embed/#?secret=BYafrQt6TC" data-secret="BYafrQt6TC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/cosi-raises-e20m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122346</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Porter Road&#8217;s sustainable, whole animal butchery raises $10 million to expand across the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/porter-roads-sustainable-whole-animal-butchery-raises-10-million-to-expand-across-the-u-s/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/porter-roads-sustainable-whole-animal-butchery-raises-10-million-to-expand-across-the-u-s/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 17:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FJ Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kentucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nashville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slow ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tribeca Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the nearly 10 years since it launched as a whole animal butchery out of a storefront in East Nashville, the founders of Porter Road have wanted to herd America&#8217;s meat industry down a new path. Now the company has $10 million in financing from investors including L37 Ventures, River Park Ventures, Middleland, FJ Labs, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the nearly 10 years since it launched as a whole animal butchery out of a storefront in East Nashville, the founders of <a href="https://porterroad.com/">Porter Road</a> have wanted to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/30/porter-road-was-to-herd-the-meat-industry-in-a-new-direction/">herd America&#8217;s meat industry down a new path</a>.</p>
<p>Now the company has $10 million in financing from investors including L37 Ventures, River Park Ventures, Middleland, FJ Labs, Kelvin Beachum along with previous investors MAX Ventures, Tribeca Venture Partners and Slow Ventures to bring that mission to a broader swath of the country.</p>
<p>Since the company bought its own slaughterhouse back in 2015 and expanded to e-commerce in 2018 it has been shipping its selections of lamb, beef, pork, chicken and sausages from local farms to tables across the U.S.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RVs5Q67POy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/30/porter-road-was-to-herd-the-meat-industry-in-a-new-direction/">Porter Road wants to herd the meat industry in a new direction</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Porter Road wants to herd the meat industry in a new direction&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/30/porter-road-was-to-herd-the-meat-industry-in-a-new-direction/embed/#?secret=RVs5Q67POy" data-secret="RVs5Q67POy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The new money will be used to scale the company&#8217;s sustainable agriculture and its pasture-raised meat for the direct-to-consumer business, its shop in Nashville and for wholesale distribution to restaurants around the country.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s going to expand its operations in Princeton, Kentucky with a new USDA processing facility that&#8217;s 4.5 times larger to meet new demand. That move will create 80 new jobs in the small town and is part of a broader agricultural renaissance in Kentucky.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;It’s easy to back founders who are as comfortable on the manufacturing line as they are</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">in the boardroom, and who see the world differently and have the deep domain expertise to</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">execute on that vision,&#8221; said L37 Partner Randall Ussery in a statement. &#8220;They have spent years perfecting the Porter Road way, which no</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">company nor incumbent can replicate overnight. They are a category killer in the meat industry</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and have built a moat around their brand.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2122380" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122380" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2122380" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Porter_Road_Hero_Box_Horiz.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Porter_Road_Hero_Box_Horiz.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Porter_Road_Hero_Box_Horiz.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Porter_Road_Hero_Box_Horiz.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Porter_Road_Hero_Box_Horiz.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Porter_Road_Hero_Box_Horiz.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Porter_Road_Hero_Box_Horiz.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Porter_Road_Hero_Box_Horiz.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2122380" class="wp-caption-text">Porter Road delivery box of a selection of its steaks, sausages and bacon. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Porter Road</p></div></p>
<p>One indication of the ways in which Porter Road differs from its larger competitors is in the way it handled the COVID-19 pandemic at its facilities.</p>
<p>Due to its limited production schedule and measures like staggered break times, mask requirements and social distancing rules, the company was able to avoid having any outbreaks at its facilities, according to the company&#8217;s co-founder and chief executive, Chris Carter. &#8220;We had a handful of people who got sick, but [COVID-19] didn&#8217;t spread in Princeton,&#8221; said Carter.</p>
<p>Despite the push for more plant-based diets, Carter says that his company&#8217;s focus on pasture-raised animals and whole animal butchery should appeal to folks who care about sustainable production. &#8220;We care about our farmers and we care about the way our animals are raised,&#8221; said Carter. &#8220;That&#8217;s the whole point of what we&#8217;re doing …<span style="font-weight: 400;"> Porter Road is about animal utilization. It’s about honoring the life of an animal so we find an outlet for every single piece.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Porter Road is expanding its product line into cooking tallow and fats, and cross-cut bones for bone marrow dishes, Carter said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The food system is broken and in need of a substantial change. Today’s consumer is</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">demanding a deeper level of connection to their food </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">and can see past misleading labels and buzzwords,”</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">said Carter, in a statement. “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">W</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">e are delivering trust, transparency and flavor so no one has to compromise, all while supporting our farmers.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JQKYz2Go5Y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/startups-in-energy-storage-housing-transportation-and-agriculture-could-see-boost-under-biden-plans/">Biden&#8217;s infrastructure plans could boost startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Biden&#8217;s infrastructure plans could boost startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/startups-in-energy-storage-housing-transportation-and-agriculture-could-see-boost-under-biden-plans/embed/#?secret=JQKYz2Go5Y" data-secret="JQKYz2Go5Y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/porter-roads-sustainable-whole-animal-butchery-raises-10-million-to-expand-across-the-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122352</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple teams with Common Sense Media to curate podcasts for kids</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/apple-teams-with-common-sense-media-to-curate-podcasts-for-kids/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/apple-teams-with-common-sense-media-to-curate-podcasts-for-kids/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 17:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[families]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trends]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple announced this morning it&#8217;s teaming up with Common Sense Media to curate a selection of kid-friendly podcasts in the U.S. in light of what appears to be growing interest in spoken-word entertainment among families. That interest, in part, may have been prompted by the pandemic and parents&#8217; desire to reduce kids&#8217; screen time for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple announced this morning it&#8217;s teaming up with Common Sense Media to curate a selection of kid-friendly podcasts in the U.S. in light of what appears to be growing interest in spoken-word entertainment among families. That interest, in part, may have been prompted by the pandemic and parents&#8217; desire to reduce kids&#8217; screen time for entertainment.</p>
<p>Via a new website at <a href="http://apple.co/showsforkids">Apple.co/showsforkids</a> (which launches Apple Podcasts), Apple has collaborated with Common Sense Media to group podcasts by age group as well as by theme. At launch, the collection features creators like Tinkercast, American Public Media, Gen-Z Media, Pinna, Tumble, Highlights, WNYC Studios, Rebel Girls and Nickelodeon, among others.</p>
<p>In addition to groups by age, there are also four thematic collections available: <em>Common Sense Media Picks</em>, which are all-time family favorites; <em>One More!,</em> which features mysterious tales and action-packed dramas; <em>Kids Know Best</em>, which feature shows picked by kids themselves; and <em>Story Time</em>, which are story-driven shows.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2122364" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122364" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2122364" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-08-at-12.28.04-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="483" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-08-at-12.28.04-PM.jpg 2794w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-08-at-12.28.04-PM.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-08-at-12.28.04-PM.jpg?resize=300,213 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-08-at-12.28.04-PM.jpg?resize=768,545 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-08-at-12.28.04-PM.jpg?resize=680,483 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-08-at-12.28.04-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1091 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-08-at-12.28.04-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1454 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-08-at-12.28.04-PM.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2122364" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> screenshot of Apple Podcasts</p></div></p>
<p>The site will be updated monthly to feature new and popular shows and to introduce timely collections around historical and cultural moments, like Women&#8217;s History Month or Back to School ideas, Apple says.</p>
<p>The company also notes the selection of shows is curated using the same sort of research-backed approach that Common Sense Media applies to other entertainment, like TV shows, movies, books, apps and games.</p>
<p>The launch follows <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/03/04/apple-launches-apple-for-kids-support-page/">Apple&#8217;s recent debut of an &#8220;Apple for Kids&#8221; website</a> that helps parents set up devices for kids and learn about Family Sharing options, highlighting an increased interest in catering to the needs of families.</p>
<p>But unlike with kids&#8217; use of Apple devices, the current market for kids&#8217; podcasts is small &#8212; none of Apple&#8217;s top 100 podcasts are directed toward kids, for example.</p>
<p>However, industry experts believe the kids market may grow alongside the overall adult podcast market. Plus, as <a href="https://morningconsult.com/2020/11/10/podcasts-kids-parents-polling/">Morning Consult recently reported</a>, the COVID-19 pandemic has helped drive new interest in the audio format as parents struggled to keep kids entertained at home.</p>
<p>Case in point: one leading kids&#8217; podcast, &#8220;Wow in the World&#8221; by NPR, saw a 94% increase in downloads in the 13 weeks post-COVID compared with pre-COVID, the report said.</p>
<p>In another recent analysis, <a href="https://www.nationalpublicmedia.com/insights/reports/the-spoken-word-audio-report/">NPR&#8217;s 2020 Spoken Word Audio Report</a> found that 15% of U.S. adults were now listening to children&#8217;s spoken word audio &#8212; an indication that many parents were already co-listening with kids. In addition, research from <a href="https://www.kidslisten.org/">Kids Listen</a>, a nonprofit advocacy group for kids&#8217; podcasts, found that 89% of kids who listen to podcasts are ages 8 or under, <a href="https://morningconsult.com/2020/11/10/podcasts-kids-parents-polling/">Morning Consult pointed out.</a></p>
<p>Apple, it&#8217;s worth noting, has been rumored to be considering a new podcast subscription service to challenge Spotify, <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/apple-plans-podcasting-subscription-service-in-threat-to-spotify">The Information reported year earlier this year.</a> In the weeks since that report, Apple has seemingly begun to pay more attention to the format, having <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/apples-new-editorial-franchise-apple-podcasts-spotlight-to-highlight-interesting-creators/">launched a new editorial franchise, Apple Podcasts Spotlight,</a> to highlight interesting creators.</p>
<p>Adding kids&#8217; programing could play into Apple&#8217;s future ambitions, perhaps, as 64% of parents who listen to podcasts said they&#8217;re likely to purchase a paid subscription to podcasts for their kids.</p>
<p>The new collection is live in the U.S. in Apple Podcasts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qJtFDakAWh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/more-thoughts-on-growing-podcasts/">More thoughts on growing podcasts</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;More thoughts on growing podcasts&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/more-thoughts-on-growing-podcasts/embed/#?secret=qJtFDakAWh" data-secret="qJtFDakAWh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/apple-teams-with-common-sense-media-to-curate-podcasts-for-kids/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122324</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Europe&#8217;s Android &#8216;choice&#8217; screen keeps burying better options</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/europes-android-choice-screen-keeps-burying-better-options/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/europes-android-choice-screen-keeps-burying-better-options/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android choice screen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Margrethe Vestager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been over a year since Google begun auctioning slots for a search engine &#8216;choice&#8217; screen on Android in Europe, following a major antitrust intervention by the European Commission back in 2018. But despite hitting Google with a record-breaking fine over two years ago almost nothing has changed. The tech giant&#8217;s search marketshare remains undented [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s been over a year since Google begun <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/02/google-to-auction-slots-on-android-default-search-choice-screen-in-europe-next-year-rivals-cry-pay-to-play-foul/">auctioning slots</a> for a search engine &#8216;choice&#8217; screen on Android in Europe, following a major antitrust intervention by the European Commission back in 2018. But despite hitting Google with a record-breaking fine over two years ago almost nothing has changed.</p>
<p>The tech giant&#8217;s search marketshare remains undented and the most interesting regional search alternatives are being priced out of a Google-devised &#8216;remedy&#8217; that favors those who can pay the most to be listed as an alternative to its own dominant search engine on smartphones running Google&#8217;s Android OS.</p>
<p>Quarterly choice screen winners have been getting increasingly same-y. Alternatives to Google are expecting another uninspiring batch of &#8216;winners&#8217; to drop in short order.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The <a href="https://www.android.com/choicescreen-winners/">results for Q1 2021</a> were dominated by a bunch of ad-targeting search options few smartphone users would likely have heard of: Germany&#8217;s GMX; California-based info.com; and Puerto Rico-based PrivacyWall (which is owned by a company whose <a href="https://socialgamemedia.com/#services">website</a> is emblazoned with the slogan &#8220;100% programmatic advertising&#8221;) &#8212; plus another, more familiar (ad)tech giant&#8217;s search engine (Microsoft-owned) Bing.</p>
<p>Lower down the list: The Russian &#8216;Google&#8217; &#8212; Yandex &#8212; which won eight slots. And a veteran player in the Czech search market, Seznam.cz, which bagged two.</p>
<p>On the &#8216;big loser&#8217; side: Non-tracking search engine, DuckDuckGo &#8212; which has been standing up for online privacy for over a decade yet won only one slot (in Belgium). It&#8217;s been come to be almost entirely squeezed out vs<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/10/duckduckgo-still-critical-of-googles-eu-android-choice-screen-auction-after-wining-a-universal-slot/"> winning a universal slot in all markets</a> at the start of the auction process.</p>
<p>Tree-planting not-for-profit search engine, <a href="https://www.ecosia.org/?c=en">Ecosia</a>, was almost entirely absent in the last round too: Gaining only one slot on the screen showed to Android users in Slovenia. Yet back in December Ecosia was added as a default search option with Safari on iOS, iPadOS and macOS &#8212; having grown its global usage to more than 15 million users.</p>
<p>While another homegrown European search option &#8212; which has a privacy-focus &#8212; France&#8217;s Qwant, went home with just one slot. And not in its home market, either (in tiny Luxembourg).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ywqLGhTRZN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/googles-eu-android-choice-screen-isnt-working-say-search-rivals-calling-for-a-joint-process-to-devise-a-fair-remedy/">Google&#8217;s EU Android choice screen isn&#8217;t working say search rivals, calling for a joint process to devise a fair remedy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google&#8217;s EU Android choice screen isn&#8217;t working say search rivals, calling for a joint process to devise a fair remedy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/googles-eu-android-choice-screen-isnt-working-say-search-rivals-calling-for-a-joint-process-to-devise-a-fair-remedy/embed/#?secret=ywqLGhTRZN" data-secret="ywqLGhTRZN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>If Europe&#8217;s regulators had fondly imagined that a Google-devised &#8216;remedy&#8217; for major antitrust breaches they identified would automagically restore thriving competition to the Android search market they should feel rudely awakened indeed. The bald fact is Google&#8217;s marketshare has not even been scratched, let alone dented.</p>
<p>Statista data for Google&#8217;s search market share on mobile (across both Android and iOS; the latter where the tech giant pays Apple billions of dollars annually to be set as the default on iPhones) shows that in February 2021 its share in Europe stood at 97.07% &#8212; up from 96.92% in July 2018 when the Commission made the antitrust ruling.</p>
<p>Yes, Google has actually <em>gained</em> share running this &#8216;remedy&#8217;.</p>
<p>By any measure that&#8217;s a spectacular failure for EU competition enforcement &#8212; more than 2.5 years after its headline grabbing antitrust decision against Android.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9e2GUNi1yk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/18/google-gets-slapped-5bn-by-eu-for-android-antitrust-abuse/">Google gets slapped with $5BN EU fine for Android antitrust abuse</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google gets slapped with $5BN EU fine for Android antitrust abuse&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/18/google-gets-slapped-5bn-by-eu-for-android-antitrust-abuse/embed/#?secret=9e2GUNi1yk" data-secret="9e2GUNi1yk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The Commission has also been promoting a goal of European tech sovereignty throughout the period Google has been running this auction. President Ursula von der Leyen links this overrarching goal to her digital policy programming.</p>
<p>On the measure of tech sovereignty the Android choice screen must be seen as a sizeable failure too &#8212; as it&#8217;s not only failed to support (most) homegrown alternatives to Google (another, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/01/cliqz-pulls-the-plug-on-a-european-anti-tracking-alternative-to-google-search/">Cliqz, pulled the plug on its search+browser effort entirely last year</a>, putting part of the blame on the region&#8217;s political stakeholders for failing to understand the need for Europe to own its own digital infrastructure) &#8212; but it&#8217;s actively burying the most interesting European alternatives by forcing them to compete against a bunch of ad-funded Google clones.</p>
<p>(And if Brave Search takes off it&#8217;ll be another non-European alternative &#8212; albeit, one that will have benefitted from expertise and tech that was made-in-Europe&#8230; )</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E4nLE3s8bh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/brave-is-launching-its-own-search-engine-with-the-help-of-ex-cliqz-devs-and-tech/">Brave is launching its own search engine with the help of ex-Cliqz devs and tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Brave is launching its own search engine with the help of ex-Cliqz devs and tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/brave-is-launching-its-own-search-engine-with-the-help-of-ex-cliqz-devs-and-tech/embed/#?secret=E4nLE3s8bh" data-secret="E4nLE3s8bh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This is because the auction mechanism means only companies that pay Google the most can buy themselves a chance at being set as a default option on Android.</p>
<p>Even in the rare instances where European players shell out enough money to appear in the choice list (which likely means they&#8217;ll be losing money per search click) they most often do so alongside other non-European alternatives <em>and Google</em> &#8212; further raising the competitive bar for selection.</p>
<p>It doesn&#8217;t have to be this way. Nor was it wasn&#8217;t initially; Google started with a choice screen based on marketshare.</p>
<p>However it very quickly switched to a pay to play model &#8212; throttling at a stroke the discoverability of alternative business models that aren&#8217;t based on exploiting user data (or, indeed, aren&#8217;t profit-driven in Ecosia&#8217;s case; as it uses ad-generated revenue to fund tree planting with a purely environmental goal).</p>
<p>Such alternatives say they typically can&#8217;t afford to win Google&#8217;s choice screen auctions. (It&#8217;s worth noting that those who do participate in the game are restricted in what they can say as Google requires they sign an NDA.)</p>
<p>Clearly, it&#8217;s no coincidence that the winners of Google&#8217;s auction skew almost entirely to the track and target side of the tracks, where its own business sits; all data-exploiting business models bandied together. And then, from a consumer point of view, why would you <em>not</em> pick Google with such a poorly and artificially limited &#8216;choice&#8217; on offer &#8212; since you&#8217;re generally only being offered weaker versions of the same thing?</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Ecosia tells TechCrunch it&#8217;s now considering pulling out of the auction process altogether &#8212; which would be a return to its first instinct; which was to boycott the auction before saying it felt it had to participate. </span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">A few months playing Google&#8217;s pay-to-play &#8216;no choice&#8217; (as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/googles-no-choice-screen-on-android-isnt-working-says-ecosia-querying-the-eus-approach-to-antitrust-enforcement/">Ecosia dubs the auction</a>) game has cemented its view that the system is stacked against genuine alternatives.  </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="M7jV0LDio6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/googles-no-choice-screen-on-android-isnt-working-says-ecosia-querying-the-eus-approach-to-antitrust-enforcement/">Google&#8217;s &#8216;no choice&#8217; screen on Android isn&#8217;t working, says Ecosia &#8212; querying the EU&#8217;s approach to antitrust enforcement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google&#8217;s &#8216;no choice&#8217; screen on Android isn&#8217;t working, says Ecosia &#8212; querying the EU&#8217;s approach to antitrust enforcement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/googles-no-choice-screen-on-android-isnt-working-says-ecosia-querying-the-eus-approach-to-antitrust-enforcement/embed/#?secret=M7jV0LDio6" data-secret="M7jV0LDio6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span class="il">Over two auction rounds when Ecosia has only ended up winning the one slot each time it says it&#8217;s</span> seen no positive effect on user numbers. A decision on whether or not to withdraw entirely will be taken after the results of the next auction process are revealed, it said. (The next round of results are expected shortly, in early March.)</p>
<p>&#8220;We definitely realized it&#8217;s less and less &#8216;fun&#8217; to play the game,&#8221; Ecosia founder Christian Kroll told us. &#8220;It&#8217;s a super unfair game &#8212; where it&#8217;s not only &#8216;David against Goliath&#8217; but also Goliath gets to choose the rules, gets a free ticket, he can change the rules of game if he likes to. So it&#8217;s not amusing for us to participate in that.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve been participating now for nine months and if you look at overall marketshare in Europe nothing has changed. We don&#8217;t know the results yet of this round but I assume also nothing will change &#8212; the usual suspects will be there again&#8230; Most of the options that you see there now are not interesting to users.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Calling it a &#8216;choice&#8217; screen is still a little bit ironic if you remove all the interesting choices from the screen. So the situation is still the same and it becomes less and less fun to play the game and at some point I think we might make the decision that we&#8217;re not going to be part of the game anymore,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Other alternative search engines we spoke to are continuing to participate for now &#8212; but all were critical of Google&#8217;s &#8216;pay-to-play&#8217; model for the Android &#8216;choice screen&#8217;.</p>
<p>DuckDuckGo founder, Gabriel Weinberg, told us: &#8220;We are bidding, but only to help further expose to the European Commission how flawed Google&#8217;s rigged process really is, in hopes they will help more actively take a role in reforming it into something that actually works for consumers. Due to our strict privacy policy, we expect to be eliminated, same as last time.&#8221;</p>
<p>He pointed to a <a href="https://spreadprivacy.com/search-preference-menu-duckduckgo-elimination/">blog post</a> the company put out last fall, denouncing the &#8220;fundamentally flawed&#8221; auction model &#8212; and saying that &#8220;whole piece still stands&#8221;. In the blog post the company wrote that despite being profitable since 2014 &#8220;we <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">have been priced out of this auction because we choose to not maximize our profits by exploiting our users&#8221;. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;In practical terms, this means our commitment to privacy and a cleaner search experience translates into less money per search. This means we must bid less relative to other, profit-maximizing companies,&#8221; DuckDuckGo went on, adding: &#8220;</span>This EU antitrust remedy is only serving to further strengthen Google’s dominance in mobile search by boxing out alternative search engines that consumers want to use and, for those search engines that remain, taking most of their profits from the preference menu.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;This auction format incentivizes bidders to bid what they can expect to profit per user selection. The long-term result is that the participating Google alternatives must give most of their preference menu profits to Google! Google’s auction further incentivizes search engines to be worse on privacy, to increase ads, and to not donate to good causes, because, if they do those things, then they could afford to bid higher,&#8221; it also said then.</p>
<p>France&#8217;s Qwant has been similarly critical and it told us it is &#8220;extremely dissatisfied&#8221; with the auction &#8212; calling for &#8220;urgent modification&#8221; and saying the 2018 Commissio decision should be fully respected &#8220;in text and in spirit&#8221;.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;We are extremely dissatisfied with the auction system. We are asking for an urgent modification of the Choice Screen to allow consumers to find the search engine they want to use and not just the three choices that are only the ones that pay the most Google. We demand full respect for the 2018 decision, in text and in spirit,&#8221; said CEO Jean-Claude Ghinozzi.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;We are reviewing all options and re-evaluating our decision on a quarterly basis. In any case, we want consumers to be able to freely choose the search engine they prefer, without being limited to the only three alternative choices sold by Google. Consumers&#8217; interests must always come first,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Russia&#8217;s Yandex confirmed it has participated in the upcoming Q2 auction. But it was also critical of Google&#8217;s implementation, saying it falls short of offering a genuine &#8220;freedom of choice&#8221; to Android users.</p>
<div>
<div>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;We aim to offer high-quality and convenient search engine around the world. We are confident that freedom to select a search engine will lead to greater market competition and motivate each player to improve services. We don’t think that the current EU solution fully ensures freedom of choice for users, by only covering devices released from March 2020,&#8221; a Yandex spokeswoman said.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;There are currently very few such devices on the EU market in comparison with the total number of devices in users&#8217; hands. It is essential to provide the freedom of choice that is genuine and real. Competition among service providers ultimately benefits users who will receive a better product.&#8221;</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>One newcomer to the search space &#8212; the anti-tracking browser Brave (which, as we mentioned above, just bought up some Cliqz assets to underpin the forthcoming launch of an-own brand Brave Search) &#8212; confirmed it will not be joining in at all.</p>
<p>&#8220;Brave does not plan to participate in this auction. Brave is about putting the user first, and this bidding process ignores users&#8217; best interests by limiting their choices and selecting only for highest Google Play Store optimizing bidders,&#8221; a spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&#8220;An irony here is that Google gets to profit off its own remedy for being found guilty of anti-competitive tying of Chrome into Android,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>Asked about its strategy to grow usage of Brave Search in the region &#8212; outside of participation in the Android choice screen &#8212; she said: &#8220;Brave already has localized browsers for the European market, and we will continue to grow by offering best-in-class privacy showcased in marketing campaigns and referrals programs.&#8221;</p>
<p>Google&#8217;s self-devised &#8216;remedy&#8217; followed a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/18/google-gets-slapped-5bn-by-eu-for-android-antitrust-abuse/">2018 antitrust decision by the Commission</a> &#8212; which led to a record-breaking $5BN penalty and an order to cease a variety of infringing behaviors. The tech giant&#8217;s implementation remains under active monitoring by EU antitrust regulators. However Kroll argues the Commission is essentially just letting Google buy time rather than fix the abusive behavior it identified.</p>
<p>&#8220;The way I see this at the moment is the Commission feels like the auction screen isn&#8217;t necessarily something that they&#8217;ve requested as a remedy so they can&#8217;t really force Google to change it &#8212; and that&#8217;s why they also maybe don&#8217;t see it as their responsibility,&#8221; he said. &#8220;But at the same time they requested Google to solve the situation and Google isn&#8217;t doing anything.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think they are also allowing Google to get the credit from the press and also from users that it seems like Google is doing something &#8212; so they are allowing Google to play on time&#8230; I don&#8217;t know if a real choice screen would be a good solution but it&#8217;s also not for me to decide &#8212; it&#8217;s up to the European Commission to decide if Google has successfully remedied the damage&#8230; and has also compensated some of the damage that it&#8217;s done and I think that has not happened at all. We can see that in the [marketshare] numbers that basically still the same situation is happening.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The whole thing is designed to remove interesting options from the screen,&#8221; he also argued of Google&#8217;s current &#8216;remedy&#8217;. &#8220;This is how it&#8217;s &#8216;working&#8217; and I&#8217;m of course disappointed that nobody is stepping in there. So we&#8217;re basically in this unfair game where we get beaten up by our competitors. And I would hope for some regulator to step in and say this is not how this should go. But this isn&#8217;t happening.</p>
<p>&#8220;At the moment our only choice is to hang in there but at the moment if we really see there is no effect and there&#8217;s also no chance that regulators will ever step in we still have the choice to completely withdraw and let Google have its fun but without us&#8230; We&#8217;re not only not getting anything out of the [current auction model] but we&#8217;re of course also investing into it. And there are also restrictions because of the NDA we&#8217;ve signed &#8212; and even those restrictions are a little bit of a pain. So we have all the negative effects and don&#8217;t get any benefits.&#8221;</p>
<p>While limited by NDA in what he can discuss about the costs involved with participating in the auction, Kroll suggested the winners are doing so at a loss &#8212; pursuing reach at the expense of revenue.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you look at the bids from the last rounds I think with those bids it would be difficult for us to make money &#8212; and so potentially others have lost money. And that&#8217;s exactly also how this auction is designed, or how most auctions are designed, is that the winners often lose money&#8230; so you have this winner&#8217;s curse where people overbid,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;This hasn&#8217;t happened to us &#8212; also because we&#8217;re super careful &#8212; and in the last round we won this wonderful slot in Slovenia. Which is a beautiful country but again it has no impact on our revenues and we didn&#8217;t expect that to happen. It&#8217;s just for us to basically participate in the game but not risk our financial health,&#8221; he added. &#8220;We know that our bids will likely not win so the financial risk [to Ecosia as it&#8217;s currently participating and mostly losing in the auction] is not that big but for the companies who actually win bids &#8212; for them it might be a different thing.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kroll points out that the auction model has allowed Google to continue harvesting marketshare while weakening its competitors.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are quite a few companies who can afford to lose money in search because they just need to build up marketshare &#8212; and Google is basically harvesting all that and at the same time weakening its competitors,&#8221; he argued. &#8220;Because competitors need to spend on this. And one element that &#8212; at least in the beginning when the auction started &#8212; that I didn&#8217;t even see was also that if you&#8217;re a real search company&#8230; then you&#8217;re building up a brand, you&#8217;re building up a product, you&#8217;re making all these investments and you have real users &#8212; and if you have those then, if there was really a choice screen, people would naturally choose you. But in this auction screen model you&#8217;re basically paying for users that you would have anyway.</p>
<p>&#8220;So it&#8217;s really putting those kind of companies at a disadvantage: DuckDuckGo, us, all kinds of companies who have a &#8216;real USP&#8217;. Also Lilo, potentially even Qwant as well if you have a more nationalist approach to search, basically. So all of those companies are put at an even bigger disadvantage. And that&#8217;s &#8212; I think &#8212; unfair.&#8221;</p>
<p>Since most winners of auction slots are, like Google, involved in surveillance capitalism &#8212; gathering data on search users to profit off of ad targeting &#8212; if anyone was banking on EU competition enforcement being able to act as a lever to crack open the dominant privacy-hostile business model of the web (and allow less abusive alternatives get a foot in the door) they must be sorely disappointed.</p>
<p>Better alternatives &#8212; that do not track consumers for ads; or, in the case of Ecosia, are on an entirely non-profit mission &#8212; are clearly being squeezed out.</p>
<p>The Commission can&#8217;t say it wasn&#8217;t warned: <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The moment the auction model was announced by Google <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/02/google-to-auction-slots-on-android-default-search-choice-screen-in-europe-next-year-rivals-cry-pay-to-play-foul/">rivals decried it</a> as flawed, rigged, unfair and unsustainable &#8212; warning it would put them at a </span>competitive disadvantage (exactly because they aren&#8217;t just cloning Google&#8217;s &#8216;track and target for ad profit model&#8217;).</p>
<p>Nonetheless, the Commission has so far shown itself unwilling or unable to respond &#8212; despite making a big show of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">proposing major new rules for the largest platforms</a> which it says are needed to ensure they play fair. But that raises the question of why it&#8217;s not better-enforcing existing EU rules against tech giants like Google?</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">When we raised criticism of Google&#8217;s Android choice screen auction model with the Commission</span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> it sent us its standard set of talking points &#8212; </span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">writing that: &#8220;</span><span lang="EN-IE" style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">We have seen in the past that a choice screen can be an effective way to promote user choice&#8221;.</span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-IE" style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;The choice screen means that additional search providers are presented to users on start-up of every new Android device in every EEA country. So users can now choose their search provider of preference when setting up their newly purchased Android devices,&#8221; it also said, adding that it is </span><span lang="EN-IE" style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;committed to a full and effective implementation of the decision&#8221;.</span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-IE" style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;We are therefore monitoring closely the implementation of the choice screen mechanism,&#8221; it added &#8212; a standard line since Google begin its &#8216;compliance&#8217; with the 2018 EU decision. </span></p>
<p>In a slight development, the Commission did also confirm it has had discussions with Google about the choice screen mechanism &#8212; <span lang="EN-IE">following what it described as &#8220;relevant feedback from the market&#8221;.  </span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-IE">It said these discussions focused on &#8220;the presentation and mechanics of the choice screen and to the selection mechanism of rival search providers&#8221;.</span></p>
<p>But with the clock ticking, and genuine alternatives to Google search being actively squeezed out of the market &#8212; leaving European consumers to be offered no meaningful choice to privacy-hostile search on Android &#8212; you do have to wonder what regulators are waiting for?</p>
<p>A pattern of reluctance to challenge tech giants where it counts seems to be emerging from Margrethe Vestager&#8217;s tenure at the helm of the competition department (and also, since 2019, a key shaper of EU digital policy).</p>
<p>Despite gaining a reputation for being willing to take on tech giants &#8212; and hitting Google (and others) with a number of headline-grabbing fines over the past five+ years &#8212; she cannot claim success in rebalancing the market for mobile search nor smartphone operating systems nor search ad brokering, in just the most recent Google cases.</p>
<p>Nonetheless she was content to green light Google&#8217;s acquisition of wearable maker Fitbit <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/europe-clears-google-fitbit-with-a-ten-year-ban-on-using-health-data-for-ads/">at the end of last year</a> &#8212; despite a multitude of voices raised against allowing the tech giant to further entrench its dominance.</p>
<p>On that she argued defensively that concessions secured from Google would be sufficient to address concerns (such as a promise extracted from Google not to  use Fitbit data for ads for at least ten years).</p>
<p>But, given her record on monitoring Google&#8217;s compliance with a whole flush of EU antitrust rulings, it&#8217;s hard to see why anyone other than Google should be confident in the Commission&#8217;s ability or willingness to enforce its own mandates against Google. Complaints against how Google operates, meanwhile, just <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/act-now-before-google-kills-us-135-strong-coalition-of-startups-warns-eu-antitrust-chief/">keep stacking up</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think they are listening,&#8221; says Kroll of the Commission. &#8220;But what I am missing is action.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ywqLGhTRZN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/googles-eu-android-choice-screen-isnt-working-say-search-rivals-calling-for-a-joint-process-to-devise-a-fair-remedy/">Google&#8217;s EU Android choice screen isn&#8217;t working say search rivals, calling for a joint process to devise a fair remedy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google&#8217;s EU Android choice screen isn&#8217;t working say search rivals, calling for a joint process to devise a fair remedy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/googles-eu-android-choice-screen-isnt-working-say-search-rivals-calling-for-a-joint-process-to-devise-a-fair-remedy/embed/#?secret=ywqLGhTRZN" data-secret="ywqLGhTRZN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rDgZDLHB6Q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/14/travel-startups-cry-foul-over-what-googles-doing-with-their-data/">Travel startups cry foul over what Google&#8217;s doing with their data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Travel startups cry foul over what Google&#8217;s doing with their data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/14/travel-startups-cry-foul-over-what-googles-doing-with-their-data/embed/#?secret=rDgZDLHB6Q" data-secret="rDgZDLHB6Q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IuTn54b3TY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/act-now-before-google-kills-us-135-strong-coalition-of-startups-warns-eu-antitrust-chief/">Act now before Google kills us, 135-strong coalition of startups warns EU antitrust chief</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Act now before Google kills us, 135-strong coalition of startups warns EU antitrust chief&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/act-now-before-google-kills-us-135-strong-coalition-of-startups-warns-eu-antitrust-chief/embed/#?secret=IuTn54b3TY" data-secret="IuTn54b3TY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/europes-android-choice-screen-keeps-burying-better-options/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121515</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>While eyeing a SPAC, Swedish autonomous EV company Einride nears $75 million in new funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/while-eyeing-a-spac-swedish-autonomous-ev-company-einride-nears-75-million-in-new-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/while-eyeing-a-spac-swedish-autonomous-ev-company-einride-nears-75-million-in-new-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 17:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Swedish autonomous electric vehicle startup Einride is aiming to continue the momentum sparked by partnerships with Oatly and Lidl by seeking additional capital, TechCrunch has learned.  Einride is seeking $75 million in new financing, while at the same time exploring the potential for a public listing through a special purpose acquisition company, according to people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Swedish autonomous electric vehicle startup <a class="c-link" href="https://www.einride.tech/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://www.einride.tech/" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Einride</a> is aiming to continue the momentum sparked by partnerships with Oatly and Lidl by seeking additional capital, TechCrunch has learned.<span class="c-message__edited_label" dir="ltr" data-sk="tooltip_parent" aria-describedby="sk-tooltip-1917"> </span></p>
<p>Einride is seeking $75 million in new financing, while at the same time exploring the potential for a public listing through a special purpose acquisition company, according to people with knowledge of the company&#8217;s plans.</p>
<p>SPACs, a mechanism in which a publicly traded shell company merges with a private business, have taken the U.S. capital markets by storm led, in part, by startups focused on the electrification of mobility.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Early successes of public listings for companies like Nikola (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/nikolas-stock-crashes-after-announcing-cancelation-of-contract-with-republic-services-for-2500-garbage-trucks/">despite its dubious claims</a>) helped set the stage for the SPAC boom. Canoo, Fisker Inc, ChargePoint and Lordstown Motors are just a few of the U.S.-based EV companies that have gone public via a SPAC in the past year.</p>
<p>Unlike some newly minted SPAC companies, Einride has some fundamentals. The company has already piloted its technology <a href="https://www.einride.tech/press/oatly-reduces-carbon-footprint-first-month-einride-electric-trucks">through a partnership with Oatly</a>, the Swedish oat milk maker.</p>
<p>Oatly began using Einride’s electric trucks on its delivery routes from each of its Swedish production sites in October 2020. Thus far, the trucks have driven over 8,600 km electric and as a result have saved over 10,500 kg of CO2 compared to diesel, according to a statement from the companies.</p>
<p>“Sustainability is at the core of everything we do, and we work hard to lower our emissions across the board. This includes our emissions for transports, which is why we are now shifting to electrical vehicles, which reduces our climate footprint by 87% on these routes,” said Simon Broadbent, supply chain director at Oatly, in a statement at the time.</p>
<p>The deal with Oatly was just the beginning. As the ink dried on that partnership, Einride quickly signed other marquee Swedish businesses including the food shipping and logistics company Lidl and the electronics manufacturer Electrolux.</p>
<p>Big automakers have electric and autonomous plans of their own. Argo, a developer of self-driving technology, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/self-driving-startup-argo-ai-hits-7-5-billion-valuation/">is now worth $7.5 billion</a> thanks to an investment from Ford and the VW Group. And VW&#8217;s Traton Group is pushing low emission and electrification through a $2.2 billion investment <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-10-02/traton-to-pour-2-2-billion-into-electric-trucks-software">announced in 2019</a>.</p>
<p>Daimler, Paccar, and Volvo<a href="https://medium.datadriveninvestor.com/18-companies-and-startups-that-are-leading-the-race-for-the-autonomous-trucks-4ba5a50e6dee"> all have plans</a> as well.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NngBcuMkwS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/self-driving-startup-argo-ai-hits-7-5-billion-valuation/">Self-driving startup Argo AI hits $7.5 billion valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Self-driving startup Argo AI hits $7.5 billion valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/self-driving-startup-argo-ai-hits-7-5-billion-valuation/embed/#?secret=NngBcuMkwS" data-secret="NngBcuMkwS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That&#8217;s just scratching the surface of the money that&#8217;s pouring in to autonomous, electrified transport. Of course, <a href="https://www.tesla.com/semi">Tesla is in the game with its own semi truck</a> and, in China, Plus AI, is automating a number of vehicles from Manbang, Suning and FAW Jiefang.</p>
<p id="bc9a" class="is it ez iu b fy iv iw ix gb iy iz ja jb jc jd je jf jg jh ji jj jk jl jm jn dm fw" data-selectable-paragraph="">All of this money is aiming to capture a portion of the market for autonomous, electrified vehicles that the consulting firm McKinsey estimated would save the trucking industry over $100 billion. It&#8217;s a potentially huge opportunity in the $260 billion U.S. trucking market alone. Worldwide, businesses spend about $1.2 trillion on trucking, <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/travel-logistics-and-infrastructure/our-insights/distraction-or-disruption-autonomous-trucks-gain-ground-in-us-logistics">according to McKinsey</a>.</p>
<p data-selectable-paragraph="">The benefits that would accrue to the industry are more than just financial. Trucking is a huge component of the greenhouse gas emissions that come from the transportation sector &#8212; which includes road, rail, air and marine transportation. In 2016, trucking and transport broadly contributed to roughly 24% of the world&#8217;s total greenhouse gas emissions &#8212; and that number has been steadily increasing.</p>
<p>Any reduction in carbon emissions from the transport sector would be a huge step forward on the path toward a more environmentally sustainable future.</p>
<p data-selectable-paragraph="">No wonder venture investors are falling all over each other to invest in these companies. Einride counts EQT Ventures and NordicNinja VC, a fund backed by Panasonic, Honda, Omron and the Japan Bank for International Cooperation, among its investors. Along with backing from Ericsson Ventures, Norrsken Foundation, Plum Alley Investments and Plug and Play Ventures the startup has raised $32 million to date.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6I59t98aGq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/from-electric-charging-to-supply-chain-management-inmotion-ventures-preps-jaguar-for-a-sustainable-future/">From electric charging to supply chain management, InMotion Ventures preps Jaguar for a sustainable future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;From electric charging to supply chain management, InMotion Ventures preps Jaguar for a sustainable future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/from-electric-charging-to-supply-chain-management-inmotion-ventures-preps-jaguar-for-a-sustainable-future/embed/#?secret=6I59t98aGq" data-secret="6I59t98aGq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="48JKVLWNtx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/autonomous-trucking-startup-einride-eyes-u-s-market-with-25-million-in-new-funding/">Autonomous trucking startup Einride eyes US market with $25 million in new funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Autonomous trucking startup Einride eyes US market with $25 million in new funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/autonomous-trucking-startup-einride-eyes-u-s-market-with-25-million-in-new-funding/embed/#?secret=48JKVLWNtx" data-secret="48JKVLWNtx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/while-eyeing-a-spac-swedish-autonomous-ev-company-einride-nears-75-million-in-new-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122231</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Makers of &#8216;kid&#8217;s first virtual world&#8217; Animal Jam targets Gen Z teens with Fer.al debut</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/makers-of-kids-first-virtual-world-animal-jam-targets-gen-z-teens-with-fer-al-debut/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/makers-of-kids-first-virtual-world-animal-jam-targets-gen-z-teens-with-fer-al-debut/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 16:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gen z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual worlds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WildWorks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Before kids graduate to the expansive virtual worlds in games like Roblox, Minecraft and Fortnite, they often get their start in online social gaming with a game like Animal Jam. Here, kids learn to personalize their avatar, explore a world, chat with other players and trade items in a safe environment with parental controls. Today, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Before kids graduate to the expansive virtual worlds in games like Roblox, Minecraft and Fortnite, they often get their start in online social gaming with a game like <a href="https://www.animaljam.com/en">Animal Jam</a>. Here, kids learn to personalize their avatar, explore a world, chat with other players and trade items in a safe environment with parental controls. Today, the company behind this popular title, WildWorks, is launching a new game, <a href="https://fer.al/en">Fer.al</a>, which builds on Animal Jam&#8217;s legacy while catering to a slightly older crowd of Gen Z teens.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we started talking about Fer.al, it was the idea of where do kids go when they age out of Animal Jam?,&#8221; explains Clark Stacey, co-founder and CEO of WildWorks. &#8220;Because there isn&#8217;t a transitional space between a completely walled garden like Animal Jam and … Instagram and the adult social networks and games that don&#8217;t have those same protections,&#8221; he continues.</p>
<p>&#8220;We knew we wanted to provide a place for these older kids to go where the walls are a little bit lower,&#8221; Stacey adds.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The new game is meant to cater to older kids &#8212; meaning young teens ages 13 to around 18 &#8212; who are now choosing their own games, have their own email address and don&#8217;t need parental permission to play. The guardrails on chat also won&#8217;t be as high on Fer.al as on Animal Jam and will focus more on preventing bullying and abuse than blocking words. Players will also be able to connect their online social accounts to their game accounts in the future.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2122288" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122288" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2122288" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Creature_Customize.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Creature_Customize.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Creature_Customize.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Creature_Customize.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Creature_Customize.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Creature_Customize.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Creature_Customize.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Creature_Customize.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2122288" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> WildWorks</p></div></p>
<p>With <a href="https://fer.al/en">Fer.al</a>, WildWorks is introducing another animal-centered title, but this time it&#8217;s moving into the fantasy realm. Players choose between bipedal humanoid creatures based on folklore and myth including a Kitsune, Senri, Dragon, Jackelope, Werewolf, Kirin or a Shinigami, with more to come in time.</p>
<p>The characters&#8217; style was inspired by Animal Jam fan art, Stacey says, where kids would create animal avatars that were sort of a mix between manga, Animal Jam&#8217;s style, and other, older animation styles.</p>
<p>Like its predecessor, Fer.al players will also be able to personalize their character and change their appearance, design their personal space (this time, a &#8220;sanctuary&#8221; instead of a &#8220;den,&#8221;) discover a world where they can interact with other players, collect items and trade, and venture on quests. But the storyline has also evolved to reflect teens&#8217; interests, including their growing understanding of social media and the desire to grow an online fan base.</p>
<p>The larger narrative involves a reality show where two warring queens, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/aradiafellqueen/?hl=en">Aradia</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/delilahlichqueen/?hl=en">Delilah</a> &#8212; each with their own Instagram account, naturally &#8212; are angling for control. The company isn&#8217;t offering a lot of details as to how this narrative plays out in the long term, but it will involve weekly and monthly contests as the game ramps up, in addition to the everyday missions and quests that are undertaken to gain ingredients to create new clothes or a new &#8220;glamour&#8221; (a rendering effect that goes around your character.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2122287" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122287" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2122287" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Roleplaying.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Roleplaying.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Roleplaying.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Roleplaying.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Roleplaying.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Roleplaying.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Roleplaying.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Roleplaying.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2122287" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> WildWorks</p></div></p>
<p>Much like Animal Jam &#8212; or even other virtual worlds like some Roblox games &#8212; players are meant to engage in cooperative gameplay to advance. There will be tasks you can&#8217;t complete on your own, meaning you&#8217;ll need to interact and chat. You will also be able to join factions, initially driven by the two queens, as the game advances.</p>
<p>Another notable aspect to Fer.al is that it&#8217;s largely designed to cater to girl gamers.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s certainly not intended to be to the exclusion of boys who are in this age range,&#8221; explains Stacey. &#8220;But we recognize the fact that, among the most engaged Animal Jam players, it&#8217;s about 80% girls. We&#8217;ve leaned into that pretty heavily in Animal Jam &#8212; we&#8217;re trying to feature a lot of female scientists and working with them on causes that promote girls in STEM. So we know a lot of the built-in audience is coming from that,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>&#8220;And I think the need that we recognized is that it&#8217;s not hard for adolescent boys to find online communities that jive with them. It&#8217;s pretty hard for girls to find the same thing. So, as we&#8217;re creating this community &#8212; everything from the rules to the visuals &#8212; we are very conscious of that. And the people that we&#8217;re going to and asking for what works for you and what doesn&#8217;t, is primarily girls,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2122285" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122285" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2122285" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Craft_Trade.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Craft_Trade.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Craft_Trade.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Craft_Trade.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Craft_Trade.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Craft_Trade.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Craft_Trade.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_Craft_Trade.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2122285" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> WildWorks</p></div></p>
<p>Building off the Animal Jam fan base has been an advantage for getting Fer.al off the ground. Today, Animal Jam has anywhere between 2.5 million to 4 million monthly active users out of a total of 135 million registered accounts. The gulf between the registered and active figures is indicative of how many kids have grown out of Animal Jam since its October 2010 launch. But Stacey admits the title has seen some decline since its peak usage, as well.</p>
<p>Still, there&#8217;s a lot of interest in what WildWorks does next, it seems.</p>
<p>Within a week of launching the Fer.al website, the game had 75,000 kids sign up to become beta testers. The testers were brought into the beta slowly, starting in April 2020, and initially on desktop only. Now, the beta version of the game sees daily actives in the low 10,000&#8217;s pre-launch. On the Apple App Store and Google Play, over 100,000 people have registered for the pre-release, as well.</p>
<p>Like Animal Jam, Fer.al will offer a freemium experience. But while Animal Jam generated nearly 80% of revenues through subscriptions, Fer.al will use a season pass model of monetization. Users buy the season &#8212; priced around $10 to $20 &#8212; via an in-app purchase, which will unlock unique items and experiences specific to that season. It expects to launch around seven seasons per year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2122289" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122289" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2122289" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_SanctuaryDesign.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_SanctuaryDesign.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_SanctuaryDesign.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_SanctuaryDesign.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_SanctuaryDesign.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_SanctuaryDesign.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_SanctuaryDesign.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Feral_SanctuaryDesign.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2122289" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> WildWorks</p></div></p>
<p>The company didn&#8217;t offer seasons until later in the beta test, but Stacey says the conversion rate was at &#8220;the high end of our expectations so far on desktop.&#8221; If the mobile conversion rates remain as high as desktop, it will be in the range to start investing in user acquisition, he says. The company may also consider ads at a later date as well as merchandise, if all goes well.</p>
<p>Salt Lake City-headquartered WildWorks (formerly Smart Bomb Interactive) is majority owned by Signal Peak Ventures, which has invested $20+ million into the company over the years. The company shifted in 2008 to focus on its own IP, resulting in the launch of Animal Jam and other titles.</p>
<p>Over the past few years, WildWorks&#8217; revenue &#8212; largely from Animal Jam and another game, Tag with Ryan &#8212; has ranged between $20+ million to below $30 million. If Fer.al is able to successfully capture the Animal Jam graduates who are looking to move up to &#8220;older kid&#8221; gameplay, it could grow that revenue base by a sizable amount.</p>
<p>Fer.al is launching publicly today in all countries and will be available initially in English. It can be played on PC, Mac, iOS and Android.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear firsthand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product-market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built in — there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/makers-of-kids-first-virtual-world-animal-jam-targets-gen-z-teens-with-fer-al-debut/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122245</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A glimpse inside the minds of tech&#8217;s DEI leaders</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/a-glimpse-inside-the-minds-of-techs-dei-leaders/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/a-glimpse-inside-the-minds-of-techs-dei-leaders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 16:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bo Young Lee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sandra Altine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCJUSTICE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wade Davis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Diversity and inclusion as an idea has been on the agenda of tech companies for years now. But the industry still lacks true inclusion, despite best efforts put forth by heads of diversity, equity and inclusion at these companies. At TC Sessions: Justice, I spoke with Uber Chief Diversity Officer Bo Young Lee and Netflix [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Diversity and inclusion as an idea has been on the agenda of tech companies for years now. But the industry still lacks true inclusion, despite best efforts put forth by heads of diversity, equity and inclusion at these companies.</p>
<p>At TC Sessions: Justice, I spoke with Uber Chief Diversity Officer Bo Young Lee and Netflix VP of Inclusion Strategy for Product Wade Davis about the work that still needs to be done, the effects of California&#8217;s Proposition 22 and more.</p>
<hr />
<h3>On last summer&#8217;s racial justice uprising</h3>
<p>Last summer, after the murder of George Floyd and the subsequent collective consciousness around racial injustice in the U.S., many tech companies spoke out about racism and equality. Davis said he was happy to see more people speaking about those issues but also a bit frustrated that &#8220;it takes something like that for folks to get truly engaged.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p><strong>Davis: </strong>And inside of Netflix, one of the things that I was really intentional about is to tell our employees who are not Black, right, to not ask our employees how they feel but for them to be much more introspective of what it felt like for them, right, as a white person, or however they identify for them to do the introspection. Because that&#8217;s what it means to be an ally &#8212; to not put the labor on the group that is already feeling the impact and the oppression. And what we found was that many of our employees, for the first time had to wrestle with like, what it means to be white. What it means to be in a situation where you are seeing someone who looks like you take the life of someone who looks like me. So we really tried to switch the actual narrative and the conversation to not add more labor and trauma on our Black employees. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 1:10)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Lee said she was a bit skeptical at the time because we&#8217;ve seen this type of response before in light of the violent killings of Black people.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Lee: </strong>And then within a few weeks you see that interest and that focus wane once more. So I was skeptical that the enthusiasm would continue and enthusiasm in a way to try to solve all of our racism problems in a short period of time. I was surprised that it did continue. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 3:31)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>In her conversations with her counterparts at Uber, Lee said she wanted to make sure that the company didn&#8217;t make such a wide commitment that &#8220;those commitments became nothing more than virtue signaling at the end of the day.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Lee: </strong>I said to my leadership, if you really want to come out and make some bold statements about being anti-racist, I&#8217;m going to create almost a litmus test to make sure that you really understand what that means because I don&#8217;t want to go up as a company to say we&#8217;re going to be anti-racist and then do nothing about it because that just relives and rehashes the injustices that we&#8217;ve seen in the past. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 4:25)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>So when Uber&#8217;s first post-anti-racism diversity report came out, and it showed Uber&#8217;s Black employee base declined, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/despite-focus-on-anti-racism-ubers-black-employee-base-has-decreased/">Lee said at the time that was not acceptable</a>.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Lee: </strong>I think part of the commitments we made around being really anti-racist is transparency at all costs, even when we know that transparency could potentially make us look, not reflect as positively on us. So the question did go back, as you know, when we were putting together our diversity report is, &#8216;wow, these numbers are not where we want them to be. None of us are happy about it.&#8217; But in our commitment of being accountable, you know, we want the public to hold us accountable. We want to hold people accountable, we want to be accountable to our workforce, we&#8217;re going to be as transparent about why that decline in black employees happened and underrepresented people happened, what the cause was and what we are doing. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 6:11)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/despite-focus-on-anti-racism-ubers-black-employee-base-has-decreased/">Despite commitment to anti-racism, Uber’s Black employee base has decreased</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:12801,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;15&quot;:&quot;Open Sans&quot;,&quot;16&quot;:12}">On being early in the DEI journey</span></h3>
<p>Netflix, despite having previously reported diversity numbers, only released its <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/netflix-inclusion-report-2021">first official diversity report this year</a>. That&#8217;s partly because the team has only been in place for the last three years, Davis said.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Davis: </strong>So we&#8217;re still at the awareness building phase, like from a foundational standpoint, and we&#8217;re really trying to double down so that folks know why I&amp;D matters. Like, what it actually is, and how it impacts all of us. Because oftentimes, folks think of all of these isms and phobias as something that happens to other people. But if we can really make folks understand that there&#8217;s a cost to all these isms, and phobias to all of us individually, interpersonally, culturally and institutionally, then it makes it easier down the road when folks start to feel somewhat fatigued, right? Because there is always that fatigue factor. So we&#8217;re really trying to get ahead of that. And to have folks to think through like, what is in it for me, and what is in it for my colleagues. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 17:33)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/17/the-future-of-diversity-and-inclusion-in-tech/">The future of diversity and inclusion in tech</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>Sharing the DEI load</h3>
<p>Too often does the work of DEI fall on just a handful of people. At Netflix, Davis said it&#8217;s important that there is a shared load, and that all of its leaders are able to speak to the importance of diversity at the company.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Davis: </strong>And I would say our other largest goal is to make sure that all of our leaders can speak to the importance of AI and be more than just a talking point. So how do we build a model that&#8217;s a train the trainer model, where each of our leaders has a one to one inclusion coach, which requires them to have monthly sit-downs with their inclusion partner, where they go on a real intensive journey, so that they can understand how does their leadership style need to evolve and adapt and expand and flex to meet the needs of a larger set of individuals and not the historical ones who folks have engaged with? And we found that to put our leaders on the spot, so that when someone calls me to give a talk, I can say &#8216;No, our COO Greg Peters is just as competent and capable to sit on this panel about inclusion as I am.&#8217; And we feel that we&#8217;re modeling and signaling to our entire organization that this is not just a nice to have, but it&#8217;s part and parcel to your success as an employee, as a leader and to our success as an organization. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 18:26)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="m0sH0JqoLH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/on-the-diversity-front-2020-may-prove-a-tipping-point/">On the diversity front, 2020 may prove a tipping point</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;On the diversity front, 2020 may prove a tipping point&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/on-the-diversity-front-2020-may-prove-a-tipping-point/embed/#?secret=m0sH0JqoLH" data-secret="m0sH0JqoLH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<h3>On Prop 22&#8217;s impact on people of color</h3>
<p>Prop 22 went into effect in California earlier this year after a contentious battle where one side, including Uber, Lyft and other tech companies, wanted workers to remain independent contractors and the other side wanted gig workers to be made employees and therefore entitled to more benefits. Prop 22&#8217;s passage was a win for Uber and its counterparts, which collectively spent north of $200 million on its campaign efforts.</p>
<p>Some have wondered how Uber can reconcile its commitment to anti-racism given that many gig workers are people of color. Lee, however, pushed back on that characterization.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Lee: </strong>I would challenge some of those that believe that Prop 22 actually disproportionately hurts people of color. If you actually look at the way the civil rights organizations that came out in support of Prop 22, the NAACP of Northern California and Hawaii came out in support of Prop 22, most of the Hispanic civil rights organizations as well. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 24:59)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Prop 22, of course, was in response to the passage of AB 5, which set new standards of worker classification that were designed to make it harder for companies to classify workers as independent contractors.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Lee: </strong>And you looked at the way those exceptions were being made to AB 5, you saw that the exceptions were disproportionately being made for those IC &#8212; you know, independent contractor roles that were predominantly represented by white workers. And they were all getting exceptions from AB 5. And then you look at the roles that were predominantly represented by people of color, especially underrepresented people of color, and those roles were not getting exceptions in AB 5. [&#8230;] For me, how I define racism isn&#8217;t based on intent but it&#8217;s based on impact. And when I see that kind of level of disparate, disproportionate impact, that&#8217;s when I think about, you know, what is racist or not. So I would challenge this notion that [Prop 22] actually disproportionately hurt people of color, especially given that we had civil rights organizations that said we support Prop 22. So, I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s anything that really needs to be reconciled, from my perspective and from the organization&#8217;s perspective. <em><strong>(Timestamp: 24:59)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ca-supreme-court-denies-lawsuit-challenging-prop-22s-constitutionality/">CA Supreme Court denies lawsuit challenging Prop 22’s constitutionality</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/uber-lobbies-for-prop-22-style-gig-work-standards-in-the-eu/">Uber lobbies for ‘Prop 22’-style gig work standards in the EU</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/">An even bigger battle for gig worker rights is on the horizon</a></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:12801,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;15&quot;:&quot;Open Sans&quot;,&quot;16&quot;:12}"> <div embedded-video-placeholder="60400dc3303d501d18141bbc" post-id="2120707"></div> </span></p>
<p><a href="https://otter.ai/u/zN--5q60dfqViVw9Tfh4fJwG0as">You can read the entire transcript here</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier &#8220;how-to&#8221; event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear firsthand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product-market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in &#8212; there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/a-glimpse-inside-the-minds-of-techs-dei-leaders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121359</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla’s utility-scale batteries are coming to Texas </title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/teslas-utility-scale-batteries-are-coming-to-texas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/teslas-utility-scale-batteries-are-coming-to-texas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 16:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gambit Energy Storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Elon Musk is bringing his utility-scale battery ambitions to the Lone Star state.  An under-the-radar Tesla subsidiary has been at work building a 100 MW energy storage project in Angleton, Texas, according to an application with the Public Utilities Commission of Texas, and other documents. Bloomberg was the first to report on the documents and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elon Musk is bringing his utility-scale battery ambitions to the Lone Star state. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An under-the-radar Tesla subsidiary has been at work building a 100 MW energy storage project in Angleton, Texas, according to an application with the Public Utilities Commission of Texas, and other documents. Bloomberg was </span><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-03-08/tesla-is-plugging-a-secret-mega-battery-into-the-texas-grid"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the first to report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on the documents and link a previously unknown subsidiary to Tesla. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gambit Energy Storage LLC applied for an application with the Public Utilities Commission of Texas, the regulatory body charged with overseeing the state’s electric utilities, in June of last year. Gambit said in the application, viewed by TechCrunch, that it intends to provide wholesale electricity and grid-balancing services on the Energy Reliability Council of Texas grid. The project is located in Angleton, a town about 50 miles west of Galveston near the Gulf Coast. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="H01lVkIETm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/">Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/embed/#?secret=H01lVkIETm" data-secret="H01lVkIETm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The project’s proposed date of commercial operation is June 1, according to reporting from Bloomberg. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Texas grid has been under the microscope since mid-February, when an unprecedented blast of Arctic weather knocked 46,000 MW of power off line at its peak — more than a third of the system’s overall generation capacity. The disaster left millions of Texans in sub-freezing temperatures for days. The ERCOT board of directors fired its CEO and the chair of the PUCT resigned in the wake of the catastrophe, while legislators at the capital mull major changes to Texas power market operations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tesla already has contracts for battery storage systems with California Utilities Southern California Edison and PG&amp;E, but this is the company’s first major project elsewhere. </span></p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier &#8220;how-to&#8221; event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear firsthand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product-market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in &#8212; there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/teslas-utility-scale-batteries-are-coming-to-texas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122300</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vendr raises huge $60M Series A as its SaaS-purchasing service scales</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/vendr-raises-huge-60m-series-a-as-its-saas-purchasing-service-scales/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/vendr-raises-huge-60m-series-a-as-its-saas-purchasing-service-scales/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 16:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vendr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Vendr announced a $60 million Series A round, a huge funding event led by Tiger Global, with participation from Y Combinator, Sound Ventures, Craft Ventures, F-Prime Capital and Garage Capital. The outsized Series A comes after Vendr last raised $4 million in a mid-2020 seed round, with TechCrunch reporting that the company was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://www.vendr.com/">Vendr</a> announced a $60 million Series A round, a huge funding event led by Tiger Global, with participation from Y Combinator, Sound Ventures, Craft Ventures, F-Prime Capital and Garage Capital.</p>
<p>The outsized Series A comes after Vendr <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/vendr-raises-4m-from-david-sackss-craft-ventures-to-reduce-saas-bills/">last raised $4 million in a mid-2020 seed round</a>, with TechCrunch reporting that the company was profitable at the time. Vendr had raised just over $6 million total before this latest round.</p>
<p>TechCrunch had a few questions. First, how the company had managed to attract so much capital so quickly. According to an interview with Vendr CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanneu/">Ryan Neu</a>, his startup grew just under 5x in 2020, and was cash flow-positive last year as well. The startup&#8217;s model of standing between SaaS buyers and sellers, speeding up transactions while lowering their cost, appears to have fit well into 2020&#8217;s twin trends of rising software reliance and a focus on cost control.</p>
<p>Second, how did the company manage to grow so much? Vendr charges its customers between 1% and 5% of their software spend that it manages, which can add up. Neu told TechCrunch that a somewhat standard 500-person company might spend $2 million to $3.5 million on software each year, which by our math would make that company worth no less than $20,000 to $35,000 in revenue for Vendr at 1% of spend. At Vendr&#8217;s midpoint 2.5%, those figures rise $50,000 to $87,500.</p>
<p>At those prices, Vendr can stack up annual revenue pretty quickly. But why would Vendr customers pay it to handle their software spend? Savings, effectively. So long as they save more than Vendr charges, they are coming out ahead. And as the startup claims that it can cut the time to buying, its own customers can reduce time spent on securing tooling.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="blSstaS2gm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/the-future-of-saas-is-on-demand-use-experts-to-drive-growth-and-engagement/">The future of SaaS is on-demand: Use experts to drive growth and engagement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The future of SaaS is on-demand: Use experts to drive growth and engagement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/the-future-of-saas-is-on-demand-use-experts-to-drive-growth-and-engagement/embed/#?secret=blSstaS2gm" data-secret="blSstaS2gm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Everyone wins, it seems, except for software sellers. After all, they are the ones losing a chance to get less-sophisticated buyers to pay more for their code, right? Neu said that his company&#8217;s model isn&#8217;t too bad for selling companies as they close deals much more quickly, at a higher rate of closure. That could save their sales team time, which might help balance the price differential.</p>
<p>Pressed on what Vendr might be able to do for the selling side of the software market given its present-day buyer focus, Neu declined to share any possible plans.</p>
<p>Returning to the round, why did Vendr raise the money at all if it was doing just fine sans new external funding? The company told TechCrunch that it has scaled its staff to 60 from 10 a year ago, and that it wanted a stronger balance sheet. That&#8217;s fine. We&#8217;d be hard-pressed to find the startup that wouldn&#8217;t take such a large check from Tiger, given the valuation gain the raise implies for Vendr, so there isn&#8217;t too much mystery to unpack.</p>
<p>A theme that TechCrunch has explored in recent weeks has been the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/rapid-growth-in-2020-reveals-okr-software-markets-untapped-potential/">huge depth of the software market</a>. Given the TAM for bits and bytes, Vendr may be able to keep up the hypergrowth that its new round implies its investors will expect. Let&#8217;s see how 2021 winds up for the company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1rLq9sF9G5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/rapid-growth-in-2020-reveals-okr-software-markets-untapped-potential/">Rapid growth in 2020 reveals OKR software market&#8217;s untapped potential</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rapid growth in 2020 reveals OKR software market&#8217;s untapped potential&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/rapid-growth-in-2020-reveals-okr-software-markets-untapped-potential/embed/#?secret=1rLq9sF9G5" data-secret="1rLq9sF9G5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier &#8220;how-to&#8221; event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear firsthand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product-market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in &#8212; there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/vendr-raises-huge-60m-series-a-as-its-saas-purchasing-service-scales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122280</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Olo&#8217;s IPO could value the company north of $3B as Toast waits in the wings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/olos-ipo-could-value-the-company-north-of-3b-as-toast-waits-in-the-wings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/olos-ipo-could-value-the-company-north-of-3b-as-toast-waits-in-the-wings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Targeting $16 to $18 per share, Olo could raise as much as $372.6 million in its public offering.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.olo.com/">Olo</a>, the New York-based fintech startup that provides order processing software to restaurants, shared its initial IPO price range this morning. The company&#8217;s debut comes ahead of <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/restaurant-software-provider-toast-prepares-for-ipo-11613938981?mod=hp_lista_pos2">the expected IPO of Toast</a>, a Boston-based unicorn with a similar market remit.</p>
<p>Targeting $16 to $18 per share, Olo could raise as much as $372.6 million in its public offering.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Unlike most companies going public in recent quarters that we&#8217;ve tracked, Olo has a history of growth and profitability, making its impending pricing all the more interesting. It&#8217;s unknown if Toast is profitable, but because most venture-backed IPOs aren&#8217;t, we&#8217;re presuming it isn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>This morning, we&#8217;re doing our usual work: parsing the company&#8217;s pricing interval to get a valuation range for Olo. We&#8217;ll calculate both simple and fully diluted pricing and then do some quick work on its revenue scale to come to grips with its total scale.</p>
<p>Are investors willing to pay more for profits? And, if so, how much? This is a niche question because most IPOs look a bit more like Coursera than Olo, but it&#8217;s still worth answering.</p>
<h2>Olo&#8217;s IPO valuation range</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;d like to follow along, you can read the new S-1 filing <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001431695/000119312521072308/d867519ds1a.htm">here</a>. Our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/understanding-toasts-expected-ipo-through-the-lens-of-olos-2020-results/">first look at Olo is here</a>, and its fundraising history is <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/olo">here</a>, per Crunchbase.</p>
<p>The company is targeting $16 to $18 per share with an expected sale of 18 million shares. The company is also reserving 2.7 million shares for its underwriters. At the upper end of its range, not counting shares reserved for its bankers, Olo could raise $324 million in its debut.</p>
<p>Per the company, its total number of Class A and B shares outstanding after its IPO would come to 142,012,926, or what we calculate to be 144,712,926 shares, including its underwriters&#8217; option. Using the latter — because we tend to look for valuation extremes — Olo would be worth $2.32 billion to $2.6 billion.</p>
<p>But what about its fully diluted valuation? Adding in shares that are currently tied to unexercised but vested stock options bring Olo to around 188,085,714 shares. Add in the underwriters&#8217; option and the total rises to 190,785,714 shares.</p>
<p>Using the latter figure, at $16 and $18 per share Olo could be worth $3.05 billion to $3.43 billion on a fully diluted basis.</p>
<h2>Is that expensive?</h2>
<p>Let&#8217;s find out! Digging back into Olo&#8217;s growth, we can see a business with rapidly expanding software incomes. And the same software revenues are improving in quality over time. From 2019 to 2020, for example, Olo&#8217;s &#8220;platform&#8221; revenues — a mix of subscription and transaction top line from software — grew from $45.1 million to $92.8 million. Over the same time, the company&#8217;s platform revenue saw its gross margin improve from 73.6% to 84.5%.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/olos-ipo-could-value-the-company-north-of-3b-as-toast-waits-in-the-wings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122236</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investors discuss alt-financing and the role of venture capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/investors-discuss-alt-financing-and-the-role-of-venture-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/investors-discuss-alt-financing-and-the-role-of-venture-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astrid J. Scholz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brian brackeen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sydney thomas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCJUSTICE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121723</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are so many ways to secure capital for your startup beyond traditional venture capital, from crowdfunding to debt financings to revenue-share agreements. But is all money created equal if you are on route to becoming a billion-dollar business? Dr. Astrid Scholz, the co-founder of Zebras Unite; Sydney Thomas, a principal at Precursor Ventures; and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There are so many ways to secure capital for your startup beyond traditional venture capital, from crowdfunding to debt financings to revenue-share agreements. But is all money created equal if you are on route to becoming a billion-dollar business? Dr. Astrid Scholz, the co-founder of Zebras Unite; Sydney Thomas, a principal at Precursor Ventures; and Brian Brackeen, the founding partner of Lightship Capital, joined us at TC Sessions: Justice to discuss alternative pathways to funding, and if the democratization of capital is a façade.</p>
<hr />
<h3><strong>On the choice to stay away from traditional venture capital</strong></h3>
<p>Scholz is currently building out Zebras Unite, a founder-led cooperative that is focused on making startups more sustainable, ethical and inclusive. During the panel, she mentioned that the capital arm of Zebras Unite could have been a traditional fund, but the organization ultimately decided to pursue more creative alternatives, such as the <a href="https://zebrasunite.coop/capital-services">Future Economy Lab</a>. This lab, which focuses on helping founders find financing instruments that fit their sectors, took place in Montreal with a focus on climate tech.</p>
<p>Scholz shared why she went this route, versus a traditional fund:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>In the big scheme of things, [VC] really is just a tiny drop in the large capital pool of capital that&#8217;s out there. And then on the other extreme, you have bank loans. That may or may not be accessible to startup founders, especially if they&#8217;re from certain demographics in this country. Of course we have a massive racial wealth gap and access to capital.</p>
<p>To me, that sounds just like two flavors of capital: vanilla and chocolate. It&#8217;s not interesting, if that was an ice cream store, it was not interesting. At Zebras Unite, we&#8217;re looking to increase the diversity of capital, as well as the diversity of managers of capital. So we&#8217;re very interested in revenue-based financing mechanisms. We&#8217;re very interested in non-dilutive early-stage forms of support to entrepreneurs who don&#8217;t have friends and family wealth. We were looking at new sorts of character-based lending instruments and a bunch of blended approaches, so there&#8217;s more room on the capital spectrum to color in, beyond the two ends of the spectrum. <em><strong>(Timestamp: 3:52)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/04/sec-loosens-crowdfunding-regs-so-small-businesses-can-raise-alternative-financing-in-pandemic/">SEC loosens crowdfunding regs so small businesses can raise alternative financing in pandemic</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/angellist-pioneers-rolling-vc-funds-in-pivot-to-saas/">AngelList pioneers rolling VC funds in pivot to SaaS</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/19/who-are-the-major-revenue-based-investing-vcs/">Who are the major revenue-based investing VCs?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/how-to-approach-and-work-with-the-3-types-of-corporate-vcs/">How to approach (and work with) the 3 types of corporate VCs</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3><strong>On why venture capital paths can be formed around a more inclusive strategy</strong></h3>
<p>Now, venture capital isn’t the devil, and in a market as hot as right now it’s clear that there is a huge demand to back great ideas. The problem starts when you look at which ideas get backed versus which don’t, and underrepresented founders lose out at a disproportionately higher rate than white founders.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="O9udKYybo4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/07/8-black-investors-discuss-the-intersection-of-race-tech-and-vc/">8 Black investors discuss the intersection of race, tech and funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;8 Black investors discuss the intersection of race, tech and funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/07/8-black-investors-discuss-the-intersection-of-race-tech-and-vc/embed/#?secret=O9udKYybo4" data-secret="O9udKYybo4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Standards help everyone get on the same page, and in venture, any clarity around how one investor cuts checks versus another can help curb signaling risk and help set expectations on early-stage founders. Lightship Capital uses traditional venture capital but applies it in a way Brackeen thinks is more inclusive to founders.</p>
<blockquote><p>Oftentimes, VCs talk about designing your product for your customer, but then they don&#8217;t design themselves around the customer. They completely ignore what they tell people to do. And so we&#8217;re designed for the underrepresented founders. And for us, that&#8217;s women, minorities, LGBTQ, plus disabled. And so the capital path for that founder is different from the white-male Zuckerberg founder. Oftentimes, a Series A is very, very difficult, so we bridge that. We’ll write a smaller check &#8212; half a million dollars first &#8212; and then we’ll reserve $1.5 million so they can go out and get a Series A done. And so to do that, we don&#8217;t require board seats and things of that nature, we do require strong collaboration<em>. <strong>(Timestamp: 7:03)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/revenue-based-financing-the-next-step-for-private-equity-and-early-stage-investment/">Flexible VC: A new model for startups targeting profitability</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/10/venture-capital-gets-less-diverse-in-2020/">Venture capital gets less diverse in 2020</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/if-youre-not-investing-in-diverse-founders-youre-a-bad-investor/">If you’re not investing in diverse founders, you’re a bad investor</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3><strong>On how your first check could impact your next check </strong></h3>
<p>Thomas noted that Indie.vc, an alternative financing program that was aimed at slow-growth, bootstrapped founders, shutting down this past week could be a lesson for founders who look to finance their companies from the plethora of programs out there.</p>
<blockquote><p>They were at the frontiers of building access to new capital. I think one of the things that we saw when we would talk to founders who were considering Indie.vc capital versus our capital was, ‘does the investor that you would like after you get that Indie.vc funding, if you decide to go to a more traditional VC firm? Can they actually even do revenue based financing investments, some people actually legitimately can&#8217;t because of the regulatory limits of their fund.<em><strong>(Timestamp: 16:28)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<p>She went on to explain how this isn’t simply a one-off problem that could happen with. Precursor founding partner Charles Hudson penned a post, months ago, about the <a href="https://www.charleshudson.net/we-only-have-100-points-of-equity-to-split-up">messiness in early-stage cap tables. </a></p>
<blockquote><p>I don&#8217;t want to say it&#8217;s unfair, but you have to make a pretty final decision, pretty early on in what type of company you want to build. And I don&#8217;t think that allows for a lot of the flexibility that is the reality of building a startup. When you pivot like five to 10 to 20 to 30 times before you finally get to something that, you know, matters. And so how do we also allow for more flexibility between multiple different types of revenue structures? I just don’t think that exists right now. <strong>(Timestamp: 17:12) </strong></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/10/a-recapitalization-reckoning/">A recapitalization reckoning</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/founders-seeking-their-first-check-need-a-fundraising-sales-funnel/">Founders seeking their first check need a fundraising sales funnel</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Brackeen added that his form loves non-dilutive financing before, and after, they are nicest. Pitch competitions might help a startup launch, but it won’t help founders get from stage to stage. This banter basically answers the question that I set early on: is all capital created equal in the eyes of investors? A cap table filled with different types of financing structures and notes, as Thomas mentions, could lead to your next check investor declining to invest based on a semantic versus a lack of believing in your vision. One side effect we see here is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/10/a-recapitalization-reckoning/">recapitalizations</a>, an event where startups restructure their entire cap table to squeeze out old investors, bring on new ones and shift the way equity and debt is managed.</p>
<p>Scholz chimed in about how startups should think about capital limitations, but also other corporate structures that could shape the trajectory of a startup.</p>
<blockquote><p>I think that point about founders basically getting locked into a corporate structure and an investment strategy before they even really know what they&#8217;re building or how it&#8217;s selling is just so important. I always joke, you know, like 99 out of 100 corporate lawyers will tell you to incorporate as a Delaware C. [But] that may or may not be the right answer. There may be a good reason to become a cooperative, and incorporating as a Delaware C will make your life very difficult.<strong> (Timestamp: 17:46)</strong></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/02/should-your-startup-take-the-b-corp-route/">Should your startup take the public benefit or B corp route?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/08/which-types-of-startups-are-most-often-profitable/">Which types of startups are most often profitable?</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3><strong>On if VC will be even more relevant five years from now</strong></h3>
<p>The conversation turned into a broader discussion on if venture capital will be as relevant five years from now as it is today. While Scholz said that she doesn’t even think venture is that important today, the two venture capitalists on the panel &#8212; Brackeen and Thomas &#8212; were good sports about the future of the asset class on which they have bet their careers.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Thomas:</strong> The IPOs just keep on coming, and they keep getting bigger. It’s crazy. I think that there is recreating an immense amount of wealth, and that we need to be thoughtful, we need to be careful. And we need to be just considerate of that fact. And so I plan to be in venture for the next 10 years. But I I think, to Astrid’s point, we are not the only ones on the island. We are connected to all of these other different capital structures, and different communities. But my bet is still here. <strong>(Timestamp 25:14) </strong></p>
<p><strong>Brackeen:</strong> Capital will continue to play a large role in capitalism, because the two are hand in hand. And venture capital is a version of that. Watch what we do. To see billions of dollars go into these geographies, these communities, these groups, the value creation is outrageous. Morgan Stanley, and others say that racism and sexism cost this country somewhere between $4 trillion and $16 trillion in kind of untapped value. So venture capital can be a key lever in opening that faucet. <strong>(Timestamp: 25:52)</strong></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/venture-capital-is-going-to-get-even-bigger-faster-and-more-expensive-this-year/">Venture capital is going to get even bigger, faster and more expensive this year</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/21/lame-lps-founder-referenceability-and-the-future-of-vc-signaling/"> Lame LPs, founder referenceability and the future of VC signaling</a></li>
</ul>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/XXgr2a_su4s?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p><a href="https://otter.ai/u/NwS2G1_Oe5NvNKaQvpEnccKVNy8">You can read the entire transcript here.</a></p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier &#8220;how-to&#8221; event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear firsthand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product-market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in &#8212; there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/investors-discuss-alt-financing-and-the-role-of-venture-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121723</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebs like Rob Dyrdek, Joe Jonas and Travis Barker are backing the nootropic nosh company, Mindright</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/celebs-like-rob-dyrdek-joe-jonas-and-travis-barker-are-backing-the-nootropic-nosh-company-mindright/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/celebs-like-rob-dyrdek-joe-jonas-and-travis-barker-are-backing-the-nootropic-nosh-company-mindright/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rob dyrdek]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was only a matter of time before someone married the nascent nootropic supplements for brain health to the snack bar craze that continues to attract dollars and exits. That time is apparently now, as Rob Dyrdek, the MTV-famous celebrity, pro-skater and entrepreneur, and Chris Bernard announce a new investment in the company they co-founded, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It was only a matter of time before someone married the nascent nootropic supplements for brain health to the snack bar craze that continues to attract dollars and exits.</p>
<p>That time is apparently now, as Rob Dyrdek, the MTV-famous celebrity, pro-skater and entrepreneur, and Chris Bernard announce a new investment in the company they co-founded, <a href="http://www.getmindright.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mindright</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, alongside celebrity investors including Joe Jonas, Travis Barker and The Profit&#8217;s Marcus Lemonis. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;When we started down the path of condition-specific food and beverage&#8230; we started doing a lot of research into the nootropics and adaptogens space,&#8221; said co-founder Bernard. Working with a food scientist who did not want to be named (which isn&#8217;t sketchy at all), Dyrdek and Bernard were introduced to several companies producing ashwagandha, which the two had settled on as the new key ingredient in their snack bars.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Along with ginseng and cordyceps mushrooms, the company has a trifecta of new (and old) supplements that have taken the nutraceutical world by storm.</p>
<p>Bernard had initially approached the <a href="https://dyrdekmachine.com/">Dyrdek Machine</a> group about another product, but the company was too far along and not something that Dyrdek felt passionate about backing. The story changed when Bernard returned with plans for this nootropic nosh.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;[Bernard] brought back the concept of the path of what’s evolved from functional foods and probiotics and collagen and sort of the mental health and adaptogen and the supplement world and said here’s how to merge these,&#8221; Dyrdek said of Bernard&#8217;s second pitch. &#8220;It was a home-run for us. Our process is supporting a solopreneur where we help shape and build the company together and provide the outsourced resources. We fund the development of the idea to go to the capital markets.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>So far, Dyrdek and his team have made 15 investments in consumer and entertainment businesses, and five of those business have since been acquired.</p>
<p>Most deals from Dyrdek Machine follow a similar trajectory. The firm becomes a co-founder and shares common stock and then negotiate a preferred equity investment for the capital infusion. Typically those deals range from $250,000 to $500,000.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We co-found it and we share that common share class and our first money is preferred and pick a valuation that balances out the deal,&#8221; Dyrdek said. &#8220;How much equity do we want to develop it with you is what we negotiate with that initial capital.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2122278" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122278" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2122278" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dyrdek.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dyrdek.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dyrdek.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dyrdek.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dyrdek.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dyrdek.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dyrdek.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dyrdek.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dyrdek.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2122278" class="wp-caption-text">Portrait of Rob Dyrdek, founder of <a href="https://dyrdekmachine.com/">Dyrdek Machine</a>. Image Credits: Dyrdek Machine</p></div></p>
<p>Dyrdek describes his investment firm as founder-driven and market agnostic. &#8220;We want a well-rounded, multi-dimensional founder and then we look at the market and how do we evolve it into something that has a larger, broader appeal,&#8221; Dyrdek said. &#8220;Rather than chasing down nootropics, we found that &#8216;good mood&#8217; was the important thing to the consumer base. That&#8217;s why we drove &#8216;Good mood superfood.&#8217; &#8221;</p>
<p>Bernard&#8217;s faith in Dyrdek&#8217;s ability to move the business forward has been proven in the evolution of other companies in the firm&#8217;s portfolio. Dyrdek pointed to Outstanding Foods, another investment, which he said had recently closed a $10 million round at a $100 million valuation. Another startup in the portfolio, Momentous, a supplement manufacturer, also closed on a big round recently after raising $5 million in 2019, Dyrdek said.</p>
<p>For Mindright, Dyrdek&#8217;s involvement brought in other celebrity names once they tried the product. The company counts Joe Jonas and Travis Barker among its seed investors.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;They were excited to get involved in this because they believed in what we took the time to create,&#8221; Bernard said. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Q6CrvAGfaa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/iot-and-data-science-will-boost-foodtech-in-the-post-pandemic-era/">IoT and data science will boost foodtech in the post-pandemic era</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;IoT and data science will boost foodtech in the post-pandemic era&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/iot-and-data-science-will-boost-foodtech-in-the-post-pandemic-era/embed/#?secret=Q6CrvAGfaa" data-secret="Q6CrvAGfaa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/celebs-like-rob-dyrdek-joe-jonas-and-travis-barker-are-backing-the-nootropic-nosh-company-mindright/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122262</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The path forward for essential workers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-path-forward-for-essential-workers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-path-forward-for-essential-workers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tc justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCJUSTICE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gig workers and warehouse workers have become essential in a pandemic-ravaged economy. In California, a law went into effect earlier this year that makes gig workers independent contractors. Meanwhile, Amazon warehouse workers in Alabama are actively seeking to form a union to ensure better protections at the workplace. At TC Sessions: Justice, I spoke with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Gig workers and warehouse workers have become essential in a pandemic-ravaged economy. In California, a law went into effect earlier this year that makes gig workers independent contractors. Meanwhile, Amazon warehouse workers in Alabama are actively seeking to form a union to ensure better protections at the workplace.</p>
<p>At TC Sessions: Justice, I spoke with Gig Workers Collective co-founder and organizer Vanessa Bain, The Congress of Essential Workers founder and former Amazon warehouse worker Christian Smalls and National Council for Occupational Safety and Health Co-Executive Director Jessica E. Martinez about what’s next for gig workers and tech’s contractor workforce, and what battles lie ahead for these essential workers.</p>
<hr />
<h3>On the Amazon union drive</h3>
<p>Amazon warehouse workers in Bessemer, Alabama are in the midst of a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/07/amazon-warehouse-workers-begin-historic-vote-to-unionize/">historic union drive</a>. Smalls, who was fired from his job at an Amazon warehouse in Staten Island last year after speaking out about the lack of personal protective equipment, told me he recently spent a few days in Bessemer.</p>
<blockquote><p>The building opened up when coronavirus started. When New York City became the epicenter, that&#8217;s when the Bessemer facility opened up. So the union got a head start on talking to workers. So that&#8217;s a gem for anybody or any union that plans on trying to unionize the building &#8212; that you have a facility in your community that&#8217;s about to open up, when opening, that&#8217;s the best time to connect with workers. That&#8217;s what happened last year. And as a result, the workers had seen what happened to the workers that were unprotected and they don&#8217;t want that. They want better for themselves. And they rightfully deserve that, especially in Alabama. It&#8217;s a right to work state, a state with no state minimum, obviously a red state. So I think it&#8217;s a lot of intangibles against them. But these workers now see the window of opportunity for change systemically. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 4:40)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, President Biden recently came out in support of the unionizing efforts in Bessemer.</p>
<blockquote><p>I would hope that he is a man of his word. He&#8217;s a pro-union guy. He ran his campaign off of that, saying he&#8217;s a union guy and unions need to be strong, and he supports unions all the way. It was powerful to see that the president, the man, the highest plateau in the country, supports the union. <em><strong>(Timestamp: 13:11)</strong></em></p>
<p>[&#8230;] But once again, like Vanessa said, I don&#8217;t put all my eggs in that basket either. I just want to hold him accountable. Make sure that, you know, we see this all the way through to the end. Even if Alabama is not successful, if we were to try again, in other locations, other parts of the country, that we have the support of the highest power in the country, that is the most powerful thing that will resonate with workers. So it&#8217;s good to see that it&#8217;s happening now. <em><strong>(Timestamp: 14:17)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/07/amazon-warehouse-workers-begin-historic-vote-to-unionize/">Amazon warehouse workers to begin historic vote to unionize</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/amazon-faces-lawsuit-alleging-failure-to-provide-ppe-to-workers-during-pandemic/">Amazon faces lawsuit alleging failure to provide PPE to workers during pandemic</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/amazon-ny-ag-lawsuit/">NY AG sues Amazon over treatment of warehouse workers</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3>On the effects of Prop 22</h3>
<p>Already, Prop 22 has affected industries outside of tech. In December, supermarket chain Albertsons began replacing delivery drivers with contractors and hundreds of employees in California were swapped for DoorDash workers, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-02-17/gig-economy-coming-for-millions-of-u-s-jobs-after-california-s-uber-lyft-vote?sref=gni836kR">Bloomberg reported</a>. Meanwhile, tech companies have spoken about implementing Prop 22-like legislation in other parts of the country. Martinez described how some California residents who voted to pass Prop 22 thought they were supporting workers for better access to rights.</p>
<blockquote><p>And unfortunately, you have workers who have possibly died. We have a California rideshare driver who died from COVID-19 last month. His independent classification means his family will receive no workers&#8217; compensation. That is a huge impact to workers and the reality of how it impacts day to day life for workers and in the midst of a pandemic. So I share that, because Prop 22 sets the tone, again, for what could happen nationally. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 17:00)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, Bain said she sees the passing of Prop 22 as a failure of &#8220;our entire structure of economy.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p>And we have really allowed tech to run rampant under this pretense that somehow it&#8217;s innovative, and especially within the gig economy. I mean, it&#8217;s the opposite of innovative, right? Like it&#8217;s feudalism on your phone, right? It&#8217;s 1-800 dial listserv. So it&#8217;s like, they&#8217;re not doing anything new that justifies creating an entirely different classification of labor than existed before, which is what Prop 22 did, right? It literally created this category of marketplace contractor that retains neither the protections of an independent contractor nor an employee. And allowing, you know, companies to write their own laws in this way is a systemic failure. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 18:57)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/">An even bigger battle for gig worker rights is on the horizon</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/gig-workers-survey-san-francisco/">Gig workers in San Francisco are mostly people of color and many are immigrants, according to survey</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/ex-postmates-vp-of-global-public-policy-on-the-future-of-gig-work/">Ex-Postmates VP of global public policy on the future of gig work</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3>On the PRO Act</h3>
<p>There&#8217;s legislation in the U.S. Senate right now that aims to make it easier for workers to organize and form unions in the country. The Protecting the Right to Organize Act seeks to change labor laws in favor of giving workers more power.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TwVEjKJh2q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/24/tech-at-work-black-gig-workers-speak-out-and-a-look-at-uber-commitment-to-being-anti-racist-and-facebooks-diversity-report/">Black gig workers speak out, Uber&#8217;s commitment to being anti-racist and Facebook&#8217;s diversity report</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Black gig workers speak out, Uber&#8217;s commitment to being anti-racist and Facebook&#8217;s diversity report&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/24/tech-at-work-black-gig-workers-speak-out-and-a-look-at-uber-commitment-to-being-anti-racist-and-facebooks-diversity-report/embed/#?secret=TwVEjKJh2q" data-secret="TwVEjKJh2q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Bain spoke about the importance of getting the PRO Act across the line in light of the passing of Prop 22 in California.</p>
<blockquote><p>These things shouldn&#8217;t be at the mercy of who happens to be, you know, held to a position. These are things that should be codified and enshrined really in law. And things that should be consistent and stable protections that people can rely on and count on. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 20:22)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Martinez explained how the PRO Act aligns with the <a href="https://nationalcosh.org/sites/default/files/2021-02%20National%20Agenda%20for%20Worker%20Safety%20and%20Health.pdf">work she&#8217;s doing at COSH</a>. The organization recently released a national agenda for worker safety and health, along with some recommendations.</p>
<blockquote><p>We want stronger safety laws, tougher enforcement, including a mandatory emergency standard to prevent the spread of infectious disease. And again, this is federally so if there is an ETS or an emergency [temporary] standard pass, it applies all over and impacts all kinds of workers, stronger protections against retaliation. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 07:53)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Martinez added:</p>
<blockquote><p>Employers will funnel resources to try scare tactics to scare workers from organizing, demanding safer workplaces, job security, and so forth. [The agenda] also includes workers are included in all policy decisions. We believe strongly that workers, more than anyone, understand the job, know the solutions and controls to health and safety issues, and also equity and inclusion to end the misclassification and better protections for temporary gig workers. Paid sick and family leave for workers, also worker centered health protocols, including health for high-risk workers and getting access to vaccines. And we want to confront the workplace effects of climate change. Finally, also prevent chemical catastrophes and harmful exposure. [&#8230;] With that said, this is not working in isolation. It works in collaboration with laws, we&#8217;re hoping that will pass, such as the PRO Act, allowing workers to gain bargaining power when organizing, essentially giving them the ability to negotiate with the employer to get access to benefits again, such as some job security paid sick leave, workers comp and so forth. <strong><em>(Timestamp: 8:23)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:12801,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;15&quot;:&quot;Open Sans&quot;,&quot;16&quot;:12}"> <div embedded-video-placeholder="603fd6c1fb2e1e3363ff491c" post-id="2120505"></div> </span></p>
<p>You can read the <a href="https://otter.ai/u/UGTB23Mu9JiPv-cYY5YHKQ3IZOA">entire transcript here</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier &#8220;how-to&#8221; event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear firsthand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product-market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in &#8212; there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-path-forward-for-essential-workers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119188</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Attend TechCrunch&#8217;s free virtual Miami meetup on March 11</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/attend-techcrunchs-free-virtual-miami-meetup-on-march-11-2/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/attend-techcrunchs-free-virtual-miami-meetup-on-march-11-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tc meetup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch is hosting a small virtual meetup this Thursday centered around Miami. We hope you can attend. It&#8217;s free. This is our first (virtual) field trip to Miami. Even though we can’t be there physically right now, it’ll sure feel like we are. All lights will be shining on the Magic City. The area is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch is hosting a small virtual meetup this Thursday centered around Miami. We hope you can attend. It&#8217;s free.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-miami">This is our first (virtual) field trip to Miami</a>. Even though we can’t be there physically right now, it’ll sure feel like we are. All lights will be shining on the Magic City. The area is quickly transforming thanks to active investors, interesting companies, a Twitter-proficient mayor and beautifully scenic living.</p>
<p>If you’re interested in what’s happening in Miami in general, seeking out a new, up-and-coming city to live in, looking for cool companies and talented founders to invest in, then you’ll want to <a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-miami">register</a> and drop March 11 on your calendar. This is a virtual event, but space is still limited, so register early.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here’s just some of what you can expect:</p>
<ul>
<li>Networking &#8211; It’s what you can always count on us for. Companies are started and deals get done at TechCrunch events (yes, even the virtual ones!).</li>
<li>Pitch-off &#8211; We’re going to tap into the local tech scene in Miami and bring on some VCs to take a look at  your pitches. They’ll give you feedback live from the stage. Sign up to pitch by <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/kZ4l728t">filling out this form</a>.</li>
<li>Panels &#8211; Meet the movers and shakers up close and personal. Hear about their journey, ask them questions and find out what’s special to them about Miami.</li>
</ul>
<p>All along the way we’ll be asking for your feedback by way of polls, Q&amp;As and surveys. We want to hear from everyone who lives in the birthplace of sunscreen, and we’re looking to you for suggestions on folks who should be getting all of the attention we can throw at them on March 11. Drop suggestions in the comments below.</p>
<p>It’s going to be one to remember, and it’s the perfect setup for when we can safely crash the city in person again!</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xFirjM0Gyi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/have-a-startup-in-miami-apply-to-pitch-at-techcrunchs-miami-virtual-meetup/">Have a startup in Miami? Apply to pitch at TechCrunch&#8217;s Miami virtual meetup</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Have a startup in Miami? Apply to pitch at TechCrunch&#8217;s Miami virtual meetup&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/have-a-startup-in-miami-apply-to-pitch-at-techcrunchs-miami-virtual-meetup/embed/#?secret=xFirjM0Gyi" data-secret="xFirjM0Gyi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cq4hKuO0lZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/6-miami-based-investors-share-their-views-on-the-regions-startup-scene/">8 Miami-based investors share their views on the region&#8217;s startup scene</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;8 Miami-based investors share their views on the region&#8217;s startup scene&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/6-miami-based-investors-share-their-views-on-the-regions-startup-scene/embed/#?secret=cq4hKuO0lZ" data-secret="cq4hKuO0lZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/miami/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2107272" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="141" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=768,106 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=680,94 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=1536,211 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=2048,282 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/attend-techcrunchs-free-virtual-miami-meetup-on-march-11-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122271</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: More money for fintech, Deliveroo&#8217;s IPO and AI startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/equity-monday-more-money-for-fintech-deliveroos-ipo-and-ai-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/equity-monday-more-money-for-fintech-deliveroos-ipo-and-ai-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bay area]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coursera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deliveroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postscript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/0f9f0b12-a7b5-4ebc-9033-fa2eaf71b4cb?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a> and myself <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">here</a> — and make sure to check out our Friday show that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/softbank-makes-mountains-of-cash-off-of-human-laziness/">featured the Square-Tidal deal, some recent IPOs and some super-neat rounds</a>.</p>
<p>Much like today&#8217;s show, if I am being honest. Here&#8217;s the rundown:</p>
<ul>
<li>Coursera <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/a-first-look-at-courseras-s-1-filing/">filed to go public</a>, which could help set the tone for edtech founders and startups regarding their own valuations and fundraising prospects.</li>
<li>Bay Area startups <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/tech-companies-leaving-san-francisco-exagerated-telstra-survey-austin-texas-2021-3?op=1&amp;scrolla=5eb6d68b7fedc32c19ef33b4">did not leave</a>.</li>
<li>And the world of <a href="https://aiindex.stanford.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/2021-AI-Index-Report_Master.pdf">AI venture-capital funding</a> shows that while there&#8217;s plenty of capital, the number of startups being founded in the space is dipping.</li>
<li>Starling <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/uk-challenger-bank-starling-raises-376m-now-valued-at-1-9b/">raised a huge new round</a> in the fintech space, and Deliveroo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/deliveroo-posted-narrowed-loss-of-309m-with-gross-transactions-surging-to-5-7b-in-2020-eitf-shows/">dropped some financial numbers</a> on its path to going public in short-order.</li>
<li>Postscript <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/postscript-raises-35m-to-give-shopify-stores-sms-superpowers/">raised $35 million</a> for its Shopify-SMS service; Praava Health raised $10.6 million to bring better healthcare to Bangladesh.</li>
</ul>
<p>A packed kickoff to what promises to be a packed week!</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 AM PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gNmAvAeVT6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/a-first-look-at-courseras-s-1-filing/">A first look at Coursera’s S-1 filing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A first look at Coursera’s S-1 filing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/a-first-look-at-courseras-s-1-filing/embed/#?secret=gNmAvAeVT6" data-secret="gNmAvAeVT6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/equity-monday-more-money-for-fintech-deliveroos-ipo-and-ai-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122229</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>McAfee sells enterprise biz to Symphony Technology Group for $4B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/mcafee-sells-enterprise-biz-to-symphony-technology-group-for-4b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/mcafee-sells-enterprise-biz-to-symphony-technology-group-for-4b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[McAfee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Symphony Technology Group]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Security firm McAfee announced this morning that it will be selling its enterprise business to a consortium led by the private equity firm Symphony Technology Group for $4 billion. It should pair well with RSA, another enterprise-focused security company the private equity firm purchased last February for $2 billion. McAfee President and Chief Executive Officer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Security firm <a href="http://www.mcafee.com">McAfee</a> announced this morning that it will be selling its enterprise business to a consortium led by the private equity firm <a href="https://stgpartners.com/">Symphony Technology Group</a> for $4 billion.</p>
<p>It should pair well with RSA, another enterprise-focused security company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/dell-sells-rsa-to-consortium-led-by-symphony-technology-group-for-over-2b/">the private equity firm purchased</a> last February for $2 billion.</p>
<p>McAfee President and Chief Executive Officer Peter Leav says that his company has decided to direct the firm&#8217;s resources to the consumer side of the business. &#8220;This transaction will allow McAfee to singularly focus on our consumer business and to accelerate our strategy to be a leader in personal security for consumers,&#8221; he said in a statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company has been making some moves in the last year, <a href="https://www.bloombergquint.com/business/mcafee-ipo-is-said-to-raise-740-million-in-return-to-market#:~:text=the%20stock%20market.-,(Bloomberg)%20%2D%2D%20McAfee%20Corp.,Wednesday%2C%20according%20to%20a%20statement.">returning to the public markets</a> after a decade as a private company. In January, the company <a href="https://www.channele2e.com/business/talent/mcafee-layoffs-2021-staff-cuts/">reportedly laid off a couple of hundred employees</a> and shut down its software development center in Tel Aviv.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ULnNqFGV53"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/02/cybersecurity-vc-survey-investing-valuations/">12 top cybersecurity VCs discuss investing, valuations and no-go zones</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;12 top cybersecurity VCs discuss investing, valuations and no-go zones&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/02/cybersecurity-vc-survey-investing-valuations/embed/#?secret=ULnNqFGV53" data-secret="ULnNqFGV53" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Although Symphony did not point directly to the RSA acquisition, the two investments create a large combined legacy security business for the firm, both of which have strong brand recognition, but might have lost some of their edge to more modern competitors in the marketplace.</p>
<p>Looking at McAfee&#8217;s <a href="https://ir.mcafee.com/static-files/86dedd74-00e2-4f57-8995-5fef120cef51">latest earning&#8217;s report</a>, Q42020, which the company reported on February 24, 2021, the consumer business grew at a much brisker rate than the enterprise side of the house. The former was up 23% YoY, while the latter grew at a far slower 5% rate.</p>
<p>As for the entire year, the company reported $2.9 billion in total FY2020 revenue, up 10% YoY. That broke down to $1.6 billion in consumer net revenue up 20% YoY, and $1.3 billion in enterprise net revenue, an increase of just 1% for the full year.</p>
<p>The company has a complex history, starting life in the 1980s selling firewall software. It eventually went public before being <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2010/08/19/intel-buys-cyber-security-giant-mcafee-for-7-68-billion-in-cash/">purchased by Intel for $7.7 billion</a> in 2010 and going private again. In 2014, <a href="https://money.cnn.com/2014/01/07/technology/security/intel-mcafee/index.html">the company changed names</a> to Intel Security before <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/03/intel-security-is-mcafee-again/#:~:text=Today%2C%20Intel%20is%20officially%20inking,retain%20a%2049%20percent%20stake.">Intel sold a majority stake to TPG in 2017</a> for $4.2 billion and changed the name back to McAfee.</p>
<p>The transaction is expected to close by the end of this year, subject to regulatory oversight.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ar0yugytYg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/dell-sells-rsa-to-consortium-led-by-symphony-technology-group-for-over-2b/">Dell sells RSA to consortium led by Symphony Technology Group for over $2B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dell sells RSA to consortium led by Symphony Technology Group for over $2B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/dell-sells-rsa-to-consortium-led-by-symphony-technology-group-for-over-2b/embed/#?secret=Ar0yugytYg" data-secret="Ar0yugytYg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier &#8220;how-to&#8221; event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear firsthand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product-market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in &#8212; there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/mcafee-sells-enterprise-biz-to-symphony-technology-group-for-4b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122238</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PayPal to acquire cryptocurrency security startup Curv</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/paypal-to-acquire-cryptocurrency-custody-startup-curv/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/paypal-to-acquire-cryptocurrency-custody-startup-curv/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Curv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PayPal has announced that it plans to acquire Curv, a cryptocurrency startup based in Tel Aviv, Israel. Israeli newspaper Calcalist originally reported the move. And PayPal has now made an official announcement. Curv is a cryptocurrency security company that helps you store your crypto assets securely. The company operates a cloud-based service that lets you [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">PayPal has <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/paypal-to-acquire-curv-301242347.html">announced</a> that it plans to acquire Curv, a cryptocurrency startup based in Tel Aviv, Israel. Israeli newspaper Calcalist <a href="https://www.calcalist.co.il/internet/articles/0,7340,L-3896291,00.html">originally reported</a> the move. And PayPal has now made an official announcement.</p>
<p>Curv is a cryptocurrency security company that helps you store your crypto assets securely. The company operates a cloud-based service that lets you access your crypto wallets without any hardware device.</p>
<p>Curv also lets you set up sophisticated policies so that the new intern cannot withdraw crypto assets without some sort of approval chain. Similarly, you can create allow lists so that regular transactions can go through more easily.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Behind the scenes, Curv uses multi-party computation to handle private keys. When you create a wallet, cryptographic secrets are generated on your device and on Curv’s servers. Whenever you’re trying to initiate a transaction, multiple secrets are used to generate a full public and private key.</p>
<p>Secrets are rotated regularly and you can’t do anything with just one secret. If somebody steals an unsecured laptop, a hacker cannot access crypto funds with the information stored on this device alone.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SA253zbkwZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/in-the-buy-now-pay-later-wars-paypal-is-primed-for-dominance/">In the &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; wars, PayPal is primed for dominance</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;In the &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; wars, PayPal is primed for dominance&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/in-the-buy-now-pay-later-wars-paypal-is-primed-for-dominance/embed/#?secret=SA253zbkwZ" data-secret="SA253zbkwZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As you can see, Curv isn’t a cryptocurrency wallet for end users. The company offers its services to exchanges, brokers and over-the-counter desks. If you’re running a fund and you plan on buying a large amount of cryptocurrencies, you could also consider using Curv.</p>
<p>Finally, financial institutions that are looking for a solution to store digital assets and diversify their balance sheet could also work with Curv.</p>
<p>PayPal says that the Curv team will join the cryptocurrency group within PayPal. The payment giant has been gradually rolling out cryptocurrency products. It has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/paypal-to-let-you-buy-and-sell-cryptocurrencies-in-the-us/">partnered with Paxos</a> so that users in the U.S. can buy, hold and sell cryptocurrencies from their PayPal account.</p>
<p>In the near future, PayPal also plans to let you buy and sell items using cryptocurrencies. During its <a href="https://s1.q4cdn.com/633035571/files/doc_financials/2020/q4/PYPL_Q4-20_Investor_Update-%281%29.pdf">most recent earnings release</a>, the company also said that it plans to launch cryptocurrency products in other countries and in Venmo, the consumer fintech super app owned by PayPal.</p>
<p>Terms of the deal are undisclosed and the transaction should close at some point during the first half of 2021. Calcalist <a href="https://www.calcalist.co.il/internet/articles/0,7340,L-3896291,00.html">reported</a> that PayPal was paying between $200 million and $300 million for the acquisition. A person close to the company says that the transaction was under $200 million. I guess we’ll find out what happened exactly in the next earnings release.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oh0dJRkMPb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/paypal-to-let-you-buy-and-sell-cryptocurrencies-in-the-us/">PayPal to let you buy and sell cryptocurrencies in the US</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;PayPal to let you buy and sell cryptocurrencies in the US&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/paypal-to-let-you-buy-and-sell-cryptocurrencies-in-the-us/embed/#?secret=oh0dJRkMPb" data-secret="oh0dJRkMPb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier &#8220;how-to&#8221; event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear firsthand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product-market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in &#8212; there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/paypal-to-acquire-cryptocurrency-custody-startup-curv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122248</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The rise of the tech workers union and what comes next</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-rise-of-the-tech-workers-union-and-what-comes-next/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-rise-of-the-tech-workers-union-and-what-comes-next/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 14:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kickstarter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCJUSTICE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[union]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While not entirely non-existent, the union has been an elusive phenomenon in Silicon Valley. More recently, however, big names like Google and Kickstarter have taken key steps toward forming unions, as have smaller startups like Glitch, which made history this week by signing a collective bargaining agreement &#8212; the first team of software engineers to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While not entirely non-existent, the union has been an elusive phenomenon in Silicon Valley. More recently, however, big names like Google and Kickstarter have taken key steps toward forming unions, as have smaller startups like Glitch, which made history this week by signing a collective bargaining agreement &#8212; the first team of software engineers to do so. Amazon warehouse workers in Alabama, meanwhile, are currently on the cusp of forming their own historic union. In this panel from TC Sessions: Justice, we discuss how we got here, what comes next and steps tech employees can take.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="u1n5jV3u1P"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/03/the-future-of-gig-work-could-involve-unions-and-co-ops/">The future of gig work could involve unions and co-ops</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The future of gig work could involve unions and co-ops&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/03/the-future-of-gig-work-could-involve-unions-and-co-ops/embed/#?secret=u1n5jV3u1P" data-secret="u1n5jV3u1P" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<h3>On why now?</h3>
<p>As has been the case with management throughout history, tech companies have long fought tooth and nail against labor organizing. Over the course of the last couple of years, however, we may have seen something of a critical mass that could represent the beginnings of a sea change for the industry.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Clarissa Redwine (NYU):</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>It seems like tech workers are reacting to some of the maturity of tech and the expansion of the platforms that we all work on, and also more worker instability in general in the U.S., especially. I think it&#8217;s sort of a response that workers are becoming more formal in their organizing efforts<em>.<strong> (Timestamp: 1:08)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Parul Koul (Google):</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>A variety of tactics and strategies have been tried, and we’ve been able to analyze the successes and failures of past movements and arrive at a point where we’ve developed enough institutional and organizational knowledge to try something new and &#8212; in some ways &#8212; more complex.<strong> (</strong><em><strong>Timestamp: 3:25)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/google-alphabet-employees-union/">Google, Alphabet employees unionize</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/13/online-code-collaboration-tool-glitch-votes-to-unionize/">Online code collaboration tool Glitch votes to unionize</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3>On whether the pandemic will spur more organizing</h3>
<p>COVID-19 has radically transformed where &#8212; and how &#8212; we work. It’s upended many industries and caused millions to lose jobs. Could the pandemic prove to be yet another inflection point for a growing movement?</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Koul:</strong> In our case, what we saw was companies moving to work from home and then, in certain categories of employees, not really receiving the same benefits […] whether it’s a stipend to buy equipment or even having the benefit from working from home […] We also saw a mass movement and social and political protests against police brutality erupt right in the middle of the pandemic. For me, and many other organizers at Google, it really galvanized us to do something and respond to that in the streets and in our own way. <strong>(</strong><em><strong>Timestamp: 6:56)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<hr />
<h3>On how – or if – unions can protect against layoffs</h3>
<p>For many industries, layoffs have become all but an inevitability during the pandemic. In a number of the aforementioned cases, they’ve continued even in the wake of employee unionizing. Ultimately, how much protection does a union give workers against layoffs?</p>
<p><strong>Grace Reckers (Office and Professional Employees International Union):</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>Kickstarter won its union on February 18, 2020. The pandemic hit in mid-March. The company announced that they were going to have pretty massive layoffs in early-April. That was a very difficult time. We looked at the numbers and did see that a number of the people they were proposing to layoff were advocates for the union or union members. That was very hard to stomach. What happens, though &#8212; and where the union comes into play &#8212; is that the company was not able to just lay people off like that. Especially under the terms that they wanted to impose unilaterally, without any consultation with staff. The difference was that when the company proposed these layoffs, because there was already a union in place, Kickstarter had to negotiate with the group of employees about the terms of that layoff. <em><strong>(</strong><strong>Timestamp: 9:10)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/kickstarter-workers-vote-to-unionize/">Kickstarter workers vote to unionize</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/following-unionization-glitch-signs-collective-bargaining-agreement/">Following unionization, Glitch signs collective bargaining agreement</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3>On how to get started</h3>
<p>First steps toward unionization are often difficult in an environment where organizing is frowned upon by management. Many early conversations happen after hours and off-the-clock for fear of repercussions. This can be doubly difficult in an environment like white-collar workers at tech company, where some employees don’t tacitly understand the benefits of organizing.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Reckers:</strong> You can best support each other by getting into conversations with your co-workers and understanding what’s been going on with them. The first question I often get from people is how to first start having conversations. I think that’s a challenge, especially since we’re not taught how to do that. But starting a conversation about what their experiences have been like at the organization or company, how long they’ve been there? What did they want to see when they were hired? What sort of workplace were they looking for? And how can we make sure that we have some way of achieving that? (<em><strong>Timestamp: 24:04)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/03/the-state-of-the-unions/">The state of the unions</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/07/amazon-warehouse-workers-begin-historic-vote-to-unionize/">Amazon warehouse workers to begin historic vote to unionize</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3>On whether expressions of support from management are always positive</h3>
<p>Management often adopts the narrative that they support unions following hard-fought battles. In the wake of support from certain tech executives and political leaders like Joe Biden, the question arises about whether such sentiments can ultimately have negative repercussions for organizing.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Redwine:</strong> First and foremost, it’s really important to remember that the things that people in power say do not matter. All of the power that you have doesn’t come from people at the top giving it to you. It comes from linking arms with the people next to you and taking that power and influence for yourself. (<em><strong>Timestamp: 28:27)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<p> <div embedded-video-placeholder="603fcd9c303d501d18130c54" post-id="2120478"></div> </p>
<p><a href="https://otter.ai/u/i0DkDLOSHPirJCiNuUEGKrr4SaU">You can read the entire transcript here.</a></p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier &#8220;how-to&#8221; event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear firsthand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product-market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in &#8212; there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-rise-of-the-tech-workers-union-and-what-comes-next/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121318</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
