<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 11:51:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Mesh Payments racks up $50M to help corporate users manage spend and payments</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/mesh-payments-racks-up-50m-to-help-corporate-users-manage-spend-and-payments/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/mesh-payments-racks-up-50m-to-help-corporate-users-manage-spend-and-payments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 11:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bill.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entreé Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[falcon edge capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hippo insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Curtius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mesh payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monday.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetSuite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quickbooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TLV Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel expenses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Now that the world appears to have settled longer-term into working in a significantly more distributed way in the wake of Covid-19, companies are getting more serious about using tools to manage how their teams operate within those new parameters. Today, a startup that&#8217;s addressing that challenge and how it relates specifically to expenses is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Now that the world appears to have settled longer-term into working in a significantly more distributed way in the wake of Covid-19, companies are getting more serious about using tools to manage how their teams operate within those new parameters. Today, a startup that&#8217;s addressing that challenge and how it relates specifically to expenses is announcing some funding.</p>
<p><a href="https://meshpayments.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mesh Payments</a>, which provides a platform for companies to oversee and manage employees&#8217; expenses, and for employees themselves to better track and manage how and where they spend money, has raised $50 million. It plans to use the funding to continue expanding the functionality of its platform, as well as for further business development. It&#8217;s been on a growth boom in the last nine months, growing tenfold in that period, it said.</p>
<p>The round, a Series B, is being led by the very prolific Tiger Global, with participation also from Entrée Capital and Falcon Edge Capital, as well as past backers TLV Partners and Meron Capital. Mesh Payments &#8212; founded in Israel and now headquartered in New York &#8212; had previously raised $13 million, and it is not disclosing valuation.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247053" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Currently the company&#8217;s tools cover areas like travel expenses, spend cards and other forms of spend management, but potentially the more interesting aspect of how Mesh works lies in its name.</p>
<p>Mesh Payments&#8217; platform integrates with various other pieces of software and apps that a company might use to run its business, and continually scans that network to determine whether a particular purchase is a useful one, or one that might be overlapping with something that already exists, not to mention not in line with other parts of a company&#8217;s specific expenditure policy.</p>
<p>&#8220;We start with the notion that there is different context to different kinds of spend,&#8221; Oded Zehavi, co-founder and CEO of Mesh Payments, said in an interview. &#8220;The process for a trip versus software differs, so we started building models for these unique cases.&#8221;</p>
<p>Today, the platform integrates with the likes of QuickBooks, Slack, Netsuite, Xero, G Suite from Google, and more. &#8220;We are adding more connectors to connect data from organizations&#8217; services on the cloud to be exposed to more company behavior,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The combination of that data and the intelligence that we designed in a more superior way is what sets us apart.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>So, for example, if an employee suddenly decides to set up an iCloud storage subscription, Mesh would scan the network to determine if that fits with corporate policy, and would also set out to see if the organization already has an account with another cloud storage company. If either of those questions raises a flag, the purchase is flagged, too.</p>
<p>Employees get notifications of these, and so to spend managers on the finance team. It&#8217;s up to the finance team to decide how strict they would like the policy to be: whether purchases are blocked, or rejected in the aftermath, or issued with a warning/alert.</p>
<p>Understandably, the system requires some substantial onramping from customers: they have to already be working in a digital enough way in order for Mesh&#8217;s modelling to work to its best ability. So unsurprisingly, the current customer list is heavy with technology companies, which are already working in the cloud and thus representing an easy port to working with Mesh: Monday.com, Hippo Insurance, Sezzle, Riskified and Snyk are on the list.</p>
<p>As recent rounds for Pleo (which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/pleo-picks-up-200m-at-a-4-7b-valuation-to-build-the-next-generation-of-business-expense-management/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised at a $4.7 billion valuation</a> just last week) and Soldo (which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/soldo-raises-180m-for-its-expense-management-platform-for-businesses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $180 million in July</a>) show, there is currently a huge appetite in the market for better and more updated tools for managing expenses, both at a time when employees may be needing to spend more independently than before because of how they&#8217;re working, but also because companies are simply looking to get smarter and to better grips with the systems and financial management they have in place.</p>
<p>Mesh&#8217;s focus on larger businesses gives it a very wide funnel, targeting an area that has been particularly rife with legacy tools from companies like SAP (although to be fair they are all focusing on improving user experience and tapping into modern technology more).</p>
<p class="p3">Nevertheless, it&#8217;s a massive opportunity that is likely to stay, just like at least some of our newly-distributed working practices.</p>
<p class="p3">&#8220;Mesh Payments is an example of a true disruptor &#8212; a company who&#8217;s innovations are transforming an already-established industry,&#8221; said John Curtius, a partner at Tiger Global who led this investment, in a statement. &#8220;We&#8217;re proud to support a business that continues to deliver on its ambitions, and we look forward to helping Mesh modernize the payments space even further.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/mesh-payments-racks-up-50m-to-help-corporate-users-manage-spend-and-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247053</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google-backed neobank Open acquires Finin for $10 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/google-backed-neobank-open-acquires-finin-for-10-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/google-backed-neobank-open-acquires-finin-for-10-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 11:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temasek]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247047</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Open has acquired consumer neo-banking startup Finin for $10 million as the Bangalore-based, Google-backed business-focused neobanking platform looks to broaden its offerings and deepen relationships with banks. The deal involves both cash and stock, the two said. Launched in 2019, Finin is among the first consumer-focused neobanking startups in India. The startup, which had raised [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Open has acquired consumer neo-banking startup Finin for $10 million as the Bangalore-based, Google-backed business-focused neobanking platform looks to broaden its offerings and deepen relationships with banks.</p>
<p>The deal involves both cash and stock, the two said. Launched in 2019, <a href="https://finin.in">Finin</a> is among the first consumer-focused neobanking startups in India. The startup, which had raised about $1 million from Unicorn India Ventures and others, will see key executives including the founder and chief executive Suman Gandham move to Open.</p>
<p>Anish Achuthan, co-founder and chief executive of Open, told TechCrunch in an interview that the acquisition of Finin compliments Open&#8217;s broader offerings.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247047" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><a href="https://open.money/">Open</a>, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/google-and-temasek-back-indian-neobank-open-in-100-million-fundraise/">recently received the backing from Google and Temasek</a>, operates an SME banking platform and also provides banks with infrastructure to launch their own digital banks. Over a dozen banks today use Open’s infrastructure to offer their banking services. Open currently has partnerships with 14 banks in India and a few more in Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>Finin offers a savings account that allows consumers to save and invest their money.</p>
<p>“Finin complements our offerings to banks. We will now help banks launch their own consumer-focused neobanking offerings under their own brand names,” he said. “There are many banks that are looking to launch their own modern platforms.”</p>
<p>Open still plans to continue to focus on its enterprise offerings to banks and isn’t looking to launch a consumer-focused neobanking service, he said. “Direct-to-consumer is not in our DNA,” he said. “But as part of our SME offerings such as payroll management, we may complement some B2C features.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“When we first launched Finin, I promised my squad that we would make a hallmark in the fintech industry, and show Indian consumers what neo-banking can really do for them,” said Gandham in a statement.</p>
<p>“Now with the acquisition by Open, I’m absolutely convinced that we are speeding towards that goal. The outcome of a consumer-facing neo-banking platform working hand-in-hand with a B2B neo-banking platform is going be exemplary as we will be able to add a lot of value to Open’s SMEs wanting to open salary accounts for employees, expose consumer banking rails to fintechs using Open’s embedded finance platform Zwitch, and also add value to banks wanting to launch digital banking propositions using Open’s cloud native digital banking OS BankingStack.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/google-backed-neobank-open-acquires-finin-for-10-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247047</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Superside nabs $30M to connect and manage freelance creatives working with in-house marketing and design teams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/superside-nabs-30m-to-connect-and-manage-freelance-creatives-working-with-in-house-marketing-and-design-teams/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/superside-nabs-30m-to-connect-and-manage-freelance-creatives-working-with-in-house-marketing-and-design-teams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 10:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creative tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delivery Hero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lugard Road Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oslo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prosus Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Superside]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upwork]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As advertising and marketing become increasingly automated and thus commoditized, design has emerged as a savior to help brands stand out. And today, a startup that&#8217;s helping companies connect with a wider range of designers and other creatives to meet that demand is announcing a round of funding to fuel its business growth. Superside, which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As advertising and marketing become increasingly automated and thus commoditized, design has emerged as a savior to help brands stand out. And today, a startup that&#8217;s helping companies connect with a wider range of designers and other creatives to meet that demand is announcing a round of funding to fuel its business growth. <a href="https://www.superside.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Superside</a>, which operates a network of freelance creatives that are tapped by companies to work on logos, display ads, packaging, bigger marketing campaigns and other design-based efforts, has picked up $30 million, money that it will be investing in further international expansion and growing its team of people, both in-house staff and the creatives network.</p>
<p>Prosus Ventures and Lugard Road Capital are co-leading the round, with previous investors Slack Fund and Acequia Capital also participating. Investors and company would not confirm but I understand from sources to be just over $400 million.</p>
<p>The round is the first sizable funding that Oslo-based, but very distributed, Superside has raised &#8212; it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/05/superside-konsus-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">founded as Konsus back in 2015 and had picked up only $5.5 million</a> up to now &#8212; and it comes on the heels of some impressive growth in its nearly-bootstrapped state.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247042" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Its customers include the likes of Amazon, Facebook, Salesforce, Cisco, Shopify and Coinbase, &#8220;Really any hot company in the Valley,&#8221; Fredrik Thomassen, Superside’s co-founder and CEO, told me in his understated, Norwegian-accented clip the other day. (This helps downplay the words, which come off as matter-of-fact rather than boastful as a result.) You&#8217;d think that a company like Amazon or Facebook would have no end of people on in-house teams to handle whatever design need might arise, but in fact, no matter how big or small an organization is, there is always something that will need an extra pair of creative hands, especially these days. Superside provides them.</p>
<p>Those hands, meanwhile, are set to multiply. Thomassen tells me that the company currently has 500 on its &#8220;team&#8221; &#8212; his word to include both those working on staff (150 people) and the wider creatives network (350).</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s important for us to think of us all in the same boat and creating equal opportunities globally,&#8221; he said. Creatives are freelancers technically, though, and thus free to do whatever they want, although the idea, he said, is that Superside provides them with enough engagement, interesting work, and non-frustrating tools to manage it all to make it less likely that they would turn to 99designs, Fiverr, Upwork, or any of the other platforms that might provide them with gigs elsewhere.</p>
<p>The plan will be to expand that network in earnest in the coming months. &#8220;We want to go from 350 to 1,000 creatives,&#8221; he said, &#8220;and then maybe 10,000, or 100,000.&#8221; (Again, you have to read this thinking of Thomassen&#8217;s understated clip, which makes all this sound perfectly reasonable.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Design &#8212; and in this case branding, advertising and other fields that have been described traditionally in the industry as &#8220;creative&#8221; work done by creatives &#8212; has faced a massive evolution in the digital age: most if not all work is carried out on software; more often than not, it is intended to be consumed on digital screens; and the nature of global, localized campaigns created by virtue of digital mediums mean that there is simply a lot more creative work needing to be done.</p>
<p>Added to this, even before the Covid-19 pandemic, designers long ago cut their tether to the office, working remotely, putting in extra hours at home even when they do not, picking up side-hustles where they never meet clients in person, and so on.</p>
<p>All of this has played neatly into the creation of really excellent design software, designed to be used, edited, shared and consumed in the cloud, and it&#8217;s played neatly too into the hand of companies like Superside to build platforms to help connect creatives to opportunities.</p>
<p>Superside itself has focused its technology development on making that engagement and following through on work as seamless as possible, with very specific project management software that it has designed itself to manage the processes, including remuneration and related accounting alongside the steps around seeking people, engaging them and working through projects. It has not built design tools up to now, and it has no plans to.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are using exclusively established tools,&#8221; said Thomassen. &#8220;It&#8217;s much more difficult to built competitors to companies like Figma and Adobe. We are incredibly bullish on Figma especially, since it&#8217;s a less closed system than Adobe&#8217;s.&#8221;</p>
<p>It will be interesting to see whether Superside sticks to that, or whether it becomes an attractive company to tap for those big firms that are taking on Adobe and building more bridges to creatives alongside the creative tools themselves. (Adobe&#8217;s ownership of Behance, which gives it a kind of link into those networks of creatives already, implies it might not be in the running if that were the case.)</p>
<p>In the meantime, what sets the company apart is how well it has identified the shortcomings of working with alternatives &#8212; Thomassen himself comes from a marketing background and said he built Superside specifically out of his own frustrations in trying to find, engage and work with creatives &#8212; and built a platform to solve that.</p>
<p>“What sets Superside apart from all the other players in the creative economy is their long-term approach to solving the underlying problems of marketing and creative teams,” said Mats Diedrichsen, the former CMO of Delivery Hero, who is joining the board with this round. “I believe Superside has the potential to become the ‘agency-killer’ while truly levelling the playing field for creatives all over the world.”</p>
<p>Superside has seen significant growth in the last few years, working with reputable brands, including Amazon, Salesforce and Cisco, who have consistently praised Superside’s fast turnaround times, creative diversity, high-quality content, and impressive access to global top talent.</p>
<p>Long-time customer Amir Jaffari, Growth lead at Shopify summarized: “Superside makes it easy for Shopify&#8217;s Growth team to get design done quickly without impacting the quality. Their platform is intuitive and enables speed, and the dedicated team model ensures everyone thoroughly understands our brand and day-to-day needs, allowing for scale.”</p>
<p>“As the need for high-quality, fast-turnaround digital content continues to rise, and companies look for increasing brand distinction, Superside is fulfilling the demand by offering a unique subscription that provides fast, flexible and diverse design from some of the world’s top creative talent,&#8221; added Sandeep Bakshi, head of European investments at Prosus Ventures, in a statement. &#8220;In addition, as the the pandemic has accelerated the momentum of flexible and independent work, Superside is highly attractive for creative team members, offering remote, flexible, and high paying jobs, allowing them to work with top brands globally. We believe Superside can usher in a new era of creative solutions for top companies globally, and are excited to partner with them on this vision.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/superside-nabs-30m-to-connect-and-manage-freelance-creatives-working-with-in-house-marketing-and-design-teams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247042</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BHub secures $20M to become LatAm companies’ back-office administrator</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/bhub-secures-20m-to-become-latam-companies-back-office-administrator/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/bhub-secures-20m-to-become-latam-companies-back-office-administrator/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 10:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bookkeeping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clocktower Technology Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jorge Vargas Neto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monashees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Picus Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[QED Investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rappi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Valor Capital Group]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Company owners can integrate BHub with their financial systems and view everything through one financial dashboard.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://bhub.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BHub</a> announced Tuesday that it took in a new round of capital just three months after receiving <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/funding_round/bhub-ai-pre-seed--190bf1a0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$4.4 million in pre-seed investment</a> to offer full back-office SaaS for small and medium businesses in Latin America.</p>
<p>Monashees and Valor Capital Group are doubling down on their investment in the company by leading an inside round of $20 million in Series A funds that included QED Investors, Picus Capital and Clocktower Technology Ventures.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246866" style="width: 328px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246866" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2246866" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bhub.jpeg?w=318" alt="BHub" width="318" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bhub.jpeg 599w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bhub.jpeg?resize=70,150 70w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bhub.jpeg?resize=140,300 140w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bhub.jpeg?resize=318,680 318w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bhub.jpeg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 318px) 100vw, 318px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246866" class="wp-caption-text">BHub&#8217;s mobile dashboard. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> BHub</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246863" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Founded in June, the Brazil-based company provides what it calls “back-office-as-a-service,” which includes bookkeeping, CFO services, legal and HR services so entrepreneurs can focus on their core business, Jorge Vargas Neto, founder and CEO of BHub, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>BHub is Neto’s third company and his third in the financial sector. He was previously CEO of Zen Finance, which was sold to Rappi in 2020, and Biva, which sold to PagSeguro in 2017, he said. While integrating with Rappi, Zen Finance was told by its accounting firm that it had to pay capital gains taxation, which ended up requiring the company to redo all of its bookkeeping in 10 days.</p>
<p>“It was hellish, but I’m grateful for that experience because I became passionate about how I could help people avoid the same hurdles in Brazil and Latin America,” Neto added. “We tested the market by inviting entrepreneurs to talk about their hurdles of administering business. Some 500 people RSVP’d, and we ended up doing 300 interviews that enabled us to see the pain points and to come up with our vision for a solution.”</p>
<p>For a monthly subscription starting at $349, company owners can integrate BHub with their financial systems and view everything through one financial dashboard that includes a chat function for requesting reports, solving queries and any other activities.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Neto explained that in Brazil, hundreds of thousands of businesses closed in 2020, driven partly by the global pandemic and partly by little financial literacy. Brazilian legislation requires every business owner to have a third-party accountant. The market is reserved for them, and they are protected by the law, “so they don&#8217;t have to be that good,” he added. Where the typical accounting firm doesn’t use much technology, this is BHub’s “magic spot,” to provide a service based on a technology approach and with startups in mind, he said.</p>
<p>The Series A came fast for the company due to a combination of factors: achieving early product market fit, steady growth over a period of three months and high referral rates by customers.</p>
<p>The company counts 134 companies as customers and looks to hire 100 people across engineering, technical, accounting, legal, human resources, marketing and customer service.</p>
<p>“Considering the growth we’ve had and what we project we will do, we need to enhance the team of 51 people and grow to 2,000, 2,500 customers by next year,” Neto added. “We do think if we keep up the pace we will get there.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="b6wnJt70ri"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/5-factors-that-can-make-or-break-a-startups-growth-journey/">5 factors that can make or break a startup&#8217;s growth journey</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 factors that can make or break a startup&#8217;s growth journey&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/5-factors-that-can-make-or-break-a-startups-growth-journey/embed/#?secret=b6wnJt70ri" data-secret="b6wnJt70ri" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/bhub-secures-20m-to-become-latam-companies-back-office-administrator/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246863</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weather-focused IBISA raises seed round to back its microinsurance solutions for low-income small farmers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/weather-focused-ibisa-raises-seed-round-to-back-its-microinsurance-solutions-for-low-income-small-farmers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/weather-focused-ibisa-raises-seed-round-to-back-its-microinsurance-solutions-for-low-income-small-farmers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AgTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emerging markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insurtech Gateway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luxembourg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rockstart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Agricultural microinsurance startup IBISA raised a seed round of approximately $1.70 million led by London-based Insurtech Gateway, with participation from Rockstart’s AgriFood fund and others.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Agricultural microinsurance startup <a href="https://ibisa.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IBISA</a> announced that it has raised a seed round of €1.5 million – approximately $1.70 million. The round was led by London-based specialized investor Insurtech Gateway, with participation from Rockstart’s AgriFood fund and others.</p>
<p>Microinsurance typically refers to offering coverage to low-income people against a specific class of risks. In IBISA&#8217;s case, these are small farmers whose livelihoods might be affected by adverse climate events, which are unfortunately <a href="https://www.un-ilibrary.org/content/books/9789210054478" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on the rise</a>.</p>
<p>While based in Luxembourg, the startup is focused on emerging markets, with a partnership-based approach. &#8220;We work with mutuals, insurers, microfinance institutions, research institutions, farmers and breeders associations and governments,&#8221; its site explains.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246798" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Since being founded in 2019, the company has worked with partners in the Philippines, India, and Niger. It now plans to use its funding to hire and expand its presence in existing and new markets.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s easy to see why farmers might be relieved to get compensated when their crops get damaged. But there are also several reasons for them not to have agricultural insurance – most of them don&#8217;t, according to IBISA. On one hand, options might be too costly; on the other, paperwork to claim a payout might be too daunting.</p>
<p>This is where technology comes in: IBISA&#8217;s payouts are meant to be quick and hassle-free, because rather than requesting individual claims, it relies on a collective index. That&#8217;s index-based insurance, also known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parametric_insurance" target="_blank" rel="noopener">parametric insurance</a>, since payouts are triggered by a certain parameter – for instance, notice of catastrophic weather events.</p>
<p>This approach also helps reduce operating costs on the insurer&#8217;s side, making lower rates worth offering, said Insurtech Gateway&#8217;s co-founder Stephen Brittain.</p>
<p>&#8220;Historically, microinsurance was not commercially viable due to many reasons such as low premiums, expensive claims handling, challenging distribution and a lack of trust.&#8221;</p>
<p>What changed? Again, technology.</p>
<p>If IBISA and others put trust into an index, it&#8217;s because it is supported by data. Its co-founder and CEO María Mateo Iborra worked for several years in the satellite industry, and a key element of the startup&#8217;s approach is its reliance on orbit images to assess damage. In addition, it relies on crowdsourced data from local &#8216;watchers.&#8217;</p>
<p>Spacetech and crowdsourcing aside, there&#8217;s also a blockchain element to IBISA, which sees it <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jhXJHRbvEaA&amp;t=969s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">as a way to keep costs low</a>. Its name actually stands for &#8220;Inclusive Blockchain Insurance Using Space Assets,&#8221; and it has been <a href="https://blockis.eu/2021/03/16/block-is-innovator-ibisa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">accelerated</a> by the European Union’s blockchain-focused project Block.IS.</p>
<p>The company also recently <a href="https://twitter.com/rockstart/status/1463873090228822017" target="_blank" rel="noopener">presented itself</a> at Rockstart&#8217;s AgriFood demo day. At the time of joining the program last September, IBISA&#8217;s co-founder Jean-Baptiste Pleynet <a href="https://www.facebook.com/rockstart/photos/a.260435713990127/4743682128998774/?type=3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">made mention</a> of IBISA&#8217;s insurance, satellite and blockchain components, as well as of its potential to drive positive impact.</p>
<p>But Pleynet also emphasized an interesting point of synergy: &#8220;We believe our solution will be very valuable for the food industry to bring resilience to the supply chain and manage climate risks and we wanted to accelerate this path,&#8221; he explained.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/weather-focused-ibisa-raises-seed-round-to-back-its-microinsurance-solutions-for-low-income-small-farmers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246798</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>E-scooter company Tier acquires Wind Mobility&#8217;s Italian subsidiary</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/e-scooter-company-tier-acquires-wind-mobilitys-italian-subsidiary/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/e-scooter-company-tier-acquires-wind-mobilitys-italian-subsidiary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 09:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-scooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tier Mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vento Mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wind Mobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tier, a Berlin-based e-scooter company that&#8217;s quickly expanding throughout Europe, has acquired Vento Mobility, the Italian subsidiary of Wind Mobility. The companies are not sharing the terms of the deal, but it will mark Tier&#8217;s entry into the Italian market. Just last month, Tier also acquired Nextbike, a German bike-sharing platform, a move to both [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tier, a Berlin-based e-scooter company that&#8217;s quickly expanding throughout Europe, has acquired Vento Mobility, the Italian subsidiary of Wind Mobility. The companies are not sharing the terms of the deal, but it will mark Tier&#8217;s entry into the Italian market.</p>
<p>Just last month, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/e-scooter-startup-tier-buys-nextbike-to-double-down-on-commitment-to-e-bikes/">Tier also acquired Nextbike</a>, a German bike-sharing platform, a move to both become multi-modal and further consolidate its micromobility empire. Since its founding, Tier has also acquired Makery, a provider of digital services like product strategy, design and management, engineering, testing and quality, training and support, and staff augmentation, as well as Pushme, a battery swapping company.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">On the Wind side of things, the company also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/russian-tech-giant-yandex-expands-israeli-footprint-with-acquisition-of-winds-tel-aviv-operations/">recently sold off its Israeli operations to Yandex</a>, the Russian tech giant, so it&#8217;s possible Wind is succumbing piece by piece to the inevitable industry consolidation. The company has raised a total of $72 million; its last funding round was a Series A back in 2019. Tier, for comparison, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/tier-scoots-off-with-first-close-of-its-200m-series-d/">raised $200 million as only part of its Series D round in October</a>, bringing its total funding up to around $647 million.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246953" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Wind did not respond to TechCrunch&#8217;s inquiry for more information about its strategy moving forward.</p>
<p>As of Tuesday, the first Tier e-scooters will be available on the streets of Bari and Palermo, with other Italian cities to follow in the coming days and weeks, according to the company. Tier is already present in 165 cities in 18 countries, offering its scooters that include an integrated helmet, turn signals on the handlebar and rear wing, and triple brakes with a large front wheel.</p>
<p>Wind&#8217;s Italian fleet had 4,500 e-scooters across 11 towns and cities in Italy. Tier did not respond to requests for more information about what would be done with those scooters, or if Tier would inherit all, or just some key members, of Wind&#8217;s Italian staff.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/e-scooter-company-tier-acquires-wind-mobilitys-italian-subsidiary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246953</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Struggling to win subscribers, Netflix cuts prices in India</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/struggling-to-win-subscribers-netflix-cuts-prices-in-india/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/struggling-to-win-subscribers-netflix-cuts-prices-in-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 08:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hotstar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prime video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nearly six years after Netflix launched its service in India, the global streaming giant is still struggling to find customers willing to pay for what is already its cheapest subscription globally. The American firm on Tuesday further lowered the subscription price in India, cutting each monthly subscription tier&#8217;s cost by at least 18% and up [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nearly six years after Netflix launched its service in India, the global streaming giant is still struggling to find customers willing to pay for what is already its cheapest subscription globally.</p>
<p>The American firm on Tuesday further lowered the subscription price in India, cutting each monthly subscription tier&#8217;s cost by at least 18% and up to 60.1%. The Netflix Basic plan, which permits streaming on any device but caps the resolution at 480p, now costs ₹199 ($2.6) in India, down from ₹499 ($6.6).</p>
<p>Netflix Standard, which improves the video resolution to HD (720p) and permits two simultaneous views, now costs ₹499, down from ₹649 ($8.5). Netflix Premium, which offers four simultaneous views and streams in UltraHD (4K) video quality, now costs ₹649, down from ₹799 ($10.5).</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247023" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>This isn’t the first time Netflix has played around with prices in India. In 2019, after months of testing, Netflix <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/netflix-launches-rs-199-2-8-mobile-only-monthly-plan-in-india/">unveiled a “mobile only” tier in India</a> in a global first that was priced at ₹199. That plan is now available for ₹149 ($1.96), Netflix said today. Existing subscribers on any tier will be able to switch to the new offerings, the firm said.</p>
<p>India is one of the world’s largest entertainment markets. But Netflix has struggled to produce content that helps it court customers beyond a small circle of loud Twitter users in the country &#8212; despite <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/netflix-to-release-41-original-indian-shows-and-movies-this-year/">sinking nearly $1 billion on it to date</a>.</p>
<p>At the same time, Disney&#8217;s Hotstar continues to dominate the market &#8212; without much assistance from the Twitter crowd &#8212; thanks to a much larger ad-supported local content library, syndication deals with international giants such as HBO, as well as nearly all sports streaming rights. Their biggest challenger in the country remains YouTube, which per App Annie, reaches about half a billion users in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>At roughly $20 a year for the top offerings, Disney&#8217;s Hotstar as well as Amazon Prime Video are also much more affordable to customers in India.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Research firm Mobile Partners Asia estimates that India will have 89 million individuals who pay for subscription services by the end of this year, up from 57 million last year.</p>
<p>Tuesday&#8217;s price cut in India, for which Netflix offered no explanation, comes at a time when the streaming giant has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/netflix-is-raising-prices-on-most-of-its-plans-in-the-us/">raised the monthly tariff</a> in several parts of the world.</p>
<p><strong>Further reading</strong>: <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/how-netflix-fumbled-india?rc=48qqgg">How Netflix fumbled India</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/struggling-to-win-subscribers-netflix-cuts-prices-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247023</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fast groceries startup Grovy hopes Eastern Europe and sustainability will set it apart</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/fast-groceries-startup-grovy-hopes-eastern-europe-and-sustainability-will-set-it-apart/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/fast-groceries-startup-grovy-hopes-eastern-europe-and-sustainability-will-set-it-apart/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 08:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[central europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delivery Hero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distribution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eastern europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frankfurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prague]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warsaw]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246799</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yet another ‘quick commerce’ 15-minute groceries startup is hoping to make a name for itself in this space, adding to the myriad of companies currently crowding out this market. But Grovy is avoid the crowded cities of Western Europem, setting its sights on becoming a daily-delivery leader in the East. It’s now finalized a €3 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Yet another ‘quick commerce’ 15-minute groceries startup is hoping to make a name for itself in this space, adding to the myriad of companies currently crowding out this market. But <a href="https://grovy.store/en">Grovy</a> is avoid the crowded cities of Western Europem, setting its sights on becoming a daily-delivery leader in the East.</p>
<p>It’s now finalized a €3 million financing round led by Lighthouse Ventures to expand across Central and Eastern Europe, with offices already running in Prague and Bucharest, after entering the German market in Frankfurt and Mainz.</p>
<p>While many players rely on significant mark-ups, which can be as high as 20%, as well as low-paid gig workers, Grovy says it only employs full-time workers and leverages a 5% markup on deliveries, with a flat delivery fee that is waived for orders above €40.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246799" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It’s other schtick is sustainability, with deliveries only on bikes and EVs, discounts on “ugly” produce and soon-to-expire perishables (helping to cut down on food waste) and working with food waste startups such as <a href="https://toogoodtogo.com/">Too Good To Go</a>, while employing a carbon offset program.</p>
<p>Justin Adam, co-founder and CEO of Grovy said: “Frankfurt and Mainz, with their high demand for quick commerce solutions, served as the perfect sandbox. But rather than replicate our model in other German cities, we are bringing it to larger cities across the CEE region, where 10-minute delivery is still a novelty and the potential to scale is massive.”</p>
<p>Michal Zalesak, managing partner at lead investor Lighthouse Ventures said: “Grovy has made achievements in mere weeks that would take a normal grocery chain a year to accomplish. Despite enormous competitive pressures, their unique approach to quick commerce has landed them phenomenal success in Germany, and we want to support them as they take on Central and Eastern Europe’s cities.”</p>
<p>Grovy faces competition from Gorillas and Flink in Germany, Lisek in Warsaw, but tends to face only one-hour delivery competition from the likes of Bolt or Delivery Hero in most other European cities it’s operating in.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/fast-groceries-startup-grovy-hopes-eastern-europe-and-sustainability-will-set-it-apart/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246799</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fresha, a business platform for salons, spas and beauty and wellness pros, extends Series C by $52.5M at a $640M+ valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/fresha-a-business-platform-for-salons-spas-and-beauty-and-wellness-pros-extends-series-c-by-52-5m-at-a-640m-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/fresha-a-business-platform-for-salons-spas-and-beauty-and-wellness-pros-extends-series-c-by-52-5m-at-a-640m-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 07:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accounting software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beco Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fresha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maryland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quickbooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wix]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246481</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The beauty and wellness industry, annually worth some $4 trillion, is underpinned by tens of thousands of businesses and millions of professionals carrying out haircuts, treatments and workouts. Today, a company called Fresha, which provides a software stack to help them run those operations, is announcing new funding of $52.5 million to continue building out [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The beauty and wellness industry, annually worth <a href="https://www.glamourmagazine.co.uk/article/future-post-coronavirus-beauty-trends" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some $4 trillion</a>, is underpinned by tens of thousands of businesses and millions of professionals carrying out haircuts, treatments and workouts. Today, a company called <a href="https://www.fresha.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fresha</a>, which provides a software stack to help them run those operations, is announcing new funding of $52.5 million to continue building out its own business.</p>
<p>Fresha got its start, and is best known among its 60,000 customers, for its booking software, which it provides on a subscription-free basis, <a href="https://www.fresha.com/pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">charging</a> instead based on taking a cut on payments, or first-time bookings and marketing messages (if a customer chooses those latter two options). But its ambitions, co-founder and CEO William Zeqiri said in an interview, are to be the go-to destination for any digital tool that a salon or independent professional might need to run a business: like Shopify, LinkedIn, Wix, Square or QuickBooks, but tailored for the specific demands of beauty and wellness professionals.</p>
<p>&#8220;Stylists [and other beauty and wellness professionals] are not really trained in business management,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Our goal is to free that up and automate all aspects of their business.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246481" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Michael Lahyani and BECO Capital co-led the round, with previous backers General Atlantic, Partech, Target Global and FMZ Ventures also participating. Fresha has raised $182 million overall.</p>
<p>This latest funding is coming in the form of a Series C extension &#8212; Fresha <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/fresha-raises-100m-for-its-beauty-and-wellness-booking-platform-and-marketplace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised the first $100 million</a> in June of this year &#8212; and with it, the startup&#8217;s valuation has shot up to over $640 million. For context, the company previously had not disclosed its valuation, but Zeqiri confirmed that it increased significantly in the extension due to the company&#8217;s own growth in the last six months.</p>
<p>Beauty and wellness had a mixed bag of luck as the pandemic took hold across the world. People overall were going out a lot less, or not at all, and thus spending significantly more on products to treat themselves at home. But on the other hand, Covid-19 led to a lot of municipalities shutting down salons to help curb the spread of the virus; and in cases where they were open follow more restrictive protocols for the customers who did show up.</p>
<p>That presented an obvious challenge to a company like Fresha, built around the premise of providing appointment booking and payments for in-person, very physical businesses. However, like other tech companies that have carved out a niche for themselves in providing tools specifically catering to and mastering the needs of a specific service-industry vertical &#8212; Toast being on strong example &#8212; Fresha&#8217;s focus helped it identify the opportunity inherent in that challenge.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Today, Fresha&#8217;s tools include booking and point-of-sale payment software &#8212; used in some 120 countries with its biggest markets the U.S., the U.K., Canada, Australia, New Zealand and Europe, where it sees tens of millions of appointments booked monthly and has processed $15 billion in transactions to date.</p>
<p>But Zegiri said that with the big shift among Fresha&#8217;s customers to move more interactions and services online in the wake of Covid-19, Fresha has built a &#8220;Shopify&#8221; for beauty and wellness websites to sell goods and services (this is launching in the coming days). It&#8217;s now in the process of finishing up its &#8220;Wix&#8221; for designing sites.</p>
<p>&#8220;We want to build the Amazon of the beauty and wellness industry, with a full suite of services that compete at every level, and in all markets,&#8221; he said. That will include marketing, and marketing automation tools, and more down the line, he said. It will in the meantime face a pretty big army of competitors, from Square through to Booksy, Phorest, Treatwell, SalonIQ and many others.</p>
<p>There has also been an interesting shift in the business models around beauty and wellness that has also played into Fresha&#8217;s hand, said Nick Miller, the company&#8217;s other co-founder and chief product officer.</p>
<p>Specifically, the pressures of the pandemic forced a lot of salons and brick and mortar businesses to downsize; or sometimes shut down altogether and &#8220;go mobile&#8221; where pro&#8217;s paid people home visits to carry out services.</p>
<p>Or, in cases where they were willing to stick it out and continue paying rent on premises, increasingly there was a move to models where pros were no longer directly employed by salons and spas, but rather hired out space within them to serve their own client lists; or some variation on that theme, for example staying on the books as contractors and sharing a common appointment book, but still &#8220;renting&#8221; the space to carry out work.</p>
<p>All of this presents a complex mix of new use cases, and customers, to sign on to a platform like Fresha&#8217;s, Miller noted.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s been one of the Covid effects,&#8221; he said. And because its users are not tech-interested in the main, the idea of using multiple services for different aspects of running their businesses, and &#8220;jumping to different platforms,&#8221; in his words, they appealed to Fresha to bring in the functionality that they wanted to have. &#8220;It was great timing for us,&#8221; Miller said.</p>
<p>Sadly, one of the other consequences of the pandemic has been the closure of a lot of small and independent businesses. Zeqiri noted that Fresha has had multiple offers from its customers to buy them up, but that&#8217;s not the core of how the startup sees itself growing: its aim is instead to build tools to make those businesses viable again, he said.</p>
<p>“Fresha has positioned itself as a major player in the beauty and wellness industry with a large and loyal customer base,” said Aaron Goldman, global co-head of financial services and MD of General Atlantic, in a statement. “We strongly believe in Fresha&#8217;s balanced strategy of providing one of the best products in the market at no cost to salons and then driving monetization via payments and value-added services.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/fresha-a-business-platform-for-salons-spas-and-beauty-and-wellness-pros-extends-series-c-by-52-5m-at-a-640m-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246481</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Topi is building a new payment solution designed for B2B transactions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/topi-is-building-a-new-payment-solution-designed-for-b2b-transactions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/topi-is-building-a-new-payment-solution-designed-for-b2b-transactions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 07:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[topi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meet Topi, a Berlin-based startup that raised a $4.5 million pre-seed funding round co-led by Index Ventures and Creandum. The company is working on a payment solution that is both fast and capital efficient for businesses. On the B2C front, consumer payments have evolved at a rapid pace over the last few years. When it’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Meet <a href="https://www.topi.tech">Topi</a>, a Berlin-based startup that raised a $4.5 million pre-seed funding round co-led by <a href="https://www.indexventures.com">Index Ventures</a> and <a href="https://www.creandum.com">Creandum</a>. The company is working on a payment solution that is both fast and capital efficient for businesses.</p>
<p>On the B2C front, consumer payments have evolved at a rapid pace over the last few years. When it’s time to check out, customers expect to be able to choose between several payment methods that all offer different advantages and drawbacks.</p>
<p>Usually you can pay with your debit or credit card, which could let you take advantage of some kind of insurance and accumulate points or cash back. You can also choose to pay with a digital wallet, like PayPal. Sometimes, you may choose to spread a big purchase over several months with Klarna, Affirm, Afterpay, etc.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246765" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>And yet, B2B transactions haven’t changed as much. Businesses often face a simple dilemma — they pay directly or they spend some time negotiating a financing offer. A supplier can offer some financing options directly. Sometimes companies ask their bank directly. In all cases, it’s a lengthy, bureaucratic and manual process.</p>
<p>Topi wants to reach the ideal Venn diagram of B2B payments —&nbsp;a payment solution that doesn’t require any paperwork, but a payment method with some financing offers. Topi thinks it can offer financing options of up to five years with instant approval.</p>
<p>“We’re building all of that ourselves. We’re building the first product right now and it’ll come on the market during the course of next year,” co-founder Estelle Merle told me.</p>
<p>This payment solution would be particularly useful for expensive purchases — a new machine, a big event or an upgrade for the restaurant kitchen. Topi expects to integrate its payment solution directly in the checkout flow of popular B2B merchants.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Many merchants already offer financing options, but they usually just link to a help page with some information to go further. “We’re digitizing this manual process and brining it straight to the point of sale,” Merle said.</p>
<p>This isn’t just a technical challenge as there’s some financial risk involved with SMB financing. The company wants to be able to make smart decisions without asking for too much input. A customer should be able to know if they are eligible for financing options in just a few minutes.</p>
<p>“We have an in-house risk team,” co-founder Charlotte Pallua told me. “What we don’t want to do is ask SMBs to upload financial statements from three years ago. Everything has to be digital.”</p>
<p>She then gave me some hints about data sources. For instance, Topi could get some sales data from a payment processor, or e-commerce performance from a Shopify account. With open banking rolling out across Europe, you could also imagine entering your business bank account login information to let Topi fetch the past few months of transactions.</p>
<p>In addition to Index Ventures and Creandum, several business angels invested in the startup, such as HelloFresh founder Dominik Richter, N26 founder Max Tayenthal, Adyen founding team member Thijn Lamers and WeFox founder Fabian Wesemann.</p>
<p>Topi’s two co-founders Charlotte Pallua and Estelle Merle originally met during their MBA at Harvard. Pallua spent some time working for Apple on financing programs while Merle has previously worked for Goldman Sachs and Via Transportation. Topi’s CTO Ernesto Jiménez worked for GoCardless and led a big engineering team there.</p>
<p>When you look further down the road, Topi’s vision goes beyond simplifying payments. If the startup manages to become an important brick in B2B transactions, companies who use Topi could end up spending a lot of time on Topi’s portal. They could see upcoming payments and manage early repayments.</p>
<p>But Topi’s portal could also become a SaaS product on its own. For instance, customers could choose insurance products from Topi directly. Once you control the customer relationship, there are a lot of possibilities to expand horizontally. And Topi is well aware of that opportunity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/topi-is-building-a-new-payment-solution-designed-for-b2b-transactions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246765</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VentureFriends raises $112M fund aimed at Southern Europe, Middle East and LatAm</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/venturefriends-raises-112m-fund-aimed-at-southern-europe-middle-east-and-latam/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/venturefriends-raises-112m-fund-aimed-at-southern-europe-middle-east-and-latam/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 07:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apostolos Apostolakis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B2B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daimler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delivery Hero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Investment Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[George Dimopoulos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greece]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LAUNCHub Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marathon Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketplaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Middle East]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proptech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united arab emirates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VentureFriends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warsaw]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Southern Europe has sometimes been seen as a little bit of a backwater in terms of venture capital funding. However, that has gradually started to change in recent years. Earlier this year Marathon Venture Capital in Athens raised a $47M fund. And LAUNCHub Ventures, is closing in on a €70 million final close. But today [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Southern Europe has sometimes been seen as a little bit of a backwater in terms of venture capital funding. However, that has gradually started to change in recent years. Earlier this year Marathon Venture Capital in Athens <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/greeces-marathon-venture-capital-completes-first-close-for-fund-ii-reaching-47m/">raised</a> a $47M fund. And LAUNCHub Ventures, is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/launchub-ventures-heading-towards-a-85m-fund-for-south-eastern-european-startups/">closing</a> in on a €70 million final close.</p>
<p>But today there’s news that <a href="https://venturefriends.vc/">VentureFriends</a>, a European early-stage VC that started from Athens but now has offices in London and Warsaw, has completed the first closing of its new fund at €90 million, with an aim for a hard cap at €100 million ($112M). This is the third fund for VentureFriends, which launched in 2016.</p>
<p>The new fund is backed by family offices/HNW, founders and operators, the European Investment Fund and the Hellenic Development Bank of Investments.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246842" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The Seed and Series A focus of the fund remains the same. It invests €500,000 to €2.5 million per company but can follow-on up to €10 million. It invests in B2C and B2B startups, including Consumer, PropTech, FinTech, Marketplaces, and SaaS.</p>
<p>VentureFriends’ portfolio includes proptech Blueground ($180 million Series C), grocery delivery marketplace Instashop in the Middle East (acquired by Delivery Hero), fintech B2B Belvo in Mexico ($43 million Series A), fintech Plum out of London ($20 million Series A) and FBA roll-up Factory14 from Spain ($200 million Seed). There is also FlexCar, Spotawheel, Justlife, Byrd, Agro.Club and Influ2. More recently, VentureFriends invested in the UAE proptech/fintech Huspy.</p>
<p>The VC also said it intends to invest beyond Europe, in Latin America, and the Middle East.</p>
<p>George Dimopoulos co-founder and Partner said: “Raising a private only fund in Greece in 2015 wasn’t easy. We have worked hard to prove the investment worthiness of the asset class in the region. We are now happy to have reached a point where we experience multi-hundred million exits as with Instashop, and companies reaching Unicorn status such as Blueground.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Apostolos Apostolakis, co-founder &amp; Partner at VentureFriends said: “We have steadily grown our presence and access to great entrepreneurs by providing relevant support and having a value-based and founder-friendly approach. We are excited about the first closing of our 3rd fund that hopefully is a testament of the work we have done and we look forward to expanding the network of entrepreneurs we will support.”</p>
<p>VentureFriends’s founders were previously entrepreneurs and angels, exiting e-food.gr to Delivery Hero in 2015 in which Apostolakis was a co-founder. They also exited taxi-hailing company Beat to Daimler in which both founding Partners were angels.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/venturefriends-raises-112m-fund-aimed-at-southern-europe-middle-east-and-latam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246842</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Warehouse robotics startup ForwardX raises $31M in first Series C close</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/forwardx-warehoue-robot-series-c1/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/forwardx-warehoue-robot-series-c1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 02:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5g]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JD.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semiconductor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ForwardX Robotics, a Beijing-headquartered company that makes autonomous mobile robots (AMR), said Tuesday it has closed the initial tranche of its Series C funding round as it looks to expand globally. The startup is fundraising for the rest of its Series C round at a time investors are courting warehousing and manufacturing robot makers in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.forwardx.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ForwardX Robotics</a>, a Beijing-headquartered company that makes autonomous mobile robots (AMR), said Tuesday it has closed the initial tranche of its Series C funding round as it looks to expand globally.</p>
<p>The startup is fundraising for the rest of its Series C round at a time investors are courting warehousing and manufacturing robot makers in China, the company&#8217;s chief operating officer Yaxin Guan told TechCrunch during an interview.</p>
<p>The new investment lifted ForwardX&#8217;s total raise to about $100 million since Nicolas Chee, a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicolas-chee-0352502a/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">former vice president at Oracle</a>, founded the company in 2016. The startup declined to disclose its post-money valuation or how much it plans to rake in for the entire Series C.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246434" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The C1 round was led by Taikang Life Insurance, a Chinese insurer, with participation from Qualcomm Ventures and Starlight Capital, an early-stage Chinese investment firm focused on industrial upgrades.</p>
<p>In 2014, Qualcomm <a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/news/releases/2014/07/23/qualcomm-commits-150-million-strategic-venture-fund-china" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that it had committed $150 million to fund Chinese startups advancing mobile technologies for the internet, e-commerce, semiconductor, health and education.</p>
<p>Having the chipmaking giant onboard will allow ForwardX to &#8220;work with a 5G technology leader to further advance the use of 5G in its smart warehousing and manufacturing projects,&#8221; the company said, though the startup is currently using chips from another major supplier.</p>
<p>With the new financial injection, the Chinese startup plans to accelerate its R&amp;D timeline, ramp up its deployment capabilities in &#8220;key markets&#8221; such as the U.S., and expand sales into new markets.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Most of its revenues currently come from China, with e-commerce powerhouse JD.com and logistics behemoth SF Supply Chain China, which has a partnership with DHL, being two of its main customers. The robot maker so far has accured more than 5 million picks for JD.com&#8217;s warehouses, according to Guan.</p>
<p>Like a few other <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/flexiv-100-million-series-b/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chinese robotics startups</a>, ForwardX is making a steady foray into overseas markets. It already opened an office in Tokyo, is on course to launch a U.S. branch and plans to enter Europe next year.</p>
<p>That means it&#8217;s coming after its American counterparts like Locus Robotics and 6 River Systems. To compete, the company claimed its solution requires less initial investment than its competitors due to &#8220;competitive hardware costs and a need for fewer robots per person in its solutions.&#8221; Its robots can carry up to 1,200 kilograms of goods each.</p>
<p>Aside from selling AMR solutions, ForwardX also touts a fleet management system that can determine how robots roam about within a warehouse, not unlike algorithms used by ride-hailing platforms to optimize driver productivity.</p>
<p>With help from its lidar- and deep learning-enabled robots, workers can spend more time picking than walking around, and new hires are spared from having to memorize where everything is within the warehouse, Guan explained.</p>
<p>Chinese tech companies are increasingly under scrutiny abroad by regulators. From a &#8220;business perspective,&#8221; Guan doesn&#8217;t see how U.S.-China tensions could hobble the firm&#8217;s U.S. expansion.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are even fewer people available in the U.S., so robots are what logistics customers need in the U.S.,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/forwardx-warehoue-robot-series-c1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246434</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The macro trends forcing change on the investment management industry</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/the-macro-trends-forcing-change-on-the-investment-management-industry/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/the-macro-trends-forcing-change-on-the-investment-management-industry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 01:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hedge fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural language processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2244087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Power in the investment management industry is shifting to the money holders from money managers, driven by several major economic, social and political trends.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">David Teten</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dteten">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		David Teten is founder of <a href="https://versatilevc.com/">Versatile VC</a> and writes periodically at <a href="https://teten.com/">teten.com</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/dteten">@dteten</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/the-peculiar-investment-management-industry/">The peculiar investment management industry</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/governments-should-invest-in-their-diaspora-founders/">Governments should invest in their diaspora founders</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Katina Stefanova</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/katinastefanova">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Katina Stefanova is CIO and CEO of <a href="https://www.martocapital.com/">Marto Capital</a>, a multistrategy asset manager based in New York that creates customizable investment solutions for institutional clients. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/the-peculiar-investment-management-industry/">The peculiar investment management industry</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Power in the investment management industry is shifting to the money holders from money managers, driven by several major economic, social and political trends.</p>
<p>Collectively, these are irresistible forces meeting a moveable object: the traditional asset management industry structure. Below are five key trends impacting the investment management industry.</p>
<h2>A new group of underserved customers</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/financial-services/our-insights/women-as-the-next-wave-of-growth-in-us-wealth-management">Women in the U.S. are expected to control as much as $30 trillion in assets</a> over the next three to five years, and <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research/report/millennials-and-the-future-of-wealth-management/">millennials $20 trillion</a> by 2030. The new decision-makers will expect the industry to reflect better gender balance and be more accessible.</p>
<p>Women and millennials tend to invest differently than the past generation of older men. Millennials are both <a href="http://spectrem.com/Content/Millennial-Investors-Have-Greater-Concern-Over-Social-Responsibility.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">more risk averse and more socially conscious</a> when selecting investments. In addition, because they came of age during the financial crisis, millennials have a negative perception of some of the traditionally dominant financial services companies. The change in the values of the investor base helps explains the popularity of ESG investing.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2244212" style="width: 1000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2244212" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2244212 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/image1-1.png" alt="power is moving from money managers to money holders" width="990" height="583" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/image1-1.png 990w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/image1-1.png?resize=150,88 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/image1-1.png?resize=300,177 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/image1-1.png?resize=768,452 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/image1-1.png?resize=680,400 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/image1-1.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 990px) 100vw, 990px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2244212" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> BCG Center for Sensing and Mining the Future</p></div></p>
<p>Additionally, allocators are becoming a lot less tolerant and unwilling to turn a blind eye toward toxic cultures of sexual harassment and discrimination, which have been tolerated at some largely male-led investment managers for years. Our view is that as the culture and preferences of allocators change, so will their investment criteria and the tolerance for bad behavior.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			VCs tout our industry as frontier technology investors, but many of us are using the same infrastructure tools we have used for the past 20+ years.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Millennials are, “inherently distrustful of authority so the traditional financial adviser model is not going to work for them,&#8221; said Suzanne Ley, formerly head of financial institutions at Westpac. &#8220;They demand complete transparency in all aspects of their life, so hidden/opaque fees structures are not going to be tolerated. They also have a high propensity to move jobs more frequently than past generations, so the portability of financial assets is going to be very important going forward,&#8221; she added.</p>
<h2>Geopolitical risk leads to capital flight</h2>
<p>Political volatility is not good for savers and allocators, as it tends to destroy asset value. The new cold war between the U.S. and China is ideological in part, but it is also in large part about technology dominance and cybersecurity.</p>
<p>The new cold war has only increased the movement of capital to regions of relative stability. The fear of totalitarian regimes or anarchy in China, Russia, the Middle East and South America has millions of well-educated and wealthy citizens looking to protect themselves and their nest eggs. We are seeing the first net private capital outflows in emerging markets due to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-emerging-markets-flows-idUSKBN26M5Q6">&#8220;risk-off&#8221; sentiment</a> and risk of rising rates in the U.S. and Europe. Even though the economic outlook in the U.S. is negative and the COVID-19 response inadequate, the country remains relatively stable. Together with places like Switzerland, Singapore and the U.K., the U.S. remains an attractive safe haven.</p>
<p>Pension funds and wealth management funds have a big opportunity in growing their footprint geographically. While traditional markets in Europe, the U.S. and Japan are saturated, India, for example, provides the perfect environment for the growth of a new wealth management industry. A combination of a strong middle and upper-middle class, well-educated professional class, a free-market economy and expansion of disposable wealth will drive demand for wealth management products, both in the institutional and retail spaces.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/the-macro-trends-forcing-change-on-the-investment-management-industry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2244087</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Max Q: Astra heads to the Space Coast</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/max-q-astra-heads-to-the-space-coast/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/max-q-astra-heads-to-the-space-coast/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 23:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Q]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2244782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Max Q! Happy December everyone. We&#8217;re officially nearing the end of the year, and what a year it&#8217;s been. Despite the ongoing effects of the COVID-19 pandemic, I think it&#8217;s pretty safe to say that this has been a watershed 365 days for the space industry. I can&#8217;t wait to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hello and welcome back to Max Q! Happy December everyone. We&#8217;re officially nearing the end of the year, and what a year it&#8217;s been. Despite the ongoing effects of the COVID-19 pandemic, I think it&#8217;s pretty safe to say that this has been a watershed 365 days for the space industry. I can&#8217;t wait to see what the next year has in store. OK, now onto the news!</p>
<p><em>Don’t forget to sign up to get the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">free newsletter version</a> of Max Q delivered to your inbox.</em></p>
<h2>Astra is heading to Cape Canaveral</h2>
<p>Fresh on the heels of its first successful launch to orbit, space startup Astra is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/06/astra-will-launch-a-rocket-from-cape-canaveral-in-florida-for-the-first-time-in-january/">heading to the Space Coast</a>. The company said it would carry CubeSats for NASA for its first mission to take place outside of Pacific Spaceport Complex Alaska on Kodiak Island. The launch, which is scheduled for January, will fly as part of a Venture Class Launch Services program contract Astra won last year.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2244782" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s a big win for the company. Multiple launch locations means Astra can finally demonstrate one of its key value propositions: that its on-site launch operations are agile, lightweight and can be effectively deployed from a number of sites. The Florida location will also give the company access to more orbits &#8212; which means being able to serve even more customers.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2028531" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2028531" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2028531" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/8E6A7661-5AD6-4F9A-9599-6A89CA5AF88D-scaled-1.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/8E6A7661-5AD6-4F9A-9599-6A89CA5AF88D-scaled-1.jpeg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/8E6A7661-5AD6-4F9A-9599-6A89CA5AF88D-scaled-1.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/8E6A7661-5AD6-4F9A-9599-6A89CA5AF88D-scaled-1.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/8E6A7661-5AD6-4F9A-9599-6A89CA5AF88D-scaled-1.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/8E6A7661-5AD6-4F9A-9599-6A89CA5AF88D-scaled-1.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/8E6A7661-5AD6-4F9A-9599-6A89CA5AF88D-scaled-1.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2028531" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> John Kraus / Astra</p></div></p>
<h2>Ursa Major wants to disrupt the vertically integrated rocket launch sector</h2>
<p>Ursa Major is scaling up its ambitions to disrupt the vertically integrated launch sector with a fresh round of funding. The company raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/ursa-major-raises-85m-to-disrupt-the-vertically-integrated-launch-sector/">an $85 million Series C</a> led by funds and accounts managed by BlackRock, as well as participation from XN, Alsop Louie, Alpha Edison, Dolby Family Ventures, KCK, Space Capital, Explorer 1, Harpoon Ventures and others.</p>
<p>The startup has already put its first product into production, a 5,000-pound thrust liquid oxygen and kerosene engine called Hadley, and it&#8217;s at work on the Ripley, the next-gen engine that’s 10 times more powerful than Hadley, with a 50,000-pound thrust.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>CEO Joe Laurienti likened Ursa Major to a company like Intel, which is constantly innovating more powerful processors and outsourcing that expertise to brands like Dell and Lenovo. “We really like the notion that we are a technology development company, and the companies that are flying rockets today should not be flying the same engine that they architected for their rocket 10 years ago. That’s the paradigm we see in vertical integration.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246155" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246155" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2246155" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/hadley_darkroom-1.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="569" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/hadley_darkroom-1.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/hadley_darkroom-1.jpeg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/hadley_darkroom-1.jpeg?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/hadley_darkroom-1.jpeg?resize=768,427 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/hadley_darkroom-1.jpeg?resize=680,378 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/hadley_darkroom-1.jpeg?resize=1536,854 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/hadley_darkroom-1.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246155" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://www.ursamajor.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ursa Major <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>Other news from TC and beyond</h2>
<p><strong>Astranis </strong>signed a $90 million agreement with Latin American telecom company Grupo Andesat to deliver broadband internet access to rural Peru. The first launch will take place in 2023.</p>
<p><strong>The Federal Aviation Administration </strong>will end its Commercial Space Astronaut Wings program at the beginning of 2022, citing the advent of commercial space tourism. Now, individuals who travel 50 miles above Earth will be recognized on the administration&#8217;s website.</p>
<p><strong>Loft Orbital </strong>raised $140 million in a new round of funding led by investment company BlackRock. The space infrastructure startup has already launched two spacecraft, and aims to use the funds to scale its business, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/12/07/space-company-loft-orbital-raises-140-million-from-blackrock.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CNBC reports</a>.</p>
<p><strong>NanoAvionics</strong> was awarded a mission contract from Los Alamos National Labs to build a small spacecraft about the size of a microwave. It will host instruments to measure diffuse gamma-ray background, a type of radiation.</p>
<p><strong>Planet Labs</strong> is officially a public company. It began trading on the Nasdaq under the ticker sybol $PL on Tuesday, after closing a merger with blank-check firm dMY Technology Group Inc. IV. Planet received around $590 million in proceeds and PIPE from the transaction.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Here we go! Today, we will be listed on the <a href="https://twitter.com/NYSE?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NYSE</a> as a Public Benefit Corporation, furthering our mission to use space to help life on Earth. <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24PL&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$PL</a> <a href="https://t.co/e7eTvSOOXz">pic.twitter.com/e7eTvSOOXz</a></p>
<p>— Planet (@planet) <a href="https://twitter.com/planet/status/1468565766270332939?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><strong>Rocket Lab </strong>has now deployed 109 satellites to orbit, after successfully delivering two satellites to orbit for geospatial intelligence company BlackSky. Rocket Lab also announced <a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/updates/rocket-lab-to-launch-three-dedicated-electron-missions-for-earth-imaging-company-synspective/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a three-launch deal</a> with Japanese Earth imaging company Synspective in 2022 and 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Tomorrow.ai</strong> is the space industry&#8217;s most recent company to announce a merger with a blank-check firm, in a deal that the startup says could inject it with up to <a href="https://www.pinetechnology.com/_files/ugd/462bf1_b55c1ddabdb34d7bac7907b1d17f5122.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$420 million in capital</a>. Tomorrow is aiming to operate a network of weather satellites and an intelligence platform for customers. It will merge with special purpose acquisition corporation Pine Technology Acquisition Corp.</p>
<h2>TC Sessions: Space is NEXT WEEK</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s finally (almost) here!!!! That&#8217;s right folks: TC Sessions: Space is set to kick off next week, December 14 and 15. It’s once again going to be an entirely virtual conference, so people from all over the world will be able to join — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=TCnewsletter&amp;tpcc=TCspacenewsletter">and you can, too</a>.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2159308" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png" alt="" width="1024" height="575" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></h2>
<h2><a href="http://www.techcrunch.com">Read more stories on TechCrunch.com</a></h2>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/max-q-astra-heads-to-the-space-coast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2244782</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A new growth equity outfit, Camber Partners, just raised $100 million to buy stranded SaaS startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/a-new-growth-equity-outfit-camber-partners-just-raised-100-million-to-buy-stranded-saas-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/a-new-growth-equity-outfit-camber-partners-just-raised-100-million-to-buy-stranded-saas-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 23:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Camber Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debut fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rembrandt Venture Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In recent years, enterprise software companies have grown faster, and more valuable, than ever. Still, most startups never reach that kind of escape velocity, with many plodding along while their venture backers &#8212; who are returning to market more quickly and raising bigger funds &#8212; move on to newer, shinier objects. The end result is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In recent years, enterprise software companies have grown faster, and more valuable, than ever. Still, most startups never reach that kind of escape velocity, with many plodding along while their venture backers &#8212; who are returning to market more quickly and raising bigger funds &#8212; move on to newer, shinier objects.</p>
<p>The end result is many thousands of stranded companies with a limited number of options. One of these is to simply shut down. Another option for some companies is buy back their shares. A third option for some is sell to a private equity firm that is interested in potentially rolling up sub-scale properties or bolting a startup onto another asset. There is so much opportunity for PE firms, in fact, that according to the Financial Times, the software-focused buyout firm Thoma Bravo plans to raise up to <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/456f2fd7-f868-4ea6-abd7-fce34e783333" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$35 billion </a>for its next fund.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, newer players are also getting in on the action. Among them is <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.camber.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Camber Partners</a>, a San Francisco-based growth equity firm founded last year by investor Scott Irwin, long of the venture firm Rembrandt Venture Partners.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246838" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Camber is today taking the wraps off a $100 million debut fund that promises to either buy &#8212; or buy a majority stake in &#8212; stranded SaaS companies, reinvigorate them with its own in-house data science technology, then sell them within what would ideally be around five years or less.</p>
<p>Irwin says he founded Camber Partners largely out of aggravation with the current venture environment, which requires that startups scale up unnaturally fast in order for VCs to return the massive amounts of capital they&#8217;ve been raising in recent years.</p>
<p>He says he grew tired of &#8220;some of those adverse incentives&#8221; involved. As he puts it, &#8220;100% growth isn&#8217;t interesting; it&#8217;s gotta be 200%. Earning $100,000 a month isn&#8217;t interesting; it has to be a million. A good solid management team that&#8217;s going to learn over time and grow the business isn&#8217;t interesting. It&#8217;s instead, &#8216;How do we jump ahead faster and hire more experienced people?'&#8221;</p>
<p>VCs have seen some &#8220;awesome successes because of the model but &#8220;the failure rate is also way higher.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As for Irwin&#8217;s alternative, he says that helped by co-founder and serial operator Jason Hable, along with Scott Ernst, Camber&#8217;s VP of data and engineer, the young outfit is positioned with a data platform called Gemini to isolate companies across the globe with a specific profile, then help fuel their growth. Its targets should make a &#8220;well-loved product&#8221; that enjoys &#8220;strong, organic inbound&#8221; interest from potential customers; they should be generating between $3 million and $10 million in annual recurring revenue; and they will be looking to overcome an &#8220;under-optimized go-to-market&#8221; strategy.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you feel like you haven&#8217;t fully realized the growth potential of the business, that&#8217;s a really good fit,&#8221; says Irwin.</p>
<p>Already Camber has backed two companies: Scout APM and SE Ranking. It spent $8 million to pick up a majority interest in Scout, which makes application performance software, along with a related business called ExceptionTrap.</p>
<p>It has not disclosed terms of its deal with SE Ranking, which makes SEO software, but Irwin says a typical investment will be &#8220;$10 million to $25 million checks.&#8221;</p>
<p>Altogether, Camber Partners expects to invest this first fund in six to seven companies.</p>
<p>As for exits, Irwin says he expects that they will look like typical SaaS exits, including sales (&#8220;full or partial&#8221;) to financial sponsors like Thoma Bravo or another active software investor, Vista Equity Partners. In some cases, if the stars align, he hopes initial public offerings will be in the cards.</p>
<p>Either way, &#8220;We don&#8217;t need 50 times our return,&#8221; says Irwin. &#8220;We try to get very aligned with a team that a $200 million exit can be life changing and a strong return for everyone involved.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not always an easy number to sell in today&#8217;s go-go market.</p>
<p>&#8220;The good thing about private equity interest in the space is that if investors want to accept it [a buyout proposal] and the management team wants to keep going, you can work that out,&#8221; says Irwin. &#8220;The challenge is when the investors are like, &#8216;Oh, yeah, $200 million just doesn&#8217;t move the needle for us. We&#8217;re not willing to accept that. You need to turn that down and go for a billion-dollar exit,&#8217; and then it turns out it&#8217;s a wipeout.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/a-new-growth-equity-outfit-camber-partners-just-raised-100-million-to-buy-stranded-saas-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246838</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Web3 project tool Thirdweb closes $5M round with help from Mark Cuban, Gary Vaynerchuk</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/daily-crunch-web3-project-tool-thirdweb-closes-5m-round-with-help-from-mark-cuban-gary-vaynerchuk/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/daily-crunch-web3-project-tool-thirdweb-closes-5m-round-with-help-from-mark-cuban-gary-vaynerchuk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 23:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for Monday, December 13! The theme of today is crypto, or web3 if you prefer that rebranding. Why? Because it turns out that an NFT project is making a game, a new startup wants to bring crypto and no-code together and there are several other bits of web3 startup news on our pages today.</p>
<p>Yes, we also have our normal run of funding rounds, unicorn exits and the like. But, strap in for some token talk! —<a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246819" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/12/chinas-ai-giant-sensetime-postpones-ipo-after-us-blacklisting/">Chinese AI IPO on hold:</a> </strong>The SenseTime IPO was set to raise around $767 million in a Hong Kong listing. However, after finding itself on an American technology blacklist as of Friday, the IPO is on hold. As Didi looks to delist from the American markets, seeing such a high-profile Hong Kong debut on hold is not a great look for Chinese tech liquidity.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/bored-apes-shoots-for-the-moon/"><strong>Bored Ape Yacht Club game?</strong></a> If you aren’t a fan of the Bored Ape Yacht Club NFT series — I am not, for what it’s worth — you may not be hype to hear it, but there’s a game coming from the image collection. If this is a hit, expect many games to be built atop other NFT IP. Quickly, I wonder what the market size is for this game, given that there are only 10,000 images in the series.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/cma-microsoft-nuance/">UK taking look at Microsoft-Nuance deal:</a></strong> A $19.7 billion deal between Microsoft and “speech-to-text specialist Nuance,” as TechCrunch put it, has picked up regulatory scrutiny by a U.K. watchdog. This is the prelude to an investigation, it appears, but the fact that Microsoft is even getting a second look could chill other large buys by the megacorps of the technology world.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>A few themes are obvious today, including the startup exit market and crypto. We’ll take those on first, and then close with the rest of the startup news of the day.</p>
<p><strong>Exits:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/what-2021s-ipo-pops-tell-us-about-future-flotations-and-spacs/">So much for that IPO pop:</a> </strong>A number of 2020 and 2021 IPOs had super strong first-day performances and early trading gains. This led to much complaining that tech offerings were being mispriced on purpose, to the benefit of banking customers. Well, we took a look back, and the numbers with a little time are far less clear than they once seemed.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/walmart-supported-symbotic-set-to-go-public-via-softbank-spac/"><strong>Robot company Symbotics to go public via SPAC:</strong></a> After securing greater commitment from huge American retailer Walmart, Symbotics has decided to pursue a public listing via a SPAC, or blank-check company. Notably the deal will see the robot firm link with Softbank Investment Advisers’ SVF Investment Corp. 3.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/harley-davidsons-ev-motorcycle-unit-livewire-to-go-public-via-spac/"><strong>E-motorcycle company LiveWire to go public via a SPAC:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Have you ever heard the pneumonia-rattle of a Harley-Davidson motorcycle? Well, it turns out that the company <em>also</em> makes electric bikes. Who knew! The deal, per TechCrunch, will allow Harley to hold onto a good stake in the company while also injecting capital into the business. We’re just glad that the company is making bikes that don’t sound like their engines are filled with used dentures.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>And then, crypto: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/gary-vaynerchuk-mark-cuban-web3-thirdweb/"><strong>Thirdweb raises $5M for the union of crypto and no-code:</strong></a><strong> </strong>What Thirdweb is doing sounds cool. TechCrunch reports that the company’s software helps “developers build, launch and manage their web3 projects without writing any lines of code.” Anything that makes tech more generally accessible is fine by us, including, yes, crypto.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/justin-kan-debuts-fractal-a-solana-based-marketplace-for-gaming-nfts/"><strong>Fractal is an gaming NFT marketplace built on Sol</strong><strong>ana:</strong></a> Did that make sense to you? If not, let me help. Fractal is a company that is building a market to sell gaming-related non-fungible tokens on the Solana blockchain, which rivals Ethereum and Bitcoin. How does gaming come into the speculative world of NFTs? Well, there are now play-to-earn games out there, where players are rewarded with NFTs instead of, say, internet points. So you can trade those on Fractal, I suppose.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/crypto-giant-dapper-labs-takes-its-next-shot-with-genies-nft-platform-the-warehouse/"><strong>NBA Top Shot takes another shot:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Dapper Labs became known as the team behind the NBA Top Shot NFT series that was hot a while back. Now the company — worth some $7.6 billion — is back with its next product called The Warehouse. I can’t really improve on what our own Lucas Matney wrote, so here it is: The Warehouse is “an ambitious NFT storefront that the startups hope will serve as a hub for web3 digital identity, allowing users to create animated avatars and outfit them with crypto accessories.” As with all crypto projects, I have no idea if this is going to be a hit or a flop.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The rest of it:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/former-twitter-india-head-leaving-firm-to-start-an-edtech/"><strong>Prior head of Twitter India is starting an edtech startup:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Twitter and India get along about as well as any authoritarian government does with the social network. But now the company’s former head in the country, Manish Maheshwari, is “leaving the firm to launch an edtech startup, according to nine people familiar with the matter.” Something to keep an eye on.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/snaplogic-raises-165m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-help-enterprises-integrate-and-automate-their-disparate-apps-and-data/"><strong>SnapLogic now worth $1B:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The NFT world may get more headlines than enterprise software lately, but that hasn’t stopped the more staid parts of startupland from still doing business. SnapLogic is indicative of that fact, raising $165 million at a new, higher valuation. The new unicorn helps companies bringing their work into the digital realm connect their various data sources and workflows.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/ex-snap-employees-raise-4m-for-conversational-commerce-startup-whym/"><strong>Weird startup names are still here:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Say hello to Whym, founded by ex-Snap employees. The startup is working on mobile e-commerce, a part of the larger digital purchasing world that could still use some work. I say that as someone who, at times, buys things on his phone and has dealt with all the fun that it entails. Whym just raised $4.3 million.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/notus-wants-to-suggest-the-best-ways-to-have-influence-and-then-scale-it/"><strong>Notus wants to help you find the right influencer for your brand:</strong></a> The world of influencer marketing has become mature enough that finding one’s next in-market avatar is now a business. Notus has raised $1.25 million to build a software service to help brands of all sorts find whom they should hire to rep their stuff. Neat!</li>
</ul>
<h2>Conversational UX: The missing piece in your chatbot strategy</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2246520" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246520" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2246520" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg" alt="Close​ up​ robot on a yellow background" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246520" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=krung99" target="_blank" rel="noopener">krung99 <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We don&#8217;t run many TechCrunch+ articles that are focused on basic best practices, but we make exceptions when it comes to posts about emerging technology — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/conversational-ux-the-missing-piece-in-your-chatbot-strategy">in this case, conversational UX.</a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s notoriously difficult for software to mimic human conversation. Many chatbots are so inept, it makes one long for the days of <em>press 0 for an operator</em>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Though chatbots are largely meant to handle simple customer service tasks, there is an opportunity to scale both customer service and sales messaging,&#8221; writes Raghu Ravinutala, CEO and co-founder of Yellow.ai, a conversational CX platform.</p>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/instagram-now-lets-users-reply-to-comments-with-reels/"><strong>Reply to that Instagram with a <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">TikTok</span> Reel:</strong></a><strong> </strong>TechCrunch noted today that Instagram, the Meta-built photo-sharing app, has introduced “Reels Visual Replies.” The feature will allow Instagram users to create short-form video replies to other posts. So it’s like personal gifs, I reckon. Which is cool if people use them. Let’s see.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/mozilla-expects-to-generate-more-than-500m-in-revenue-this-year/">Mozilla is a huge business:</a></strong> Sure, we moved to Chrome, but not <em>everyone</em> did. So many people, in fact, still use Mozilla products that the company should generate around $500 million this year. Not bad! And good news for browser competition.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Are you all caught up on last week’s coverage of growth marketing and software development? If not, read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/10/this-week-in-techcrunch-experts-international-expansion-2022-trends-boutique-software-devs/">here</a>.</p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03" target="_blank" rel="noopener">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/daily-crunch-web3-project-tool-thirdweb-closes-5m-round-with-help-from-mark-cuban-gary-vaynerchuk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246819</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nike acquires NFT collectibles studio RTFKT</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/nike-acquires-nft-collectibles-studio-rtfkt/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/nike-acquires-nft-collectibles-studio-rtfkt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 22:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adidas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[andreessen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CryptoPunks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RTFKT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nike is taking a plunge deeper into the world of crypto collectibles, announcing that they&#8217;re acquiring the NFT studio RTFKT (pronounced &#8220;artifact&#8221;). The acquisition announcement comes at an opportune time for the studio; RTFKT is currently behind one of the most talked-about NFT project drops of the month &#8212; a sweeping avatar partnership with artist [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nike is taking a plunge deeper into the world of crypto collectibles, announcing that they&#8217;re acquiring the NFT studio RTFKT (pronounced &#8220;artifact&#8221;).</p>
<p>The acquisition announcement comes at an opportune time for the studio; RTFKT is currently behind one of the most talked-about NFT project drops of the month &#8212; a sweeping avatar partnership with artist Takashi Murakami called CloneX. Since its initial drop less than three weeks ago, the project has already seen nearly $65 million in transaction volume according to crypto tracker <a href="https://cryptoslam.io/rtfkt-clonex-mintvial/sales/summary" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CryptoSlam</a>.</p>
<p>Terms of the acquisition were not disclosed. The startup raised an $8 million seed round back in May led by Andreessen Horowitz that valued the company at $33.3 million.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246884" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“This is a unique opportunity to build the RTFKT brand and we are excited to benefit from Nike’s foundational strength and expertise to build the communities we love,” RTFKT co-founder Benoit Pagotto said in a statement.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Adidas announced a partnership with NFT project Bored Apes Yacht Club.</p>
<p>In addition to building out its own NFT drops, RTFKT had collaborated with other crypto creators to design items like physical shoes that utilized imagery in other NFT projects, including CryptoPunks and Bored Apes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9WhfGRt4oR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/bored-apes-shoots-for-the-moon/">&#8216;Bored Apes&#8217; shoots for the moon</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;Bored Apes&#8217; shoots for the moon&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/bored-apes-shoots-for-the-moon/embed/#?secret=9WhfGRt4oR" data-secret="9WhfGRt4oR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/nike-acquires-nft-collectibles-studio-rtfkt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246884</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Honeycomb, a private social app for families, raises $4M seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/honeycomb-a-private-social-app-for-families-raises-4m-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/honeycomb-a-private-social-app-for-families-raises-4m-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[families]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honeycomb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peter boyce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo sharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stellation capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A women-led startup called Honeycomb is launching its private social app for families, backed by $4 million in seed funding led by Peter Boyce at Stellation Capital. Now out of private beta, the app offers families a way to curate and share their favorite moments and memories via their smartphone as an alternative to using [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A women-led startup called <a href="https://joinhoneycomb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Honeycomb</a> is launching its private social app for families, backed by $4 million in seed funding led by Peter Boyce at Stellation Capital. Now out of private beta, the app offers families a way to curate and share their favorite moments and memories via their smartphone as an alternative to using a more public social media platform, like Facebook, or group texting, where photos and videos can be easily lost.</p>
<p>Of note, Honeycomb is the first startup Boyce is backing with his <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/peter-boyce-stellation-capital/">new firm, Stellation Capital,</a> founded this year after he left General Catalyst. Other participants in the round include <a href="https://www.dcm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DCM</a> (Kyle Lui), <a href="https://www.blingcap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bling Capital</a> (Ben Ling) and <a href="https://precursorvc.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Precursor Ventures</a> (Charles Hudson), as well as angels including Ancestry CEO Deborah Liu, Giphy founder Alex Chung and Twitter VP of Engineering Nick Caldwell, formerly of Reddit.</p>
<p>Honeycomb itself was co-founded by CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/amelialin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amelia Lin</a>, previously of Udacity and Optimizely, and former Instagram product manager <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicolewee/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nicole Wee</a>. The co-founders had been inspired to create an app that would connect families through private social networking, but had originally approached this with a different product, called Saga. Their first app was a social audio experience that let families <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/mobile/turn-grandmas-memories-into-a-podcast-with-the-saga-app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">capture and record their life stories</a> &#8212; like tales about how the grandparents first met, for example, or even just birthday wishes for a child that can be listened to later, as a sort of audio diary.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246783" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>But while that app received <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnscottlewinski/2020/05/17/new-saga-app-lets-users-record-their-covid-18-tales-for-future-use/?sh=60a2b2d968ae">plenty</a> <a href="https://www.nbclosangeles.com/california-live/new-holiday-tech-toys-for-all-ages/2482335/">of</a> <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/mobile/turn-grandmas-memories-into-a-podcast-with-the-saga-app/">early</a> <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/columnist/2020/11/24/11-tech-tools-to-bring-joy-2020-holidays/6386052002/">press</a>, it wasn&#8217;t necessarily what families wanted. Instead, the team kept hearing from early adopters how they wanted to store their photos and videos, too, not just audio recordings. So the team pivoted and <a href="https://medium.com/joinhoneycomb/introducing-honeycomb-94395b5950f8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rebranded their app as Honeycomb</a> this past fall.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246837" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246837" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2246837" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-7.jpg?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-7.jpg 1242w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-7.jpg?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-7.jpg?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-7.jpg?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-7.jpg?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-7.jpg?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-7.jpg?resize=946,2048 946w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-7.jpg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246837" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Honeycomb</p></div></p>
<p>The new experience launched into private beta testing in September, offering a way for families to save their favorite photos and videos, which are combined with text and turned into a digital story of sorts. The experience as it stands today isn&#8217;t necessarily that much more robust compared with a group chat over iMessage, for instance, but it does offer an easy way to go back to revisit older shares which can be difficult to do when using text messaging. It also lets users set a reminder so they&#8217;ll remember to curate their favorite memories from the day &#8212; a feature that&#8217;s probably best for new parents who rapidly fill their phones with dozens of new photos daily as their baby hits new milestones.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246835" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246835" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2246835" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-5.jpg?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-5.jpg 1242w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-5.jpg?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-5.jpg?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-5.jpg?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-5.jpg?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-5.jpg?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-5.jpg?resize=946,2048 946w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-5.jpg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246835" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Honeycomb</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We help it become a really easy daily ritual of sorting through the best memories of the day,&#8221; explains Lin. &#8220;You pick your favorites and they automatically get compiled into this story that&#8217;s not only shared with your family, but also saved in this collection forever,&#8221; she says. However, she notes, the experience is not meant to replace users&#8217; existing photo services, like Google Photos, Apple&#8217;s Photos app or Dropbox, where people back up and save all their content &#8212; including duplicate photos and those that didn&#8217;t quite turn out well.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t think of that as being the curated, beautiful place that I interact with my family,&#8221; Lin says. &#8220;And then [users may have] Facebook and Instagram, but that feels really public to put my baby photos out on.&#8221; Honeycomb, by comparison, is private by default.</p>
<p>&#8220;Only your family gets to choose who is in here, and I do think that is a pretty different philosophical approach,&#8221; says Lin. Plus, she notes, &#8220;we don&#8217;t sell your photos or your data to third parties.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246834" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246834" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2246834" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-4.jpg?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-4.jpg 1242w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-4.jpg?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-4.jpg?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-4.jpg?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-4.jpg?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-4.jpg?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-4.jpg?resize=946,2048 946w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-4.jpg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246834" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Honeycomb</p></div></p>
<p>Honeycomb is also different from mainstream social apps because it will be a subscription-based service, not one that&#8217;s monetized through advertising. For now, however, the app is free as the startup gets the new app off the ground.</p>
<p>The company is working to address how to include the family&#8217;s elder users into the platform, which may include adding support for exporting its content to be shared elsewhere. But the team thinks that the draw of new baby and kid photos may be the push grandma or grandpa needs to figure out how to put the app on their phone &#8212; even if they&#8217;re not technically savvy.</p>
<p>After users download Honeycomb they&#8217;ll first gain access to a basic set of features. But soon, they&#8217;ll be opted into the new beta, which includes a more engaging story format for sharing memories with family and friends. (This opt-in won&#8217;t happen immediately, but is now rolling out, the company clarifies.)</p>
<p>The idea to return to human curation, not AI, to help users find their best photos and videos is certainly a different idea these days. But whether or not people want to sort through their daily snaps &#8212; especially after that &#8220;new baby&#8221; buzz wears off &#8212; remains to be seen.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246832" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246832" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2246832" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-2.jpg?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-2.jpg 1242w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-2.jpg?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-2.jpg?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-2.jpg?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-2.jpg?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-2.jpg?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-2.jpg?resize=946,2048 946w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/6-5-inch-Display-2.jpg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246832" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Honeycomb</p></div></p>
<p>Besides, AI can be useful. (Presumably, a smart AI would have known to feature a photo of a person, not a toy, as the cover photo after I made a birthday photo album in the app). AI can also help users automatically sort through photos by discarding those with poor lighting or bad exposure.</p>
<p>What users don&#8217;t want, generally, is having an AI have the final say on their &#8220;best&#8221; photos or putting together albums without any context about their lives and what they think is important. And they don&#8217;t want AI reminding them through automated &#8220;memories&#8221; of times they&#8217;d rather forget.</p>
<p>The best solution, however, may be a balance between AI and manual curation, but done in a private, social environment.</p>
<p>Because Honeycomb is effectively a new app, the startup isn&#8217;t sharing user figures. But Lin notes that engagement tripled since pivoting from Saga.</p>
<p>&#8220;Honeycomb is a truly mission-driven company, using technology to advance one of our most basic and long-standing human desires: to archive and share our family’s memories,&#8221; said Stellation&#8217;s Peter Boyce about his investment in the startup. &#8220;Honeycomb has the potential to bring the family album into the 21st century. It’s rare to find such a large problem space that is ripe for a step-function change in innovation. Families are ready for the next evolution of social apps, one that is meant to be personal and intimate, and this team is building it,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Honeycomb, now a team of seven, is planning to use the new funds for hiring, including engineers, who will work in-person from its San Mateo office space. It expects to add around 10 people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/honeycomb-a-private-social-app-for-families-raises-4m-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246783</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green new era dawns for crypto with global mining shift</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/green-new-era-dawns-for-crypto-with-global-mining-shift/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/green-new-era-dawns-for-crypto-with-global-mining-shift/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 20:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How well do Bitcoin and other digital assets meet ESG criteria? This question has become ever more important as crypto adoption reaches wider audiences.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Seamus Donoghue</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/seamus_don">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://ch.linkedin.com/in/seamus-donoghue-2504115a">Seamus Donoghue</a> is the VP of Strategic Alliances at<a href="https://www.metaco.com/"> METACO</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Climate change is the issue of our time. From policymakers to the individual, every one of us has a responsibility to do our part to ensure that sustainability and green practices are implemented throughout society.</p>
<p>Indeed, governments across the world, from the U.S. to China, are increasingly taking a proactive stance on climate change, with<a href="https://ukcop26.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> COP26</a>, the recent 2021 United Nations Climate Change Conference, serving as a driving impetus toward the goals of the<a href="https://unfccc.int/process-and-meetings/the-paris-agreement/the-paris-agreement#:~:text=The%20Paris%20Agreement%20is%20a,compared%20to%20pre%2Dindustrial%20levels." target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Paris Agreement</a> in inspiring climate action.</p>
<p>Corporations are also stepping forward to take greater responsibility, with many investors no longer considering financial performance alone a sufficient measure of success — ESG measures, i.e., negative externalities, are increasingly taken into account to determine the true value of business activity for society.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246517" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In this context, the process of revitalizing our financial infrastructure is increasingly under the spotlight. How well do Bitcoin and other digital assets meet ESG criteria? This question has become ever more important as crypto adoption reaches wider audiences. Multiple<a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2021/10/22/valkyrie-bitcoin-futures-etf-starts-trading-joining-fray/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Bitcoin futures ETFs have now been approved</a> and are trading in the U.S., while institutional adoption is also reaching new highs, with many of the world’s largest financial institutions, including<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/02/stanchart-unit-to-launch-cryptocurrency-trading-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Standard Chartered</a>,<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/10/state-street-is-creating-a-dedicated-cryptocurrency-division.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> State Street</a> and <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/d90ed3bf-2c8d-46c9-98b7-67859f6598e5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Citibank</a> quietly building capabilities in the space.</p>
<p>Growing regulatory clarity is also enabling a broader range of participants globally to accelerate their strategies for digital assets. The EU’s comprehensive <a href="https://www.europarl.europa.eu/legislative-train/theme-a-europe-fit-for-the-digital-age/file-crypto-assets-1">Market in Crypto-assets (MiCA) framework</a> continues to move through the legislative process in the European Parliament. While in the U.S., <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K3HRyPxXtoo&amp;ab_channel=CNBCTelevision" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gary Gensler’s Securities and Exchange Commission</a> has also signaled its intent to clarify a framework for stablecoins and decentralized finance (DeFi).</p>
<p>For digital assets to truly cement their place in the mainstream and the portfolios of investors across the globe, they must be subject to the same rigorous ESG standards that every government and corporation should now address. Significantly, the industry has gradually come to terms with this need and has ramped up a process of environmental self-regulation in response to rising adoption.</p>
<p>Organizations such as the <a href="https://bitcoinminingcouncil.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitcoin Mining Council</a> are working to increase transparency in the industry through higher reporting standards. Many crypto-native organizations are also joining the <a href="https://cryptoclimate.org/">Crypto Climate Accord</a>, committing to achieve net-zero emissions from electricity consumption associated with crypto-related operations by 2030.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Yet, for all this activity, perhaps the single greatest contribution to the energy efficiency of digital assets has been a decision entirely out of the control of the industry. In May, China’s State Council banned cryptocurrency mining and trading. Previously the global stronghold for crypto mining activity, <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/50acdea5-cad1-4f39-8e6a-9be7ab78485d">with 44% of the global share of Bitcoin mining hashrate</a>, the decision prompted an exodus of miners to other jurisdictions.</p>
<p>The move has been a significant one for the energy efficiency of the Bitcoin mining industry, moving away from the coal-heavy energy production of the Chinese economy to more renewable forms of energy in other jurisdictions.</p>
<p>North America has been the big beneficiary of this move, with the U.S. share of mining hashrate increasing from <a href="https://cbeci.org/index" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17% in April to 35% in August</a>. With the addition of a 9.5% mining hashrate in Canada, North America now dominates the global mining hashrate with close to 50% of the global supply.</p>
<p>While energy production in the U.S. is diverse across states, the shift has been a significant boon to the sustainability of Bitcoin mining. The U.S. is replete with renewable energy sources; add to the mix the fact that large mining companies are essentially competing in a low-margin industry, where the primary variable cost is energy, and the <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/13/us-beats-china-as-the-number-one-destination-for-bitcoin-miners.html">incentive is to migrate to the cheapest sources of power &#8212; which are largely renewable</a>.</p>
<p>For example, New York &#8212; one of the states with the largest share of Bitcoin hashrate, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/09/war-to-attract-bitcoin-miners-pits-texas-against-new-york-kentucky.html">according to data from Foundry USA</a> &#8212; draws a third of its in-state energy generation from renewable sources. Texas, another significant state for Bitcoin mining hashrate, is rapidly growing its share of renewable energy production, with <a href="https://comptroller.texas.gov/economy/fiscal-notes/2020/august/ercot.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20% of its power</a> coming from wind in 2019.</p>
<p>In addition, the Bitcoin mining industry has a unique feature set that actually incentivizes the use of trapped sources of renewable energy that are not yet connected to the national grid. By acting as a means of monetizing the production of renewable energy, mining can thus further accelerate the building out of renewable energy capabilities.</p>
<p>This shift toward renewable energy sources has already begun to demonstrate to critics that Bitcoin and the wider digital asset industry can succeed with an ethos of sustainability. Such a transition will not be an instantaneous one, and it will take time for large mining operations to reestablish themselves in new jurisdictions. However, this transition is firmly underway.</p>
<p>Ultimately, it is up to digital asset service providers to demonstrate the value that crypto provides is worth its consumption of energy. Significant progress has been made this year alone in reducing the carbon footprint of digital assets, and as crypto continues its sustainability journey, corporate and institutional adoption will follow suit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/green-new-era-dawns-for-crypto-with-global-mining-shift/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246517</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ex-Snap employees raise $4.3M for conversational commerce startup Whym</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/ex-snap-employees-raise-4m-for-conversational-commerce-startup-whym/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/ex-snap-employees-raise-4m-for-conversational-commerce-startup-whym/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 19:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deciens Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snap inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text messaging]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whym, a conversational commerce startup founded by former Snap employees, wants to make it easier for consumers to shop online via their mobile devices. Instead of filling out long checkout forms and entering in payment card details by hand, Whym&#8217;s solution offers a single-tap checkout experience where customers can pay via Apple Pay or Google [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.whymwallet.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Whym</a>, a conversational commerce startup founded by former Snap employees, wants to make it easier for consumers to shop online via their mobile devices. Instead of filling out long checkout forms and entering in payment card details by hand, Whym&#8217;s solution offers a single-tap checkout experience where customers can pay via Apple Pay or Google Pay or even over a text message. The startup is now announcing $4.3 million in new seed funding, following its early traction with CPG, wellness and beauty brands.</p>
<p>The round was led by Deciens Capital and included participation from DNX Ventures, Reciprocal Ventures, Unusual Ventures, Chaos Ventures and Magic Fund, as well as small investments from Sequoia, Lightspeed and Canaan Partners. Whym also has angel investments from founders and other executives from Stripe, PayPal, Venmo, Microsoft, Salesforce, Google, Facebook, Twitter, TikTok, Snapchat, Uber, Airbnb, Red Bull and Spotify.</p>
<p>The startup itself was founded in 2017 by CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellynyland/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kelly Nyland</a> and COO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rheneebartlett/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rhenee Bartlett</a>, both previously of Snap. Nyland had headed up the consumer products and marketing division of the company, where she created the go-to-market strategy for Snap&#8217;s Spectacles. Bartlett had served as the head of event marketing and partnerships for Spectacles. In addition, founding team member and Whym&#8217;s VP of Engineering, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rhornberger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ryan Hornberger</a>, had worked at Snap after the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/12/16/snapchat-emails-not-so-ephemeral/">acquired</a> his startup Scan, Inc., which formed the basis for Snapchat&#8217;s Snapcode.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246600" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2246753" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246753" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2246753" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/WHYM-Secure-Text-Checkout.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/WHYM-Secure-Text-Checkout.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/WHYM-Secure-Text-Checkout.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/WHYM-Secure-Text-Checkout.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/WHYM-Secure-Text-Checkout.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/WHYM-Secure-Text-Checkout.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/WHYM-Secure-Text-Checkout.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/WHYM-Secure-Text-Checkout.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246753" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Whym</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>While at Snap, Nyland saw how the DM (direct messaging) screen drove Snapchat&#8217;s daily usage. She proposed that the company allow brands and consumers to communicate with each other directly through that part of the app.</p>
<p>&#8220;I realized through that journey that messaging was going to become a really important part of social shopping in the future,&#8221; Nyland explains.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Whym&#8217;s team realized that combining messaging and commerce into a new experience where transactions could take place over a text or even a DM thread could enable a new form of social shopping. Its first product, launched into beta in June 2018, offered brands a way to let their customers &#8220;reply to buy&#8221; over a text message.</p>
<p>In the years since, Whym has expanded to offer brands a micro-storefront solution that can be paired with their current texting campaigns, allowing customers to shop a product or small set of products and their variations &#8212; like colors or sizes, for example &#8212; then immediately check out. Brands can also promote their links in other places across social media and messaging apps, like &#8220;link in bio&#8221; solutions, swipe-ups (now <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/instagram-rolls-out-the-ability-for-all-users-to-share-links-in-stories-via-link-stickers/">link stickers on Instagram</a>), messaging apps and more.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246746" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246746" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2246746" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Customer-Setup.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="567" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Customer-Setup.png 1440w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Customer-Setup.png?resize=150,125 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Customer-Setup.png?resize=300,250 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Customer-Setup.png?resize=768,640 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Customer-Setup.png?resize=680,567 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Customer-Setup.png?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246746" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Whym</p></div></p>
<p>As a consumer, the solution is designed to be quicker and easier than clicking through to a traditional mobile website to check out. Instead, they&#8217;re sent to the micro-storefront to customize their cart, then can tap on Apple Pay or Google Pay to complete the sale. The company also still offers its original experience that lets customers check out over text, but will soon use consumers&#8217; mobile phone numbers in a new way, too. Starting next year, consumers will be able to enter their phone number to signal their interest in a product they may want to buy in the future, as an alternative to sending themselves a website link or taking a screenshot as many do today.</p>
<p>Over time, Whym will be able to offer consumers a universal cart where they can purchase items across brands. It will also enable brands to reach out to their customers again when it&#8217;s time to repurchase.</p>
<p>&#8220;Up and coming direct-to-consumer brands, beauty, wellness, and CPG are our main focus,&#8221; notes Nyland. &#8220;We focus on businesses that have a high repurchase cadence. What Whym can do is actually rebuild each of those customers&#8217; carts one-to-one and do a reply-to-buy repurchase experience for those brands,&#8221; she says. &#8220;So we can harness the power of text message on the backend to power repurchase experiences between brands and consumers automatically.&#8221;</p>
<p>The startup today has a couple of hundred <a href="https://www.whymwallet.com/shopper" target="_blank" rel="noopener">brands</a> using its service, and charges a 3% + 10¢ transaction fee on each order. Now that the company is scaling upmarket to brands between $50 million and $250 million in annual GMV (gross merchandise volume), it&#8217;s beginning to offer tiered pricing. But these rates aren&#8217;t yet publicized.</p>
<p>Brand integrations with Whym take around 10 minutes on average, via its self-serve platform. In addition, the startup has a sales team that can demo the product and walk clients through onboarding and strategy, and aid with the creation of their first campaigns.</p>
<p>The startup, a team of under 50, plans to use the funding to reach more brands and further develop its roadmap of product features, many of which have come from customer feedback. To date, Whym has raised a total of $7 million in funding.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/ex-snap-employees-raise-4m-for-conversational-commerce-startup-whym/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246600</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
