<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 14:57:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>PayPal to acquire cryptocurrency custody startup Curv</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/paypal-to-acquire-cryptocurrency-custody-startup-curv/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/paypal-to-acquire-cryptocurrency-custody-startup-curv/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Curv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PayPal has announced that it plans to acquire Curv, a cryptocurrency startup based in Tel Aviv, Israel. Israeli newspaper Calcalist originally reported the move. And PayPal has now made an official announcement. Curv is a cryptocurrency custody company, which means that it helps you store your crypto assets securely. The company operates a cloud-based service [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">PayPal has <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/paypal-to-acquire-curv-301242347.html">announced</a> that it plans to acquire Curv, a cryptocurrency startup based in Tel Aviv, Israel. Israeli newspaper Calcalist <a href="https://www.calcalist.co.il/internet/articles/0,7340,L-3896291,00.html">originally reported</a> the move. And PayPal has now made an official announcement.</p>
<p>Curv is a cryptocurrency custody company, which means that it helps you store your crypto assets securely. The company operates a cloud-based service that lets you access your crypto wallets without any hardware device.</p>
<p>Curv also lets you set up sophisticated policies so that the new intern cannot withdraw crypto assets without some sort of approval chain. Similarly, you can create allow lists so that regular transactions can go through more easily.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Behind the scenes, Curv uses multi-party computation to handle private keys. When you create a wallet, cryptographic secrets are generated on your device and on Curv’s servers. Whenever you’re trying to initiate a transaction, multiple secrets are used to generate a full public and private key.</p>
<p>Secrets are rotated regularly and you can’t do anything with just one secret. If somebody steals an unsecured laptop, a hacker cannot access crypto funds with the information stored on this device alone.</p>
<p>As you can see, Curv isn’t a cryptocurrency wallet for end users. The company offers its services to exchanges, brokers and over-the-counter desks. If you’re running a fund and you plan on buying a large amount of cryptocurrencies, you could also consider using Curv.</p>
<p>Finally, financial institutions that are looking for a solution to store digital assets and diversify their balance sheet could also work with Curv.</p>
<p>PayPal says that the Curv team will join the cryptocurrency group within PayPal. The payment giant has been gradually rolling out cryptocurrency products. It has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/paypal-to-let-you-buy-and-sell-cryptocurrencies-in-the-us/">partnered with Paxos</a> so that users in the U.S. can buy, hold and sell cryptocurrencies from their PayPal account.</p>
<p>In the near future, PayPal also plans to let you buy and sell items using cryptocurrencies. During its <a href="https://s1.q4cdn.com/633035571/files/doc_financials/2020/q4/PYPL_Q4-20_Investor_Update-%281%29.pdf">most recent earnings release</a>, the company also said that it plans to launch cryptocurrency products in other countries and in Venmo, the consumer fintech super app owned by PayPal.</p>
<p>Terms of the deal are undisclosed and the transaction should close at some point during the first half of 2021. Calcalist <a href="https://www.calcalist.co.il/internet/articles/0,7340,L-3896291,00.html">reported</a> that PayPal was paying between $200 million and $300 million for the acquisition. A person close to the company says that the transaction was under $200 million. I guess we’ll find out what happened exactly in the next earnings release.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oh0dJRkMPb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/paypal-to-let-you-buy-and-sell-cryptocurrencies-in-the-us/">PayPal to let you buy and sell cryptocurrencies in the US</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;PayPal to let you buy and sell cryptocurrencies in the US&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/paypal-to-let-you-buy-and-sell-cryptocurrencies-in-the-us/embed/#?secret=oh0dJRkMPb" data-secret="oh0dJRkMPb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/paypal-to-acquire-cryptocurrency-custody-startup-curv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122248</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The rise of the tech workers union and what comes next</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-rise-of-the-tech-workers-union-and-what-comes-next/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-rise-of-the-tech-workers-union-and-what-comes-next/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 14:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kickstarter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCJUSTICE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[union]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While not entirely non-existent, the union has been an elusive phenomenon in Silicon Valley. More recently, however, big names like Google and Kickstarter have taken key steps toward forming unions, as have smaller startups like Glitch, which made history this week by signing a collective bargaining agreement – the first team of software engineers to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While not entirely non-existent, the union has been an elusive phenomenon in Silicon Valley. More recently, however, big names like Google and Kickstarter have taken key steps toward forming unions, as have smaller startups like Glitch, which made history this week by signing a collective bargaining agreement – the first team of software engineers to do so. Amazon warehouse workers in Alabama, meanwhile, are currently on the cusp of forming their own historic union. In this panel from TC Sessions: Justice, we discuss how we got here, what comes next and steps tech employees can take.</p>
<hr />
<h3>On Why Now?</h3>
<p>As has been the case with management throughout history, tech companies have long fought tooth and nail against labor organizing. Over the course of the last couple of years, however, we may have seen something of a critical mass that could represent the beginnings of a sea change for the industry.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Redwine:</strong> It seems like tech workers are reacting to some of the maturity of tech and the expansion of the platforms that we all work on, and also more worker instability in general in the US, especially. I think it&#8217;s sort of a response that workers are becoming more formal in their organizing efforts<em><strong>. (Timestamp: 1:08)</strong></em></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Parul Koul (Google):</strong></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Koul:</strong> A variety of tactics and strategies have been tried, and we’ve been able to analyze the successes and failures of past movements and arrive at a point where we’ve developed enough institutional and organizational knowledge to try something new and – in some ways – more complex.<strong> (</strong><em><strong>Timestamp: 3:25)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/google-alphabet-employees-union/">Google, Alphabet employees unionize</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/13/online-code-collaboration-tool-glitch-votes-to-unionize/">Online code collaboration tool Glitch votes to unionize</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3>On Whether The Pandemic Will Spur More Organizing</h3>
<p>Covid-19 has radically transformed where – and how – we work. It’s upended many industries and cause millions to lose jobs. Could the pandemic prove to be yet another inflection point for a growing movement.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Koul:</strong> In our case, what we saw was companies moving to work from home and then, in certain categories of employees, not really receiving the same benefits […] whether it’s a stipend to buy equipment or even having the benefit from working from home […] We also saw a mass movement and social and political protests against police brutality erupt right in the middle of the pandemic. For me, and many other organizers at Google, it really galvanized us to do something and respond to that in the streets and in our own way. <strong>(</strong><em><strong>Timestamp: 6:56)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<hr />
<h3>On How – or if – Unions Can Protect Against Layoffs</h3>
<p>For many industries, layoffs have become all but an inevitability during the pandemic. In a number of the aforementioned cases, they’ve continued even in the wake of employee unionizing. Ultimately, how much protection does a union give workers against layoffs?</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Reckers:</strong> Kickstarter won its union on February 18, 2020. The pandemic hit in mid-March. The company announced that they were going to have pretty massive layoffs in early-April. That was a very difficult time. We looked at the numbers and did see that a number of the people they were proposing to layoff were advocates for the union or union members. That was very hard to stomach. What happens, though – and where the union comes into play – is that the company was not able to just lay people off like that. Especially under the terms that they wanted to impose unilaterally, without any consultation with staff. The difference was that when the company proposed these layoffs, because there was already a union in place, Kickstarter had to negotiate with the group of employees about the terms of that layoff. <em><strong>(</strong><strong>Timestamp: 9:10)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/kickstarter-workers-vote-to-unionize/">Kickstarter workers vote to unionize</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/following-unionization-glitch-signs-collective-bargaining-agreement/">Following unionization, Glitch signs collective bargaining agreement</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3>On How to Get Started</h3>
<p>First steps toward unionization are often difficult in an environment where organizing is frowned upon management. Many early conversations happen after hours and off-the-clock for fear of repercussion. This can be doubly difficult in an environments like white collar workers tech company, where some employees don’t tacitly understand the benefits of organizing.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Reckers:</strong> You can best support each other by getting into conversations with your coworkers and understanding what’s been going on with them. The first question I often get from people is how to first start having conversations. I think that’s a challenge, especially since we’re not taught how to do that. But starting a conversation about what their experiences have been like at the organization or company, how long they’ve been there, how has there changed? What did they want to see when they were hired? What sort of workplace were they looking for? And how can we make sure that we have some way of achieving that? (<em><strong>Timestamp: 24:04)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/03/the-state-of-the-unions/">The state of the unions</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/07/amazon-warehouse-workers-begin-historic-vote-to-unionize/">Amazon warehouse workers to begin historic vote to unionize</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3>On Whether Expressions of Support From Management Are Always Positive</h3>
<p>Management often adopts the narrative that they support unions following hard fought battles. In the wake of support from certain tech executives and political leaders like Joe Biden, the question arises about whether such sentiments can ultimately have negative repercussions for organizing.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Redwine:</strong> First and foremost, it’s really important to remember that the things that people in power say do not matter. All of the power that you have doesn’t come from people at the top giving it to you. It comes from linking arms with the people next to you and taking that power and influence for yourself. (<em><strong>Timestamp: 28:27)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<p> <div embedded-video-placeholder="603fcd9c303d501d18130c54" post-id="2120478"></div> </p>
<p><a href="https://otter.ai/u/i0DkDLOSHPirJCiNuUEGKrr4SaU">You can read the entire transcript here.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-rise-of-the-tech-workers-union-and-what-comes-next/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121318</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Last-mile delivery robotics company Refraction AI raises $4.2M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/last-mile-delivery-robotics-company-refraction-ai-raises-4-2m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/last-mile-delivery-robotics-company-refraction-ai-raises-4-2m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 14:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Last mile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pillar vc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Refraction AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ann Arbor-based Refraction AI announced today that it has raised a $4.2 million seed round. The startup, which debuted on the TechCrunch Sessions: Mobility stage back in 2019, was founded by a pair of University of Michigan professors (Matthew Johnson-Roberson &#8212; now CTO &#8212; and Ram Vasudevan) seeking to solve a number of issues posed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ann Arbor-based <a href="https://refraction.ai/">Refraction A</a>I announced today that it has raised a $4.2 million seed round. The startup, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/video/demo-with-matthew-johnson-roberson-refraction-ai/">debuted on the TechCrunch Sessions: Mobility stage</a> back in 2019, was founded by a pair of University of Michigan professors (Matthew Johnson-Roberson &#8212; now CTO &#8212; and Ram Vasudevan) seeking to solve a number of issues posed by many delivery robots.</p>
<p>With an initial prototype built on a bicycle foundation, the company’s REV-1 robot is designed to operate in bike lanes and roads, rather than the standard sidewalk &#8216;bot. The different approach allows the robot to travel at higher speeds (topping out at 15 miles per hour) and removes some of the messy pedestrian-dodging issues that come with sidewalk use (while introducing some new ones on that narrow sliver of asphalt shared by cyclists).</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/47WNq9u4QsY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Refraction is currently testing a small fleet in its native Ann Arbor. The seed round, led by Pillar VC, will be used for R&amp;D, expanding the company’s reach and recruiting more customers, with a focus on grocery store and restaurant deliveries. Other investors include, eLab Ventures, Osage Venture Partners, Trucks Venture Capital, Alumni Ventures Group, Chad Laurans and Invest Michigan.</p>
<p>Another key differentiator is the use of cameras, versus LIDAR. The decision comes with some technological trade-offs, but benefits include a lower price point and the ability for the company to more quickly scale its fleet. The technology is also not easily districted by weather conditions encountered in the upper midwest, though it has limitations, too. As the company puts it, if you&#8217;re not comfortable walking out in it, the robot probably won&#8217;t be, either.</p>
<p>“Our platform uses technology that exists today in an innovative way, to get people the things they need, when they need them, where they live,&#8221; CEO Luke Schneider said in a release tied to the news. &#8220;And we’re doing so in a way that reduces business’ costs, makes roads less congested, and eliminates carbon emissions.”</p>
<p>With this new funding, the company plans to expand operations beyond its native Ann Arbor, though no additional test markets have been announced.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6S1tuXlhOF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/6-leading-mobility-vcs-discuss-the-road-ahead/">6 leading mobility VCs discuss the road ahead</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;6 leading mobility VCs discuss the road ahead&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/6-leading-mobility-vcs-discuss-the-road-ahead/embed/#?secret=6S1tuXlhOF" data-secret="6S1tuXlhOF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/last-mile-delivery-robotics-company-refraction-ai-raises-4-2m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121971</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon expands its food delivery service across Bangalore</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/amazon-expands-its-food-delivery-service-across-bangalore/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/amazon-expands-its-food-delivery-service-across-bangalore/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 13:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swiggy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zomato]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon said on Monday it has expanded its food delivery service, called Amazon Food, across 62 zip codes in Bangalore, in what is the first public update since entering the new category in India last May. The American e-commerce group said Amazon Food now reaches key localities in Bangalore such as Whitefield, HSR, Sarjapur, Koramangala, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon said on Monday it has expanded its food delivery service, called Amazon Food, across 62 zip codes in Bangalore, in what is the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/21/amazon-launches-food-delivery-service-in-india/">first public update since entering the new category</a> in India last May.</p>
<p>The American e-commerce group said Amazon Food now reaches key localities in Bangalore such as Whitefield, HSR, Sarjapur, Koramangala, Indiranagar, MG Road, Jayanagar, JP Nagar, Frazer Town, Malleshwaram, Rajajinagar, and Vijayanaga.</p>
<p>At the time of the launch in May last year, Amazon Food was available in just four zip codes in Bangalore.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Even as Amazon Food remains limited to one key market in India, the company is aggressively trying to undercut the competition &#8212; heavily funded startups Zomato and Swiggy &#8212; in the city.</p>
<p>Food delivery is free to Prime members, while others have to pay a fee of 19 Indian rupees (26 cents) &#8212; cheaper than fees levied by Swiggy and Zomato.</p>
<p>The company, which has committed to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/amazon-to-invest-1-billion-to-digitize-small-businesses-in-india/">investing $6.5 billion in its India operations</a>, said it has amassed 2,5000 restaurants and cloud kitchens in Bangalore &#8212; also referred as Bengaluru. Amazon Food customers can enjoy &#8220;offers&#8221; from these restaurants as well as cashbacks from Amazon, the company said.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2122243" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/amazon-food.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="834" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/amazon-food.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/amazon-food.jpg?resize=150,122 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/amazon-food.jpg?resize=300,244 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/amazon-food.jpg?resize=768,625 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/amazon-food.jpg?resize=680,554 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/amazon-food.jpg?resize=50,41 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>It, however, did not share why it has been uncharacteristically so slow with the expansion of Amazon Food in the country.</p>
<p>(Well, I mean, there is a global pandemic &#8212; but Amazon also makes a number of what its employees say &#8220;one-way door&#8221; and &#8220;two-way door&#8221; bets. Two-way door bets are those that the company has not fully committed to and is just attempting to test the waters before making a concrete decision. Think of Amazon Prime as a one-way door bet. So it&#8217;s not clear from day 1 how committed Amazon is to any new service.)</p>
<p>&#8220;With the expansion of Amazon Food in Bengaluru, we continue in our endeavor to offer unmatched convenience and value while being a part of their everyday lives. Amazon Food brings some of the city’s top restaurants including national outlets and as well as local favorites which are popular and follow strict delivery and safety protocols,&#8221; said Sameer Khetarpal, Director of Category Management at Amazon India, in a statement.</p>
<p>Ant Financial-backed Zomato and Prosus Ventures-backed Swiggy have established duopoly in the food delivery market in India, with analysts at Bank of America estimating their combined market share to be over 90%. (Uber exited the Indian food delivery market early last year after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/03/uber-sold-its-food-delivery-business-in-india-to-zomato-for-206m/">selling its local food business to Zomato</a>.)</p>
<p>The expansion of Amazon Food also comes at a time when Zomato, which according to analysts leads the market, is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/indian-food-delivery-startup-zomato-valued-at-5-4-billion-in-new-250-million-investment/">preparing to file for an IPO</a>.</p>
<p>India&#8217;s food delivery market is especially tough to crack because of local conditions. Unlike in the developed markets such as the U.S., where the value of each delivery item is about $33, in India, a similar item carries the price tag of $4, according to research firms. Both Zomato and Swiggy have significantly improved their unit economics in the past year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/amazon-expands-its-food-delivery-service-across-bangalore/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122197</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New clinical trial data from Locus Biosciences shows promise in CRISPR-Cas3 technology</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/new-clinical-trial-data-from-locus-biosciences-shows-promise-in-crispr-cas3-technology/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/new-clinical-trial-data-from-locus-biosciences-shows-promise-in-crispr-cas3-technology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Burkholder]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 13:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotechnology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cas-3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRISPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enzymes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genetic engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[locus biosciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north carolina]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Antibiotic resistance is one of the biggest potential threats to global health today. But Locus Biosciences is hoping that their crPhage technology might provide a new solution. Based in North Carolina’s Research Triangle, the startup recently announced promising phase 1b clinical trial results for their use of CRISPR-Cas3-enhanced bacteriophages as a treatment for urinary tract [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Antibiotic resistance is one of the <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/antibiotic-resistance#:~:text=Antibiotic%20resistance%20occurs%20naturally%2C%20but,treat%20them%20become%20less%20effective.">biggest potential threats to global health today</a>. But Locus Biosciences is hoping that their crPhage technology might provide a new solution.</p>
<p>Based in North Carolina’s Research Triangle, the startup recently<a href="https://www.locus-bio.com/locus-biosciences-completes-first-of-its-kind-controlled-clinical-trial-for-crispr-enhanced-bacteriophage-therapy/"> announced promising phase 1b clinical trial results</a> for their use of CRISPR-Cas3-enhanced bacteriophages as a treatment for urinary tract infections caused by escherichia coli. Led in part by former Patheon executive and current Locus CEO Paul Garofolo, the startup launched in 2015 with the goal of using a less popular application of CRISPR technology to address growing antimicrobial resistance.</p>
<p>CRISPR-Cas3 technology has notably different mechanisms from its more well-known CRISPR-Cas9 counterpart. Where the Cas9 enzyme has the ability to cleanly cut through a piece of DNA like a pair of scissors, Garofolo describes Cas3 more like a Pac-Man, shredding the DNA as it moves along a strand.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“You wouldn’t be able to use it for most of the editing platforms people were after,” he said, noting that meant there wouldn’t be as much competition around Cas3. “So I knew it would be protected for some time, and that we could keep it quiet.”</p>
<p>Garofolo and his team wanted to use CRISPR-Cas3 not to edit harmful bacteria found in the body, but to destroy it. To do this, they took the DNA-shredding mechanism of Cas3 and used it to enhance bacteriophages—viruses that can attack and kill different species of bacteria. Together, co-founder and Chief Scientific Officer Dave Ousterout—who has a Ph.D. in biomedical engineering from Duke—thinks this technology offers an extremely direct and targeted way of killing bacteria.</p>
<p>“We armed the phages with this Cas3 system that attacks E. coli, and that sort of dual mechanism of action is what comes together, essentially, as a really potent way to remove just E. coli,” he said in an interview.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ysswavaKuA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/techs-role-in-the-covid-19-response-assist-dont-reinvent/">Tech&#8217;s role in the COVID-19 response: Assist, don&#8217;t reinvent</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tech&#8217;s role in the COVID-19 response: Assist, don&#8217;t reinvent&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/techs-role-in-the-covid-19-response-assist-dont-reinvent/embed/#?secret=ysswavaKuA" data-secret="ysswavaKuA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That specificity is something that antibiotics lack. Rather than targeting only harmful bacteria in the body, antibiotics typically wipe out all bacteria they come across. “Every time we take antibiotics, we’re not thinking about all the other parts of us that are impacted by the bacteria that do good things,” said Garofolo. But the precision of Locus Biosciences’ crPhage technology means that only the targeted bacteria would be wiped out, leaving those necessary to the body’s normal function intact.</p>
<p>Beyond offering this more specific approach to treatment of pathogens, or any bacteria-based disease, Garofolo and his team also suspect that their approach will also be extremely safe. Though deadly to bacteria, <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/phage-therapy">bacteriophages are typically harmless to humans</a>. The safety of CRISPR in humans is well-established, too.</p>
<p>“That’s our secret sauce,” said Garofolo. “We can build drugs that are more powerful than the antibiotics they’re trying to replace, and they use phage, which is probably one of the world’s safest ways to deliver something into the human body.”</p>
<p>While this new technology could certainly help treat pathogens and infectious diseases, Garofolo hopes that indications in immunology, oncology, and neurology might benefit from it too. “We’re starting to figure out that <a href="https://www.cancer.org/cancer/cancer-causes/infectious-agents/infections-that-can-lead-to-cancer/bacteria.html">some bacteria might promote cancer</a>, or inflammation in your gut,” he said. If researchers can identify the bacteria at the root cause of those conditions, Garofolo and Ousterout think the crPhage technology might prove to be an effective treatment.</p>
<p>“If we’re right about that, it’s not just about infections or antimicrobial resistance, but helping people overcome cancer or delay the onset of dementia,” Garofolo said. “It’s changing the way we think about how bacteria really help us live.”</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/new-clinical-trial-data-from-locus-biosciences-shows-promise-in-crispr-cas3-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121964</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Egypt&#8217;s customer engagement platform for F&#038;B brands in MENA, Koinz, raises $4.8M seed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/egypts-customer-engagement-platform-for-fb-brands-in-mena-koinz-raises-4-8m-seed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/egypts-customer-engagement-platform-for-fb-brands-in-mena-koinz-raises-4-8m-seed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 13:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the restaurant industry across different cities was massively hit by the pandemic-induced lockdowns last year, food aggregator platforms helped by driving online customers to them. Koinz is one such startup in Egypt. Its value for food and beverages brands before, during and after the lockdowns has bagged the startup a $4.8 million seed round. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="" data-block="true" data-editor="7jsg2" data-offset-key="6m929-0-0">
<div class="public-DraftStyleDefault-block public-DraftStyleDefault-ltr" data-offset-key="6m929-0-0">
<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the restaurant industry across different cities was massively hit by the pandemic-induced lockdowns last year, food aggregator platforms helped by driving online customers to them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.getkoinz.com/">Koinz</a> is one such startup in Egypt. Its value for food and beverages brands before, during and after the lockdowns has bagged the startup a $4.8 million seed round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded in 2018 by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hussein-momtaz/">Hussein Momtaz</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed-said-496278b2/">Ahmed Said</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahkhaldi/?lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Acompanies_company_people_index%3BDkf5dpxeRFybMPZ%2Bev8Ifw%3D%3D">Abdullah Al Khaldi</a>, Koinz set out to solve two major problems in Egypt&#8217;s food aggregation industry.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The offline and online food and restaurant experience in the country are totally separate. Most food aggregators who deal with delivery tend to focus on the online customer, and there&#8217;s no sophisticated experience for the offline customer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next, the unit economics of the food aggregation industry is quite challenging. According to Momtaz, the startup&#8217;s CEO, the food aggregation industry usually takes about 25%-30% average commission from F&amp;B players for business to start to make sense.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;This is not because they want to squeeze money from the hands of restaurants or brands,&#8221; Momtaz said to TechCrunch. &#8220;But the cost of acquiring customers and retaining them for the food aggregator itself is very high; that&#8217;s why they need very high commissions from the brands or restaurants.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is where Koinz comes in. The company developed a mobile app for takeout and delivery orders that manages offline customer experiences while delivering an engagement platform to manage loyalty programs, customer feedback and analytics about the online and offline customer base.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2122070" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122070" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2122070" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-Founders.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="407" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-Founders.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-Founders.jpg?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-Founders.jpg?resize=300,180 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-Founders.jpg?resize=768,460 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-Founders.jpg?resize=680,407 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-Founders.jpg?resize=1536,920 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-Founders.jpg?resize=2048,1226 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-Founders.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2122070" class="wp-caption-text">Abdullah Al Khaldi (CRO), Hussein Momtaz (CEO), and Ahmed Said (CTO)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Online food experience for Koinz customers is like a treasure hunt, and Momtaz claims the company&#8217;s business model has cracked the industry&#8217;s unit economics. This, alongside providing brands with insights, differentiates the platform from other aggregators and makes its customer acquisition cost and retention cost 60% less than most of them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here&#8217;s how the platform works. When customers visit a brand using for the first time, they enter their phone numbers to instantly receive points for their order via text message. After various restaurant visits and making orders, they accumulate enough points. They&#8217;ll need to download the Koinz mobile application to redeem them, thereby converting these offline customers to online ones.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Furthermore, these offline customers can now discover new places to eat, read and leave reviews, and order delivery or takeout.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;None of the small or big brands in the region had something like this before. The offline customer is like a ghost. He walks into the brands, takes his orders, and leaves without the brands knowing anything about him. Koinz is changing that,&#8221; the CEO remarked.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Building its platform this way, Koinz tries to be different from other online aggregators that erode restaurant owners&#8217; profit margins while delivering limited customer access and interaction. How? By collecting real-time data and leveraging a digital rewarding system designed to drive customers to deepen their relationship with restaurants.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2122071" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122071" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2122071" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-app-Points.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-app-Points.png 1125w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-app-Points.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-app-Points.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-app-Points.png?resize=768,1663 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-app-Points.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-app-Points.png?resize=709,1536 709w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-app-Points.png?resize=946,2048 946w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Koinz-app-Points.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2122071" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Koinz</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brands can configure their gifts lists and determine what customers can redeem their points for. For instance, customers in an Egyptian restaurant called Buffalo Burger can exchange 68 points for a Diablo Fries Medium; or wait till they get to 160 points to get a Mozzarella Sticks Medium; or 236 points for a Double Diggler.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Similarly, every brand has its own configuration. A customer cannot get points in Buffalo Burger and redeem them at Hamburgini. Koinz charges subscriptions to the brands for its engagement and feedback platform and collects commission whenever an order is made via its platform, which varies across its markets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because of its original business model, Koinz had to iterate several times. Before using phone numbers to collect customers&#8217; information, the company used QR codes and NFC tags. Momtaz says this was highly ineffective, and the move to phone numbers helped skyrocket its growth and value.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The six-man team back in 2018 is now 80, and the platform, which is basically powering the growth of restaurants in the Middle East, claims to have had up to 4 million consumers earn points on its platform. These consumers have redeemed almost 300,000 rewards, while almost 800,000 customers have left reviews.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since launching in Egypt, Koinz has expanded to Saudi Arabia and the UAE. Like Egypt, these markets have similar dynamics and demographics. They have also witnessed one of the <a href="https://www.consultancy-me.com/news/3151/online-grocery-sales-in-ksa-and-uae-doubles-during-covid-19">highest rates of new or increased users</a> in online deliveries &#8212; restaurant products and groceries &#8212; during the pandemic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides, consumers in the Middle East are outpacing the global appetite in food delivery, <a href="https://www.thenationalnews.com/business/money/majority-of-middle-east-consumers-plan-to-spend-more-this-year-1.977492">with 64% ordering in at least once a week</a> compared to 40% made by global consumers. And with the fast-food industry in MENA was estimated at nearly $31 billion in 2020 and is expected to reach nearly $60 billion by 2025, there&#8217;s so much room for Koinz to grow in the region. Momtaz says the company is also considering a move to Sub-Saharan Africa in the nearest future despite them having distinct demographics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Entrepreneur and investor Justin Mateen led this seed round. Since leaving Tinder in 2014, Mateen has been an active investor in early-stage companies. Koinz is his first investment in the MENA region. According to him, Koinz&#8217;s ability to allow food and beverages brands to understand their customers&#8217; needs and simultaneously increase their profit margins was one of the reasons he invested in the Egyptian-based startup.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;The company&#8217;s unique business model will continue to scale as the food delivery space evolves. Hussein&#8217;s drive and excitement for what the team is building are what convinced me to lead a round in the Middle East for the first time,&#8221; Mateen added.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">African-focused VC 4DX Ventures and strategic angel investors from Egypt, Turkey and Saudi Arabia participated as well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Peter Orth, co-founder and managing director of the firm, said of the investment that with restaurants in the region suffering under the traditional aggregator model, especially during the pandemic, Koinz has quickly become a win-win for both consumers and restaurant owners across the Middle East.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the three-year-old company plans to use the capital to hire more talent and fuel its expansion across the Middle East, Mateen and Orth will join its board of directors.</span></p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/egypts-customer-engagement-platform-for-fb-brands-in-mena-koinz-raises-4-8m-seed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122067</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Station: Another Uber spinout is born and EVs dominate SPACs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-station-another-uber-spinout-is-born-and-evs-dominate-spacs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-station-another-uber-spinout-is-born-and-evs-dominate-spacs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aston Martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instacart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postmates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volocopter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volvo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox.  Hi friends and new readers, welcome back to The Station, a newsletter dedicated to all the present and future ways people and packages move from Point A to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox</a>. </em></p>
<p>Hi friends and new readers, welcome back to The Station, a newsletter dedicated to all the present and future ways people and packages move from Point A to Point B.</p>
<p>Our transportation desk is taking shape. Two new reporters, Aria Alamalhodaei and Rebecca Bellan started Monday and have already provided some new and interesting coverage. Tamara Warren, a former editor at the Verge who has been writing about automotive and tech for two decades, reviewed the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/the-aston-martin-dbx-is-a-tale-of-two-vehicles/">Aston Martin DBX</a>. This week, Abigail Basset, a World Car Juror former CNN producer who writes about cars, tech, business — pretty much everything — break down the new VW ID. 4.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We&#8217;re just getting started. <em>Vamos.</em></p>
<p>Please help welcome them and follow them on Twitter and maybe even drop them a DM. You can find them @RebeccaBellan and Aria over @breadfrom.</p>
<h2>Micromobbin&#8217;</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1894192 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png" alt="the station scooter1a" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Scooter clutter has prompted a number of entrepreneurs to start companies, all aiming to solve the problem. Tortoise has its repositioning software, companies like Swiftmile offer docking stations that also charge scooters.</p>
<p>But what about a solution that works across brands? Paris aims to find out.</p>
<p>The city is testing universal charging infrastructure for electric scooters in a pilot project that will kick off in the second quarter of this year. DUCKT, which <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6773179827798200322/">was awarded the pilot</a>, will install 150 dock and charge points that can be plugged into bus stations and street lighting to provide the power source.</p>
<p>DUCKT was one of 15 companies that were named <a href="https://urbanlab.parisandco.paris/QIU3">Urban Innovation District winners</a>. Each winner is testing a different urban project in the 13th arrondissement. The competition, which is run by Paris &amp; Co.&#8217;s urban innovation lab, includes pilots focused on food waste, rainwater collection, revegetation and waterproofing as well as several mobility projects. Ezymob will test a mobile app that helps visually impaired people navigate public transit, Mobilypod is launching a subscription-based cargo bike service and bike shelters and the LaCroix Lab is piloting 4SafeMobilities, a system designed to streamline traffic at intersections and pedestrian crossings.</p>
<hr />
<p>Meanwhile, Porsche is taking its electrification ambitions to two wheels. The German automaker unveiled this week<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/porsche-unveils-two-new-electric-bikes-alongside-the-taycan-gran-turismo/"> two electric bikes</a> alongside the global debut of the Porsche Taycan Cross Turismo, the latest variant to its EV flagship. These bikes cost between $8,000 and more than $10,000 — prices one might expect from the luxury performance brand.</p>
<h2>Deal of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896226 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png" alt="money the station" width="1600" height="400" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=1536,384 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Forget the &#8220;deal of the week.&#8221; How about we take a stroll down memory lane and look at all the deals of 2020? CB Insights, released March 3 its <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research/report/mobility-trends-2020/">State of Mobility report</a> that looks at 2020 investment data and trends surrounding all things transportation.</p>
<p>The upshot: The COVID-19 pandemic did help push total funding down 5% year-over-year to $27.19 billion, although CB Insights saw recovery in the second half of the year. There were 522 deals, a 21% drop from the previous year.</p>
<p>Total funding only tells part of the story though. If 2020 will be known for anything — aside from the whole global pandemic thing — it&#8217;ll be for the incredible number of SPAC deals across auto and mobility. There were 107 exits last year with 22 of them from startups going public via a merger with a special purpose acquisition, or &#8220;blank check&#8221; company. Having trouble gauging if that&#8217;s a big deal? Here&#8217;s some help: there were five auto and mobility SPACs between 2015 and 2019. Five. Electric vehicle companies and those with technology that supports EVs made up 68% of those SPAC deals in 2020.</p>
<p>The SPAC spree isn&#8217;t stopping either with Joby Aviation, Hellbiz and Otonomo are just a few that have reached merger agreements and will go public in 2021.</p>
<p>Electric vehicle tech and autonomous vehicle tech both reached peaks in 2020. EV tech companies raised $12.8 billion across 193 deals, while AVs brought in $7.3 billion across 105 deals, according to CB Insights. It&#8217;s worth noting that the AV industry appears to be maturing — at least in a funding perspective — with the average deal size rising 16.8% from the previous year to $104 million.</p>
<p>Connected car tech and auto commerce both saw dips in funding last year. For the second straight year, connected car tech saw a drop in funding and total number of deals. Funding plummeted 52% to $1 billion in 2020 compared to the previous year. CB Insights said the drop is because connectivity solutions have been widely adopted and investors have shifted their attention and money to other areas of auto tech such as electrification and autonomy.</p>
<p>Perhaps to no one&#8217;s surprise, bike and scooter companies saw funding rise 52% year-over-year to $2.4 billion in 2020. That&#8217;s still below funding seen in those heady days of 2017 and 2018 when scooters won over the hearts and minds of investors. Scooter and bike companies raked in $3.2 billion in 2017 and $4.9 billion in 2018.</p>
<p>And finally, funding to shared mobility companies (MaaS) fell 20% in 2020 to $6.3 billion across 116 deals.</p>
<p><strong>Other deals that got my attention &#8230;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Aero</strong>, a startup backed by Garrett Camp&#8217;s startup studio Expa, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/aero-series-a/">raised $20 millio</a>n in Series A funding round led by Keyframe Capital, with Keyframe’s chief investment officer John Rapaport joining the Aero board. Cyrus Capital Partners and Expa also participated.</p>
<p><strong>Boom Supersonic</strong>, the aerospace startup building supersonic jets, landed a strategic investment from American Express Ventures. The funds will be used for the development of the company&#8217;s flagship product, the supersonic airliner Overture.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary"><strong>Fluid Truck</strong>,  a Denver-based app-based platform that lets users make short-term rentals of commercial vehicles, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/fluid-truck-the-zipcar-of-commercial-trucks-raises-63m-to-take-on-rental-giants/">raised $63 million in a Series A funding round</a>. The truck sharing platform is aimed at mid-mile and last-mile delivery companies, which use it to remotely manage an on-demand rental fleet via web or mobile app. Private equity firm Bison Capital led the round, with participation from Ingka Investments (part of Ingka Group, the main Ikea retailer), Sumitomo Corporation of Americas and Fluid Vehicle Owners.</p>
<p><strong>Instacart</strong>, the n-demand grocery delivery platform, raised $265 million in funding from existing investors Andreessen Horowitz, Sequoia Capital, D1 Capital Partners and others. The new funding pushed the company&#8217;s valuation to $39 billion &#8212; more than double its $17.7 billion valuation when it raised $200 million just six months ago.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/instacart-raises-265m-at-a-39b-valuation/">TechCrunch&#8217;s Darrell Etherington writes</a>: What&#8217;s behind the massive increase in the value investors are willing to ascribe to the business? Put simply, the pandemic. Last year, Instacart announced three separate raises, including a $225 million round in June, followed by a $100 million round in July. The rapid sequence of venture capital injections were likely designed to fuel growth as demand for grocery delivery services surged while people attempted to quarantine or generally spend less time frequenting high-traffic social environments like grocery stores.</p>
<p><strong>Loggi Tecnologia</strong>, the Brazilian delivery company backed by SoftBank and Microsoft Corp., raised 1.15 billion reais ($205 million) in a round led by CapSur Capital, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-01/softbank-backed-loggi-valued-near-2-billion-in-funding-round?srnd=deals&amp;sref=gni836kR">Bloomberg reported</a>. The company is now valued close to $2 billion.</p>
<p><strong>Rollick</strong>, the online powersports, RV and boat buying marketplace, raised $8.5 million in a funding round that included investors Sandbox Insurtech Ventures, TechNexus Venture Collaborative, Dallas Venture Capital, Alumni Ventures, and London Technology Club. Existing investors LiveOak Venture Partners, Silverton Partners, Autotech Ventures, ManchesterStory, Anthem Venture Partners and Capital Factory also participated.</p>
<p><strong>Volocopter</strong>, a startup out of southern Germany that has been building and testing electric VTOL (vertical take-off and landing) aircraft, raised €200 million (about $241 million) in a Series D round of funding. New investors include funds managed by BlackRock, global infrastructure company Atlantia SpA., Avala Capital; Tier 1 supplier Continental AG, Japan’s NTT via its venture capital arm, Tokyo Century and multiple family offices.. Volocopter also said that all of its existing investors — a list that includes Geely, Daimler, DB Schenker, Intel Capital, btov Partners, Team Europe and Klocke Holding and more — also contributed to the round.</p>
<p>Alongside its aircraft, Volocopter has also been building a business case in which its vessels will be used in a taxi-style fleet in urban areas. CEO Florian Reuter told <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/flying-taxi-startup-volocopter-picks-up-another-241m-says-service-is-now-two-years-out/">TechCrunch editor Ingrid Lunden</a> that live services are now two years out for the two vehicle models it has been developing.</p>
<h2>Policy salmagundi</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896228 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png" alt="the station electric vehicles1" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-electric-vehicles1.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Policy: it&#8217;s what for dinner.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m trying out a new, semi-regular section in the newsletter that will cover notable legislative activity around electric vehicles, autonomous vehicles, public transit and personal mobility.</p>
<p>This week, let&#8217;s head on over to California, where State Sen. Dave Min introduced a bill that would require all autonomous vehicles to also be zero emission by 2025. The bill was sponsored by the Union of Concerned Scientists, a group says it doesn&#8217;t want to see future means of transportation married to the technology of the past. Proponents point out the potential for AVs to either help or hurt attempts to cut emissions.</p>
<p>While the amendment is in line with the state&#8217;s goals to reduce emissions, it also adds a wrinkle to the plans of any AV developer that doesn&#8217;t currently use electric vehicles. Cruise and Zoox, for instance, only use electric vehicles. AV giant Waymo and numerous others use a mix of vehicles, notably the Chrysler Pacifica Hybrid minivan.</p>
<p>As Rebecca Bellan <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/california-bill-would-require-all-self-driving-vehicles-to-be-zero-emission-by-2025/">notes in her article</a>, this proposed bill is in its infancy stages, so there are plenty of opportunities for it to be quashed.</p>
<p>The responses from the industry offered up the kind of political neutrality that aims to placate everyone. My interpretation of the various comments and statements — both on record and more informal on background chatter — is that work will soon begin to modify the language of the proposed bill to be more accommodating to the industry while hanging onto its original intent. That might mean pushing the deadline, adding hybrids and creating an exception for long-haul trucks.</p>
<hr />
<p>Meanwhile, over in the land of passenger electric vehicles, work is underway to pass laws that would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/ev-rivals-tesla-rivian-unite-to-target-direct-sales-legislation/">allow direct sales</a> in at least eight states. Passage of such legislation would clear the way for EV giants like Tesla, along with newcomers Lucid and Rivian, which have yet to bring a vehicle to market, to sell directly to consumers.</p>
<p>Tesla, Rivian and other EV entrants are working together to pass these laws. Industry alliances are not unheard of on issues in which all the parties stand to benefit. Tesla&#8217;s cooperation is notable because it would end its monopoly on direct sales in some states.</p>
<h2>Notable reads and other tidbits</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2037863 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png" alt="the-station-delivery" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Here are a few other stories that are worth sharing.</p>
<p><strong>Aston Martin</strong> CEO Tobias Moers&#8217; <a href="https://europe.autonews.com/automakers/why-aston-martins-ceo-confident-turnround-will-succeed?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+autonews%2FEuropeNews+%28Automotive+News+Europe+News+Feed%29">interview</a> with Automotive News Europe is a complementary side dish to Tamara Warren&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/the-aston-martin-dbx-is-a-tale-of-two-vehicles/">review of the DBX</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Postmates X</strong>, the robotics division of the on-demand delivery startup that Uber acquired last year for $2.65 billion, has officially spun out as an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/uber-spins-out-delivery-robot-startup-as-serve-robotics/">independent company called Serve Robotics</a>. (Y&#8217;all might recall I previously <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/uber-planning-to-spin-out-postmates-delivery-robot-arm/">reported that a deal</a> was being shopped to investors.)</p>
<p>Serve Robotics raised seed funding in a round led by venture capital firm Neo. Other investors included Uber as well as Lee Jacobs and Cyan Banister&#8217;s Long Journey Ventures, Western Technology Investment, Scott Banister, Farhad Mohit and Postmates co-founders Bastian Lehmann and Sean Plaice.</p>
<p><strong>Tesla</strong> is closing its forums and launching a new <a href="https://engage.tesla.com/articles/14-welcome-tesla-engagement-platform">social media platform</a> called the Tesla Engagement Platform. The move has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/tesla-has-closed-its-forums-to-launch-a-social-platform-and-fans-are-not-happy/">raised the ire</a> of a community of its most ardent supporters.</p>
<p><strong>Tortoise</strong> landed another deal, this time with Albertsons Companies, the grocery giant that owns Safeway and Jewel-Osco. Albertson said it has launched a pilot program that will test grocery delivery using remote-controlled delivery robots developed Tortoise. The pilot will start at two Safeway locations in Northern California, although Tortoise co-founder and president Dmitry Shevelenko said if successful, he expects the pilot to continue to scale to other stores in the state and possibly throughout the West Coast.</p>
<p><strong>Toyota Motor</strong> said it plans to sell 500 billion yen ($4.7 billion) in <a href="https://global.toyota/en/newsroom/corporate/34860933.html">&#8220;Woven Planet Bonds&#8221;</a> to fund a variety of <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">renewable energy</span> and transportation<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> projects, including  assisted mobility vehicles, and increased use of </span></p>
<p><strong>Volkswagen</strong> said it plans to launch an electric sedan in 2026. The company said that the vehicle, dubbed Project Trinity, will set &#8220;new standards&#8221; with its charging speed, battery range, and in other technology, <a href="https://www.caranddriver.com/news/a35741685/vw-to-build-ev-trinity-2026/">Car and Driver reported</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Volvo Cars</strong> said it will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/volvo-to-sell-only-all-electric-vehicles-by-2030/">only make and sell all-electric vehicles</a> by 2030 as part of a broader transformation of the automaker that will include shifting sales online. The announcement was tied to the launch of the C40 Recharge, a low-slung crossover based on the company&#8217;s CMA vehicle platform.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/the-station-another-uber-spinout-is-born-and-evs-dominate-spacs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122163</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swiss maker of meat alternatives Planted will expand and diversify with $18M Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/swiss-maker-of-meat-alternatives-planted-will-expand-and-diversify-with-18m-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/swiss-maker-of-meat-alternatives-planted-will-expand-and-diversify-with-18m-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 11:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative protein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planted]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Planted, a startup pursuing a unique method of creating a vegetarian chicken alternative, has raised an $18M (CHF 17M) Series A to expand its product offerings and international footprint. With new kebabs and pulled-style faux meats available and steak-like cuts in the (literal) pipeline, Planted has begun to set its sights outside central Europe. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://en.eatplanted.com">Planted</a>, a startup pursuing a unique method of creating a vegetarian chicken alternative, has raised an $18M (CHF 17M) Series A to expand its product offerings and international footprint. With new kebabs and pulled-style faux meats available and steak-like cuts in the (literal) pipeline, Planted has begun to set its sights outside central Europe.</p>
<p>The company was a spinout from ETH Zurich and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/10/planted-joins-the-meatless-meat-melee-with-its-pea-protein-chicken/">made its debut in 2019</a>, but has not rested on the success of its plain chicken recipe. Its approach, which relied on using pea protein and pea fiber extruded to recreate the fibrous structure of chicken for nearly 1:1 replacement in recipes, has proven to be adaptable for different styles and ingredients as well.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JjXvtjBjEn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/10/planted-joins-the-meatless-meat-melee-with-its-pea-protein-chicken/">Planted joins the meatless meat melee with its pea-protein &#8216;chicken&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Planted joins the meatless meat melee with its pea-protein &#8216;chicken&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/10/planted-joins-the-meatless-meat-melee-with-its-pea-protein-chicken/embed/#?secret=JjXvtjBjEn" data-secret="JjXvtjBjEn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We aim to use different proteins, so that there is diversity, both in terms of agriculture and dietary aspects,&#8221; said co-founder Christoph Jenny.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2121959" style="width: 460px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-ad.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2121959" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2121959" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-ad.jpg" alt="A woman bites into a artificial pulled pork sandwich." width="450" height="384" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-ad.jpg 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-ad.jpg?resize=150,128 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-ad.jpg?resize=300,256 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-ad.jpg?resize=768,656 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-ad.jpg?resize=680,581 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-ad.jpg?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2121959" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Planted</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;For example our newly launched planted.pulled consists of sunflower, oat and yellow pea proteins, changing both structure and taste to resemble pulled pork rather than chicken. The great thing about the sunflower proteins, they are upcycled from sunflower oil production. Hence, we are establishing a circular economy approach.&#8221;</p>
<p>When I first wrote about Planted, its products were only being distributed through a handful of restaurants and grocery stores. Now the company has a presence in more than 3,000 retail locations across Switzerland, Germany, and Austria, and works with restaurant and food service partners as well. No doubt this strong organic (so to speak) growth, and the growth of the meat alternative market in general, made raising money less of a chore.</p>
<p>The cash will be directed, as you might expect for a company at this stage, towards R&amp;D and further expansion.</p>
<p>&#8220;The funding will be used to expand our tech stack, to commercialize our prime cuts that are currently produced at lab scale,&#8221; said Jenny. &#8220;On the manufacturing side we look to significantly increase our current capacity of half a ton per hour to serve the increasing demand coming from international markets, first in neighboring countries and then further into Europe and overseas.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2121960" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-lab-2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2121960" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2121960" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-lab-2.jpg" alt="A large laboratory environment with clear walls. A person works at machinery in the foreground." width="1024" height="719" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-lab-2.jpg 2456w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-lab-2.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-lab-2.jpg?resize=300,211 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-lab-2.jpg?resize=768,539 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-lab-2.jpg?resize=680,478 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-lab-2.jpg?resize=1536,1079 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-lab-2.jpg?resize=2048,1438 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/planted-lab-2.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2121960" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Planted</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We will further invest in our structuring and fermentation platforms. Combining structuring technologies with the biochemical toolboxes of natural microorganisms will allow <span lang="en-US">u</span>s to create ultimately new products with transformative character &#8211; all clean, natural, healthy and tasty,&#8221; said co-founder <span lang="en-US">Lukas Böni in a press release.<br />
</span></p>
<p>No doubt this all will also help lower the price, a goal from the beginning but only possible by scaling up.</p>
<p>As other companies in this space also raise money (incidentally, rather large amounts of it) and expand to other markets, competition will be fierce — but Planted seems to be specializing in a few food types that aren&#8217;t as commonly found, at least in the U.S., where sausages, ground &#8220;beef,&#8221; and &#8220;chicken&#8221; nuggets have been the leading forms of meat alternatives.</p>
<p>No word on when Planted products will make it to American tables, but Jenny&#8217;s &#8220;overseas&#8221; suggests it is at least a possibility fairly soon.</p>
<p>The funding round was co-led by Vorwerk Ventures and Blue Horizon Ventures, with participation from Swiss football (soccer) player Yann Sommer and several previous investors.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/swiss-maker-of-meat-alternatives-planted-will-expand-and-diversify-with-18m-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121781</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK challenger bank Starling raises $376M, now valued at $1.9B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/uk-challenger-bank-starling-raises-376m-now-valued-at-1-9b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/uk-challenger-bank-starling-raises-376m-now-valued-at-1-9b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 10:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenger banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobanks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Challenger banks continue to see huge infusions of cash from investors bullish on the opportunity for smaller and faster-moving tech-based banking startups to woo customers from their larger rivals. In the latest development, UK-based Starling announced that is has closed £272 million ($376 million at current rates), at a pre-money valuation of £1.1 billion. This [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Challenger banks continue to see huge infusions of cash from investors bullish on the opportunity for smaller and faster-moving tech-based banking startups to woo customers from their larger rivals. In the latest development, UK-based <a href="https://www.starlingbank.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Starling</a> announced that is has closed £272 million ($376 million at current rates), at a pre-money valuation of £1.1 billion.</p>
<p>This means that the round, a Series D, values the company at £1.372 billion ($1.9 billion) post-money.</p>
<p>Starling &#8212; which competes against incumbent banks, as well as other challengers like Monzo and Revolut &#8212; said it will be using the money to continue its growth. The bank is already profitable. In updated financials posted today, Starling said it generated revenue of £12 million ($16.6 million) in January of this year, up 400% compared to a year ago, with an annualized revenue run rate of £145 million. It posted operating profits for a fourth consecutive month, and net income currently exceeds £1.5 million per month.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Starling, founded in 2017, has now pased 2 million accounts, with 300,000 business accounts among them. It&#8217;s not clear how many of those accounts are active: the figures are for opened accounts, Starling said. Gross lending has passed £2 billion, with deposits at £5.4 billion.</p>
<p>Starling said it plans to use the funding both to expand its lending operations in the UK, to expand into other parts of Europe, and make some strategic acquisitions.</p>
<p>“Digital banking has reached a tipping point,&#8221; said Anne Boden, founder and CEO of Starling Bank, in a statement. &#8220;Customers now expect a fairer, smarter and more human alternative to the banks of the past and that is what we are giving them at Starling as we continue to grow and add new products and services. Our new investors will bring a wealth of experience as we enter the next stage of growth, while the continued support of our existing backers represents a huge vote of confidence.”</p>
<p>This latest round is being led by Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company, with Qatar Investment Authority (QIA); RPMI Railpen (Railpen), the investment manager for the £31 billion Railways Pension Scheme; and global investment firm Millennium Management also participating, and it comes on the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/06/starling-fund-raising/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">heels of us reporting in November</a> that it was raising at least £200 million.</p>
<p>The funding arrives at a critical time in consumer banking. The trend in the UK &#8212; the market where Starling is active &#8212; for the last several years has been a gradual shift to online and mobile banking. To decelerate the spread of Covid-19, those trends rapidly picked up pace in the last year of lock-downs and enforced social distancing.</p>
<p>Challenger (neo) banks have been some of the biggest winners of evolving consumer habits. Using rails provided as white-label services by way of APIs from banking infrastructure providers (another startup category in itself with companies like Rapyd, Plaid, Mambu, CurrencyCloud and others all involved) they will offer the same basic services such as checking and deposit, but they will typically do so with considerably  more flexibility, and additional savings and financial tips, and other services provided to customers (such as monthly financial calculators) &#8212; all carried out over digital platforms.</p>
<p>Big, incumbent banks have scrambled to keep up with innovation, but newer generations of users are less beholden to their brands and incumbency, not least a result of the banking crisis last decade that revealed many of them to be cosiderably less competent and solid than many might have assumed.</p>
<p>That bigger market picture has also meant a surge of many neobanks, and so Starling competes with more than just the incumbents. Others include Monese, Revolut, Tide, Atom and Monzo &#8212; the latter a particularly acute competitor, founded by the ex-CTO of Starling.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/uk-challenger-bank-starling-raises-376m-now-valued-at-1-9b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122170</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deliveroo posted narrowed loss of $309M, with gross transactions surging to $5.7B in 2020, EITF shows</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/deliveroo-posted-narrowed-loss-of-309m-with-gross-transactions-surging-to-5-7b-in-2020-eitf-shows/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/deliveroo-posted-narrowed-loss-of-309m-with-gross-transactions-surging-to-5-7b-in-2020-eitf-shows/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deliveroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on-demand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122166</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The clock has officially started ticking on Deliveroo&#8217;s plans to go public in April. After announcing last week that it planned to list on the London Stock Exchange, today the on-demand food delivery company backed by Amazon and others published selected updated financials for the previous fiscal year, along with its Expected Intention to Float (EITF) [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The clock has officially started ticking on <a href="http://deliveroo.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Deliveroo&#8217;s</a> plans to go public in April. After announcing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/deliveroo-confirms-anticipated-8bn-floatation-in-london-will-be-among-first-to-use-dual-shares-structure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last week</a> that it planned to list on the London Stock Exchange, today the on-demand food delivery company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/16/amazon-takes-a-bite-into-deliveroo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">backed by Amazon</a> and others published selected updated financials for the previous fiscal year, along with its <a href="https://corporate.deliveroo.co.uk/protected_file/166/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Expected Intention to Float (EITF)</a> &#8212; a more formal document that marks the two-week period until the company publishes its prospectus and, at the start of April, embarks on its subsequent IPO.</p>
<p>The bottom line is that Deliveroo is still unprofitable. It posted a 2020 underlying loss of £223.7 million ($309 million), but that figure was down by nearly £100 million from 2019, when it chalked up a loss of £317 million ($438 million). It did not disclose revenues (sometimes called turnover) in today&#8217;s statement.</p>
<p>The company said that it now serves some 6 million customers, with its three-sided marketplace also including more than 115,000 restaurants, takeaways and grocery stores, and 100,000 riders in 800 locations among 12 markets.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At the same time, Deliveroo showed some clear momentum in a year where many restaurants had to close their doors and shift operations to take-away models because of Covid-19.</p>
<p>It notes that it has been profitable on an &#8220;Adjusted EBITDA basis&#8221; over two quarters, with underlying gross profit up by 89.5% to £358 million ($495 million) compared to £189 million in 2019.</p>
<p>Its gross transaction volume (total amount spent by consumers ordering food) grew by 64% to £4.1 billion ($5.67 billion) with the run-rate in Q4 surging to £5 billion. This figure is unsurprising when you consider that Q4 represented the holiday period, and additionally the UK market (Deliveroo&#8217;s primary market and its home) went through not one but two different periods of being locked down in that quarter (the second of these is still in place).</p>
<p>It also notes that gross profit margin as a percentage of GTV has grown from 5.8% in 2018 to 8.8% in 2020, with some markets getting to 12%.</p>
<p>&#8220;The company remains focused on investing in driving growth in a nascent online food market,&#8221; it noted in the EITF, although I&#8217;m not sure nascent is exactly the word I&#8217;d use. Its drivers are easily the most visible of the many delivery services that exist in London. Deliveroo estimates that the restaurant and grocery sectors represent an addressable market of £1.2 trillion ($1.66 trillion) across the 12 regions where it offers services. In that figure, it says that just 3% of sales are estimated to be online, &#8220;equivalent to less than 1 out of the 21 weekly meal occasions being online.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company was valued at <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-17/deliveroo-s-latest-funding-round-values-firm-at-over-7-billion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">over $7 billion</a> in it last fundraising, a $180 million round from Durable, Fidelity and others, as recently as January of this year.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a huge leap that is the stuff that tech myths are made of (with untold hours of blood, sweat and tears, and a lot of luck too). I met Will Shu, the CEO and founder, when he was just really getting started at Deliveroo, and he seemed somewhat bewildered by how fast the startup was growing and where it was leading him. It&#8217;s interesting that he himself hasn&#8217;t forgotten those early days, either, which surely help keep the company focused at a time when there are a lot of opportunities, and therefore a lot of potential for focus unravelling.</p>
<p>&#8220;I never set out to be a founder or a CEO. I was never into start-ups, I didn’t read TechCrunch. I’m not one of those Silicon Valley types with a million ideas,&#8221; he noted in his letter published in the EITF. &#8220;I had one idea. One idea born out of personal frustration. An idea that I was fanatically obsessed with: I wanted to get great food delivered from amazing London restaurants.&#8221;</p>
<p>The prospectus will tell us how much the company intends to raise in its IPO so we&#8217;ll know those numbers soon. In the meantime, Deliveroo said that it plans to &#8220;invest in its long-term proposition by developing its core marketplace, enhancing its superior consumer experience, providing restaurant and grocery partners with unique tools to help them grow their businesses, and providing riders with the flexible work they value alongside security.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also going to continue building out &#8220;dark kitchens&#8221; (which it brands Editions); Signature, a white-label service for restaurants to offer delivery via their own online channels; Plus, a Prime-style loyalty subscription service; and on-demand grocery &#8212; which is also shaping up to be a huge market in Europe and the rest of the world.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/deliveroo-posted-narrowed-loss-of-309m-with-gross-transactions-surging-to-5-7b-in-2020-eitf-shows/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122166</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Porsche raises stake in electric car and components maker Rimac Automobili</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/porsche-raises-stake-in-electric-car-and-components-maker-rimac-automobili/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/porsche-raises-stake-in-electric-car-and-components-maker-rimac-automobili/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 08:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rimac automobili]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122128</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rimac Automobili, the Croatian company known for its electric hypercars and battery and powertrain development, has gained yet another investment from Porsche AG. Porsche said Monday it has invested 70 million euros ($83.3 miilion) into Rimac, a move that increases its stake from 15% to 24%. This is the third time Porsche has invested into [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rimac Automobili, the Croatian company known for its electric hypercars and battery and powertrain development, has gained yet another investment from Porsche AG.</p>
<p>Porsche said Monday it has invested 70 million euros ($83.3 miilion) into Rimac, a move that increases its stake from 15% to 24%.</p>
<p>This is the third time Porsche has invested into Rimac. The German automaker made its first investment into Rimac in 2018. Porsche increased its equity stake into Rimac in September 2019. A few months earlier, Hyundai Motor Company and Kia Motors jointly <a href="https://www.rimac-automobili.com/en/press/news/hyundai-motor-and-kia-motors-invest-80m-eur-in-rimac-and-establish-a-technology-partnership/?fbclid=IwAR1DZRsy0vQRCQVufkAiW4nBeLPRz6DaQiTQedv4ZughZIDaxfQ0FMNfCRo">invested €80 million</a> ($90 million at the time) into Rimac.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Rimac was founded by Mate Rimac in 2009 and is perhaps best known for its electric hypercars, such as the two-seater C Two that it debuted in 2018 at the Geneva International Motor Show. The vehicle produces an eye-popping 1,914 horsepower, has a top speed of 256 miles per hour and can accelerate from 0 to 60 mph in 1.85 seconds. Rimac plans to unveil C Two in its final form in 2021.</p>
<p>However, Rimac does more than produce hypercars. The company, which employs 1,000 people, <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">also focuses on battery technology within the high-voltage segment, engineers and manufactures electric powertrains and develops digital interfaces between humans and machines. </span></p>
<p>Porsche is most interested in Rimac&#8217;s development of components, according to comments made by Lutz Meschke, the deputy chairman of Porsche AG&#8217;s executive board. Meschke noted that Rimac is &#8220;excellently positioned in prototype solutions and small series&#8221; and &#8220;is well on its way to becoming a Tier 1 supplier for Porsche and other manufacturers in the high-tech segment.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Porsche has already placed its first orders with Rimac for the development of highly innovative series components, according to Meschke.</span></p>
<p>Despite its continued investments, Porsche said it doesn&#8217;t have a controlling stake in Rimac.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/porsche-raises-stake-in-electric-car-and-components-maker-rimac-automobili/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122128</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hong Kong fintech unicorn WeLab raises $75M led by insurance giant Allianz</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/welab-75-million-fundraise-allianz/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/welab-75-million-fundraise-allianz/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 07:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ant Financial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ant group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeLab]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the few industries that have benefited from the COVID-19 crisis is online finance. Around the world, the pandemic has forced consumers to adopt digital banking. Hong Kong&#8217;s WeLab, a fintech company founded in 2013, saw users soar by 20% year-over-year in 2020, bringing its accumulative user base to 50 million. Facing innovative players [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">One of the few industries that have benefited from the COVID-19 crisis is online finance. Around the world, the pandemic has forced consumers to adopt digital banking. Hong Kong&#8217;s WeLab, a fintech company founded in 2013, saw users soar by 20% year-over-year in 2020, bringing its accumulative user base to 50 million.</p>
<p>Facing innovative players like WeLab, which aims to bring more convenience, transparency, and affordability to consumers, financial incumbents feel compelled to reinvent themselves. That&#8217;s in part why <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/20/allianz-x-1-billion-eur/">Allianz X</a>, a venture capital arm of the 131-year-old European financial conglomerate Allianz, led WeLab&#8217;s latest funding round of $75 million. The Series C1, which involved other investors, followed WeLab&#8217;s <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/welab-raises-us156m-in-series-c-strategic-financing-completing-the-largest-fintech-fundraising-in-greater-china-in-2019-300973821.html">$156 million Series C round</a> in late 2019.</p>
<p>&#8220;Obviously, Allianz is one of the largest asset managers and insurers in the world with a strong presence and solid footprint,&#8221; co-founder and CEO Simon Loong told TechCrunch during an interview.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Loong declined to disclose WeLab&#8217;s latest valuation but said the number has gone up since the firm last reached the $1 billion unicorn status.</p>
<p>When WeLab set out to build a digital bank, which launched in Hong Kong last year, one of the products it had in mind was &#8220;a new generation of wealth advisory on digital banks.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Allianz saw what we did over the last couple of years and identified this very interesting opportunity to co-develop a wealth technology for digital banks, so they came to us and said, why don&#8217;t they lead the round?&#8221; Loong explained.</p>
<p>Through the strategic investment, the partners will jointly develop and distribute investment and insurance solutions across Asia. Those products will diversify Welab&#8217;s current offerings, including a virtual bank and a lending product in Hong Kong, as well as several types of lending services in mainland China and Indonesia. Around 47 million of its total users are in mainland China, 2.5 million in Indonesia, and less than one million in Hong Kong, a city with a 7.5 million population.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s an interesting four-way cooperation,&#8221; said Loong, referring to the roles of Allianz as an asset management and insurance firm, and WeLab as a bank and fintech solution provider. &#8220;I think it will really be an interesting inflection point for the company to scale.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Working with titans</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2122158" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122158" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2122158" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/WeLab-Team-Photo.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="749" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/WeLab-Team-Photo.jpg 6706w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/WeLab-Team-Photo.jpg?resize=150,110 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/WeLab-Team-Photo.jpg?resize=300,220 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/WeLab-Team-Photo.jpg?resize=768,562 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/WeLab-Team-Photo.jpg?resize=680,498 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/WeLab-Team-Photo.jpg?resize=1536,1124 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/WeLab-Team-Photo.jpg?resize=2048,1499 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/WeLab-Team-Photo.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2122158" class="wp-caption-text">The WeLab team</p></div></p>
<p>Equally important to WeLab&#8217;s revenue is enterprise services, according to Loong, which are helping conventional banks and financial institutions build up a digital presence. The strategy is not unlike Ant Group&#8217;s effort to be an &#8220;<a href="https://www.techinasia.com/ant-financial-wants-to-be-tech-company">enabler</a>&#8221; for traditional financial players.</p>
<p>In spite of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/tencent-vs-alibaba-ant-fintech/">massive combined market share</a> of Ant and Tencent in China&#8217;s fintech market, there remains room for smaller and more specialized players like WeLab. To date, WeLab has attracted about 600 enterprise customers, most of whom are in mainland China.</p>
<p>&#8220;[We have] an interesting dynamics with Ant,&#8221; said Loong, when asked how WeLab wrestles with a goliath like Ant, whose e-commerce affiliate Alibaba is an investor in WeLab through the Alibaba Hong Kong Entrepreneurs Fund.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are businesses where we compete, and there are also areas where we work well together,&#8221; he added. For example, WeLab introduced one of the first smartphone leasing services on Alipay, Ant&#8217;s flagship app that works as a marketplace for third-party financial products and end consumers. But Ant also has its own in-house financial products, which could clash with outside suppliers peddling on its marketplace.</p>
<p>&#8220;In short, I would say that because we are a rather independent company, we work with everyone,&#8221; Loong asserted.</p>
<h2>Greater Bay links</h2>
<p>As a Hong Kong-founded firm, WeLab has actively taken part in the Chinese government&#8217;s push to integrate what&#8217;s dubbed the Greater Bay Area, which spans the two special administrative regions of China, Hong Kong and Macau, and nine cities in the southern province of Guangdong, including Shenzhen.</p>
<p>An objective of the GBA blueprint is to encourage cross-border talent flow. In a way, the area has all the right conditions to run a fintech startup, which would gain access to technological and banking talents respectively in Shenzhen and Hong Kong, two adjoining cities. WeLab has done exactly that, with a larger base of tech staff in Shenzhen compared to its Hong Kong office which has more finance professionals. <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">It&#8217;s planning to add around 100 hires this year to its 800-person headcount.</span></p>
<p>Aside from shared talent pools, Beijing also wants to encourage more financial integration in the GBA. WeLab has taken notice and plans to roll out its forthcoming wealth management products first in Hong Kong and later into other parts of the GBA through the government-supported scheme called the <a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/cn/en/pages/financial-services/articles/wealth-management-connect-in-the-gba.html">Wealth Management Connect</a>, which allows residents of Hong Kong and Macau to invest in wealth management products distributed by mainland banks in the GBA. Vice versa, residents in the mainland GBA cities will be able to buy wealth management products in Hong Kong and Macau.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hong Kong is a great testbed, but for online business, you need to subject your successful business model to a large population,&#8221; said Loong, explaining the company&#8217;s expansion plan. &#8220;The Greater Bay Area gives us the opportunity to do so. There is a 72 million population with a GDP of $1.7 trillion, which is larger than South Korea&#8230; Naturally, it is a good area to scale.&#8221;</p>
<p>WeLab was looking to go public back in 2018 but halted the plan because &#8220;we didn&#8217;t feel that it was the right market window to do this,&#8221; Loong recalled. The company was also in the process of securing a banking license, so it decided to work on the critical permit before going public.</p>
<p>&#8220;Obviously if you look now, it&#8217;s very hot in terms of the equity market,&#8221; said Loong. &#8220;So we are talking to a lot of people. We keep a close eye on this and we are always open-minded to explore the next right market window for us.&#8221;</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/welab-75-million-fundraise-allianz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121509</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OnePlus recruits Hasselblad for three-year smartphone imaging deal</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/oneplus-recruits-hasselblad-for-three-year-smartphone-imaging-deal/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/oneplus-recruits-hasselblad-for-three-year-smartphone-imaging-deal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 06:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hasselblad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OnePlus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Imaging has long been the primary battlefield on which the smartphone battles are waged. It makes sense. The thing about smartphones in 2021 is that they’re mostly very good. Sure, there are differentiators, but if you spend a decent amount on a device from any major manufacturer, you’re probably going to get a pretty good [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Imaging has long been the primary battlefield on which the smartphone battles are waged. It makes sense. The thing about smartphones in 2021 is that they’re mostly very good. Sure, there are differentiators, but if you spend a decent amount on a device from any major manufacturer, you’re probably going to get a pretty good device.</p>
<p>But there’s still plenty of opportunity to continually bridge the gap between smartphone imaging and devoted camera systems. And today OnePlus takes a potentially key step in that direction by announcing a partnership with Hasselblad. The DJI-owned Swedish camera maker has signed onto a three-year partnership with OnePlus.</p>
<p>According to a release tied to the news, the pair plan to spend $150 million over the course of the deal, in an attempt to vault OnePlus to the front of the pack. Hasselblad has dipped its toes in the mobile market, including a Moto Z attachment, and has created cameras for DJI drones, but this represents a pretty big move for the 180-year-old camera company.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The first fruits of the partnership will arrive on the OnePlus 9, a new handset set to launch on March 23. The companies promise a “revamped camera system.” The phone will feature a Sony IMX789 sensor, coupled with HDR video and the ability capture 4K at 120FPS and 8K at 30FPS.</p>
<p>Per the release:</p>
<blockquote><p>The partnership will continuously develop over the next three years, starting with software improvements including color tuning and sensor calibration, and extending to more dimensions in the future. The two parties will jointly define the technology standards of the mobile camera experience and develop innovative imaging technologies, continuing to improve the Hasselblad Camera for Mobile. Both companies are committed to delivering immediate benefit for OnePlus users, while continuously collaborating to further improve the user experience and quality for the long-term.</p></blockquote>
<p>The deal includes the development of four global labs, including U.S. and Japan locations and:</p>
<blockquote><p>Pioneering new areas of smartphone imaging technology for future OnePlus camera systems, such as a panoramic camera with a 140-degree field of view, T-lens technology for lightning-fast focus in the front-facing camera, and a freeform lens – to be first introduced on the OnePlus 9 Series – that practically eliminates edge distortion in ultrawide photos.</p></blockquote>
<p>It will be interesting to see how a company like Hasselblad will take to mobile imaging, though such a deal could be a secret weapon as OnePlus looks to keep on the flagship end of the mobile spectrum against the likes of Apple and Samsung.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8fNtYPIdiP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/will-apples-spectacular-iphone-12-sales-figures-boost-the-smartphone-industry-in-2021/">Will Apple&#8217;s spectacular iPhone 12 sales figures boost the smartphone industry in 2021?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will Apple&#8217;s spectacular iPhone 12 sales figures boost the smartphone industry in 2021?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/will-apples-spectacular-iphone-12-sales-figures-boost-the-smartphone-industry-in-2021/embed/#?secret=8fNtYPIdiP" data-secret="8fNtYPIdiP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="x4FFuea5bl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/23/onepluss-8t-handset-brings-faster-charging-and-a-120hz-display-for-749/">OnePlus’s 8T handset brings faster charging and a 120Hz display for $749 </a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;OnePlus’s 8T handset brings faster charging and a 120Hz display for $749 &#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/23/onepluss-8t-handset-brings-faster-charging-and-a-120hz-display-for-749/embed/#?secret=x4FFuea5bl" data-secret="x4FFuea5bl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/oneplus-recruits-hasselblad-for-three-year-smartphone-imaging-deal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121922</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google unveils $25 million in grants aimed at empowering women and girls</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/google-unveils-25-million-in-grants-aimed-at-empowering-women-and-girls/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/google-unveils-25-million-in-grants-aimed-at-empowering-women-and-girls/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Pay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google.org]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google announced a range of programs as well as grants worth $25 million on Monday to fund works of nonprofits and social enterprises that are committed to empower women and girls. Google.org&#8217;s new Impact Challenge, unveiled on Internet Women&#8217;s Day, is aimed at addressing systemic barriers and inequities so that women have access to economic equality, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google announced a range of programs as well as grants worth $25 million on Monday to fund works of nonprofits and social enterprises that are committed to empower women and girls.</p>
<p>Google.org&#8217;s new <a href="https://impactchallenge.withgoogle.com/womenandgirls2021">Impact Challenge</a>, unveiled on Internet Women&#8217;s Day, is aimed at addressing systemic barriers and inequities so that women have access to economic equality, opportunity to build financial independence and pursue entrepreneurism, said Google chief executive Sundar Pichai at a virtual event.</p>
<p>&#8220;Whatever these teams need, we are going to be alongside them and help carry out their vision,&#8221; said Jacquelline Fuller, President of Google.org, at the event. The company said it will accept applications from teams worldwide until April 9.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Fuller also announced that Google.org is going to invest an additional $1 million to help underserved women in India. Even as India is the world&#8217;s second largest internet market, women make up a small percentage of online users in the country.</p>
<p>Five years ago, Google launched a program called <a href="https://internetsaathiindia.org/">Internet Saathi</a> to bring internet literacy to women in rural parts of India. The company said the program, for which it collaborated with Indian conglomerate Tata, significantly helped improve women&#8217;s participation on Indian internet.</p>
<p>Four of 10 internet users in rural India are now women, said Google, up from one in 10 in 2015. The company, citing its own research, said Internet Saathi program benefited more than 30 million women in India &#8212; and that it&#8217;s now concluding the program to focus on other efforts to continue this mission.</p>
<p>“This program created a cascading effect,” said Sanjay Gupta, the head of Google India, at the event.</p>
<p>But simply getting online &#8220;isn&#8217;t progress enough,&#8221; said Sapna Chadha, Senior Marketing Director for Google in India and Southeast Asia. &#8220;Women in India have traditionally been held back from economic participation.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company has partnered with Nasscom Foundation, the social arm of influential Indian trade group, to bring digital and financial literacy to 100,000 women farmers in India, and is creating a program called &#8220;Women Will&#8221; to enable and support 1 million women entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>As part of Women Will program, Chadha unveiled a <a href="http://g.co/skillingindia">repository website</a> that she said will feature tutorials, business ideas and other opportunities in English and Hindi languages.</p>
<p>Google is also working on rolling out a new feature on Google Pay app that will allow entrepreneurs to showcase their business pages within the payments app at no charge, said Chadha. And women entrepreneurs can now choose to highlight that their business is led by a woman or women across Google Search and Google Maps listings, Chadha said.</p>
<p>&#8220;I call upon you to come together to build a future we can all be proud of &#8212; a future where no daughter of ours is shackled by the burdens of her gender,&#8221; said Smriti Irani, Minister of Women and Child Development, Government of India, at the event.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/google-unveils-25-million-in-grants-aimed-at-empowering-women-and-girls/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122133</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese beauty app Meitu bought $40 million worth of cryptocurrency</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/china-meitu-crypto-investment/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/china-meitu-crypto-investment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meitu]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following in the footsteps of Tesla, Chinese app maker Meitu has joined the ranks of cryptocurrency investment. In the early 2010s, Meitu reached such dominance in the portrait touch-up space that its eponymous flagship app became a verb for &#8220;photo beautifying&#8221; in China. But in recent years, as smartphones became to offer built-in filters, photo [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Following in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/teslas-bitcoin-investment-could-be-bad-for-the-companys-climate-reputation-and-its-bottom-line/">the footsteps of Tesla</a>, Chinese app maker Meitu has joined the ranks of cryptocurrency investment.</p>
<p>In the early 2010s, Meitu reached such dominance in the portrait touch-up space that its eponymous flagship app became a verb for &#8220;photo beautifying&#8221; in China. But in recent years, as smartphones became to offer built-in filters, photo editors like Meitu are struggling to hold their lead. Meitu&#8217;s stock shrank from HK$18 apiece in 2017 to less than HK$3 today.</p>
<p>As the company turns 13 years old and seeks alternative growth, it sets its eyes on cryptocurrency.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Meitu purchased 15,000 units of Ether and 379.1214267 units of Bitcoin worth around $22.1 million and $17.9 million respectively on March 5 in open market transactions, the company <a href="https://corp-static.meitu.com/corp-new/92016878a68bac4ad8121e906eae6687_1615115628.pdf">disclosed </a>Sunday. The purchase is the first tranche of the firm&#8217;s investment plan to buy up to $100 million worth of cryptocurrency, which is financed by its cash reserves.</p>
<p>In recent times, Meitu chairman Cai Wensheng has been an outspoken <a href="https://weibo.com/1729853157/GeXMxjpF4?from=page_1003061729853157_profile&amp;wvr=6&amp;mod=weibotime">advocate of blockchain technologies</a>. Though China has banned initial coin offerings and crypto trading exchanges, Cai said in 2018 that he personally <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/chinese-angel-investor-amassed-10000-bitcoins-amid-q1-price-slump">bought about 10,000 bitcoins</a>.</p>
<p>His support for cryptocurrencies is manifested in Meitu&#8217;s latest investment move. In the disclosure, the company states:</p>
<p>&#8220;The Board takes the view that blockchain technology has the potential to disrupt both existing financial and technology industries, similar to the manner in which mobile internet has disrupted the PC internet and many other offline industries. The Board believes that the blockchain industry is still in its early stage, analogous to the mobile internet industry in circa 2005.&#8221;</p>
<p>It continues: &#8220;Against this backdrop, the Board believes cryptocurrencies have ample room for appreciation in value and by allocating part of its treasury in cryptocurrencies can also serve as a diversification to holding cash treasury management.&#8221;</p>
<p>Meitu further explains that the Bitcoin investment is part of its &#8220;asset allocation&#8221; plan while its bet on Ether will aid its general blockchain endeavor, wherein it&#8217;s considering baking blockchain into its various overseas businesses, including Ethereum-based dApps. It&#8217;s also looking to invest in overseas blockchain projects &#8220;that can be synergistic to its large user base.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://corp-static.meitu.com/corp-new/a4f85272b958835d2079f0895f3c22df_1598524316.pdf">As of June 2020</a>, Meitu claimed nearly 300 million monthly active users on its suite of apps released across the globe.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nA1LunuCvw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/bsn-china-national-blockchain/">China&#8217;s national blockchain network embraces global developers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China&#8217;s national blockchain network embraces global developers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/bsn-china-national-blockchain/embed/#?secret=nA1LunuCvw" data-secret="nA1LunuCvw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/china-meitu-crypto-investment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122127</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Praava Health raises $10.6M to increase access to quality healthcare in Bangladesh</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/praava-health-raises-10-6m-to-increase-access-to-quality-healthcare-in-bangladesh/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/praava-health-raises-10-6m-to-increase-access-to-quality-healthcare-in-bangladesh/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 02:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Before launching Praava Health, a company that combines telemedicine with physical clinics, Sylvana Sinha had a successful career in international law, including serving as a foreign policy advisor to Barack Obama&#8217;s 2008 presidential campaign and working for the World Bank in Afghanistan. While visiting Bangladesh in 2011 for a family wedding, however, Sinha had a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2122060" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/P1177418.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122060" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2122060" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/P1177418.jpg" alt="Praava Health founder and chief executive officer Sylvana Sinha (third from left) at one of the company's healthcare centers" width="1024" height="738" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/P1177418.jpg 5021w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/P1177418.jpg?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/P1177418.jpg?resize=300,216 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/P1177418.jpg?resize=768,553 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/P1177418.jpg?resize=680,490 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/P1177418.jpg?resize=1536,1106 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/P1177418.jpg?resize=2048,1475 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/P1177418.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2122060" class="wp-caption-text">Praava Health founder and chief executive officer Sylvana Sinha (third from left) at one of the company&#8217;s healthcare centers</p></div></p>
<p>Before launching <a href="https://praavahealth.com/">Praava Health</a>, a company that combines telemedicine with physical clinics, Sylvana Sinha had a successful career in international law, including serving as a foreign policy advisor to Barack Obama&#8217;s 2008 presidential campaign and working for the World Bank in Afghanistan. While visiting Bangladesh in 2011 for a family wedding, however, Sinha had a &#8220;lightbulb moment&#8221; after her mother nearly died after an operation at a top private hospital.</p>
<p>&#8220;When I had this experience with my mom, I observed that there was really no amount of money that could afford you access to quality healthcare in Bangladesh,&#8221; she told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;It really struck me that despite all the progress the country had made, and the fact that there is now a middle class of 40 million people, that there are still not really great options for excellent healthcare,&#8221; she added. &#8220;You have thousands of people traveling abroad every day and billions of dollars a year going outside the country to access better healthcare.&#8221;</p>
<p>Born and raised in the United States, Sinha moved to Bangladesh in 2015 to start working on Praava. Today the company is announcing a Series A Prime round that brings its total raised to $10.6 million. Praava claims to have tripled its growth every year since launching services in 2018, and now serves 150,000 patients. In 2020, it also processed 75,000 COVID-19 tests in-house.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2122061" style="width: 460px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/patient-portal.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2122061" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2122061" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/patient-portal.jpg" alt="Praava Health's patient portal app" width="450" height="498" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/patient-portal.jpg 1175w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/patient-portal.jpg?resize=135,150 135w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/patient-portal.jpg?resize=271,300 271w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/patient-portal.jpg?resize=768,850 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/patient-portal.jpg?resize=614,680 614w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/patient-portal.jpg?resize=45,50 45w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2122061" class="wp-caption-text">Praava Health&#8217;s patient portal app</p></div></p>
<p>Praava&#8217;s backers include a list of prominent angel investors: retired United States Army General David H. Petraeus, chairman of the KKR Global Institute and former director of the Central Intelligence Agency, who also invested in Praava’s seed round; Wellville executive founder Esther Dyson; SBK Tech Ventures; Dr. Jeremy Lim, advisor of digital health to Singapore’s Agency for Science, Technology and Research; Dr. Rushika Fernandopoulle, co-founder and CEO of Iora Health; and Geoff Price, co-founder and chief operating officer of Oak Street Health.</p>
<p>The company has a flagship medical center in the Dhaka, Bangladesh’s capital, and a network of 40 smaller clinics throughout the city. Praava plans to open more clinics in Dhaka, before expanding into Chittagong, the country’s second-largest city.</p>
<p>Its &#8220;brick-and-click&#8221; model, including online consultations, also allows it to reach patients throughout the country. Virtual healthcare accounts for about 40% of Praava’s services including telemedicine and an online pharmacy.</p>
<p>Bangladesh is one of the<a href="https://www.cfr.org/blog/reach-its-economic-dreams-bangladesh-needs-rethink-healthcare"> fastest-growing economies in the world</a>, but there is a critical shortage of healthcare workers for its 170 million people. The <a href="https://www.who.int/workforcealliance/countries/bgd/en/">World Health Organization estimates</a> that there are only about 3 physicians and 1 nurse for every 10,000 people, and most work in urban hospitals, even though 70% of Bangladesh’s population is in rural areas. This means people often travel long distances for consultations that may last less than a minute.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="moyv8He6IN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/bangladesh-based-maya-a-startup-focused-on-accessible-healthcare-raises-2-2-million-seed-round/">Maya, a startup focused on accessible healthcare in Asia, raises $2.2 million seed for regional expansion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Maya, a startup focused on accessible healthcare in Asia, raises $2.2 million seed for regional expansion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/bangladesh-based-maya-a-startup-focused-on-accessible-healthcare-raises-2-2-million-seed-round/embed/#?secret=moyv8He6IN" data-secret="moyv8He6IN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;One of the things that we see telemedicine really help with is patients outside of Dhaka to figure out if they even need to make that trip,&#8221; said Sinha.</p>
<p>The company found that in over 80% of cases, especially primary care, its providers are able to address patient needs online. In the remaining 20% of cases, they will ask them to come into one of Praava’s clinics, which provide a wide range of outpatient services, imaging and lab diagnostics and a pharmacy.</p>
<p>At the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, about 90% of Praava&#8217;s consultations were happening virtually, though clinic visits have picked up again. Most of Praava&#8217;s doctors are salaried full-time employees and one of its goals is to create deeper provider-patient relationships, with appointments typically lasting about 15 minutes.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think technology is the future of health, there’s absolutely no doubt about that,&#8221; Sinha said. &#8220;But when it come to seeing a doctor and the kind of healthcare needs that we all have over the course of our lifetime, technology is not going to be able to replace that entirely.&#8221;</p>
<p>Most of Praava&#8217;s patients currently pay per visit, and its pricing is at market rate, between Bangladesh&#8217;s public healthcare system and more expensive private hospitals. It has also introduced membership plans with a flat rate for unlimited access to services.</p>
<p>Sinha said this is a very new type of model in Bangladesh, where only 1% of people have health insurance, primarily to cover hospitalizations.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s our experiment of introducing value-based care to the region, so we&#8217;re very excited about the product, but it&#8217;s a new product and we expect it to pick up more in the coming years,&#8221; she added. &#8220;It&#8217;s already picked up a lot in the last year, because I think people are more health conscious and corporations are more willing to invest in employees’ health.&#8221;</p>
<p>With its new funding, Praava will focus on building a &#8220;super app&#8221; for patients, to consolidate all of its digital services into one mobile app. It also plans to open 10 more healthcare centers in Dhaka, before expanding into Chittagong. Praava&#8217;s &#8220;brick-and-click&#8221; model can scale into other emerging markets, but it plans to concentrate on Bangladesh for the next few years.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are 170 million people to take care of first,&#8221; Sinha said. &#8220;So we’re really focused on this market on this market for now.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XgCD96w4zl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-healthcare-b2b-and-infrastructure/">Where top VCs are investing in healthcare B2B and infrastructure</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Where top VCs are investing in healthcare B2B and infrastructure&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-healthcare-b2b-and-infrastructure/embed/#?secret=XgCD96w4zl" data-secret="XgCD96w4zl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/praava-health-raises-10-6m-to-increase-access-to-quality-healthcare-in-bangladesh/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122057</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: Win Win</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/gillmor-gang-win-win/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/gillmor-gang-win-win/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 23:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122078</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just finished a Twitter Spaces session. It is an engaging platform, somewhat clunky in feature set but easily a tie overall with Clubhouse. I don&#8217;t see this as a horse race, however, more as cooperating teams fleshing out a platform where both will be major players. Like notifications in iOS and Android, the feature set [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/-OuIKIyUXU0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Just finished a Twitter Spaces session. It is an engaging platform, somewhat clunky in feature set but easily a tie overall with Clubhouse. I don&#8217;t see this as a horse race, however, more as cooperating teams fleshing out a platform where both will be major players. Like notifications in iOS and Android, the feature set is a push and pull motion where Android delivers deep functionality and Apple alternately pulls ahead and consolidates gains. Though the details can vary, the combined energy of effectively 100 percent of the consumer base mandates best practices and opportunities for innovation.</p>
<p>Something similar is going on in Washington as the Democrats test out their majority of none on the pandemic stimulus bill. The headline in the Times says bipartisanship is dead, but the subheading is the real story. The battle for control of the Senate is closing in on the arcane gerrymandering of the filibuster, or what passes for it after Republican whittling of the original talk &#8217;til you drop croaking of Jimmy Stewart as in Mr. Smith Goes to Washington.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The telltale giveaway is Senator Lindsay Graham, who complains bitterly that the Democrats are steamrolling the COVID Rescue Bill without Republican votes &#8220;because they can.&#8221; The actual bipartisanship is between the progressives and moderates in the Democratic Party, as the Senator from West Virginia moderates one aspect of the bill to gain the prize of something the President can sign. Not only does it establish Biden&#8217;s power to govern but it also provides a roadmap for justifying the necessity of altering the filibuster equation.</p>
<p>Notice how Biden changed the subject from bipartisan negotiations to the power play it turned into. He used the polls to squeeze the Republican moderates where they fear most, the primary battles for control of the House in the midterms. The wave of vaccines are making it almost impossible to put up a political firewall; the anti-mask mandates seem like clueless floundering as people begin to have hope of an exit from the gridlock of partisan obstructionism. It will be hard to run on a platform of denial and death as we reach the end of May.</p>
<p>Governing by success undercuts the argument that government doesn&#8217;t work. Breaking the back of the filibuster requires the framing of the issue as finding a way to let government keep working in a bipartisan way. That brings us back to changing the definition of bipartisan as evidenced in the technology arena. In the Apple/Android example, two viable entities bring different strengths to insuring the ability to survive long enough to govern. Google&#8217;s lock on the network effect in advertising and &#8220;free&#8221; services may be challenged by Apple&#8217;s focus on privacy and a hardware revenue base, but the net effect is to cancel each other&#8217;s vulnerabilities due to the market force of their positions. The bipartisan finesse is that each platform has the other as a dominant customer.</p>
<p>In the same vein, Twitter v. Clubhouse is really not the point. Certainly we can cherrypick the battle as startup v. incumbent: Clubhouse filled with unicorn celebrities and rockstar investors and a builtin tension with the media, Twitter protectively fast following with its natural social graph advantages and struggling with scalability and the fear they&#8217;ve sown of abandoning projects before they can thrive. The question begged: what is the nature of the bipartisan compromise that will ensure both end up winners?</p>
<p>The answer is how to make each player the best customer of the other. Twitter&#8217;s problem is focus, and harnessing the power of users to hack the system to both theirs and the company&#8217;s advantage. The @mention spawned the retweet, providing the analytics that drive Twitter&#8217;s indelible social graph. Instagram may be Facebook&#8217;s best attempt so far at challenging the fundamental strategic value that the former president used to dominate, but Clubhouse promises to go one big step better with its hybrid of mainstream media and a Warholesque factory engine that creates new stars and the media they generate. This in turn migrates through the entertainment disruption led by the streaming realignment. What exactly is this NFT thing really about?</p>
<p>So Clubhouse has to open up its ability to multitask with Twitter and other curated social graphs. Facebook as a source for Clubhouse notifications and suggested conversations is different than Twitter’s But patching into the sharing icon on iOS will offer substantial access to blunt Twitter&#8217;s native integration in Spaces. On the flip side, Twitter&#8217;s Revue newsletter tools present an opportunity to mine the burgeoning newsletter surge, using its drag and drop tools to bring not just default social network citations but the implicit social graph of curated editorial rockstars. Not only is the influencer audience rich in signal for advertisers, but these same brands will prove most attractive to Clubhouse listeners looking for value. Win win.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><em>from the <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang"> Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, March 5, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang">Subscribe to the new Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></strong> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/gillmor-gang-win-win/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122078</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The iMac Pro is being discontinued</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/the-imac-pro-is-being-discontinued/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/the-imac-pro-is-being-discontinued/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 22:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple silicon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imac pro]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2122075</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chalk this up to inevitability. The iMac Pro is soon to be no more. First noted by 9to5Mac, TechCrunch has since confirmed with Apple that the company will stop selling the all-in-one once the current stock is depleted. One configuration of the desktop is still available through Apple’s site, listed as “While Supplies Last” and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chalk this up to inevitability. The iMac Pro is soon to be no more. First noted <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/03/06/apple-discontinues-imac-pro-apple-store-says-buy-while-supplies-last/">by 9to5Mac</a>, TechCrunch has since confirmed with Apple that the company will stop selling the all-in-one once the current stock is depleted.</p>
<p>One configuration of the desktop is still available through Apple’s site, listed as “While Supplies Last” and priced at $5,000. Some other versions can also still be found from third-party retailers, as well, if you&#8217;re so inclined.</p>
<p>The space gray version of the popular system was initially introduced in 2017, ahead of the company’s long-awaited revamp<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/05/apples-2019-imac-pro-will-be-shaped-by-workflows/"> of the Mac Pro</a>. Matthew called it a “love letter to developers” at the time, though that particular letter seems to have run its course.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7QFjbIreml"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/06/apple-27-inch-imac-review/">Apple 27-inch iMac review</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple 27-inch iMac review&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/06/apple-27-inch-imac-review/embed/#?secret=7QFjbIreml" data-secret="7QFjbIreml" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Since then, Apple has revamped the standard iMac, focusing the 27-inch model at those same users. The company notes that the model is currently the most popular iMac among professional users. The system has essentially made the Pro mostly redundant, prefiguring its sunsetting. Of course, there’s also the new Mac Pro at the high end of Apple&#8217;s offerings.</p>
<p>And let us not forget that the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/macbook-air-m1-review-the-right-apple-silicon-mac-for-most/">Apple silicon-powered</a> iMacs should be on the way, as well. Thus far the company has revamped the MacBook, MacBook Air and Mac Mini with its proprietary chips. New versions of the 21.5-inch and 27-inch desktop are rumored for arrival later this year, sporting a long-awaited redesign to boot.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GlesVlYH9z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/14/apples-imac-pro-is-a-love-letter-to-developers/">Apple’s iMac Pro is a love letter to developers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple’s iMac Pro is a love letter to developers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/14/apples-imac-pro-is-a-love-letter-to-developers/embed/#?secret=GlesVlYH9z" data-secret="GlesVlYH9z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/07/the-imac-pro-is-being-discontinued/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2122075</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investors still love software more than life</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/06/investors-still-love-software-more-than-life/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/06/investors-still-love-software-more-than-life/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bigcommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Next Insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121927</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s broadly based on the daily column that appears on Extra Crunch, but free, and made for your weekend reading. Want it in your inbox every Saturday morning? Sign up here. Ready? Let’s talk money, startups and spicy IPO rumors. Despite some recent market volatility, the valuations [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s broadly based on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/">the daily column that appears on Extra Crunch</a>, but free, and made for your weekend reading. Want it in your inbox every Saturday morning? Sign up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">here</a>.</em></p>
<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Ready? Let’s talk money, startups and spicy IPO rumors.</em></p>
<p>Despite some <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/the-technology-selloff-is-getting-to-be-somewhat-material/">recent market volatility</a>, the valuations that software companies have generally been able to command in recent quarters have been impressive. On Friday, we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/understanding-how-investors-value-growth-in-2021/">took a look</a> into why that was the case, and where the valuations could be a bit more bubbly than others. Per <a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/497410287/Battery-Ventures-Software-2021-Report">a report</a> written by few Battery Ventures investors, it stands to reason that the middle of the SaaS market could be where valuation inflation is at its peak.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Something to keep in mind if your startup’s growth rate is ticking lower. But today, instead of being an enormous bummer and making you worry, I have come with some historically notable data to show you how good modern software startups and their larger brethren have it today.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2121929 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-1.15.20-PM.png" alt="" width="889" height="204" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-1.15.20-PM.png 889w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-1.15.20-PM.png?resize=150,34 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-1.15.20-PM.png?resize=300,69 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-1.15.20-PM.png?resize=768,176 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-1.15.20-PM.png?resize=680,156 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-1.15.20-PM.png?resize=50,11 50w" sizes="(max-width: 889px) 100vw, 889px" /></p>
<p>In case you are not 100% infatuated with tables, let me save you some time. In the upper right we can see that SaaS companies today that are growing at less than 10% yearly are trading for an average of 6.9x their next 12 months’ revenue.</p>
<p>Back in 2011, SaaS companies that were growing at 40% or more were trading at 6.0x their next 12 month’s revenue. Climate change, but for software valuations.</p>
<p>One more note from my chat with Battery. Its investor Brandon Gleklen riffed with The Exchange on the definition of ARR and its nuances in the modern market. As more SaaS companies swap traditional software-as-a-service pricing for its consumption-based equivalent, he declined to quibble on definitions of ARR, instead arguing that all that matters in software revenues is whether they are being retained and growing over the long term. This brings us to our next topic.</p>
<h2>Consumption v. SaaS pricing</h2>
<p>I’ve taken a number of earnings calls in the last few weeks with public software companies. One theme that’s come up time and again has been consumption pricing versus more traditional SaaS pricing. There is some data showing that consumption-priced software companies are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/why-do-saas-companies-with-usage-based-pricing-grow-faster/">trading at higher multiples</a> than traditionally priced software companies, thanks to better-than-average retention numbers.</p>
<p>But there is more to the story than just that. Chatting with Fastly CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/joshuabixby?lang=en">Joshua Bixby</a> after his company&#8217;s <a href="https://investors.fastly.com/files/doc_financials/2020/q4/4Q20-Shareholder-Letter.pdf">earnings report</a>, we picked up an interesting and important market distinction between where consumption may be more attractive and where it may not be. Per Bixby, Fastly is seeing larger customers prefer consumption-based pricing because they can afford variability and prefer to have their bills tied more closely to revenue. Smaller customers, however, Bixby said, prefer SaaS billing because it has rock-solid predictability.</p>
<p>I brought the argument to <a href="https://twitter.com/poyark?lang=en">Open View Partners Kyle Poyar</a>, a venture denizen who has been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/subscription-based-pricing-is-dead-smart-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-models/">writing on this topic for TechCrunch</a> in recent weeks. He noted that in some cases the opposite can be true, that variably priced offerings can appeal to smaller companies because their developers can often test the product without making a large commitment.</p>
<p>So, perhaps we’re seeing the software market favoring SaaS pricing among smaller customers when they are certain of their need, and choosing consumption pricing when they want to experiment first. And larger companies, when their spend is tied to equivalent revenue changes, bias toward consumption pricing as well.</p>
<p>Evolution in SaaS pricing will be slow, and never complete. But folks really are thinking about it. Appian CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mattcalkins/">Matt Calkins</a> has a general pricing thesis that price should “hover” under value delivered. Asked about the consumption-versus-SaaS topic, he was a bit coy, but did note that he was not “entirely happy” with how pricing is executed today. He wants pricing that is a “better proxy for customer value,” though he declined to share much more.</p>
<p>If you aren’t thinking about this conversation and you run a startup, what&#8217;s up with that? More to come on this topic, including notes from an interview with the CEO of BigCommerce, who is betting on SaaS over the more consumption-driven Shopify.</p>
<h2>Next Insurance, and its changing market</h2>
<p>Next Insurance <a href="https://www.nextinsurance.com/blog/next-insurance-acquisition-ap-intego/">bought</a> another company this week. This time it was AP Intego, which will bring integration into various payroll providers for the digital-first SMB insurance provider. Next Insurance should be familiar because TechCrunch has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/as-next-insurance-makes-its-first-acquisition-insurtech-looks-energetic/">written about its growth a few times</a>. The company doubled its premium run rate to $200 million in 2020, for example.</p>
<p>The AP Intego deal brings $185.1 million of active premium to Next Insurance, which means that the neo-insurance provider has grown sharply thus far in 2021, even without counting its organic expansion. But while the Next Insurance deal and the <a href="https://hippo-static.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/investors/Hippo+Reinvent+Presentation+March+2021+(vF+Announced).pdf">impending Hippo SPAC</a> are neat notes from a hot private sector, insurtech has shed some of its public-market heat.</p>
<p>Stocks of public neo-insurance companies like Root, Lemonade and MetroMile have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/the-technology-selloff-is-getting-to-be-somewhat-material/">lost quite a lot of value in recent weeks</a>. So, the exit landscape for companies like Next and Hippo &#8212; yet-private insurtech startups with lots of capital backing their rapid premium growth &#8212; is changing for the worse.</p>
<p>Hippo decided it will debut via a SPAC. But I doubt that Next Insurance will pursue a rapid ramp to the public markets until things smooth out. Not that it needs to go public quickly; it raised a quarter billion back in September of last year.</p>
<h2>Various and Sundry</h2>
<p>What else? Sisense, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/02/kicking-off-2020-with-4-new-members-of-the-100m-arr-club/">$100 million ARR club</a> member, <a href="https://itbrief.com.au/story/sisense-appoints-new-cfo-adam-towns">hired a new CFO</a>. So we expect them to go public inside the next four or five quarters.</p>
<p>And the following chart, which is <a href="https://twitter.com/deenashakir/status/1367243151769968642">via Deena Shakir of Lux Capital</a>, via <a href="http://nasdaq.com">Nasdaq</a>, via <a href="https://spacalpha.com/">SPAC Alpha</a>:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2121931 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-2.00.13-PM.png" alt="" width="551" height="387" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-2.00.13-PM.png 551w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-2.00.13-PM.png?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-2.00.13-PM.png?resize=300,211 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-03-05-at-2.00.13-PM.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 551px) 100vw, 551px" /></p>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/06/investors-still-love-software-more-than-life/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121927</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Product Manager asterisk</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/06/the-product-manager-asterisk/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/06/the-product-manager-asterisk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 19:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AgTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups Weekly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2121859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Product manager might be one of the most grey roles within a startup. However, as a company progresses and the team grows, there comes a time when a founder needs to carve out dedicated roles. Of these positions, product management might be one of the most elusive — and key — roles to fill. Ken [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Product manager might be one of the most grey roles within a startup. However, as a company progresses and the team grows, there comes a time when a founder needs to carve out dedicated roles. Of these positions, product management might be one of the most elusive — and key — roles to fill.</p>
<p>Ken Norton, who recently left his job as director of product at Figma to consult rising PMs, thinks it’s easier to start with defining what they aren’t: the CEO of the product.</p>
<p>“Product managers need to realize that there is a lot of janitorial work that gets done in product management,” he said. “It’s not fun or glamorous, and it’s certainly not being the CEO of the product. It’s just stuff that needs to get done.” I wrote up a guide <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/product-manager-hiring-for-startups/?tpcc=ECTW2020">on how and when to hire your first product manager</a> that expands on some of these insights, including how focus might be the biggest trait to interview for:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/product-manager-hiring-for-startups/?tpcc=ECTW2020">How and when to hire your first product manager </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/in-freemium-marketing-product-analytics-are-the-difference-between-conversion-and-confusion/">In freemium marketing, product analytics are the difference between conversion and confusion </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/create-a-handbook-and-integrate-ai-to-onboard-remote-employees/">Create a handbook and integrate AI to onboard remote employees</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Hiring continues to be one of the hardest parts of building a startup, and those early employees can define the trajectory, culture and eventual success of it. Even during TC Sessions: Justice this past week, Precursor’s Sydney Thomas explained how startups need to make “pretty final decisions, pretty early on in what type of company you want to build.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="L5Bg8dTFfm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/product-manager-hiring-for-startups/">How and when to hire your first product manager</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How and when to hire your first product manager&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/product-manager-hiring-for-startups/embed/#?secret=L5Bg8dTFfm" data-secret="L5Bg8dTFfm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It’s a slight asterisk to the common narrative of how startups pivot every other day. It’s not that simple, and I’ll probably remind you of that every other week, dear Startups Weekly readers.</p>
<p>The rest of today’s newsletter will include notes on a hot up-and-coming edtech IPO, an exit that includes Jay-Z, and the latest in agricultural tech robots. Also, remember you can always find me on Twitter @nmasc_ or e-mail me at <a href="mailto:natasha.m@techcrunch.com">natasha.m@techcrunch.com</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>The public markets get educated</strong></h2>
<p>It’s been yet another busy week for the public markets. I published a scoop earlier this week that <a href=" https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/coursera-is-planning-to-file-to-go-public-tomorrow/ ">Coursera is filing to go public</a> soon, which would be one of the first debuts that will let us see how an education company’s finances changed, and accelerated, amid the pandemic’s impact on remote learning.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>Like clockwork, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/a-first-look-at-courseras-s-1-filing/">Coursera&#8217;s S-1</a> dropped late Friday, giving us the first glance of the numbers behind the business. The startup tried to pain a picture of a path of profitability, with rising revenues as well as rising net losses. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/a-first-look-at-courseras-s-1-filing/">We get into the meat of it here. </a></p>
<ul>
<li><a href=" https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/unraveling-thredups-ipo-filing-slow-growth-but-a-shifting-business-model/ ">Unraveling ThredUp’s IPO filing: Slow growth but a shifting business model </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/first-impressions-of-applovins-ipo-filing/ ">First impressions of AppLovin’s IPO filing </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/oscar-health-prices-ipo-at-39-and-secures-a-9-5b-valuation/">Oscar Health prices IPO at $39 and secures a $9.5 billion valuation</a></li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2087345" style="width: 872px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2087345" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2087345" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-1210550354.jpg" alt="" width="862" height="587" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-1210550354.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-1210550354.jpg?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-1210550354.jpg?resize=300,204 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-1210550354.jpg?resize=768,523 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-1210550354.jpg?resize=680,463 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-1210550354.jpg?resize=1536,1046 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-1210550354.jpg?resize=2048,1394 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-1210550354.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 862px) 100vw, 862px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2087345" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Fotograzia / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<h2><strong>What&#8217;s better than one billionaire? Two </strong></h2>
<p>One of the biggest headlines of this past week was<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/square-buys-majority-of-tidal-adds-jay-z-to-its-board-in-bid-to-shake-up-the-artist-economy/"> Square buying a majority stake of Tidal. </a>A fintech and music collaboration might not seem that obvious, but the music economy remains one of the most under-tapped (and under-innovated) opportunities that remains out there.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="238dVuUZkD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/square-buys-majority-of-tidal-adds-jay-z-to-its-board-in-bid-to-shake-up-the-artist-economy/">Square buys majority of Tidal, adds Jay-Z to its board in bid to shake up the artist economy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Square buys majority of Tidal, adds Jay-Z to its board in bid to shake up the artist economy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/square-buys-majority-of-tidal-adds-jay-z-to-its-board-in-bid-to-shake-up-the-artist-economy/embed/#?secret=238dVuUZkD" data-secret="238dVuUZkD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>Square CEO Jack Dorsey used his other company, Twitter, to share more information about the $297 million deal. As part of this transaction, Tidal owner Jay-Z got a board seat with Square, triggering conversations<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/square-buys-majority-of-tidal-adds-jay-z-to-its-board-in-bid-to-shake-up-the-artist-economy/"> about the future of musical NFTs.</a> The deal also officially confirmed that Jay-Z isn&#8217;t just a businessman, he&#8217;s a business, man.</p>
<ul>
<li>3Lau spoke on the Good Time Show, hosted by Sriram Krishnan and Aarthi Ramamurthy, <a href="https://twitter.com/sriramk/status/1367662401726730242">about his NFT audio journey. </a></li>
<li>Cappuccino<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/cappuccino-lets-you-share-short-intimate-audio-stories-with-your-friends/"> lets you share short, intimate audio stories with your friends</a>.</li>
<li>Plus, stay tuned for an NFT-focused Equity show next week. If there’s anyone you think we need to interview for the episode, <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">DM me names. </a></li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_1460720" style="width: 848px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1460720" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-1460720" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gettyimages-155579103.jpg" alt="" width="838" height="590" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gettyimages-155579103.jpg 3939w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gettyimages-155579103.jpg?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gettyimages-155579103.jpg?resize=300,211 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gettyimages-155579103.jpg?resize=768,540 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gettyimages-155579103.jpg?resize=680,479 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gettyimages-155579103.jpg?resize=1536,1081 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gettyimages-155579103.jpg?resize=2048,1441 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gettyimages-155579103.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 838px) 100vw, 838px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1460720" class="wp-caption-text">Singer Jay-Z performs before US President Barack Obama speaks at a campaign rally in Columbus, Ohio, on November 5, 2012. After a grueling 18-month battle, the final US campaign day arrived Monday for Obama and Republican rival Mitt Romney, two men on a collision course for the world&#8217;s top job. The candidates have attended hundreds of rallies, fundraisers and town halls, spent literally billions on attack ads, ground games, and get out the vote efforts, and squared off in three intense debates. AFP PHOTO/Jewel Samad (Photo credit should read JEWEL SAMAD/AFP/Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<h2><strong>Decentralized insect farming, anyone? </strong></h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/100-million-for-mealworms/">In this week’s Equity Wednesday episode</a>, we brought on TC’s climate tech editor, Jonathan Shieber, to talk about the opportunities within agtech right now. We covered a lot within<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/100-million-for-mealworms/"> the 20-minute episode</a>: from $100 million for mealworms, farm-to-grill robots and decentralized insect farming.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nMdcB1ktyc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/100-million-for-mealworms/">$100 million for mealworms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;$100 million for mealworms&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/100-million-for-mealworms/embed/#?secret=nMdcB1ktyc" data-secret="nMdcB1ktyc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>Farms have always had a compelling reason to turn to robotics to make tedious work much, much easier. We got into two different businesses and their approaches on how to serve farm robots, from SaaS leases to selling the robots one by one.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/corporate-sustainability-initiatives-may-open-doors-for-carbon-offset-startups/">Corporate sustainability initiatives may open doors for carbon offset startups </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/farmwise-plans-to-add-autonomous-crop-dusting-to-its-suite-of-robotic-services/">Autonomous dust cropping might be a new suite of services amid agtech robotics</a></li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2038698" style="width: 806px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2038698" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2038698" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-1026461726.jpg" alt="" width="796" height="531" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-1026461726.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-1026461726.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-1026461726.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-1026461726.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-1026461726.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-1026461726.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-1026461726.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-1026461726.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 796px) 100vw, 796px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2038698" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Fernando Trabanco Fotografía / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<h2><strong>Around TechCrunch</strong></h2>
<p>Thanks to all of you who tuned into TC Sessions: Justice this past week, it was so fun to hang &#8212; and make sure to give virtual kudos to my colleague, and showrunner, <a href="https://twitter.com/meganrosedickey">Megan Rose Dickey.</a></p>
<p>Next up is TechCrunch Early Stage, our yearly event that is all about tactical advice to help new and first-time founders navigate the Wild West world that is venture capital and startups. We just <a href=" https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/announcing-the-early-stage-pitch-off-judges/ ">announced the judges</a> of the pitch-off competition, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/early-stage-investor-mayfield-shows-how-to-scaleup-your-biotech-startup-at-tc-early-stage-in-april/ ">have already landed top-tier venture capitalists </a>to share what you won’t find on Twitter: behind the scenes startup advice that is beyond 180 characters.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ad1N1dbWrG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/announcing-the-early-stage-pitch-off-judges/">Announcing the Early Stage Pitch-Off judges</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Announcing the Early Stage Pitch-Off judges&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/announcing-the-early-stage-pitch-off-judges/embed/#?secret=Ad1N1dbWrG" data-secret="Ad1N1dbWrG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>It’s the bootcamp you always wished you could attend, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/">so get your tickets here. </a></strong></p>
<h2><strong>Across the week</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Seen on Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href=" https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/understanding-how-investors-value-growth-in-2021/">Understanding how investors value growth in 2021 </a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/dear-sophie-can-you-demystify-the-h-1b-process-and-e-3-premium-processing/ ">Dear Sophie: Can you demystify the H-1B process and E-3 premium processing </a></p>
<p><a href=" https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/">11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/making-sense-of-the-6-5b-okta-auth0-deal/">Making sense of the $6.5B Okta-Auth0 deal</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oBMO3wuOPE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/">11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/embed/#?secret=oBMO3wuOPE" data-secret="oBMO3wuOPE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Seen on TechCrunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/softbank-makes-mountains-of-cash-off-of-human-laziness/ ">SoftBank makes mountains of cash off of human laziness </a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/mary-meeker-bond-2-billion/ ">Mary Meeker’s Bond has closed its second fund with $2 billion</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/the-technology-selloff-is-getting-to-be-somewhat-material/">The technology selloff is getting to be somewhat material</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/two-sessions-2021-china-tech/">What China’s Big Tech CEOs propose at the annual parliament meeting</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TzMuOoOhQX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/mary-meeker-bond-2-billion/">Mary Meeker&#8217;s Bond has closed its second fund with $2 billion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mary Meeker&#8217;s Bond has closed its second fund with $2 billion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/mary-meeker-bond-2-billion/embed/#?secret=TzMuOoOhQX" data-secret="TzMuOoOhQX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>And finally&#8230;</h2>
<p>I wanted to end by using this platform to address the rise of anti-Asian violence across our country. Conversations around how to be a more inclusive and anti-racist society need to be more loud, and more collaborative in order for change to actually happen. Intention around inclusion will impact the world we live in, the startups we create and the success of our collective. <a href="https://anti-asianviolenceresources.carrd.co/">Here are some resources to donate, petition and learn. </a></p>
<p>Thanks,</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">N</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/06/the-product-manager-asterisk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2121859</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
