<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 18:57:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: Which immigration options are the fastest?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/dear-sophie-which-immigration-options-are-the-fastest/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/dear-sophie-which-immigration-options-are-the-fastest/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 18:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m getting this question quite frequently now as more and more startups with recent funding rounds are looking to quickly expand.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/dear-sophie-tips-for-filing-for-a-green-card-for-my-soon-to-be-spouse/">Dear Sophie: Tips for filing for a green card for my soon-to-be spouse</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/dear-sophie-how-can-i-improve-our-startups-international-recruiting/">Dear Sophie: How can I improve our startup&#8217;s international recruiting?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie: </strong></p>
<p><strong>Help! Our startup needs to hire 50 engineers in artificial intelligence and related fields ASAP. Which visa and green card options are the quickest to get for top immigrant engineers? </strong></p>
<p><strong> And will Biden’s new immigration bill help us?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Mesmerized in Menlo Park</strong></p>
<p>Dear Mesmerized,</p>
<p>I’m getting this question quite frequently now as more and more startups with recent funding rounds are looking to quickly expand. In the latest episode of my <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/">podcast</a>, I discuss some of the quickest visa categories for startups to consider when they need to add talent quickly.</p>
<p>As always, I suggest consulting with an experienced immigration lawyer who can help you quickly strategize and implement an efficient and cost-effective hiring and immigration plan. An immigration lawyer will also be up to date on any immigration policy changes and plans in the event that the Biden administration’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UeWaeO5u3Vo&amp;feature=youtu.be">U.S. Citizenship Act of 2021</a> passes. It was introduced in the House and Senate this month.</p>
<p>That proposed legislation would enable more international talent to come to the U.S. for jobs and clear employment-based visa backlogs, among other things. Given the legislation’s substantial benefits offered to employers, I encourage your startup — and other companies — to let congressional representatives know you support it.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Given that most U.S. embassies and consulates remain at limited capacity for routine visa and green card processing due to the pandemic, it is generally quicker to hire American and international workers who are already in the U.S. Although U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) is experiencing substantial delays in processing cases due to the coronavirus, as well as an increase in applications, Premium Processing is currently available for most employment-based petitions. We are still able to support many folks with U.S. visa appointment scheduling at consulates abroad using various national interest strategies.</p>
<p>With all of that in mind, here are the visa categories that offer the quickest way to hire international talent.</p>
<h2>H-1B transfers</h2>
<p>Hiring individuals by transferring their H-1B to your startup can be completed in a couple of months with premium processing. Premium processing is an optional service that for a fee guarantees USCIS will process the petition within 15 calendar days.</p>
<p>What’s more, <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/030-h-1b-nitty-gritty-1-transfer-extensions-amendments-in-tech/">H-1B transferees</a> can start working for your startup even before USCIS has issued a receipt notice or made a decision in the case. You just need to make sure that USCIS received the petition, which is why I always recommend sending all packages to USCIS with tracking.</p>
<p>Premium processing can help to get a digital receipt as the paper receipts are often backlogged. I stopped suggesting this route during the Trump administration, but am feeling more comfortable providing it as an option under the Biden administration. The H-1B is the only type of visa that allows somebody to start working upon the filing of a transfer application.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/dear-sophie-which-immigration-options-are-the-fastest/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kapor Capital is raising a $125 million fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/kapor-capital-is-raising-a-125-million-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/kapor-capital-is-raising-a-125-million-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 18:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kapor Capital, the venture firm focused on funding social impact ventures and founders of color, is raising a $125 million fund, called Fund III, a source familiar with the situation told TechCrunch. What&#8217;s notable about this fund is that it will be the first time Kapor Capital is accepting outside money from investors for a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Kapor Capital, the venture firm focused on funding social impact ventures and founders of color, is raising a $125 million fund, called Fund III, a source familiar with the situation told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s notable about this fund is that it will be the first time Kapor Capital is accepting outside money from investors for a fund. Historically, the capital have come directly from Kapor Capital founders Mitch Kapor and Freada Kapor Klein.</p>
<p>The fund will be led by Kapor Capital partners Brian Dixon and Ulili Onovakpuri. The two will function as co-managing partners.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/06/kapor-capital-promotes-ulili-onovakpuri-to-partner/">Onovakpuri was promoted</a> from principal to partner back in 2018. At the time, she told me was interested in technology that makes access to healthcare more accessible, either through reimbursements to low-income people or through subsidized payments. On the people operations side, Onovakpuri said she was looking at investing in startups that help create inclusive cultures.</p>
<p>“What we have found is that more needs to be done in order to keep [people from diverse backgrounds] in and happy, so that’s what I’ve invested in,” Onovakpuri said.</p>
<p>Her first couple of investments were in mSurvey <a href="http://msurvey.co.ke/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mSurvey</a>, which started as a text message platform to identify disparities in the world, and <a href="https://www.tequitable.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tEQuitable</a>, which aims to help companies be more inclusive.</p>
<p>Her co-manager, Dixon, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/11/10/kapor-capital-invests-100000-in-three-people-operations-startups/">became one of the first Black investors to be promoted to partner at a venture capital in 2015</a>. At the time, Dixon told me he was focused on increasing the number of founders who identify as women and/or an underrepresented person of color in Kapor Capital&#8217;s portfolio to above 50%.</p>
<p>“As partner, that’s what I’m trying to continue to do,” Dixon said at the time. “We’re still looking for the best companies. We’re still looking for companies that are going to be impact companies, but also have VC-like returns, so I think that’s what unique about Kapor Capital, is that not many early-stage firms have that focus, and we think we do it pretty well.”</p>
<p>Today, 59% of the companies in Kapor Capital&#8217;s portfolio have a founder who identifies as a woman and/or an underrepresented person of color. Kapor Capital has been instrumental in advancing diversity and inclusion in the tech industry. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/01/21/kapor-capital-founders-commitment/">Back in 2016</a>, for example, Kapor Capital began requiring new portfolio companies to invest in diversity and inclusion as part of a Founders&#8217; Commitment.</p>
<p>Kapor Capital has invested in companies like AngelList, Pigeonly, Bitwise Industries, Blavity, Bloc Power, Hustle and others.</p>
<p>Kapor Capital declined to comment for this story.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DsYoPz9egu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/30/freada-kapor-klein-warns-of-vulture-capitalists-during-the-pandemic/">Freada Kapor Klein warns of &#8216;vulture capitalists&#8217; during pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Freada Kapor Klein warns of &#8216;vulture capitalists&#8217; during pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/30/freada-kapor-klein-warns-of-vulture-capitalists-during-the-pandemic/embed/#?secret=DsYoPz9egu" data-secret="DsYoPz9egu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/kapor-capital-is-raising-a-125-million-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117388</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 18:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Market Map]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lithium ion batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panasonic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[QuantumScape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the market for EVs shifts to include commercial vehicles, aerospace, off-roaders and microtransit, the commercial future for SSBs is finally looking a little more solid.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Lithium-ion batteries power almost every new phone, laptop and electric vehicle. But unlike processors or solar panels, which have improved exponentially, lithium-ion batteries have inched along with only incremental gains.</p>
<p>For the last decade, developers of solid state battery systems have promised products that are vastly safer, lighter and more powerful. Those promises largely evaporated into the ether &#8212; leaving behind a vapor stream of disappointing products, failed startups and retreating release dates.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			For the last decade, developers of solid state battery systems have promised products that are vastly safer, lighter and more powerful.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>A new wave of companies and technologies are finally maturing and attracting the funding necessary to feed batteries&#8217; biggest market: transportation. Electric vehicles account for about 60% of all lithium-ion batteries made today, and IDTechEx predicts that <a href="https://www.idtechex.com/de/research-article/solid-state-batteries-will-create-a-6-billion-market-in-2030/21315">solid state batteries</a> will represent a $6 billion industry by 2030.</p>
<p>Electric vehicles have never been cooler, faster or cleaner, yet they still account for only around one in 25 cars sold around the world (and fewer still in the United States). A <a href="https://www.castrol.com/en_gb/united-kingdom/home/technology-and-innovation/electric-vehicle-adoption.html">global survey of 10,000 drivers</a> in 2020 by Castrol delivered the same perennial complaints that EVs are too expensive, too slow to charge and have too short a range.</p>
<p>Castrol identified three tipping points that EVs would need to drive a decisive shift away from their internal combustion rivals: a range of at least 300 miles, charging in just half an hour and costing no more than $36,000.</p>
<p>Theoretically, solid state batteries (SSB) could deliver all three.</p>
<p>There are many different kinds of SSB but they all lack a liquid electrolyte for moving electrons (electricity) between the battery&#8217;s positive (cathode) and negative (anode) electrodes. The liquid electrolytes in lithium-ion batteries limit the materials the electrodes can be made from, and the shape and size of the battery. Because liquid electrolytes are usually flammable, lithium-ion batteries are also prone to runaway heating and even explosion. SSBs are much less flammable and can use metal electrodes or complex internal designs to store more energy and move it faster &#8212; giving higher power and faster charging.</p>
<h2>The players</h2>
<p>&#8220;If you run the calculations, you can get really amazing numbers and they&#8217;re very exciting,&#8221; Amy Prieto, founder and CTO of solid state Colorado-based startup <a href="https://www.prietobattery.com/">Prieto Battery</a> said in a recent interview. &#8220;It&#8217;s just that making it happen in practice is very difficult.&#8221;</p>
<p>Prieto, who founded her company in 2009 after a career as a chemistry professor, has seen SSB startups come and go. In 2015 alone, Dyson acquired Ann Arbor startup <a href="https://careers.dyson.com/en-gb/where-we-are/americas/us/ann-arbor/">Sakti3</a> and Bosch bought Berkeley Lab spin-off SEEO in separate automotive development projects. Both efforts failed, and Dyson has since abandoned some of Sakti3&#8217;s patents.</p>
<p>Prieto Battery, whose strategic investors include Intel, Stout Street Capital and Stanley Ventures, venture arm of toolmaker Stanley Black &amp; Decker, pioneered an SSB with a 3D internal architecture that should enable high power and good energy density. Prieto is now seeking funding to scale up production for automotive battery packs. The first customer for these is likely to be electric pickup maker <a href="https://herculesev.com/">Hercules</a>, whose debut vehicle, called Alpha, is due in 2022. (Fisker also says that it is developing a 3D SSB for its debut Ocean SUV, which is expected to arrive next year.)</p>
<p>Another Colorado SSB company is <a href="https://solidpowerbattery.com/#ourSolution">Solid Power</a>, which has had investments from auto OEMs including BMV, Hyundai, Samsung and Ford, following a $20 million Series A in 2018. Solid Power has no ambitions to make battery packs or even cells, according to CEO Doug Campbell, and is doing its best to use only standard lithium-ion tooling and processes.</p>
<p>Once the company has completed cell development in 2023 or 2024, it would hand over full-scale production to its commercialization partners.</p>
<p>&#8220;It simply lowers the barrier to entry if existing producers can adopt it with minimal pain,&#8221; Campbell said.</p>
<p>QuantumScape is perhaps the highest profile SSB maker on the scene today. Spun out from Stanford University a decade ago, the secretive <a href="https://www.quantumscape.com/">QuantumScape</a> attracted funding from Bill Gates and $300 million from Volkswagen. In November, QuantumScape went public via a special purpose acquisition company at a $3.3 billion valuation. It then soared in value over 10 times after CEO Jagdeep Singh claimed to have solved the short lifetime and slow charging problems that have plagued SSBs.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116636</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canva acquires background removal specialists Kaleido</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/canva-acquires-background-removal-specialists-kaleido/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/canva-acquires-background-removal-specialists-kaleido/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 18:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaleido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unscreen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117335</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kaleido, makers of a drag-and-drop background removal service for images and video, have been acquired by up and coming digital design platform Canva. While the price and terms are not disclosed, it is speculated that this young company may have fetched nearly nine figures. It&#8217;s the right product at the right time, seemingly. In 2019, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Kaleido, makers of a drag-and-drop background removal service for images and video, <a href="https://www.kaleido.ai/press.html">have been acquired</a> by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/canva-raises-60-million-on-a-6-billion-valuation/">up and coming digital design platform Canva</a>. While the price and terms are not disclosed, it is speculated that this young company may have fetched nearly nine figures.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the right product at the right time, seemingly. In 2019, the Vienna-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/08/remove-bg-photoshop-free-image-background-editor/">Kaleido made remove.bg</a>, a quick, simple, free, and good-enough background removal tool for images. It became a hit among the many people who need to quickly do that kind of work but don&#8217;t want to fiddle around in Photoshop.</p>
<p>Then late last year they <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/kaleidos-unscreen-is-dead-simple-drag-and-drop-background-removal-for-video/">took the wraps off Unscreen</a>, which did the same thing for video — a similar task conceptually, but far more demanding to actually engineer and deploy. The simplicity and effectiveness of the tool practically begged to be acquired and integrated into a larger framework by the likes of Adobe, but Canva seems to have beaten the others to the punch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2117379" style="width: 691px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-demo.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2117379" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2117379" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-demo.gif" alt="Animated image showing a stack of books on a table in a room, but the table and room get deleted." width="681" height="385" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2117379" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Unscreen</p></div></p>
<p>The acquisition was announced at the same time as another by Canva: product mockup generator Smartmockups, suggesting a major product expansion by the growing design company.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span id="m_-2217041789397353648m_8076942100441458243m_-1653442914133082232m_-1937832456200069344m_3742877000802439203m_-8846956851484012103m_-9181700837316813888m_-7163273507564468607m_6571900530269087012m_-5831787669074522829m_-5258060738344163244m_1182064036883263323m_-7282904136934202709m_-5573893289930988793m_-4879724363740572952m_8723194699203980028m_-2539773578243971222gmail-docs-internal-guid-4e4631a0-7fff-3600-b628-5891a3cd5e0a">We completely bootstrapped Kaleido with no investors involved from day one,&#8221; said co-founder and CEO of Kaleido, Benjamin Groessing, in a press release. &#8220;It has just been two founders and an incredible team. We’ve been profitable from the start — so this acquisition wasn’t essential for our existence. It just made sense on so many levels.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The company declined to provide any further details on the acquisition beyond that the brand and name are expected to survive — at least Unscreen, which makes perfect sense as a product name even under another company.</p>
<p>German outlets <a href="https://www.diepresse.com/5941153/wiener-start-up-schafft-supercoup">Die Presse</a> and <a href="https://www.derbrutkasten.com/wiener-startup-kaleido-ai-schafft-einen-der-grosten-exits-der-osterreichischen-startup-geschichte/">Der Brutkasten</a> cited sources putting the purchase &#8220;reiht sich dahinter ein&#8221; or in the same rank as the largest Austrian exits (the largest of which was Runtastic at €220M), though still in the two-digit millions — which suggests a price approaching $100M.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2117382" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-team-min-f5b1046d.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2117382" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2117382" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-team-min-f5b1046d.jpg" alt="The team at kaleido celebrating their acquisition - each member has been digitally added." width="1024" height="600" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-team-min-f5b1046d.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-team-min-f5b1046d.jpg?resize=150,88 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-team-min-f5b1046d.jpg?resize=300,176 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-team-min-f5b1046d.jpg?resize=768,450 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-team-min-f5b1046d.jpg?resize=680,399 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-team-min-f5b1046d.jpg?resize=1536,900 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/kaleido-team-min-f5b1046d.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2117382" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Kaleido</p></div></p>
<p>Whatever the exact amount, it seems to have made the team very happy. And don&#8217;t worry &#8211; they put that image together using their own product for each person.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z0hZSC64rs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/canva-raises-60-million-on-a-6-billion-valuation/">Canva raises $60 million on a $6 billion valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Canva raises $60 million on a $6 billion valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/canva-raises-60-million-on-a-6-billion-valuation/embed/#?secret=Z0hZSC64rs" data-secret="Z0hZSC64rs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/canva-acquires-background-removal-specialists-kaleido/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117335</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Techstars&#8217; Neal Sáles-Griffin will join us at TechCrunch Early Stage 2021 to talk accelerators</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/techstars-neal-sales-griffin-will-join-us-at-techcrunch-early-stage-2021-to-talk-accelerators/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/techstars-neal-sales-griffin-will-join-us-at-techcrunch-early-stage-2021-to-talk-accelerators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 18:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neal Sáles-Griffin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Early Stage 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Should you try to get your startup into an accelerator program? How do you make the right impression on the application? Where does your team need to be before you apply — and once you&#8217;re in, how do you make the most of your time in the program? Join us at the TechCrunch Early Stage [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Should you try to get your startup into an accelerator program? How do you make the right impression on the application? Where does your team need to be before you apply — and once you&#8217;re in, how do you make the most of your time in the program?</p>
<p>Join us at the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=techstarspost">TechCrunch Early Stage</a> event in April, where Neal Sáles-Griffin, managing director of Techstars Chicago, will help us figure it all out.</p>
<p>Neal has seen this industry from just about every angle — as a teacher, advisor, investor and repeat co-founder. In 2011 he co-founded what is often referred to as the &#8220;first coding bootcamp,&#8221; with The Starter League, acquired by New York&#8217;s Fullstack Academy in 2016. In addition to leading the way at Techstars Chicago, he is also a venture partner at MATH Venture Partners, an early/middle-stage VC fund.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=techstarspost">TC Early Stage</a> — happening on April 1st and 2nd — is an event that we&#8217;ve tailored to be absolutely <em>packed</em> with information for early-stage founders, with key insights from the investors, founders and executives who&#8217;ve been through it all before. Day one will cover everything from fundraising, to honing your pitch deck, to finding product market fit; day two transitions into what we&#8217;ve dubbed the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/announcing-the-tc-early-stage-pitch-off/">TC Early Stage Pitch-Off</a>, where 10 companies will get a shot to pitch an incredible line-up of VC judges.</p>
<p>Oh, and it&#8217;s all fully virtual, so you can tune in straight from the comfort of your couch. You can find more details <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=techstarspost&amp;display=true">here</a>, or get your tickets directly below.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/techstars-neal-sales-griffin-will-join-us-at-techcrunch-early-stage-2021-to-talk-accelerators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116883</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Francisco Partners is acquiring MyHeritage, sources say for $600M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/francisco-partners-is-acquiring-myheritage-sources-say-for-600m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/francisco-partners-is-acquiring-myheritage-sources-say-for-600m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 18:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Genealogy tracking online is a big business, and today comes some M&#38;A news for one of the bigger names in the field. TechCrunch has learned and confirmed that Israel&#8217;s MyHeritage.com &#8212; a profitable site that lets people test DNA and track their family lineage and has some 62 million users &#8212; is getting acquired by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Genealogy tracking online is a big business, and today comes some M&amp;A news for one of the bigger names in the field. TechCrunch has learned and confirmed that Israel&#8217;s <a href="http://myheritage.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MyHeritage.com</a> &#8212; a profitable site that lets people test DNA and track their family lineage and has some 62 million users &#8212; is getting acquired by Francisco Partners, for a price that a source close to the deal tells us is $600 million.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for MyHeritage confirmed the deal to TechCrunch over the phone but not the price. Francisco Partners has not responded to our request for comment but we&#8217;ll update this post as we learn more.</p>
<p>From what we understand the deal will be announced officially very soon. <em>Update</em>: we now have received a press release, so I  guess that makes it &#8220;official.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The market for DNA tests and genealogy research is generally a very fragmented one, but within that MyHeritage has been an early player &#8212; it has been around since 2003 &#8212; and a prolific one at that.</p>
<p>In addition to its 62 million active users of its site &#8212; which is available in 42 languages &#8212; it also has a database of some 13 billion historical records. Users have built and expanded on some 58 million family trees on its platform. It&#8217;s also run nearly 5 million DNA tests for its users.</p>
<p>Pricing for the service starts at free for limited use and goes up in several increments starting at $129/year through to $319/year depending on usage and features that you want to use. DNA kits cost $59.</p>
<p>The deal is a confirmation, if one is needed, that the hunting down of DNA lineage and family trees &#8212;  perennial hobbies for people looking for more links to their histories &#8212; can be be big business.</p>
<p class="p1">“When I founded the company from my home eighteen years ago, I had a clear vision that drove me, and continues to drive me today – to make family history discovery easier using technology and to unlock the fun in genealogy: the human pursuit that bonds people,” said Gilad Japhet, founder and CEO of MyHeritage, in a statement. “With the help of an excellent and dedicated team, years of hard work, and with constant technological innovation, we created new and exciting ways for people to learn about their origins.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;In Francisco Partners we see a true partner for our journey ahead, not only demonstrated by the trust they are placing in our company through this acquisition, but in their desire for us to remain true to our vision by continuing along our path and helping us do what we do best – putting our users first and giving them life-enriching, and sometimes life-changing, experiences. This move will enable us to reach new heights, invest more resources in creating greater value for our users and to reach a larger audience. We’re incredibly excited for this next chapter in our company’s evolution.”</p>
<p>Indeed, while MyHeritage is already profitable this deal represents a moment for the company (and its new owner) to double down on investing in what it does already and expanding its services to the next level. It has grown in part through some 11 acquisitions to date, so making more consolidating purchases might be part of that.</p>
<p>It will also hopefully include investment in its cybersecurity.</p>
<p>MyHeritage has had a colorful, not always positive, profile in the public eye. It emerged as a <a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-12-08/man-in-the-window" target="_blank" rel="noopener">key player</a> in solving one of the most elusive murder cases in decades, the hunt for the Golden State Killer.</p>
<p>But is has also been the subject of a <a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbqyvx/myheritage-hacked-data-breach-92-million" target="_blank" rel="noopener">major data breach</a>, compromising some 92 million accounts in 2018. Account details of some MyHeritage users were part of a huge trove of personal details &#8212; collated from a number of breaches of several sites &#8212; that were <a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/02/11/620_million_hacked_accounts_dark_web/">posted for sale online in 2019</a>.</p>
<p>To be completely clear on data, MyHeritage as a company is not in the business of selling or using data in any way. It said that it will soon be updating its privacy policy &#8220;to include the unequivocal prohibition for the company to license or sell genetic data to any third party. These updates will be highly unique amongst the larger genealogy and genetic DNA industry and are a testament to the commitment both MyHeritage and Francisco Partners share to privacy and consumers.&#8221;</p>
<p>It also runs pro bono work including DNA Quest, for adoptees to find their biological families; and Tribal Quest, to help document the family histories and cultural heritage of remote tribes around the world. It has been running a Covid-19 testing lab in Israel as well to better track the spread of the coronavirus.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The deal is coming at a time when another major DNA player, </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-04/23andme-to-go-public-as-3-5-billion-company-via-branson-merger" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23andme</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, is going public way of a SPAC at a valuation of $3.5 billion.</span></p>
<p>Although a significantly smaller sum, $600 million would be a really strong exit for MyHeritage, which says it has only raised $49 million in funding since being founded in 2003, with investors including Accel, Index and Bessemer.</p>
<p>Part of the deal will see some individual and institutional investors continuing to keep stakes in the company alongside Francisco Partners, MyHeritage said. They include HP Beteiligungs GmbH, Yuval Rakavy, Japhet, and Gigi Levy.</p>
<p>PE firm Francisco Partners has been a prolific acquirer and investor in the tech sector, and tapping a profitable company that has more obvious growth potential is a logical move for it.</p>
<p class="p1">“By leveraging our operational expertise, market resources and strong industry networks, we believe Francisco Partners is uniquely positioned to help MyHeritage accelerate its vision for growth. We are deeply impressed by the incredible achievements and relentless determination of Gilad, a visionary leader in genealogy who has grown the company from a start-up to a profitable global market leader,” said Eran Gorev, Francisco Partners‘ President of Israel &amp; Senior Operating Partner, in a statement. “We are looking forward to partnering with Gilad and the entire MyHeritage team to help drive market expansion for the company.”</p>
<p class="p1">Gorev is joining the board along with Francisco&#8217;s Europe head Matt Spetzler with this deal.</p>
<p class="p3">“Francisco Partners shares MyHeritage’s vision for growth as well as its intense commitment to ensuring the privacy of its users. The users’ personal data is an extremely important priority and we will work together with MyHeritage to expand its already strong privacy framework going forward,&#8221; said Spetzler.</p>
<p><em>Updated with more detail about the deal and the company.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/francisco-partners-is-acquiring-myheritage-sources-say-for-600m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117363</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Europe kicks off bid to find a route to &#8216;better&#8217; gig work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/europe-kicks-off-bid-to-find-a-route-to-better-gig-work/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/europe-kicks-off-bid-to-find-a-route-to-better-gig-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 17:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platform regulations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The European Union has kicked off the first stage of a consultation process involving gig platforms and workers. Regional lawmakers have said they want to improve working conditions for people who provide labor via platforms which EU digital policy chief, Margrethe Vestager, accepted in a speech today can be &#8220;poor&#8221; and &#8220;precarious&#8221;. Yet she also [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The European Union has kicked off the first stage of a consultation process involving gig platforms and workers. Regional lawmakers have said they want to improve working conditions for people who provide labor via platforms which EU digital policy chief, Margrethe Vestager, accepted in a <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/speech_21_805">speech</a> today can be &#8220;poor&#8221; and &#8220;precarious&#8221;.</p>
<p>Yet she also made it clear the Commission&#8217;s agenda vis-a-vis the issue of gig work is to find some kind of &#8220;balance&#8221; between (poor) platform work and, er, good and stable (rights protected) employment.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no detail yet on how exactly regional lawmakers plan to square the circle of giving gig platforms a continued pass on not providing good/stable work &#8212; given that their sustainability as businesses (still with only theoretical profits, in many cases) is chain-linked to not shelling out for the full suite of employment rights for the thousands of people they rely upon to be engaged in the sweating toil of delivering their service off the corporate payroll.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But that, presumably, is what the Commission&#8217;s consultation process is aimed at figuring out. Baked into the first stage of the process is getting the two sides together to try to hash out what better looks like.</p>
<p>&#8220;The platform economy is here to stay &#8212; new technologies, new sources of knowledge, new forms of work will shape the world in the years ahead,&#8221; said Vestager, segueing into a red-line that there must be no reduction in the rights or the social safety net for platform workers (NB: The word &#8216;should&#8217; is doing rather a lot of heavy lifting here): &#8220;And for all of our work on the digital economy, these new opportunities must not come with different rights. Online just as offline, all people should be protected and allowed to work safely and with dignity.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The key issue in our consultations is to find a balance between making the most of the opportunities of the platform economy and ensuring that the social rights of people working in it are the same as in the traditional economy,&#8221; she also said, adding: &#8220;It is also a matter of a fair competition and level playing field between platforms and traditional companies that have higher labour costs because they are subject to traditional labour laws.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Commission&#8217;s two-stage consultation process on gig work starts with a consultation of &#8220;social partners&#8221; on &#8220;the need and direction of possible EU action to improve the working conditions in platform work&#8221;, as it puts it.</p>
<p>This will be open for at least six weeks. It will involve platforms talking with workers (and/or their representatives) to try to come up with agreement on what &#8216;better&#8217; looks like in the context of platform working conditions, either to steer the direction of any Commission initiative. Or &#8212; else &#8212; to kick the legislative can down the road on said initiative if they can come up with stuff they can agree to implement themselves.</p>
<p>The second phase &#8212; assuming the &#8220;social partners&#8221; don&#8217;t agree on and implement a way forward themselves &#8212; is planned to take place before the summer and will focus on &#8220;the content of the initiative&#8221;, per Vestager. (Aka: what exactly the EU ends up proposing to square the circle that must be squared.)</p>
<p>The competition component of the gig work conundrum &#8212; whereby there&#8217;s <em>also</em> the &#8217;employer fairness&#8217; dynamic to consider, given platforms aren&#8217;t playing by the same rules as traditional employers so are potentially undercutting rivals who are offering those good and stable jobs &#8212; explains why the Commission is launching a competition-focused parallel consultation alongside the social stakeholder chats.</p>
<p>&#8220;We will soon start a public consultation on this initiative that has another legal base since it is about competition law and not social policies. This is the reason why we consult differently on the two initiatives,&#8221; noted Vestager.</p>
<p>She said this will aim to ensure that EU competition rules &#8220;do not stand in the way of collective bargaining for those who need it&#8221; &#8212; suggesting the Commission is hoping that collective bargaining will form some part of the solution to achieving the sought for (precarious) balance of &#8216;better&#8217; platform work.</p>
<p>Albeit, a cynical person might predict the end goal of all this solicitation of views will probably be some kind of fudge &#8212; that offers the perception of a plug for the platform rights gap without actually disrupting the platform economy which Vestager has sworn is here to say.</p>
<p>Uber for one has scented opportunity in the Commission&#8217;s talk of improving &#8220;legal clarity&#8221; for platforms.</p>
<p>The ride-hailing giant put out a white paper last week in which it lobbied lawmakers to deregulate platform work &#8212; pushing for a Prop-22 style outcome in Europe, having succeeded in getting a carve out from tightened employment laws in California.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="y3IWDCnsXq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/uber-lobbies-for-prop-22-style-gig-work-standards-in-the-eu/">Uber lobbies for &#8216;Prop 22&#8217;-style gig work standards in the EU</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uber lobbies for &#8216;Prop 22&#8217;-style gig work standards in the EU&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/uber-lobbies-for-prop-22-style-gig-work-standards-in-the-eu/embed/#?secret=y3IWDCnsXq" data-secret="y3IWDCnsXq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Expect other platforms to follow with similarly self-serving suggestions aimed at encouraging Europe&#8217;s social contract to be retooled at the points where it intersects with their business models. (Last week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/uber-could-give-gig-workers-a-better-deal-but-its-lobbying-eu-to-lower-standards-says-fairwork/">Uber was accused</a> of intentionally stalling on improving conditions for workers in favor of lobbying for deregulation, for example.)</p>
<p>The start of the Commission&#8217;s gig work consultation come hard on heels of a landmark ruling by the UK&#8217;s Supreme Court (also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/uber-loses-gig-workers-rights-challenge-in-uk-supreme-court/">last week</a>) &#8212; which dismissed Uber&#8217;s final appeal against a long running employment tribunal.</p>
<p>The judges cemented the view that the group of drivers who sued Uber had indeed been erroneously classified as &#8216;self employed&#8217;, making Uber liable to pay compensation for the rights it should have been funding all along.</p>
<p>So if the EU ends up offering a lower level of employment rights to platform workers vis-a-vis the (post-brexit) UK that would surely make for some uncomfortable faces in Brussels.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zhqlT6ky18"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/uber-loses-gig-workers-rights-challenge-in-uk-supreme-court/">Uber loses gig workers rights challenge in UK Supreme Court</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uber loses gig workers rights challenge in UK Supreme Court&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/uber-loses-gig-workers-rights-challenge-in-uk-supreme-court/embed/#?secret=zhqlT6ky18" data-secret="zhqlT6ky18" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">While it may be unrealistic to talk about striking a &#8216;balance&#8217; in the context of business models that are inherently imbalanced, given they&#8217;re based on dodging existing employment regulations and disrupting the usual social playbook for profit, he Commission seems to think that a consultation process and a network of overlapping regulations is the way to rein in the worst excesses of the gig economy/big tech more generally.</span></p>
<p>In a <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_21_686">press release</a> about the consultation, it notes that platform work is &#8220;developing rapidly&#8221; across various business sectors in the region.</p>
<p>&#8220;It can offer increased flexibility, job opportunities and additional revenue, including for people who might find it more difficult to enter the traditional labour market,&#8221; it writes, starting with some of the positives that are, pesumably, feeding its desire for a &#8216;balanced&#8217; outcome.</p>
<p>&#8220;However, certain types of platform work are also associated with precarious working conditions, reflected in the lack of transparency and predictability of contractual arrangements, health and safety challenges, and insufficient access to social protection. Additional challenges related to platform work include its cross-border dimension and the issue of algorithmic management.&#8221;</p>
<p>It also notes the role of the coronavirus pandemic in both accelerating uptake of platform work and increasing concern about the &#8220;vulnerable situation&#8221; of gig workers &#8212; who may have to choose between earning money and risking their health (and the health of other people) via working and thus potential viral exposure.</p>
<p>The Commission <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/qanda_21_656">reports</a> that around 11% of the EU workforce (some 24 million people) say they have already provided services through a platform.</p>
<p>Vestager said most of these people &#8220;only have platform work as a secondary or a marginal source of income&#8221; &#8212; but added that some three million people do it as a main job.</p>
<p>And just imagine the cost to gig platforms if those three million people had to be put on the payroll in Europe&#8230;</p>
<p>In the bit of her speech leading up to her conclusion that platform work is here to stay, Vestager quoted a recent study she said had indicated that 35% to 55% of consumers say they intend to continue to ask for home delivery more in the future.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8230; see that the platform economy is growing rapidly,&#8221; she added. &#8220;Worldwide, the online labour platform market has grown by 30% over a period of 2 years. This growth is expected to continue and the number of people working through platforms is expected to become more significant in the years ahead.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;European values are at the heart of our work to shape Europe&#8217;s digital future,&#8221; she also went on, taking her cue to point to the smorgasbord of digital regulations in the EU&#8217;s pipeline &#8212; and perhaps illustrating the concept of an overlapping regulatory net that the Commission intends to straightjacket platform giants into more socially acceptable and fair behavior (though it hasn&#8217;t yet).</p>
<p>&#8220;Our proposals from December for a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Digital Services Act and a Digital Markets Act</a> are meant to protect us as consumers if technology poses a risk to fundamental rights. In April we will follow up on our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">white paper on Artificial Intelligence</a> from last year and our upcoming proposal will also have the aim to protect us as citizens. The fairness aspect and the integration of European values will also be a driver for our upcoming proposal on a digital tax that we plan to present before summer.</p>
<p>&#8220;All these initiatives are part of our ambition to balance the great potential that the digital transformation holds for our societies and economies.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KA36NLvVzw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/embed/#?secret=KA36NLvVzw" data-secret="KA36NLvVzw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KIHk5iTsdx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/europe-sets-out-the-rules-of-the-road-for-its-data-reuse-plan/">Europe sets out the rules of the road for its data reuse plan</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe sets out the rules of the road for its data reuse plan&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/europe-sets-out-the-rules-of-the-road-for-its-data-reuse-plan/embed/#?secret=KIHk5iTsdx" data-secret="KIHk5iTsdx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/europe-kicks-off-bid-to-find-a-route-to-better-gig-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117234</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpaceX&#8217;s floating oil rig spaceship launch pad could be operating later this year according to Elon Musk</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/spacexs-floating-oil-rig-spaceship-launch-pad-could-be-operating-later-this-year-according-to-elon-musk/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/spacexs-floating-oil-rig-spaceship-launch-pad-could-be-operating-later-this-year-according-to-elon-musk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 17:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gulf of Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyperloop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX&#8217;s grand vision for Starship, the next-generation spacecraft it&#8217;s currently in the process of developing, includes not only trips to Mars, but also regular point-to-point flights right here on Earth. These would skim the Earth&#8217;s outer atmosphere, reducing travel times for regular international flights from many hours to around 30 minutes. They&#8217;ll need to take [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SpaceX&#8217;s grand vision for Starship, the next-generation spacecraft it&#8217;s currently in the process of developing, includes not only trips to Mars, but also regular point-to-point flights right here on Earth. These would skim the Earth&#8217;s outer atmosphere, reducing travel times for regular international flights from many hours to around 30 minutes. They&#8217;ll need to take off from somewhere, however, and rockets are a bit more disturbing to their local environs than traditional aircraft, so part of SpaceX founder Elon Musk&#8217;s plan for their regular use is covering oil rig platforms into floating spaceports.</p>
<p>Musk has talked about these plans before, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/spacex-bought-two-oil-rigs-to-convert-into-offshore-launch-pads-for-starship/">SpaceX recently went so far as to purchase two rigs</a> – which it nicknamed Phoibos and Deimos after the moons of Mars. These are currently in the process of being retrofitted for use with Starship, and they&#8217;ll be stationed in the Gulf of Mexico near SpaceX&#8217;s Brownsville, Texas development site.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YFxONhVH8J"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/spacex-bought-two-oil-rigs-to-convert-into-offshore-launch-pads-for-starship/">SpaceX bought two oil rigs to convert into offshore launch pads for Starship</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX bought two oil rigs to convert into offshore launch pads for Starship&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/spacex-bought-two-oil-rigs-to-convert-into-offshore-launch-pads-for-starship/embed/#?secret=YFxONhVH8J" data-secret="YFxONhVH8J" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>On Wednesday, Musk said on Twitter that one of the two platforms could be at least partially operational by the end of 2021. The SpaceX CEO is known for his optimistic timelines, but a lot of them have actually been relatively accurate lately – or at least not quite as unrealistic as in years past.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">One of them may be in limited operation by end of year</p>
<p>&mdash; Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1364476185359642626?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 24, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>What he means by &#8220;in limited operation&#8221; isn&#8217;t necessarily clear. That could mean that they&#8217;re floating where they&#8217;re supposed to be, and technically capable of playing host to a Starship prototype, but not that SpaceX will be actively launching Starships from one by end of year. He did add that the plan is to put floating launchpads for Starship not only in the Gulf, but also at <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1364488368994848769">various points around the world</a> – which is in keeping with the bold plan he shared via CG concept videos when Starship debuted, which depicted launch and landing facilities stationed in bodies of water near urban destinations.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/zqE-ultsWt0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/spacexs-floating-oil-rig-spaceship-launch-pad-could-be-operating-later-this-year-according-to-elon-musk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117294</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet Smash Ventures, the low-flying outfit that has quietly funded Epic Games among others</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/meet-smash-ventures-the-low-flying-outfit-that-has-quietly-funded-epic-games-among-others/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/meet-smash-ventures-the-low-flying-outfit-that-has-quietly-funded-epic-games-among-others/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 17:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[byju's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DraftKings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ed catmull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Mayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smash Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When in 2018, Smash Ventures showed up as an investor in a $1.25 billion round for Epic Games &#8212; reportedly the largest ever investment in a video game company at the time &#8212; it was the first time many had heard of the investing outfit. When the brand showed up again last summer in an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When in 2018, <a href="http://smashventures.com">Smash Ventures</a> showed up as an investor in a $1.25 billion round for Epic Games &#8212; reportedly the <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/epic-games-1-billion-funding-largest-ever-gaming-investment-2018-10">largest ever investment in a video game company</a> at the time &#8212; it was the first time many had heard of the investing outfit.</p>
<p>When the brand showed up again last summer in an even bigger round for Epic &#8212;  last August, the games giant announced $1.78 billion in fresh funding at a post-money equity valuation of $17.3 billion &#8212; a diner near Epic&#8217;s Cary, North Carolina headquarters that sells &#8220;smash waffles&#8221; started getting calls from reporters, says Eric Garland, who used to lead venture and growth deals for The Walt Disney Company after <a href="https://variety.com/2011/digital/news/live-nation-acquires-big-champagne-1118047513/">selling his company</a>, BigChampagne, to Live Nation in 2011.</p>
<p>&#8220;Some reporters really turned over rocks,&#8221; he says.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Garland knows this, he says, because he cofounded Smash Ventures with Evan Richter, a former member of Disney&#8217;s corporate strategy and business development team (and who, before that, was an investor at Insight Partners).</p>
<p>The pair say they weren&#8217;t trying to duck the press after striking out on their own a few years ago; they were mostly just trying to get their firm off the ground, which they&#8217;ve seemingly done and then some. First, there&#8217;s the newly closed $75 million debut fund from strategic partners and notable investors like Kevin Mayer, the former CEO of TikTok and the former Disney executive; Pixar cofounder Ed Catmull; and journalist Willow Bay, who is now dean of the USC Annenberg School for Communication and Journalism. Yet it&#8217;s just a small piece of what they have assembled.</p>
<p>Indeed, at a time when money is more of a commodity than ever and can be accessed easily by many founders, Smash has a few tricks up its sleeve, Richter and Garland suggest.</p>
<p>One thing to know, for example, is that the two apparently have little trouble spinning up side vehicles when they wedge their way into an interesting deal. While they got to know Epic Games through Disney (it made an investment in the company in 2017 when Epic took part in its <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/blog/epic-games-selected-to-join-disneys-accelerator-program">accelerator program</a>), when they persuaded founder Tim Sweeney to take a bigger check from Smash Ventures in 2018, they were able to package together &#8220;several hundred million dollars&#8221; from their LPs for a stake in the business.</p>
<p>They also &#8220;flexed up&#8221; with the help of their limited partners to put a separate $200 million into others of its handful of portfolio companies. These include DraftKings, before it <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/draftkings-is-now-a-public-company-worth-more-than-6-billion-5-things-to-know-2020-04-27">went public</a> through a blank-check company last year; the footwear, apparel and accessory brand <a href="https://www.nobullproject.com/">Nobull</a>; the men&#8217;s grooming company <a href="https://www.manscaped.com/">Manscaped</a>; and India’s biggest e-learning startup, <a href="https://byjus.com/us/">Byju’s</a>.</p>
<p>Disney &#8212; one of the world&#8217;s most powerful brands &#8212;  is a common thread throughout. In addition to inviting Epic into its accelerator program, Disney began work on an education app with Byju back in 2018 and it <a href="https://www.legalsportsreport.com/40488/disney-draftkings-stock-public/">owned 6%</a> of DraftKings when it went public last year.</p>
<p>Mayer, the former Disney exec who more recently began launching <a href="https://www.thewrap.com/kevin-mayer-tom-staggs-and-shaquille-oneal-team-for-second-spac/">special purpose acquisition vehicles</a>, credits Richter and Garland with finding &#8220;a lot of really cool companies like Epic&#8221; while inside Disney, saying he has &#8220;been supporting them ever since, because I think they&#8217;re great.&#8221;</p>
<p>Underscoring the strength of that former Disney network &#8212; another apparent advantage here &#8212; Mayer says that in addition to being a limited partner, he will sometimes &#8220;try and talk to their CEOs, give strategic advice, and talk about exits and M&amp;A with some of their portfolio companies.&#8221; (Catmull, who was the president of Walt Disney Animation Studios after Disney acquired Pixar in 2006, was also pulled in to help seal the Epic deal, says Garland.)</p>
<p>As for whether Smash&#8217;s dealings have irritated current execs at Disney &#8212; it isn&#8217;t hard to imagine the entertainment giant would have liked a bigger stake in Epic &#8212; Garland says no, adding that, &#8220;Outside of its accelerator, Disney is not generally in the venture business.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the meantime, Smash also says it&#8217;s getting into deals by helping companies tell stories to their respective, captive audiences. As Richter explains it, &#8220;The leading consumer software and internet businesses are building massive, and dedicated, user bases, and media, whether it&#8217;s a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wYeFAlVC8qU">Travis Scott experience</a> within Epic Games, or an IP collaboration between Marvel or Disney [and Byju&#8217;s], or whether it&#8217;s doing something with the UFC [which last year <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/manscaped-and-ufc-announce-multi-year-marketing-partnership-301052874.html">partnered</a> with Manscaped], can be an incredible way to keep and grow a user base.&#8221;</p>
<p>The firm certainly appears to spend a lot of time with its portfolio companies on these efforts. While Smash wrote its first check in 2018, it has just five portfolio companies to date, and it plans only to invest in 10 to 12 companies altogether with that $75 million pool of capital, writing checks as small as $5 million to $10 million, with the ability to write far larger checks when the opportunity arises and its LP network says yes to it.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s because the firm is on the hunt now for that next big thing that Smash is suddenly going public with its efforts, Richter suggests. Not that a lot of public speaking is in the partners&#8217; future, seemingly. &#8220;We like to stay focused,&#8221; Garland says. &#8220;We make a lot of noise for our portfolio companies, but we are ourselves very heads down.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/meet-smash-ventures-the-low-flying-outfit-that-has-quietly-funded-epic-games-among-others/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116961</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Cloud puts its Kubernetes Engine on autopilot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/google-cloud-puts-its-kubernetes-engine-on-autopilot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/google-cloud-puts-its-kubernetes-engine-on-autopilot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 17:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[containers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GKE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google Cloud today announced a new operating mode for its Kubernetes Engine (GKE) that turns over the management of much of the day-to-day operations of a container cluster to Google&#8217;s own engineers and automated tools. With Autopilot, as the new mode is called, Google manages all of the Day 2 operations of managing these clusters [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google Cloud today <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/containers-kubernetes/introducing-gke-autopilot">announced</a> a new operating mode for its Kubernetes Engine (GKE) that turns over the management of much of the day-to-day operations of a container cluster to Google&#8217;s own engineers and automated tools. With Autopilot, as the new mode is called, Google manages all of the Day 2 operations of managing these clusters and their nodes, all while implementing best practices for operating and securing them.</p>
<p>This new mode augments the existing GKE experience, which already managed most of the infrastructure of standing up a cluster. This &#8216;standard&#8217; experience, as Google Cloud now calls it, is still available and allows users to customize their configurations to their heart&#8217;s content and manually provision and manage their node infrastructure.</p>
<p>Drew Bradstock, the Group Product Manager for GKE, told me that the idea behind Autopilot was to bring together all of the tools that Google already had for GKE and bring them together with its SRE teams who know how to run these clusters in production &#8212; and have long done so inside of the company.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Autopilot stitches together auto-scaling, auto-upgrades, maintenance, Day 2 operations and &#8212; just as importantly &#8212; does it in a <a href="https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/how-to/hardening-your-cluster">hardened fashion</a>,&#8221; Bradstock noted. &#8220;[&#8230;] What this has allowed our initial customers to do is very quickly offer a better environment for developers or dev and test, as well as production, because they can go from Day Zero and the end of that five-minute cluster creation time, and actually have Day 2 done as well.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2117313" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/pasted-image-0.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2117313" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2117313" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/pasted-image-0.png" alt="" width="1024" height="613" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/pasted-image-0.png 1715w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/pasted-image-0.png?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/pasted-image-0.png?resize=300,180 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/pasted-image-0.png?resize=768,460 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/pasted-image-0.png?resize=680,407 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/pasted-image-0.png?resize=1536,920 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/pasted-image-0.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2117313" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>From a developer&#8217;s perspective, nothing really changes here, but this new mode does free up teams to focus on the actual workloads and less on managing Kubernetes clusters. With Autopilot, businesses still get the benefits of Kubernetes, but without all of the routine management and maintenance work that comes with that. And that&#8217;s definitely a trend we&#8217;ve been seeing as the Kubernetes ecosystem has evolved. Few companies, after all, see their ability to effectively manage Kubernetes as their real competitive differentiator.</p>
<p>All of that comes at a price, of course, at a flat fee of $0.10 per hour and cluster (there&#8217;s also a free GKE tier that provides $74.40 in billing credits), plus, of course, the usual fees for resources that your clusters consume. Google offers a 99.95% SLA for the control plane of its Autopilot clusters and a 99.9% SLA for Autopilot pods in multiple zones.</p>
<p>Autopilot for GKE joins a set of container-centric products in the Google Cloud portfolio that also include Anthos for running in multi-cloud environments and Cloud Run, Google&#8217;s serverless offering. &#8220;[Autopilot] is really [about] bringing the automation aspects in GKE we have for running on Google Cloud, and bringing it all together in an easy-to-use package, so that if you&#8217;re newer to Kubernetes, or you&#8217;ve got a very large fleet, it drastically reduces the amount of time, operations and even compute you need to use,&#8221; Bradstock explained.</p>
<p>And while GKE is a key part of Anthos, that service is more about brining Google&#8217;s config management, service mesh and other tools to an enterprise&#8217;s own data center. Autopilot of GKE is, at least for now, only available on Google Cloud.</p>
<p>&#8220;On the serverless side, Cloud Run is really, really great for an opinionated development experience,&#8221; Bradstock added. &#8220;So you can get going really fast if you want an app to be able to go from zero to 1000 and back to zero &#8212; and not worry about anything at all and have it managed entirely by Google. That&#8217;s highly valuable and ideal for a lot of development. Autopilot is more about simplifying the entire platform people work on when they want to leverage the Kubernetes ecosystem, be a lot more in control and have a whole bunch of apps running within one environment.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/google-cloud-puts-its-kubernetes-engine-on-autopilot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117261</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple supplier Foxconn reaches tentative agreement to build Fisker&#8217;s next electric car</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/apple-supplier-foxconn-reaches-tentative-agreement-to-build-fiskers-next-electric-car/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/apple-supplier-foxconn-reaches-tentative-agreement-to-build-fiskers-next-electric-car/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 16:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fisker Inc.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foxconn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple supplier Foxconn Technology Group has reached a tentative agreement with electric vehicle startup-turned-SPAC Fisker to develop and eventually manufacture an EV that will be sold in North America, Europe, China and India. Fisker and Foxconn said Wednesday that a memorandum of understanding agreement has been signed. Discussions between the two companies will continue with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple supplier Foxconn Technology Group has reached a tentative agreement with electric vehicle startup-turned-SPAC Fisker to develop and eventually manufacture an EV that will be sold in North America, Europe, China and India.</p>
<p>Fisker and Foxconn said Wednesday that a memorandum of understanding agreement has been signed. Discussions between the two companies will continue with the expectation that a<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> formal partnership agreement will be reached during the second quarter of this year. </span></p>
<p>Under the agreement, Foxconn will begin production in the fourth quarter of 2023 with a projected annual volume of more than 250,000 vehicles. The electric vehicle will carry the Fisker brand.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Foxconn Technology Group Chairman Young-way Liu touted the company&#8217;s vertically integrated global supply chain and accumulated engineering capabilities, noting that it gives the company two major advantages in the development and manufacturing of the key elements of an EV, which includes the electric motor, electric control module and battery.</p>
<p>That supply chain and ability to scale engineering quickly will be critical for Foxconn if it hopes to meet its production target.</p>
<p>&#8220;The collaboration between our firms means that it will only take 24 months to produce the next Fisker vehicle &#8212; from research and development to production, reducing half of the traditional time required to bring a new vehicle to market,&#8221; Young-way Liu said in a statement.</p>
<p>Fisker said production of the Ocean SUV — its first EV and one that is supposed to be built by contract manufacturer Magna — will begin in the fourth quarter of 2022. The company said it plans to unveil a production-intent prototype of the Ocean later this year.</p>
<p>This is not Foxconn&#8217;s first foray into electric vehicle manufacturing.</p>
<p>Foxconn announced in January 2020 that it had formed a joint venture with Fiat Chrysler Automobiles to build electric vehicles in China. Under that agreement, each party will own 50% of the venture to develop and manufacture electric vehicles and engage in an IOV, what Foxconn parent company Hon Hai calls the “internet of vehicles” business.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">Last month, Foxconn and Chinese automaker Zhejiang Geely Holding Group agreed to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/foxconn-geely-team-up-to-build-electric-autonomous-and-shared-vehicles-for-automakers-startups/">form a joint venture</a> focused on contract manufacturing for automakers, with a specific focus on electrification, connectivity and autonomous driving technology as well as vehicles designed for sharing.</p>
<p>The joint venture between Foxconn and Geely will provide consulting services on whole vehicles, parts, intelligent drive systems and other automotive ecosystem platforms to automakers as well as ridesharing companies. Geely said it will bring its experience in the automotive fields of design, engineering, R&amp;D, intelligent manufacturing, supply chain management and quality control while Foxconn will bring its manufacturing and Information and Communication Technology (ICT) know-how.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/apple-supplier-foxconn-reaches-tentative-agreement-to-build-fiskers-next-electric-car/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117285</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MealMe raises $900,000 for its food search engine</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/mealme-raises-900000-for-its-food-search-engine/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/mealme-raises-900000-for-its-food-search-engine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 16:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mealme.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Drive Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slow ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning MealMe.ai, a food search engine, announced that it has closed a $900,000 pre-seed round. Palm Drive Capital led the round, with participation from Slow Ventures and CP Ventures. TechCrunch first became familiar with MealMe when it presented as part of the Techstars Atlanta demo day last October, mentioning it in a roundup of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://www.mealme.ai/">MealMe.ai</a>, a food search engine, announced that it has closed a $900,000 pre-seed round. <a href="https://palmdrive.vc/">Palm Drive Capital</a> led the round, with participation from <a href="https://slow-prod.herokuapp.com/">Slow Ventures</a> and <a href="https://cp.ventures/">CP Ventures</a>.</p>
<p>TechCrunch first became familiar with MealMe when it presented as part of the Techstars Atlanta demo day last October, mentioning it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/10-favorite-startups-from-techstars-october-2020-class/">in a roundup of favorite startups</a> from a group of the accelerator&#8217;s startup cohorts.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s product allows users to search for food, or a restaurant. It then displays price points from various food-delivery apps for what the user wants to eat and have delivered. And, notably, MealMe allows for in-app checkout, regardless of the selected provider.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The service could boost pricing and delivery-speed transparency amongst the different apps that help folks eat, like DoorDash and Uber Eats. But Mealme didn&#8217;t start out looking to build a search engine. Instead it took a few changes in direction to get there.</p>
<h2>From social network to search engine</h2>
<p>MealMe is an example of a startup whose first idea proved only directionally correct. The company began life as a food-focused social network, co-founder <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mealmematt/">Matthew Bouchner</a> told TechCrunch. That iteration of the service allowed users to view posted food pictures, and then find ordering options for what they saw.</p>
<p>While still operating as a social network, MealMe applied to both Y Combinator and Techstars, but wasn&#8217;t accepted at either.</p>
<p>The startup discovered that some of its users were posting food pics simply to get the service to tell them which delivery services would be able to bring them what they wanted. From that learning the company focused on building a food search engine, allowing users to search for restaurants, and then vet various delivery options and prices. That iteration of the product got the company into <a href="https://www.techstars.com/accelerators/atlanta">Techstars Atlanta</a>, eventually leading to the demo day that TechCrunch reviewed.</p>
<p>During its time in Techstars, the company adjusted its model to not merely link to DoorDash and others, but to handle checkout inside of its own application. This captures more gross merchandize value (GMV) inside of MealMe, Bouchner explained in an interview. The capability was rolled out in September of 2020.</p>
<p>Since then the company has seen rapid growth, which it measures at around 20% week-on-week. During TechCrunch&#8217;s interview with MealMe, the company said that it had reached a GMV run rate of more than $500,000, and was scaling toward the $1 million mark. In the intervening weeks the company passed the $1 million GMV run-rate threshold.</p>
<p>MealMe was slightly coy on its business model, but it appears to make margin between what it charges users for orders and the total revenue it passes along to food delivery apps.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rZRSWgb2Aq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/10-favorite-startups-from-techstars-october-2020-class/">10 favorite startups from Techstars&#8217; October 2020 class</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 favorite startups from Techstars&#8217; October 2020 class&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/10-favorite-startups-from-techstars-october-2020-class/embed/#?secret=rZRSWgb2Aq" data-secret="rZRSWgb2Aq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>TechCrunch was curious about platform risk at MealMe; could the company get away with offering price comparison and ordering across multiple third-party delivery services without raising the ire of the companies behind those apps? At the time of our interview, Bouchner said that his company had not seen pushback from the services it sends users to. His company&#8217;s goal is to grow quickly, become a useful revenue source for the DoorDashes of the world, and then reach out for some of formal agreement, he explained.</p>
<p>&#8220;We continue to be a powerful revenue generator and drive thousands of orders to food delivery services per week,&#8221; the co-founder said in a written statement. Certainly MealMe found investors more excited by its growth than concerned about Uber Eats or other apps cutting the startup off from their service.</p>
<p>What first caught my eye about MealMe was the realization of how much I would have used it in my early 20s. Perhaps the company can find enough users like my younger self to help it scale to sufficient size that it can go to the major food ordering companies and demand a cut, not merely avoid being cut off.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/mealme-raises-900000-for-its-food-search-engine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117267</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lifestyle benefits startup Fringe gets a pandemic boost, raises seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/lifestyle-benefits-startup-fringe-gets-a-pandemic-boost-raises-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/lifestyle-benefits-startup-fringe-gets-a-pandemic-boost-raises-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 16:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[benefits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fringe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscription services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117174</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Employers today often use perks to attract new talent in the form of discounts and deals, commuter funds, gym memberships, childcare, free lunches and more. But the pandemic has impacted what sort of in-office or other in-person perks employees can access. That&#8217;s led to booming growth &#8212; and now, a fundraise &#8212; for a startup [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Employers today often use perks to attract new talent in the form of discounts and deals, commuter funds, gym memberships, childcare, free lunches and more. But the pandemic has impacted what sort of in-office or other in-person perks employees can access. That&#8217;s led to booming growth &#8212; and now, a fundraise &#8212; for a startup called <a href="https://www.fringe.us/">Fringe</a>, which offers companies a personalized marketplace of perks that people really want, like Netflix, Uber, Airbnb, DoorDash, Headspace, Talkspace and over 100 other apps.</p>
<p>The idea for <a href="https://www.fringe.us/">Fringe</a> came about from the co-founders&#8217; work as financial advisors where they regularly found themselves consulting people who were weighing new job options and their associated benefits.</p>
<p>&#8220;Companies are spending a lot money on traditional benefits&#8230;$800, $1,000 a month per person. But the perceived value for most employees is relatively small, given the cost,&#8221; explains Fringe CEO Jordan Peace. &#8220;I started thinking about what could [companies] offer employees that would be a pretty low actual cost, but a really high perceived value?&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He landed on the idea of subscription services &#8212; things people use all the time in their daily lives, but sometimes feel just out of reach from a budgetary standpoint.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s where Fringe comes in.</p>
<p>Employers sign up for access to Fringe&#8217;s platform at a starting cost of $5 per employee per month. (The rate may decrease for larger organizations.) They then place the dollars they would normally spend on lifestyle benefits into the Fringe accounts of their employees, where they&#8217;re converted to &#8220;points&#8221; that can be spent on any of the apps and services.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/488622085?color=00b0f0&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" width="640" height="354" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/488622085">Fringe Platform Walkthrough</a> from <a href="https://vimeo.com/user95349913">Fringe</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>Today, the marketplace offers a range of benefits, including streaming services like Netflix, Spotify, Disney+, and Audible, as well as virtual fitness, virtual coaching and wellness, online therapy like Talkspace, food and grocery delivery, like Grubhub, Uber Eats, Instacart, and Shipt, prepackaged meals, childcare like UrbanSitter, and more.</p>
<p>In the U.S., there are 135 services partners to choose from, with another couple hundred that are available overseas.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s business model involves negotiating a discount of anywhere from 10% to up to 60% off these services, which it passes along to the employees through its points back (rebate) system. Initially, it only allowed employees to spend their employer-provided lifestyle benefits dollars on Fringe. But due to user demand, it later opened up to allow employees to spend their own money, too &#8212; a feature they wanted specifically because of the points back.</p>
<p>Fringe first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/10/fringe-pitches-a-monthly-stipend-for-app-purchases-and-subscriptions-as-the-newest-employee-benefit/">launched</a> in 2019 &#8212; well ahead of the pandemic &#8212; and saw some slow but steady growth. It ended the year with 15 clients, representing a couple of hundred employees in total.</p>
<p>But then the COVID-19 pandemic hit, which sent a number of employees to work from home in a radical change to business culture that appears to have lasting impacts.</p>
<p>&#8220;After the dust settled from the first few months of COVID, we started getting 10&#8230;20 times more inbound interest,&#8221; Peace says, as companies realized Fringe could be a way to support their employees working from home.</p>
<p>&#8220;We were just in the right place at the right time to begin to profit from this changed workplace. And it&#8217;s not just a &#8216;pandemic perk.&#8217; We&#8217;re going to get past COVID, and we&#8217;re still going to have two-thirds of people working from home. The workplace has changed,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2117255" style="width: 397px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2117255" loading="lazy" class="vertical  wp-image-2117255" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Jordan-Peace-CEO.jpg?w=454" alt="" width="387" height="580" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Jordan-Peace-CEO.jpg 935w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Jordan-Peace-CEO.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Jordan-Peace-CEO.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Jordan-Peace-CEO.jpg?resize=768,1150 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Jordan-Peace-CEO.jpg?resize=454,680 454w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Jordan-Peace-CEO.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 387px) 100vw, 387px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2117255" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fringe CEO Jordan Peace</p></div></p>
<p>By the end of 2020, Fringe had grown its client base to over 70 employers, representing now over 12,000 users on its platform. Today, its pipeline includes companies with between 200 and 2,000 employees &#8212; a sweet spot that allows them to move relatively quickly. This client base often includes tech companies, like car-sharing startup Turo or talent management system Cornerstone OnDemand, for example.</p>
<p>This year, Fringe expects to grow to well over 100,000 users on its platform, and increase its own team&#8217;s headcount, which is today around 20. It also plans to update its marketplace website to include things like automatic point gifting, charitable giving, new Slack integrations, improved navigation, and more.</p>
<p>As a result of the recent growth, Fringe has raised $2.2 million in new funding, in a round led by<a href="https://sovereignscapital.com/"> Sovereign&#8217;s Capital</a>, with participation from Felton Group, Manchester Story, the Center for Innovative Technology, and angel investors, including <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaffraywoodriff/">Jaffray Woodriff</a>. As part of this investment, the company also added longtime advisor William Boland, Senior Director of Corporate Development and Strategy at Mission Lane, to its Board of Directors.</p>
<p>With the addition of the new funds, the startup&#8217;s total raise to date is $4 million.</p>
<p>Fringe believes the advantage of its marketplace is that it can be personalized to the user. Typically, employers determine what benefits to offer by running employee surveys, where the majority wins. That&#8217;s why many companies today provide perks like backup child care or discounted gym access. But this system discounts the minority&#8217;s needs &#8212; people who may not have kids or don&#8217;t want to work out. People who wish they could use their benefits dollars in a different way.</p>
<p>In addition to employee perks, Fringe believes that having so many subscriptions under one roof could present other opportunities further down the line.</p>
<p>Woodriff, for example, sees Fringe&#8217;s potential as a big data play, in terms of who is signing up for what subscriptions and why.</p>
<p>&#8220;But if you think about the fact that you&#8217;ve got a subscription service marketplace&#8230;there&#8217;s more applications to that than just employee benefits,&#8221; Peace explains. &#8220;I&#8217;d like our Series A to be to be predicated upon the much greater total addressable market. And so I think we&#8217;re going to spend the next year to 18 months laying down concrete plans and building the tech to be ready to roll out a couple of different use cases,&#8221; he says.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/lifestyle-benefits-startup-fringe-gets-a-pandemic-boost-raises-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117174</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three days left to save on on early-bird pricing for TC Early Stage &#8211; Operations &#038; Fundraising</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/three-days-left-to-save-on-on-early-bird-pricing-for-tc-early-stage-operations-fundraising/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/three-days-left-to-save-on-on-early-bird-pricing-for-tc-early-stage-operations-fundraising/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 16:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Early Stage 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a mere 72 hours, early bird pricing disappears for TechCrunch Early Stage 2021, our two-part, founder bootcamp series focused on the building blocks you need to grow your company. The first event, TC Early Stage Operations &#38; Fundraising, happens on April 1-2 — that’s two program packed days of education, connection and opportunity. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a mere 72 hours, early bird pricing disappears for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=3daysleftpost">TechCrunch Early Stage 2021</a>, our two-part, founder bootcamp series focused on the building blocks you need to grow your company. The first event, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=3daysleftpost">TC Early Stage Operations &amp; Fundraising</a>, happens on April 1-2 — that’s two program packed days of education, connection and opportunity.</p>
<p>The second event, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-2/?promo=3daysleftpost">TC Early Stage &#8211; Marketing &amp; Fundraising</a>, takes place July 8-9. <strong>Pro Tip:</strong> each bootcamp stands alone and features different topics, content and speakers. Attend one or both events — it’s up to you. But know this: you’ll save more and learn twice as much when you score a dual-event pass at the early bird price. Beat the deadline, buy your passes before <strong>Feb 27 at 11:59 p.m. (PT)</strong> and save up to $100.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=3daysleftpost">TC Early Stage</a> is all about helping new startup founders (pre-seed through Series A) learn the essential skills required to build a successful startup. No need to reinvent the wheel — you’ll have access to the leading experts across the range of specialties. Much like an accelerator (compacted into two days), you’ll learn about legal issues, fundraising, marketing, growth, product-market fit, tech stack, pitch decks and recruiting. We’re talking highly engaging workshops with interactive Q&amp;As.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>On day one you’ll hear from experts like Eghosa Omoigui, the founder and managing general partner of EchoVC Partners, a seed and early-stage technology venture capital firm serving underrepresented founders and underserved markets. He’ll discuss ways to keep your eyes on the big picture and avoid the blind spots that lead to fragmentation and oversights.</p>
<p>Day two features the TC Early Stage Pitch Off! Out of the hundreds of applications we received, we selected 10 founders to pitch on stage for five minutes to a panel of prominent VC judges — followed by a five-minute Q&amp;A. Three founders will move into the finals and pitch to a new panel of judges and endure a more in-depth Q&amp;A. The winner receives a feature article on TechCrunch.com, a free, one-year subscription to ExtraCrunch and a free Founder Pass to <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a>.</p>
<p>Wondering whether it’s worth your time and money?</p>
<blockquote><p>“You learn from industry leaders and seasoned founders — people who’ve already been there and done that. They were genuine and honest about industry expectations. Plus, they shared first-hand accounts, which made them more relatable.” &#8212; Chloe Leaaetoa, founder of Socicraft</p></blockquote>
<p>Don’t reinvent the wheel. Go to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=3daysleftpost">TechCrunch Early Stage 2021</a> (in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=3daysleftpost">April</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-2/">July</a>), learn how-to from the best, connect with other early-stage founders and build a stronger startup. The early bird price disappears in three days on <strong>Friday, Feb 27 at 11:59 p.m. (PT)</strong>. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=3daysleftpost&amp;display=true">Buy your pass today</a> and save up to $100.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/three-days-left-to-save-on-on-early-bird-pricing-for-tc-early-stage-operations-fundraising/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Select Star raises seed to automatically document datasets for data scientists</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/select-star-raises-seed-to-automatically-document-datasets-for-data-scientists/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/select-star-raises-seed-to-automatically-document-datasets-for-data-scientists/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data discovery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2115654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Back when I was a wee lad with a very security-compromised MySQL installation, I used to answer every web request with multiple “SELECT *” database requests — give me all the data and I’ll figure out what to do with it myself. Today in a modern, data-intensive org, “SELECT *” will kill you. With petabytes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Back when I was a wee lad with a very security-compromised MySQL installation, I used to answer every web request with multiple “SELECT *” database requests — give me all the data and I’ll figure out what to do with it myself.</p>
<p>Today in a modern, data-intensive org, “SELECT *” will kill you. With petabytes of information, tens of thousands of tables (on the small side!), and millions and perhaps billions of calls flung at the database server, data science teams can no longer just ask for all the data and start working with it immediately.</p>
<p>Big data has led to the rise of data warehouses and data lakes (and apparently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/a-lake-house-architect-a-miami-vc-and-homeowner-walk-into-a-wine-bar/">data lake houses</a>), infrastructure to make accessing data more robust and easy. There is still a cataloguing and discovery problem though — just because you have all of your data in one place doesn’t mean a data scientist knows what the data represents, who owns it, or what that data might affect in the myriad of web and corporate reporting apps built on top of it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That’s where <a href="https://selectstar.com">Select Star</a> comes in. The startup, which was founded about a year ago in March 2020, is designed to automatically build out metadata within the context of a data warehouse. From there, it offers a full-text search that allows users to quickly find data as well as “heat map” signals in its search results which can quickly pinpoint which columns of a dataset are most used by applications within a company and have the most queries that reference them.</p>
<p>The product is SaaS, and it is designed to allow for quick onboarding by connecting to a customer’s data warehouse or business intelligence (BI) tool.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2115657" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2115657" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2115657" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-1-Table.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="438" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-1-Table.png 1344w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-1-Table.png?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-1-Table.png?resize=300,193 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-1-Table.png?resize=768,495 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-1-Table.png?resize=680,438 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-1-Table.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2115657" class="wp-caption-text">Select Star&#8217;s interface allows data scientists to understand what data they are looking at. Photo via Select Star.</p></div></p>
<p>Shinji Kim, the sole founder and CEO, explained that the tool is a solution to a problem she has seen directly in corporate data science teams. She formerly founded Concord Systems, a real-time data processing startup that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/04/akamai-buys-soha-systems-to-add-more-security-to-its-cloud-networking-business/">was acquired by Akamai in 2016</a>. “The part that I noticed is that we now have all the data and we have the ability to compute, but now the next challenge is to know what the data is and how to use it,” she explained.</p>
<p>She said that “tribal knowledge is starting to become more wasteful [in] time and pain in growing companies” and pointed out that large companies like Facebook, Airbnb, Uber, Lyft, Spotify and others have built out their own homebrewed data discovery tools. Her mission for Select Star is to allow any corporation to quickly tap into an easy-to-use platform to solve this problem.</p>
<p>The company raised a $2.5 million seed round led by Bowery Capital with participation from Background Capital and a number of prominent angels including Spencer Kimball, Scott Belsky, Nick Caldwell, Michael Li, Ryan Denehy and TLC Collective.</p>
<p>Data discovery tools have been around in some form for years, with popular companies like <a href="https://www.alation.com">Alation</a> having raised tens of millions of VC dollars over the years. Kim sees an opportunity to compete by offering a better onboarding experience and also automating large parts of the workflow that remain manual for many alternative data discovery tools. With many of these tools, “they don’t do the work of connecting and building the relationship,” between data she said, adding that “documentation is still important, but being able to automatically generate [metadata] allows data teams to get value right away.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2115659" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2115659" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2115659" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-Team.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="289" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-Team.png 1006w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-Team.png?resize=150,64 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-Team.png?resize=300,127 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-Team.png?resize=768,326 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-Team.png?resize=680,289 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Select-Star-Team.png?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2115659" class="wp-caption-text">Select Star&#8217;s team, with CEO and founder Shinji Kim in top row, middle. Photo via Select Star.</p></div></p>
<p>In addition to just understanding data, Select Star can help data engineers begin to figure out how to change their databases without leading to cascading errors. The platform can identify how columns are used and how a change to one may affect other applications or even other datasets.</p>
<p>Select Star is coming out of private beta today. The company’s team currently has seven people, and Kim says they are focused on growing the team and making it even easier to onboard users by the end of the year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/select-star-raises-seed-to-automatically-document-datasets-for-data-scientists/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2115654</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aquarium scores $2.6M seed to refine machine learning model data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/aquarium-scores-2-6m-seed-to-build-more-accurate-machine-learning-models/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/aquarium-scores-2-6m-seed-to-build-more-accurate-machine-learning-models/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aquarium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aquarium, a startup from two former Cruise employees, wants to help companies refine their machine learning model data more easily and move the models into production faster. Today the company announced a $2.6 million seed led by Sequoia with participation from Y Combinator and a bunch of angel investors including Cruise co-founders Kyle Vogt and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.aquariumlearning.com/">Aquarium</a>, a startup from two former Cruise employees, wants to help companies refine their machine learning model data more easily and move the models into production faster. Today the company announced a $2.6 million seed led by Sequoia with participation from Y Combinator and a bunch of angel investors including Cruise co-founders Kyle Vogt and Dan Kan.</p>
<p>When the two co-founders CEO Peter Gao and head of engineering Quinn Johnson, were at Cruise they learned that finding areas of weakness in the model data was often the problem that prevented it from getting into production. Aquarium aims to solve this issue.</p>
<p>&#8220;Aquarium is a machine learning data management system that helps people improve model performance by improving the data that it&#8217;s trained on, which is usually the most important part of making the model work in production,&#8221; Gao told me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He says that they are seeing a lot of different models being built across a variety of industries, but teams are getting stuck because iterating on the data set and continually finding relevant data is a hard problem to solve. That&#8217;s why Aquarium&#8217;s founders decided to focus on this.</p>
<p>&#8220;It turns out that most of the improvement to your model, and most of the work that it takes to get it into production is about deciding, &#8216;Here&#8217;s what I need to go and collect next. Here&#8217;s what I need to go label. Here&#8217;s what I need to go and retrain my model on and analyze it for errors and repeat that iteration cycle,&#8221; Gao explained.</p>
<p>The idea is to get a model into production that outperforms humans. One customer Sterblue offers a good example. They provide drone inspection services for wind turbines. Their customers used to send out humans to inspect the turbines for damage, but with a set of drone data, they were able to train a machine learning model to find issues. Using Aquarium, they refined their model and improved accuracy by 13%, while cutting the cost of human reviews in half, Gao said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2117231" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2117231" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2117231" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/60301667d6a4b05d1ccbdcde_team-copy.png?w=680" alt="The 7 person Aquarium startup team." width="680" height="385" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/60301667d6a4b05d1ccbdcde_team-copy.png 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/60301667d6a4b05d1ccbdcde_team-copy.png?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/60301667d6a4b05d1ccbdcde_team-copy.png?resize=300,170 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/60301667d6a4b05d1ccbdcde_team-copy.png?resize=768,435 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/60301667d6a4b05d1ccbdcde_team-copy.png?resize=680,385 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/60301667d6a4b05d1ccbdcde_team-copy.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2117231" class="wp-caption-text">The Aquarium team. Image: Aquarium</p></div></p>
<p>Aquarium currently has 7 employees including the founders, of which three are women. Gao says that they are being diverse by design. He understands the issues of bias inherent in machine learning model creation, and creating a diverse team for this kind of tooling is one way to help mitigate that bias.</p>
<p>The company launched last February and spent part of the year participating in the Y Combinator Summer 2020 cohort. They worked on refining the product throughout 2020, and recently opened it up from beta to generally available.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UW892x0W3K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/29/datasaur-snags-3-9m-investment-to-build-intelligent-machine-learning-labeling-platform/">Datasaur snags $3.9M investment to build intelligent machine learning labeling platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Datasaur snags $3.9M investment to build intelligent machine learning labeling platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/29/datasaur-snags-3-9m-investment-to-build-intelligent-machine-learning-labeling-platform/embed/#?secret=UW892x0W3K" data-secret="UW892x0W3K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/aquarium-scores-2-6m-seed-to-build-more-accurate-machine-learning-models/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117214</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet the LatinX Startup Alliance and Startout founders from TC Include at TC Sessions: Justice 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/meet-the-latinx-startup-alliance-and-startout-founders-from-tc-include-at-tc-sessions-justice-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/meet-the-latinx-startup-alliance-and-startout-founders-from-tc-include-at-tc-sessions-justice-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 15:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: Justice 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We love nothing more than highlighting notable early-stage startups, and you’ll find plenty of them in the spotlight on March 3 at TC Sessions: Justice 2021, a virtual conference exploring diversity, inclusion and the human labor that powers tech. You do not want to miss meeting and learning more about these impressive early-stage founders — [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We love nothing more than highlighting notable early-stage startups, and you’ll find plenty of them in the spotlight on March 3 at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/tickets">TC Sessions: Justice 2021</a>, a virtual conference exploring diversity, inclusion and the human labor that powers tech. You do not want to miss meeting and learning more about these impressive early-stage founders — all participants in the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/include/">TC Include Program</a>.</p>
<p>Not familiar with TC Include? TechCrunch partners with various founder organizations who act as advisors and nominate promising early-stage founders to participate in the program. In a collective collaboration with VC organizations like Kleiner Perkins, Salesforce Ventures and Initialized Capital and the founder organizations, TC Include provides educational resources and mentorship over the course of the year to help program participants develop and succeed.</p>
<p>You’ll have plenty of opportunity to meet and network with TC Include founders, and you won’t want to miss their live pitch feedback session. Each TC Include founder gets a 60-second pitch to a TechCrunch staffer. It’s a great opportunity to learn how to structure your pitch and pick up a few tips and strategies. Who knows? The pitch you improve could be your own.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We’ve already announced the TC Include startups affiliated with partner organizations Black Female Founders (<a href="https://www.blackfemalefounders.org/">here</a>) and the Female Founder Alliance (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/meet-the-female-founders-alliance-startups-from-tc-include-at-tc-sessions-justice-2021/">here</a>). Today, we’re thrilled to share with you just some of the early-stage founders affiliated with <a href="https://startout.org/">StartOut</a> and the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/LatinxStartupAlliance/">LatinX Startup Alliance</a>.</p>
<p><strong>StartOut</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="endoindustries.com">Endo Industries</a>:</strong> Endo Industries sells cannabis plants and, through collaboration with farmers, is building a platform that helps operators scale brands grounded in equity, diversity and wellness. Founded by Nancy Do.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://kyndoo.ai">Kyndoo</a>:</strong> Kyndoo is a data platform for solving social media&#8217;s biggest problems — fraud, attribution and content safety. It helps brands avoid working with #FakeFamous and helps them find companies that share their mission and values. Founded by Kelly McDonald.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://thimble.io">Thimble</a>:</strong> Thimble is a monthly subscription service that teaches kids robotics and coding skills through a curated STEM curriculum, robotics and coding kits and live, build-along classes. Founded by Oscar Pedroso.</p>
<p><strong>LatinX Startup Alliance</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.hoyhealth.com">Hoy Health</a>:</strong> Hoy Health, a digital health company with a bilingual platform, provides access to primary care products and services, at low cost, to underserved communities. Founded by Mario Anglada.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.caribu.com">Caribu</a>:</strong> Caribu‌ ‌helps‌ ‌kids have virtual playdates with family and friends by ‌playing games, reading‌ and coloring ‌together in‌ ‌an‌ ‌interactive‌ ‌video-call. Founded by Max Tuchman.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.pandocap.co/">Pandocap.co</a>:</strong> Pandocap is a financial media company built around the capital markets. Bilingual content focuses on easy-to-understand information and highlights diverse voices through different strategies. Founded by Laura Moreno.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/">TC Sessions: Justice 2021</a> takes place on March 3. Check out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/#1fa16903-b3ec-435b-ba68-d43e00bd8d70">the event agenda</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/#tickets">buy your pass today</a>, and discover the opportunities that come from building a more diverse, inclusive and just industry.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			width="99%"
			height="500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/meet-the-latinx-startup-alliance-and-startout-founders-from-tc-include-at-tc-sessions-justice-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VCs are chasing Hopin upwards of $5-6B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/vcs-are-chasing-hopin-upwards-of-5-6b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/vcs-are-chasing-hopin-upwards-of-5-6b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 15:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hopin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virtual events platform Hopin is hopin’ for a mega valuation. According to multiple sources who spoke with TechCrunch, the company, which was founded in mid-2019, is running around the fundraise circuit and perhaps nearing the end of a fundraise in which it is looking to raise roughly $400 million at a pre-money valuation of $5 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Virtual events platform <a href="https://hopin.com">Hopin</a> is hopin’ for a mega valuation.</p>
<p>According to multiple sources who spoke with TechCrunch, the company, which was founded in mid-2019, is running around the fundraise circuit and perhaps nearing the end of a fundraise in which it is looking to raise roughly $400 million at a pre-money valuation of $5 billion for its Series C. The two names out in front, likely part of a joint ticket, are thought to be Andreessen Horowitz and General Catalyst.</p>
<p>Two sources implied that the valuation could have gone as high as $6 billion, but with greater dilution based on some offered terms the company has received. The deal is in flux, and both the round size and valuation are subject to change.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>One source told TechCrunch that the company’s ARR has grown to $60 million, implying a valuation multiple of 80-100x if the valuation we’re hearing pans out. That sort of multiple wouldn’t be out of line with other major fundraises for star companies with SaaS-based business models.</p>
<p>Hopin has been on a fundraise tear in recent months. The company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/hopin-raises-125m-for-its-online-events-platform-on-the-back-of-surging-growth/">raised $125 million at a $2.125 billion valuation late last year</a> for its Series B, which came just a few months after it raised a Series A of $40 million over the summer and a $6.5 million seed round last winter. All told, the roughly 20-month-old company has <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/hopin-8ff6/company_financials">raised a known $171.4 million in VC</a> according to Crunchbase.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vaRhHCNKv0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/hopin-raises-125m-for-its-online-events-platform-on-the-back-of-surging-growth/">Hopin raises $125M for its online events platform on the back of surging growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hopin raises $125M for its online events platform on the back of surging growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/hopin-raises-125m-for-its-online-events-platform-on-the-back-of-surging-growth/embed/#?secret=vaRhHCNKv0" data-secret="vaRhHCNKv0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/hopin-raises-125m-for-its-online-events-platform-on-the-back-of-surging-growth/">When we last reported on the company</a>, Hopin’s ARR had gone from $0 to $20 million, while its overall userbase had grown from essentially zero to 3.5 million users in November. The company reported then that it had 50,000 groups using its platform.</p>
<p>Hopin’s platform is designed to translate the in-person events experience into a virtual one, providing tools to recreate the experience of walking exhibition floors, networking one-on-one and spontaneously joining fireside chats and panels. It’s become a darling in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic, which has seen most business and educational conferences canceled in the midst of mass restrictions on domestic and international travel worldwide.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2117205 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/hopin.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/hopin.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/hopin.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/hopin.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/hopin.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/hopin.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/hopin.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/hopin.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>It’s probably also useful to note that our business team uses Hopin to run all of TechCrunch’s editorial events, including Disrupt, Early Stage, Extra Crunch Live and next week’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/">TechCrunch Sessions: Justice 2021 event</a> (these software selections and their costs are — thankfully — outside the purview of our editorial team).</p>
<p>Hopin may be the mega-leader of the virtual events space right now, but it isn’t the only startup trying to take on this suddenly vital industry. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/21/virtual-events-startup-run-the-world-just-nabbed-10-8-million-from-a16z-and-founders-fund/">Run The World</a> raised capital last year, Welcome wants to be the ‘<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/welcome-raises-12-million-to-be-the-ritz-carlton-for-event-platforms/">Ritz-Carlton for event platforms</a>,’ <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/26/spotify-is-developing-a-virtual-events-feature/">Spotify is getting into the business</a>, Clubhouse is arguably a contender here, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/inevent-seed-fundng/">InEvent raised a seed earlier this month</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/26/hubilo-raises-4-5-million-led-by-lightspeed-to-focus-on-virtual-events/">Hubilo is another entrant</a> which nabbed a check from Lightspeed a few months ago. Plus, quite literally dozens of other startups have either started in the space or are pivoting toward it.</p>
<p>We have reached out to Hopin for comment.</p>
<p><em>Post updated to report that Andreessen Horowitz and General Catalyst are in the lead.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/vcs-are-chasing-hopin-upwards-of-5-6b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117202</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marc Benioff and this panel of judges will decide who gets one seat on the first all-civilian spaceflight</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/mark-benioff-and-this-panel-of-judges-will-decide-who-gets-one-seat-on-the-first-all-civilian-spaceflight/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/mark-benioff-and-this-panel-of-judges-will-decide-who-gets-one-seat-on-the-first-all-civilian-spaceflight/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 15:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benioff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[editor-in-chief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television In The United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX&#8217;s first all-civilian human spaceflight mission, which will carry four passengers to orbit using a Crew Dragon capsule later this year if all goes to plan, will include one passenger selected by a panel of judges weighing the submissions of entrepreneurs. The panel will include Salesforce CEO Marc Benioff, Fast Company Editor-in-Chief Stephanie Mehta, YouTuber [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SpaceX&#8217;s first all-civilian human spaceflight mission, which will carry four passengers to orbit using a Crew Dragon capsule later this year if all goes to plan, will include one passenger selected by a panel of judges weighing the submissions of entrepreneurs. The panel will include Salesforce CEO Marc Benioff, Fast Company Editor-in-Chief Stephanie Mehta, YouTuber Mark Rober and <em>Bar Rescue</em> TV host Jon Taffer. It may seem like an eclectic bunch, but there is some reason to the madness.</p>
<p>This seat is one of four on the ride – the first belongs to contest and mission sponsor Jared Isaacman, the founder of Shift4 Payments and a billionaire who has opted to spend a not insignificant chunk of money funding the flight. The second, Isaacman revealed earlier this week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/second-crew-member-of-first-all-civilian-spacex-mission-revealed/">will go to St. Jude Children&#8217;s Research Hospital employee and cancer survivor Hayley Arceneaux</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="K0zTeZpfs1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/second-crew-member-of-first-all-civilian-spacex-mission-revealed/">Second crew member of first all-civilian SpaceX mission revealed</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Second crew member of first all-civilian SpaceX mission revealed&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/second-crew-member-of-first-all-civilian-spacex-mission-revealed/embed/#?secret=K0zTeZpfs1" data-secret="K0zTeZpfs1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That leaves two more seats, and they&#8217;re being decided by two separate contests. One is open to anyone who is a U.S. citizen and who makes a donation to St. Jude via the ongoing charitable contribution drive. The other will be decided by this panel of judges, and will be chosen from a pool of applicants who have build stores on Shift4&#8217;s Shift4Shop e-commerce platform.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s right: This absurdly expensive and pioneering mission to space is also a growth marketing campaign for Isaacman&#8217;s Shopify competitor. But to be fair, the store of the winning entrant doesn&#8217;t have to be news – existing customers can also apply and are eligible.</p>
<p>The stated criteria for deciding the winner is &#8220;a business owner or entrepreneur the exhibits ingenuity, innovation and determination&#8221; so in other words it could be just about anybody. I&#8217;m extremely curious to see what Benioff, Mehta, Rober (also a former NASA JPL engineer in addition to a YouTuber) and Taffer come up with between them as a winner.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/spacex-is-aiming-to-fly-the-first-all-civilian-human-space-mission-by-the-end-of-2021/">Inspiration4 mission is currently set to fly in the fourth quarter of 2021</a>, and mission specifics including total duration and target orbit are yet to be determined.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tdOL5wbdzB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/spacex-is-aiming-to-fly-the-first-all-civilian-human-space-mission-by-the-end-of-2021/">SpaceX is aiming to fly the first all-civilian human space mission by the end of 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX is aiming to fly the first all-civilian human space mission by the end of 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/spacex-is-aiming-to-fly-the-first-all-civilian-human-space-mission-by-the-end-of-2021/embed/#?secret=tdOL5wbdzB" data-secret="tdOL5wbdzB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/mark-benioff-and-this-panel-of-judges-will-decide-who-gets-one-seat-on-the-first-all-civilian-spaceflight/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Metal 3D printing company Markforged announces plans to go public via SPAC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/metal-3d-printing-company-markforged-announces-plans-to-go-public-via-spac/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/metal-3d-printing-company-markforged-announces-plans-to-go-public-via-spac/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 15:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[markforged]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Big morning for Massachusetts tech companies planning to go public via SPAC. Shortly after Berkshire Grey unveiled its intentions, Watertown-based Markforged has announced its own plans. The metal 3D printing company intends to merge with ONE, a special purpose acquisition company created by Kevin Hartz, who will join its board. The deal, which could value [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Big morning for Massachusetts tech companies planning to go public via SPAC. Shortly after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/robotics-company-berkshire-grey-to-go-public-via-spac/">Berkshire Grey unveiled its intentions</a>, Watertown-based Markforged has <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210224005529/en/Markforged-Leader-in-Additive-Manufacturing-to-Become-Publicly-Listed-Through-Merger-With-one">announced its own plans</a>. The metal 3D printing company intends to merge with ONE, a special purpose acquisition company created by Kevin Hartz, who will join its board.</p>
<p>The deal, which could value the additive manufacturing company at around $2.1 billion, would bring in around $400 million in cash. Markforged plans to use the money on R&amp;D for new products, materials and building out new verticals for its tech. Shai Terem will stay on as CEO.</p>
<p>“We’ve been at the forefront of the additive manufacturing industry,” the executive said in a release tied to the news, “and this transaction will enable us to build on our incredible momentum and provide capital and flexibility to grow our brand, accelerate product innovation, and drive expanded adoption among customers across key verticals.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company says its technology has been used to print north of 10 million parts since its 2013 founding, with its machines deployed in some 10,000 locations across 70 countries. Last year, it pulled in around $70 million in revenue. It has raised north of $136 million thus far, including an $82 million round back in 2019.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aPp6wuqUyg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/20/markforged-raises-82-million-for-its-industrial-3d-printers/">Markforged raises $82 million for its industrial 3D printers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Markforged raises $82 million for its industrial 3D printers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/20/markforged-raises-82-million-for-its-industrial-3d-printers/embed/#?secret=aPp6wuqUyg" data-secret="aPp6wuqUyg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>3D printing seen some strong growth in recent years, and that’s expected to continue as companies look to the technology to expand beyond the rapid prototyping it’s best known for. Metal printing from the likes of Markforged and competitors including Desktop Metal are seen as an important step, offering far more durability than plastic deposits.</p>
<p>SPACs are, of course, becoming an increasingly popular route for taking companies public. Hardware makers haven’t been a huge player thus far (with a few exceptions like smart lock mater, Latch), though that looks like it may be changing. The deal is expected to close over the summer.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NdUiZjYJr3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/25/greg-mark-of-markforged-talks-about-putting-metal-into-the-microwave/">Greg Mark of Markforged talks about putting metal into the microwave</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Greg Mark of Markforged talks about putting metal into the microwave&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/25/greg-mark-of-markforged-talks-about-putting-metal-into-the-microwave/embed/#?secret=NdUiZjYJr3" data-secret="NdUiZjYJr3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/metal-3d-printing-company-markforged-announces-plans-to-go-public-via-spac/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117220</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
