<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 18:38:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>TikTok dodges questions about biometric data collection in Senate hearing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tiktok-dodges-questions-about-biometric-data-collection-in-senate-hearing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tiktok-dodges-questions-about-biometric-data-collection-in-senate-hearing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biometrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marsha Blackburn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terms of service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224091</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In its first-ever Congressional hearing, TikTok successfully dodged questions about what it plans to do with the biometric data its privacy policy permits it to collect on the app&#8217;s U.S. users. In an update to the company&#8217;s U.S. privacy policy in June, TikTok added a new section that noted the app &#8220;may collect biometric identifiers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In its first-ever Congressional hearing, TikTok successfully dodged questions about what it plans to do with the biometric data <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/tiktok-just-gave-itself-permission-to-collect-biometric-data-on-u-s-users-including-faceprints-and-voiceprints/">its privacy policy permits it to collect</a> on the app&#8217;s U.S. users. In an update to the company&#8217;s U.S. privacy policy in June, TikTok added a new section that noted the app &#8220;may collect biometric identifiers and biometric information&#8221; from its users’ content, including things like &#8220;faceprints and voiceprints.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company was questioned by multiple lawmakers on this matter today during a hearing conducted by the <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Senate Subcommittee on Consumer Protection, Product Safety, and Data Security. The hearing was meant to be focused on social media&#8217;s detrimental impacts on children and teens, but often expanded into broader areas of concern related, as the lawmakers dug into the business models, internal research, and policies being made at Snap, TikTok and YouTube. </span></p>
<p>Sen. Marsha Blackburn (R-TN) asked specifically why TikTok needed to collect a wide variety of biometric data, &#8220;such as faceprints, voiceprints, geolocation information, browsing and search history,&#8221; as well as &#8220;keystroke patterns and rhythms.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224091" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Instead of directly answering the question, TikTok’s VP and Head of Public Policy Michael Beckerman responded by pointing out that many outside researchers and experts have looked at its policy and found that TikTok actually collects less data than many of its social media peers. (He also later clarified in another round of questioning that keystroke patterns were collected in order to prevent spam bots from infiltrating the service.)</p>
<p>Blackburn pressed on to ask if TikTok was putting together a comprehensive profile &#8212; or &#8220;virtual dossier&#8221; &#8212; on each of its users, including younger kids and teens, which included their biometric data combined with their interests and search history.</p>
<p>Beckerman deferred answering this question as well, saying that: &#8220;TikTok is an entertainment platform where people watch and enjoy and create short-form videos. It&#8217;s about uplifting, entertaining content.&#8221;</p>
<p>While the senator&#8217;s line of questioning was a bit confusing at times &#8212; she once referred to this dossier as a &#8220;virtual you,&#8221; for example &#8212; it&#8217;s worth noting that we don&#8217;t have a full picture today as to what TikTok is doing with the data it collects from its users outside of what&#8217;s outlined in its privacy policy and, per <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/how-tiktok-recommends-videos-for-you">TikTok&#8217;s 2020 blog post</a>, how some of that data plays a role <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/tiktok-explains-how-the-recommendation-system-behind-its-for-you-feed-works/">in its recommendation algorithms.</a> And given the chance to set the record straight over its plans to collect biometric data with regard to minor users, TikTok&#8217;s policy head skirted the questions.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In a line of follow-ups on its data collection practices led by Senator Cynthia Lummis (R-WY), Beckerman was asked if this sort of &#8220;mass data collection&#8221; was necessary to deliver a high-quality experience to TikTok&#8217;s users. She noted the company&#8217;s policy allowed for the collection of the person&#8217;s location, device model of their phone, browsing history outside and inside TikTok, all the messages sent on TikTok, IP address, and biometric data.</p>
<p>In response, Beckerman said &#8220;some of those items that you listed off are things that we&#8217;re not currently collecting.&#8221;</p>
<p>He also said that the privacy policy states TikTok would get user consent if it were to begin collecting those items in the future.</p>
<p>Though not immediately clear, his statements were likely in reference to the clause about biometric data collection. In June, TikTok <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/tiktok-just-gave-itself-permission-to-collect-biometric-data-on-u-s-users-including-faceprints-and-voiceprints/">declined</a> to detail the product developments that necessitated the addition of biometric data to its list of disclosures about the information it automatically collects from users. But at the time, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/tiktok-just-gave-itself-permission-to-collect-biometric-data-on-u-s-users-including-faceprints-and-voiceprints/">company told TechCrunch</a> it would ask for user consent in the case such data collection practices began.</p>
<p>The senator said the committee would follow up with TikTok on this question.</p>
<p>Both senators were concerned about TikTok&#8217;s connection to China, given its parent company is Beijing-based ByteDance. But the issue of over-collection of user data &#8212; particularly with regard to children and minors &#8212; isn&#8217;t just a geopolitical concern or, as Trump believed, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/31/trump-ban-tiktok/">national security threat.</a> It&#8217;s a matter of transparency.</p>
<p>Privacy and security experts <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/02/07/privacy-policies-give-companies-lots-of-room-to-collect-share-data.html">generally think</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/blog/state-of-privacy-laws-in-us/">that users should</a> understand why a company needs the data it collects, what is done with it, and they should have the right to refuse to share that data. Today, users can somewhat limit data collection by disallowing access to their smartphone&#8217;s sensors and other features. Apple, for example, implements opt-outs as part of its mobile operating system, iOS, which pops up consent boxes when an app wants to access your location, your microphone, your camera, or your contacts.</p>
<p>But there is much more data that apps can track, even when these items are blocked.</p>
<p>Following the questions about data collection practices, Lummis also wanted to know if TikTok had been built with the goal of keeping users engaged for as long as possible. After all, having a treasure trove of user data could greatly boost this sort of metric.</p>
<p>In reply, Beckerman pointed to the app&#8217;s &#8220;take a break&#8221; reminders and parental controls for screen time management.</p>
<p>Lummis clarified that she wanted to know if &#8220;length of engagement&#8221; was a metric the company used in order to define success.</p>
<p>Again, Beckerman skirted the question, noting &#8220;there&#8217;s multiple definitions of success&#8221; and that &#8220;it&#8217;s not just based on how much time somebody&#8217;s spending [on the app],&#8221;</p>
<p>Lummis then restated the question a couple more times as Beckerman continued to dodge answering directly, saying only that &#8220;overall engagement is more important than the amount of time that&#8217;s being spent.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;But is it one of the metrics?,&#8221; Lummis pushed.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s a metric that I think many platforms check on how much time people are spending on the app,&#8221; Beckerman said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tiktok-dodges-questions-about-biometric-data-collection-in-senate-hearing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224091</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DeHaat raises $115 million in the largest agritech round in India</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/dehaat-raises-115-million-in-the-largest-agritech-round-in-india/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/dehaat-raises-115-million-in-the-largest-agritech-round-in-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 18:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeHaat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DeHaat, an online platform that offers full-stack agricultural services to farmers in India, has raised $115 million in what is the largest funding round for an agritech startup in India, where farm produce yields two-thirds of the country’s $1 trillion in annual retail spending. Sofina and Lightrock co-led the 10-year-old startup’s Series D financing round. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">DeHaat, an online platform that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/prosus-ventures-leads-30-million-investment-in-indian-agritech-startup-dehaat/">offers full-stack agricultural services to farmers in India</a>, has raised $115 million in what is the largest funding round for an agritech startup in India, where farm produce yields two-thirds of the country’s $1 trillion in annual retail spending.</p>
<p>Sofina and Lightrock co-led the 10-year-old startup’s Series D financing round. Temasek and existing investors Prosus Ventures, RTP Global, Sequoia Capital India and FMO also participated in the new round, which brings its to-date raise to $161 million. ($157 million of that has arrived in the last 30 months.)</p>
<p><a href="https://agrevolution.in">DeHaat</a>, which is Hindi for village, is addressing three of the biggest challenges farmers face in India (and elsewhere): working capital, securing agri-input items such as seeds and fertilizers, and finding buyers after producing the yields. Only about a third of the yields Indian farmers produce reaches the big markets.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224267" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The Gurgaon-headquartered startup has brought along brands who sell agri-input products, institutional financers, and buyers to one platform. It also works with microentrpreneurs &#8212; over 3,000 of them &#8212; to provide last-mile aggregation and delivery.</p>
<p>The startup, which runs a helpline to engage with farmers, also operates an eponymous Android app that is accessible in multiple languages.</p>
<p>“The uniqueness of its full-stack approach combined with the “phygital” go-to-market strategy further reaffirmed our view that the company is on track to become a significant player in the farming industry in India,” said Yana Kachurina, Principal at Sofina, in a statement.</p>
<p>DeHaat said it serves over 650,000 farmers in Bihar, UP, Jharkhand and Odisha.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Shashank Kumar, co-founder and chief executive of the startup, told TechCrunch in an interview that the startup will deploy the fresh funds to expand to “all major agriculture clusters of India.”</p>
<p>DeHaat has grown five times in the past seven months, he said.</p>
<p>Once an overlooked sector, scores of startups and tech giants are exploring to tap the world’s largest annual harvest of fruit and vegetables after China’s. India’s agri-tech industry has the potential to reach about $24 billion in revenue by 2025, according to EY.</p>
<p>Amazon recently began offering real-time advice and information to farmers to help them inform their decisions on crops. Microsoft is working with 100 villages to deploy AI and build a platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our team has grown to a brigade of 850+ professionals with deep expertise of growth and strategy, supply chain, technology and agricultural science,&#8221; Kumar said, adding that the startup is also looking to hire more talent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/dehaat-raises-115-million-in-the-largest-agritech-round-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224267</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequoia dramatically revamps its fund structure as it looks to rethink venture capital model</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/sequoia-dramatically-revamps-its-fund-structure-as-it-looks-to-rethink-venture-capital-model/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/sequoia-dramatically-revamps-its-fund-structure-as-it-looks-to-rethink-venture-capital-model/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 17:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial advisors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital is debuting a big shift in strategy as they look to boost their returns amid increased competition in the market for startup financing. The storied venture capital firm announced in a blog post today that they&#8217;re breaking with tradition, abandoning the traditional fund structure and their artificial timelines for returning LP capital. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Sequoia Capital is debuting a big shift in strategy as they look to boost their returns amid increased competition in the market for startup financing.</p>
<p>The storied venture capital firm announced in a <a href="https://medium.com/sequoia-capital/the-sequoia-fund-patient-capital-for-building-enduring-companies-9ed7bcd6c7da">blog post</a> today that they&#8217;re breaking with tradition, abandoning the traditional fund structure and their artificial timelines for returning LP capital. The firm&#8217;s future investments will soon all flow through a &#8220;singular, permanent structure&#8221; called The Sequoia Fund, the post from long-time GP Roelof Botha details.</p>
<blockquote><p>Moving forward, our LPs will invest into The Sequoia Fund, an open-ended liquid portfolio made up of public positions in a selection of our enduring companies. The Sequoia Fund will in turn allocate capital to a series of closed-end sub funds for venture investments at every stage from inception to IPO.</p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224193" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>These changes will notably only apply to Sequoia&#8217;s US and Europe-focused funds, the India and China-centric funds won&#8217;t adopt this structure.</p>
<p>Gone are the 10-year return cycles, which often pushed investors to liquidate holdings in public companies based on set timelines rather than determinations of when investments had fully matured. Sequoia says that investments will no longer have &#8220;expiration dates,&#8221; instead Sequoia will recycle returns from startup bets back into its central fund which it will redeploy into future investments &#8212; what the firm calls a &#8220;continuous feedback loop.&#8221; It&#8217;s a change that could greater align investor incentives with founders who will have less external pressure under this model to pursue premature exit opportunities.</p>
<blockquote><p>Once upon a time the 10-year fund cycle made sense. But the assumptions it’s based on no longer hold true, curtailing meaningful relationships prematurely and misaligning companies and their investment partners.</p></blockquote>
<p>In addition to the change to return timelines, this change will also give Sequoia much more flexibility to deploy funds from the central structure towards &#8220;Sub Funds&#8221; focused on a particular stage or sector. Sequoia says LPs will be given the option to move part of their allocation in The Sequoia Fund towards new Sub Funds.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">As part of the announcement, Sequoia also announced that they have become a </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">registered financial advisors (RIA). </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">General Catalyst and Andreessen Horowitz both become RIAs in recent years, a change which allowed them more flexibility in backing non-traditional assets outside of private markets. For these firms, it&#8217;s a change that allows them the to adjust to the fluidity of market trends, backing public companies during periods of rampant public debuts and seizing on upstart company capitalization trends like coin offerings.</span></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a significant change to the traditional venture capital model Sequoia has long pursued, and a major readjustment for the fund&#8217;s limited partners that smaller firms without Sequoia&#8217;s long-term reputation likely would not be able to pull off. It also showcases how much private equity powerhouses like Tiger have pushed storied VC firms to look inwards and adopt major changes to stay competitive.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/sequoia-dramatically-revamps-its-fund-structure-as-it-looks-to-rethink-venture-capital-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224193</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK driver shortage could steer grocery retailers toward bigger profits</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/uk-driver-shortage-could-steer-grocery-retailers-toward-bigger-e-grocery-profits/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/uk-driver-shortage-could-steer-grocery-retailers-toward-bigger-e-grocery-profits/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 17:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-grocery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home Delivery Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supermarkets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole foods]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The increasing prices as a result of today’s driver shortage could create a far more profitable e-grocery opportunity for British retailers by driving click-and-deliver customers to click-and-collect.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jacob Tveraabak</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/tveraabak">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jacob Tveraabak is the CEO of <a href="https://www.strongpoint.com/">StrongPoint</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The current driver shortage in the U.K. highlights the precarious and unpredictable nature of home delivery logistics in e-groceries. Although the market for e-groceries is bigger than ever, the shortage of drivers might trigger a new e-grocery megatrend in the U.K.</p>
<p>Costs of both first-mile and last-mile delivery are going to rise, but it’s the last mile where customers are going to see the biggest price pinch. Exactly by how much is hard to say, but depending on the scale of the impact, we could be seeing the start of a rebalancing of last-mile preferences for U.K. e-grocery consumers, with click-and-collect pickup playing a much larger role than ever before.</p>
<p>This is potentially good news for grocery retailers with a store network. They are the market players that can easily and &#8212; most importantly &#8212; profitably provide click-and-collect services at scale. A store network has often been considered more of a curse than a blessing in the e-grocery surge, but in this case, it might be one of the best assets.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224067" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The U.K. has historically been a majority home-delivery e-grocery market, with plenty of hyperlow delivery price options to tempt and retain customers. In addition, “quick commerce” has seen a big uptick in interest, with small orders delivered at lightning speed, sometimes within 15 minutes. Often backed by venture capital, they might be offering relatively low delivery costs or even running at an overall loss to gain market share.</p>
<p>But all home delivery customers, whether they’re weekly shoppers or just need a few items in a hurry, are dependent on the cost of the last mile being low enough for the service to remain economically viable in the long term.</p>
<p>The key question is this: At what price are today’s home-delivery customers going to reconsider their luxury service as unaffordable? That the market has significantly increased due to the pandemic inevitably means a greater percentage of more price-conscious customers.</p>
<p>Grocery retailers in the U.K. are already targeting these, for example, with yearly free delivery passes, but the driver shortage may make them reconsider the profitability of such offers. Just last month in the U.S., Amazon <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/amazon-says-its-adding-a-whole-foods-delivery-fee-to-avoid-raising-prices-on-merchandise-11632849441">increased</a> the price of its Whole Foods home delivery services, signifying the potential for a broader correction in the e-grocery home delivery market globally.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Internationally, home delivery of e-groceries is not as popular as it is in the U.K. In France, a country of equal size, drive-thru and at-store pickup are by far the most popular choices. In the U.S., click-and-collect overtook home delivery as the most popular last-mile choice in spring 2021.</p>
<p>One market that’s seen a similar trend is Sweden, where click-and-collect was more popular than home delivery by late 2020, but they have historically had to deal with extremely high labor costs, even without a driver shortage.</p>
<p>In-store supermarket associate costs start at £25 an hour in Sweden, and the price of labor in general is at the top of all global rankings. With their labor prices, even the tiniest cost increase could turn a small margin into a hefty loss.</p>
<p>What has Sweden done differently to cope with high labor costs? In terms of pickup or click-and-collect, the country appears to be an outlier in terms of its enthusiastic adoption of temperature-controlled grocery lockers — still a rarity in the U.K.</p>
<p>I believe the key driver of this trend is that they can be completely unmanned, with customers picking up their orders without any staff interaction. Smartphones using app-based age-verification systems could be integrated into these solutions, driving further efficiency gains.</p>
<p>But the key point is that they are leveraging their existing assets — their stores and staff — to provide these solutions.</p>
<p>If the U.K. is moving toward a larger click-and-collect pickup market, pure online players and e-grocery tech startups are going to struggle the most to serve these customers. However, because click-and-collect is less costly to provide, grocery retailers with a brick-and-mortar store network are in a prime position to capture market share at speed and scale and, consequently, turn a profit.</p>
<p>The increasing prices as a result of today’s driver shortage could, paradoxically, create a far more profitable e-grocery opportunity for British retailers by driving click-and-deliver customers to click-and-collect.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/uk-driver-shortage-could-steer-grocery-retailers-toward-bigger-e-grocery-profits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224067</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jessica Rosenworcel becomes the first woman to chair the FCC, and Gigi Sohn is nominated for 5th spot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/jessica-rosenworcel-becomes-the-first-woman-to-chair-the-fcc-and-gigi-sohn-is-nominated-for-5th-spot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/jessica-rosenworcel-becomes-the-first-woman-to-chair-the-fcc-and-gigi-sohn-is-nominated-for-5th-spot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 17:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gigi sohn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jessica rosenworcel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[net neutrality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The FCC has its first-ever woman as Chair of the agency, Jessica Rosenworcel, who has been serving as acting Chair since the beginning of the year. President Biden officially appointed her to the position today, and nominated her for a new term — as well as FCC veteran and tireless policy advocate Gigi Sohn, who [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The FCC has its first-ever woman as Chair of the agency, Jessica Rosenworcel, who has been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/the-fcc-has-its-first-chairwoman-in-jessica-rosenworcel/">serving as acting Chair</a> since the beginning of the year. President Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/10/26/president-biden-announces-key-nominations-8/">officially appointed her</a> to the position today, and nominated her for a new term — as well as FCC veteran and tireless policy advocate Gigi Sohn, who if confirmed would become the first openly LGBTQ+ Commissioner in history.</p>
<p>The appointment has been a long time coming for Rosenworcel, who has worked at the FCC for nearly 20 years, and has been a Commissioner for half that time, under three different presidents. She was among the authors and advocates for net neutrality and may yet succeed, despite the controversial binning of the policy under former Chairman Ajit Pai during the Trump administration.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s not all, of course: Rosenworcel has consistently worked for telecommunication and broadcast policies that are equitable and important, such as accessibility services and the huge Emergency Connectivity Fund currently being distributed. And she&#8217;s fought tooth and nail against robocalls, unethical data sharing, and attempts to make the FCC into, as she put it at the time, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/with-absurd-timing-fcc-announces-intention-to-revisit-section-230/">&#8220;the president&#8217;s speech police.&#8221;</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224176" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;I am deeply humbled to be designated as Chair of the Federal Communications Commission by President Biden. It is an honor to work with my colleagues on the Commission and the agency’s talented staff to ensure that no matter who you are or where you live, everyone has the connections they need to live, work, and learn in the digital age,&#8221; she said in a statement.</p>
<p>As acting Chair, Rosenworcel was fully empowered to do her duty, but there was some question as to whether she would receive the full time offer. One of the five positions at the FCC has remained conspicuously empty for more than a year, though President Biden could have nominated someone to it at any time. It was therefore an open question whether the administration was waiting to find the right person (who may also serve as Chair), avoiding an unfavorable nomination environment, or just dragging its feet. I suspect only time will tell, but whatever the case, the nomination today of Gigi Sohn is smart and portentous. (Funnily enough, I spoke with her earlier this year about, among other things, likely nominees. She did not, to my recollection, mention herself.)</p>
<p>Sohn, Georgetown Law fellow and co-founder of Public Knowledge, served as general counsel for Chairman Tom Wheeler back in 2013-2016. Some may recognize this era as the big net neutrality push.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DdF9eqZw8n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/30/commission-impossible-how-and-why-the-fcc-created-net-neutrality/">Commission Impossible: How and why the FCC created net neutrality</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Commission Impossible: How and why the FCC created net neutrality&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/30/commission-impossible-how-and-why-the-fcc-created-net-neutrality/embed/#?secret=DdF9eqZw8n" data-secret="DdF9eqZw8n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This is as big a hint as we&#8217;re likely to get that the FCC under Biden is winding up for a second shot at the popular policy, which prohibits companies from discriminating in their handling of different data streams. (For instance, Comcast couldn&#8217;t give priority on its broadband services to its own streaming apps.)</p>
<p>Having been taught a number of hard legal lessons and learned what is risky and what is merely politically charged, a new net neutrality policy would likely be leaner, smarter, and more forward thinking. Sohn, already a legal expert in these matters, has been making a study of the challenges faced during net neutrality&#8217;s extended court battle — so the new one, if and when it exists, will be likely be very shrewdly and comprehensively justified legally.</p>
<p>As if her qualifications weren&#8217;t enough, Sohn would also if confirmed become the first LGBTQ+ Commissioner, making this FCC extra historic.</p>
<p>Both will have to have their Commissioner positions (though not Rosenworcel&#8217;s chairship) confirmed by the Senate, which that august body can hopefully find time for between negotiation sessions over Biden&#8217;s spending bill.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/jessica-rosenworcel-becomes-the-first-woman-to-chair-the-fcc-and-gigi-sohn-is-nominated-for-5th-spot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224176</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple One&#8217;s Premier subscription tier is rolling out in 17 new countries on November 3</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/apple-ones-premier-subscription-tier-is-rolling-out-in-17-new-countries-on-november-3/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/apple-ones-premier-subscription-tier-is-rolling-out-in-17-new-countries-on-november-3/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 17:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple one]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscription services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple is expanding its all-in-one Apple One Premier subscription bundle to 17 new countries on November 3rd. The service will be available in Brazil, Colombia, France, Germany, Indonesia, Ireland, Italy, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Portugal, Russia, Saudi Arabia, Spain, Switzerland, and the United Arab Emirates. In these countries, Apple One Premier will include Apple Music, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple is <a href="https://www.apple.com/ie/newsroom/2021/10/apple-one-premier-expands-to-17-new-countries/">expanding</a> its all-in-one <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-one/">Apple One</a> Premier subscription bundle to 17 new countries on November 3rd. The service will be available in Brazil, Colombia, France, Germany, Indonesia, Ireland, Italy, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Portugal, Russia, Saudi Arabia, Spain, Switzerland, and the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>In these countries, Apple One Premier will include Apple Music, Apple TV+, Apple Arcade, Apple Fitness+, and 2TB of iCloud storage. The bundle can be shared among up to six family members. It’s worth noting that Apple News+ will not be part of Apple One Premier in these countries, as it is in the U.S., Canada, Australia and the U.K (News and News+ aren&#8217;t available in these new markets currently). With this upcoming expansion, Apple One Premier will be available in 21 countries in total.</p>
<p>Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/apple-one-services-subscription-bundles-start-launching-tomorrow/">launched</a> its subscription bundles in October of last year with the aim of being a one-stop-shop for all of a user’s software and service needs. Apple One Individual and Family plans are currently available in 100 countries and regions.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224207" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The Apple One Premier expansion comes as the tech giant plans to launch its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/apple-launches-fitness-group-workouts-powered-by-shareplay/">Fitness+</a> subscription service in these countries on November 3rd as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/apple-ones-premier-subscription-tier-is-rolling-out-in-17-new-countries-on-november-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224207</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UserGems raises $20M to take on ZoomInfo to help with prospecting and sales intelligence</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/usergems-raises-20m-to-take-on-zoominfo-to-help-with-prospecting-and-sales-intelligence/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/usergems-raises-20m-to-take-on-zoominfo-to-help-with-prospecting-and-sales-intelligence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 17:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medallia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[predictive sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PWC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sisense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncork Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usertesting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zoominfo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Finding a way to connect with people who might buy from you, while spending less time pursuing those who will never be interested, is something akin to a holy grail of the world of sales and marketing. Now, a startup called UserGems, which has built a platform that combines AI with data mapping to help [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Finding a way to connect with people who might buy from you, while spending less time pursuing those who will never be interested, is something akin to a holy grail of the world of sales and marketing. Now, a startup called <a href="https://www.usergems.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UserGems</a>, which has built a platform that combines AI with data mapping to help identify the most likely candidates for B2B sales and marketing prospecting &#8212; by making it easier to connect with those who have been customers before who have now moved to different jobs &#8212; is announcing $20 million in funding &#8212; pointing to the opportunity for sales tech that helps address this challenge.</p>
<p>The Series A is being led by Craft Ventures with Battery Ventures and Tiger Global &#8212; both new investors &#8212; and previous backer Uncork Capital also participating, along with individual angels. It brings the total raised by the startup to $22.4 million.</p>
<p>UserGems now has some 90 customers in the mid-market segment, including Procore, Medallia, UserTesting, Sisense, and BrightTALK. It plans to use the funding both to invest in product and talent.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223218" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Based out of San Francisco, UserGems has an interesting origin story that speaks to how sometimes ideas and businesses can grow out of unlikely places.</p>
<p>Christian Kletzl, the Austrian CEO and co-founder of UserGems, was living in Chicago after getting an MBA at Northwestern, when he encouraged his twin brother Stephan &#8212; who had been working for PwC in Europe &#8212; to come to the U.S. and join him in building a startup.</p>
<p>They came up with ShelfFlip, an e-commerce effort that aimed to compete against the eBay/Craiglists of the world with more efficient technology to sell your books, electronics and other pre-owned items. Early on, the pair applied to join Y Combinator with the idea, and they got in, but the concept wasn&#8217;t really taking off for the pair.</p>
<div>&#8220;We went into YC with <span class="il">ShelfFlip</span>, but scraped the idea during the batch,&#8221; Christian said. &#8220;We were motivated by the large list of companies that pivoted during YC and went back to the drawing board. We talked to a lot of companies in our batch and outside and came up with the idea of SmartHires,&#8221; a referral network for startups within the same investment portfolio.</div>
<p>We covered it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/03/20/yc-backed-smarthires-helps-startups-find-tech-talent-within-the-same-investment-portfolio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>, after the startup joined YC as part of the Winter &#8217;15 cohort.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Part of what the brothers built for SmartHires was software they could use to track when one customer (specifically one of SmartHires&#8217; &#8220;main champions&#8221; said Christian) moved from one company to another. Startups have a high rate of turnover, and so when the brothers mentioned this to some others in the cohort, they got enthusiastic about it&#8230; more than they were about SmartHires itself.</p>
<p>&#8220;More people seemed interested in that than our actual company, and that is how UserGems came to be,&#8221; he recalled. &#8220;Basically we pivoted twice since the YC days.&#8221;</p>
<p>UserGems is built on two basic ideas: how sales and marketing move; and how much of the modern workforce moves.</p>
<p>On the workforce side, as Christian describes it, the days of having a job for life, or even for several years, is long gone for many, and we have now entered &#8220;the great resignation.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the databases and sites that UserGems tracks &#8212; it covers and processes information from a wide range of publicly-available sources of information, ranging from Google searches through to news articles and much more &#8212; at least 20% of people change jobs every year. That means it&#8217;s hard to predict regularly when a person in one position will be there the next time you look.</p>
<p>As for sales and marketing, these have become massively data-driven exercises in the digital age: we have more information about people than ever before, and more software than ever before to manage contacting them en masse, more channels to do it, more analytics to measure how well they work, and so on. That however doesn&#8217;t change the fact that when it comes to successful sales and marketing, the hit rate is significantly higher when it involves people who are already familiar with you or might be more readily interested in what you are selling.</p>
<p>UserGems essentially brings these two state of affairs together: It&#8217;s a tool for sales and marketing types that integrates with whatever CRM they are already using, to help track people who they have done business with previously, to continue working with them elsewhere, where they become &#8220;prime candidates for marketing,&#8221; Christian said. &#8220;It&#8217;s a treasure trove to utilize in the sales process.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p11">He notes that in some ways what UserGems is not new: the best salespeople essentially already keep detailed records and tabs on their best contacts. What UserGems does is allow anyone to essentially do this &#8220;at scale.&#8221;</p>
<p>This is also just the first step of the platform that UserGems has built out. After contacts are established, machine learning algorithms then start to learn more about who users contact so that it can recommend which people they should be reaching out to next, based on similar product usage and other signals, to find those prospects who are more likely to buy.</p>
<p>On one side UserGems is competing against the likes of ZoomInfo, LinkedIn, and other platforms that help people search for the right sales prospects at specific companies; on the other it&#8217;s also sitting in another area of sales technology more generally known as predictive sales, where you have really fast-growing startups like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/21/people-ai-the-predictive-sales-startup-raises-60m-at-around-500m-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">People.ai</a> (which has seen some Covid-19 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/17/sales-startup-people-ai-lays-off-18-of-staff-raises-debt-round-amid-covid-19-uncertainty/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">growing pains</a> but bounced back and is now valued at <a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/sanfrancisco/news/2021/08/11/peopleai-joins-unicorns-in-100m-funding.html?page=all" target="_blank" rel="noopener">over $1 billion</a>), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/leadiqs-rapid-revenue-growth-snags-venture-attention-capital/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LeadIQ</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/6sense-raises-125m-at-a-2-1b-valuation-for-its-id-graph-an-ai-based-predictive-sales-and-marketing-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6sense</a> (now valued at over $2 billion). But with the trends around employment churn set to continue, and that creating yet more complexity on the sales side, it&#8217;s an area where clever approaches to solving the issue are bound to continue to get attention, one reason why the likes of Tiger Global &#8212; which has been behind also some of the biggest follow-on rounds for enterprise startups &#8212; is getting in early here.</p>
<p>&#8220;B2B sales and marketers today have a hard time cutting through the noise—most follow the same demand generation playbooks and send hundreds of generic sales emails and sequences. That’s why many sales teams miss quota and customer acquisition costs skyrockets,” said Brian Murray, Partner and COO, Craft Ventures, in a statement. “UserGems understands that past users are future opportunities, and has become an undeniable asset for high-growth teams, driving bigger pipelines, increasing win rates, and reducing churn.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/usergems-raises-20m-to-take-on-zoominfo-to-help-with-prospecting-and-sales-intelligence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223218</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Heavily VC-backed salad chain Sweetgreen heads toward public markets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/heavily-vc-backed-salad-chain-sweetgreen-heads-toward-public-markets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/heavily-vc-backed-salad-chain-sweetgreen-heads-toward-public-markets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 16:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automation technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweetgreen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sweetgreen is an incredibly well-backed unicorn that just happens to make salads instead of, say, enterprise software.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rent the Runway is expected to price <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/what-rent-the-runways-ipo-filing-says-about-the-business-of-loaner-garments/">its IPO</a> later today and trade tomorrow morning, provided that all things go as planned. Udemy is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/udemy-files-to-go-public-on-back-of-growing-b2b-incomes/">also on the way to the public markets</a>. Allbirds, too.</p>
<p>And this week, Sweetgreen <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001477815/000119312521306603/d104360ds1.htm">threw its hat into the ring</a>.</p>
<p>Sweetgreen is a food chain best known for salads that are popular with the office-lunching crew. I can safely say that as a longtime member of that cohort back when I worked in an office in a major city.</p>
<p>Why are we talking about a fast-casual restaurant chain here on TechCrunch? Because Sweetgreen <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/sweetgreen/company_financials">raised hundreds of millions of dollars</a> during its life as a private company, including myriad venture capital rounds &#8212; through a Series <em>I</em> in 2019 &#8212; along with capital from other investors.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s an incredibly well-backed unicorn, in other words. It just happens to make salads instead of, say, enterprise software.</p>
<p>So, let&#8217;s take a dive into its IPO filing, working to both understand the company&#8217;s business and its results. We&#8217;ll close with notes on how we have no idea how to price the company, a similar issue that we had with Rent the Runway.</p>
<p>The following days and weeks are going to prove illustrative in terms of the value of tech-enabled businesses, especially in contrast to more digital and hard-tech efforts. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/28/tech-valuations-vs-tech-enabled-valuations-2020-ipo-edition/">Yet again</a>.</p>
<h2>The fast-casual food game</h2>
<p>Sweetgreen operates its 140 food spots in 13 U.S. states and Washington, D.C., with some 1.35 million customers placing at least one order in the 90 days concluding September 26, 2021. And for a technology angle, some 68% of Sweetgreen revenue was generated from digital orders for its fiscal year to date, which ended September 26.</p>
<p>As noted above, office culture has proved to be no small part of Sweetgreen&#8217;s growth. Per the company&#8217;s S-1 filing, observe how it discusses the impact of COVID-19 &#8212; which disrupted going to offices, period &#8212; on its business (emphasis: TechCrunch):</p>
<blockquote><p>We experienced a decline in our In-Store Channel due to the COVID-19 pandemic in fiscal year 2020, particularly in central business districts, which was partially offset by strong sales in our suburban locations and strong off-premises digital sales across all markets. <strong>For our fiscal year to date through September 26, 2021, we experienced positive momentum across all of our channels, as COVID-19 vaccines became widely available and customers started to return to offices.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Sweetgreen has consistently expanded during its life, noting in the same filing that it had &#8220;119 restaurants as of the end of fiscal year 2020,&#8221; and 140 as of the end of September of this year. That growth has not been inexpensive, with Sweetgreen &#8220;targeting&#8221; an &#8220;average investment of approximately $1.2 million per new restaurant&#8221; in the future.</p>
<p>Powering Sweetgreen in the background are a few trends that the company views as accretive, including a consumer shift toward more plant-based eating and &#8220;rapid adoption of digital and delivery,&#8221; key channels for the food chain&#8217;s revenue growth.</p>
<p>Regardless of how you feel about Sweetgreen the brand, the company&#8217;s overall business plan appears sound on paper. People are eating healthier and ordering more via delivery. Salads transport well &#8212; they are not soup &#8212; and are as plant-based as you&#8217;d like. And because it is possible to make money selling food, why not Sweetgreen?</p>
<p>So, how has the company managed in business terms during its last few years of growth? Let&#8217;s take a look.</p>
<h2>Does Sweetgreen&#8217;s business generate sweet amounts of green?</h2>
<p>No, it does not.</p>
<p>In fact, Sweetgreen is rather unprofitable and doesn&#8217;t appear to be on the cusp of a rapid march toward profitability. Not that losing money is a sin, per se; many venture-backed companies run stiff deficits while they scale. That is the <em>point</em> of raising private capital, to invest it at the cost of near-term profitability and cash flow.</p>
<p>But Sweetgreen is no corporate child. It was founded in 2007, per Crunchbase data, making it nearly old enough to secure a learner&#8217;s permit to drive in the United States. If a human can get to the point of nigh-maturity in a time frame, surely corporations made up of adults and backed by mountains of private capital can manage the same?</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the data:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2224115" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224115" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2224115 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.31.38-AM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="284" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.31.38-AM.png 995w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.31.38-AM.png?resize=150,63 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.31.38-AM.png?resize=300,125 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.31.38-AM.png?resize=768,321 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.31.38-AM.png?resize=680,284 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-26-at-10.31.38-AM.png?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224115" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sweetgreen S-1</p></div></p>
<p>Note that time flows east to west on this particular table, so the company&#8217;s most recent full fiscal year is on the far left.</p>
<p>As we can see from the two most recent fiscal years, 2020 was a pretty hard time for Sweetgreen, which saw its revenues decline from $274.2 million to $220.6 million, and its net losses double from $67.9 million to $141.2 million over the same time frame.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/heavily-vc-backed-salad-chain-sweetgreen-heads-toward-public-markets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224057</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vercel brings new dynamic features to its Next.js framework</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/vercel-brings-new-dynamic-features-to-its-next-js-framework/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/vercel-brings-new-dynamic-features-to-its-next-js-framework/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 16:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JAMstack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[next]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[react]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223024</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vercel, the well-funded company behind the popular Next.js React framework, today announced the launch of Next.js 12 during a keynote at its annual conference. While Next.js, by default, mostly focuses on helping developers build static sites, Next.js 12 introduces what Vercel calls &#8216;middleware&#8217; that makes it easier for developers to provide users with personalized content. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://vercel.com/">Vercel</a>, the <a href="https://vercel.com/blog/series-b-40m-to-build-the-next-web">well-funded</a> company behind the popular <a href="https://nextjs.org/">Next.js</a> React framework, today announced the launch of Next.js 12 during a keynote at its <a href="https://nextjs.org/conf">annual conference</a>.</p>
<p>While Next.js, by default, mostly focuses on helping developers build static sites, Next.js 12 introduces what Vercel calls &#8216;middleware&#8217; that makes it easier for developers to provide users with personalized content. Next.js 12, which Vercel likes to call &#8220;the SDK for the Web,&#8221; also introduces support for ES modules and URL imports, instant HMR and builds, and significant workflow and collaboration innovations.</p>
<p>&#8220;<a href="https://jamstack.org/">Jamstack</a> and static sites became popular because they were empowering front-end developers to push to the edge,&#8221; Vercel CEO Guillermo Rauch said. &#8220;But over the years, we started noticing that developers and consumers loved the speed of pre-rendered artifacts at the edge. But they didn&#8217;t love the constraints of static workloads, namely anything around user personalization, feature flags and A/B testing.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223024" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Edge functions on the Vercel platform and the corresponding programming model enhancements to the Next.js framework will now give customers &#8220;the power of dynamic at the speed of static,&#8221; as Rauch put it. The combination of Middleware, as Vercel calls this new API, and Vercel&#8217;s Edge Functions allows developers to deploy this code globally with only a few lines of code at deploy time.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you&#8217;re running an A/B experiment, in the world before Middleware, your experiment would carry the bulk of both tests. I have the A test and the B test together. With middleware, because we&#8217;re able to make these choices before that request gets served, we can say, &#8216;oh, here&#8217;s just A or here&#8217;s just B and C&#8217; and you get that highly performant experiment,&#8221; Kevin Van Gundy, Vercel&#8217;s CRO, explained.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/vercel-brings-new-dynamic-features-to-its-next-js-framework/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223024</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blaseball is back for more absurdist, browser-based fun with Short Circuits</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/blaseball-is-back-for-more-absurdist-browser-based-fun-with-short-circuits/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/blaseball-is-back-for-more-absurdist-browser-based-fun-with-short-circuits/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 16:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browser games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dungeons & dragons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[major league baseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the game band]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Major League Baseball is experimenting with robot umpires to make games more interesting, but when it comes to sporty shenanigans, Internet League Blaseball has got you more than covered. After going on hiatus at the end of its public beta, the free, browser-based, absurdist baseball simulator is coming back. On November 1, the Hugo- and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Major League Baseball is experimenting with <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-10-11/mlb-rule-changes-atlantic-league-tests-tweaks-meant-to-save-baseball?sref=gni836kR">robot umpires</a> to make games more interesting, but when it comes to sporty shenanigans, Internet League <a href="http://blaseball.com">Blaseball</a> has got you more than covered. After going on hiatus at the end of its public beta, the free, browser-based, absurdist baseball simulator is coming back. On November 1, the Hugo- and Nebula-nominated game will launch Short Circuits, a &#8220;short, low-stakes, mini-series of temporary universes&#8221; designed to onboard new fans into the delightfully messy realm of Blaseball.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Developed by </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://thegameband.com/">The Game Band</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, Blaseball is just a </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/fantasy-fantasy-sport-blaseball-developers-score-3m-seed-funding-to-go-mobile/">fantasy fantasy sport</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> at first glance &#8212; you pick your team and bet on games, but players are named Peanut Bong, PolkaDot Patterson and Jaylen Hotdogfingers instead of something like&#8230; David Ortiz? Derek Jeter? Alex Rodriguez? But with its broad world-building, rogue umpires and high-stakes boss fights against peanut monsters, </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Blaseball is just as appealing to &#8220;Dungeons &amp; Dragons&#8221; roleplayers as it is to people who know what an RBI is. There&#8217;s a detailed plot to all this, which fans influence through voting in end-of-season elections. The developers say that the key difference between baseball and Blaseball is player participation &#8212; fan decisions can impact the course of league, even changing the rules of the game. The collaborative nature of the game helped Blaseball develop a deeply devoted fanbase &#8212; there&#8217;s <a href="https://twitter.com/weekinblaseball">podcasts</a>, <a href="https://blaseballthemusical.com/">musicals</a>, <a href="https://www.blaseballcares.com/">fan-run charity shops</a>, <a href="https://sibr.dev/">data analysis hubs</a>, <a href="https://blaseball.news/">news outlets</a>, even a prolific, international <a href="https://thegarages.bandcamp.com/">rock collective</a>.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223957" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223957" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2223957" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blaseball-Short-Circuits-The-Discipline-Era.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="606" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blaseball-Short-Circuits-The-Discipline-Era.png 1049w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blaseball-Short-Circuits-The-Discipline-Era.png?resize=150,134 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blaseball-Short-Circuits-The-Discipline-Era.png?resize=300,267 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blaseball-Short-Circuits-The-Discipline-Era.png?resize=768,685 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blaseball-Short-Circuits-The-Discipline-Era.png?resize=680,606 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Blaseball-Short-Circuits-The-Discipline-Era.png?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223957" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Blaseball</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223752" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>But if &#8220;broad world-building, rogue umpires and high-stakes boss fights against peanut monsters&#8221; has you feeling confused, you&#8217;re not alone. As the small team of developers found their footing over 24 week-long seasons, the lore and plot of the game started to become too confusing for even the most devoted fans to follow.</p>
<p>So, with a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/fantasy-fantasy-sport-blaseball-developers-score-3m-seed-funding-to-go-mobile/">$3 million seed round</a> in tow, the Blaseball developers are exploring ways to make the game more manageable to run and more accessible for new fans. They nullified the existing story line by <a href="https://www.blaseball.wiki/w/Season_24">absorbing the league into a Black Hole</a> (don&#8217;t worry about it) and went on hiatus in July.</p>
<p>Now, Blaseball will attempt to woo fans new and old with Short Circuits. This series of short tests will bring Blaseball back to basics, making it easy for new fans to get into the game. Each Short Circuit will last two weeks, and after each one wraps, The Game Band will send users surveys about their experience with mechanics new and old. Short Circuits will also allow Blaseball to test new betting and election systems, integral parts of the game that haven&#8217;t been meaningfully updated since Blaseball first launched in July 2020.</p>
<p>To check out the first Short Circuit, users can sign up on <a href="http://blaseball.com">blaseball.com</a>, where the games will kick off on November 1 at 8 AM PT.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/blaseball-is-back-for-more-absurdist-browser-based-fun-with-short-circuits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223752</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tasseled wants to help college students get their lives, and credits, together</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tasseled-wants-to-help-college-students-get-their-lives-and-credits-together/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tasseled-wants-to-help-college-students-get-their-lives-and-credits-together/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tasseled]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Vipul Patel lost half of his college credits while transferring from Florida Institute of Technology to Boston University, he began digging for answers. Patel soon stumbled upon equivalency tables, where universities track which courses from other institutions can be counted for credit during a transfer process. While seemingly innocuous, the tables gave him key [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vipulhpatel/">Vipul Patel</a> lost half of his college credits while transferring from Florida Institute of Technology to Boston University, he began digging for answers. Patel soon stumbled upon <a href="https://admission.gatech.edu/transfer/transfer-credit">equivalency tables</a>, where universities track which courses from other institutions can be counted for credit during a transfer process. While seemingly innocuous, the tables gave him key data of where Boston University draws a line around accepting credits from other institutions &#8211; and where it contradicts itself.</p>
<p>He eventually appealed to BU, a school I also attended, and pointed out that the university accepted credit from universities that accepted FIT&#8217;s coursework. The argument worked, and the small-yet-lucrative win inspired his other transfer friends to appeal for their once-lost credits.</p>
<p>The resulting buzz, and the fact that<a href="https://nces.ed.gov/pubs2014/2014163.pdf"> 39.4% of transfer students lose all their credits</a> when they transfer, gave Patel the confidence to turn his tool into a startup. Today, he and his co-founder, Nelson Huang, announced the launch of <a href="https://www.tasseled.com/">Tasseled</a>, a free platform to help students create and customize their own college plans with credits in mind.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223953" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.tasseled.com/">Tasseled</a>, which opened up a waitlist for its private beta today, is a member of the All Turtles product studio, the incubator behind <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/the-mmhmm-story-and-how-it-plans-to-spend-its-100m/">mmhmm</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/14/fertility-startup-carrot-raises-3-6-million-to-make-ivf-and-egg-freezing-more-affordable/">Carrot. </a>Patel says that the company has raised $750,000 in funding since its founding in 2018.</p>
<p>The service helps students identify what credits they need to graduate, and then helps them substitute expensive university classes with cheaper, more accessible community college equivalents. Taking a note from Patel’s experience, Tasseled is built with transfer students in mind: it highlights ways to fit in for-credit education from different places, either an online course or local community college class, into a four-year university plan.</p>
<p>Tasseled is pitching its service to college students, and high school students who are planning for college. The team collected, and centralized, information about application deadlines and tuition to help students turn their planning process into &#8220;a weekend.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2223956" style="width: 879px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223956" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2223956" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-3.png" alt="tasseled" width="869" height="517" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-3.png 1900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-3.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-3.png?resize=300,178 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-3.png?resize=768,457 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-3.png?resize=680,404 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-3.png?resize=1536,914 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-3.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 869px) 100vw, 869px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223956" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tasseled</p></div></p>
<p>“We’re already expecting a bunch of kids [who] are 17 and 18 to make a multi-hundred thousand dollar financial decision,” Patel said. “And, that’s kind of crazy. They&#8217;re simply making life-altering decisions with no information and our hope is that we can just close that.”</p>
<p>Tasseled&#8217;s bet on community colleges filling in gaps for students is further proof that financial inclusion is a big focus for the startup. On one end, extinguishing the stigma around community colleges will help more students lean on their local schools (and less on loans) to complete their degrees. On the other end, students who transfer from community colleges can sometimes come from low-income backgrounds, so Tasseled helps them make sure their for-credit work doesn&#8217;t go unrecognized by wherever they end up.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Rix6QnHc9u"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/fiveable-lands-10m-series-a-to-become-the-hallways-of-the-educational-internet/">Fiveable lands $10M Series A to become ‘the hallways of the educational internet’</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fiveable lands $10M Series A to become ‘the hallways of the educational internet’&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/fiveable-lands-10m-series-a-to-become-the-hallways-of-the-educational-internet/embed/#?secret=Rix6QnHc9u" data-secret="Rix6QnHc9u" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The startup has not figured out a business model yet, but could monetize using referral fees for any community college that gets a student through its platform.</span></p>
<p>Tasseled has evolved multiple times, even in its short life. It first started as an appeals tool, offering students a hacky way to get credits counted. Then, after students left campus in May, Tasseled pivoted to a full-stack solution to help colleges make transfer student decisions quicker. Then, COVID-19 dried up an already dehydrated sales cycle within higher-ed, so that didn’t work, either. Ultimately, Tasseled landed on returning to a simple but massive mission: help students save money.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2224136" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="609" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-2.png 1900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-2.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-2.png?resize=300,178 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-2.png?resize=768,457 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-2.png?resize=680,404 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-2.png?resize=1536,914 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tasseled-2.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Fittingly, Patel says that Tasseled&#8217;s early days began on Boston University campus. The startup worked with Director Ziba Cranmer over at BU Spark, an initiative for student entrepreneurship, to get a sense of how to build and how to talk to users. Cranmer introduced the co-founders to Phil Libin, a Boston University alum and the co-founder of All Turtles, at a Spark event.</p>
<p>&#8220;In startup mode, you feel like there&#8217;s every single avenue to go down, and both [of them] were the most impactful people at making sure I stay clear about building products for students,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ah9uvdyRFE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/edtech-leans-into-the-creator-economy-with-cohort-based-classes/">Edtech leans into the creator economy with cohort-based classes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Edtech leans into the creator economy with cohort-based classes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/edtech-leans-into-the-creator-economy-with-cohort-based-classes/embed/#?secret=Ah9uvdyRFE" data-secret="Ah9uvdyRFE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tasseled-wants-to-help-college-students-get-their-lives-and-credits-together/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223953</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Check out what’s happening tomorrow at TC Sessions: SaaS 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/check-out-whats-happening-tomorrow-at-tc-sessions-saas-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/check-out-whats-happening-tomorrow-at-tc-sessions-saas-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ali ghodsi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[as-a-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Casey Aylward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costanoa Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Databricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kathy Baxter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kobie Fuller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarah Guo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: SaaS 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upfront ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222488</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s officially TC Sessions: SaaS 2021 eve, and tomorrow is a big, busy day for everyone involved with or interested in building the next generation of SaaS startups. Top-line industry experts will cover vital SaaS topics — from fundraising and building to securing and scaling. You need a pass to SaaS: Buy your pass today [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s officially <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=tomorrowpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=tomorrowpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: SaaS 2021</a> eve, and tomorrow is a big, busy day for everyone involved with or interested in building the next generation of SaaS startups. Top-line industry experts will cover vital SaaS topics — from fundraising and building to securing and scaling.</p>
<p><strong>You need a pass to SaaS:</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=tomorrowpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=tomorrowpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your pass today</a> and save before the price goes up tomorrow at the door.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/#7a03cea7-ab64-4f3a-8846-1ec1e65647f6">The SaaS agenda</a> features more than 20 different presentations, interviews, panel discussions and breakout sessions. Got questions? Get answers from CEOs, investors and data masters at this highly interactive conference.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222488" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>We’re going to point out just a few of tomorrow’s highlights to help you make the most of your time. Don’t worry about schedule conflicts — your pass includes video-on-demand access when the event ends.</p>
<p>One more reminder. You’ll have ample time to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/network-your-way-to-opportunity-at-tc-sessions-saas-2021/">network your way to opportunity</a> with the people who can help you grow your business. And of course, you don’t want to miss out on product demos from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/announcing-the-startups-exhibiting-at-tc-sessions-saas-2021/">these early-stage startups</a> exhibiting throughout the day.</p>
<p>Okay, let’s look at what’s happening tomorrow at TC Sessions: SaaS 2021. Check <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/#7a03cea7-ab64-4f3a-8846-1ec1e65647f6">the agenda</a> for exact times, which will automatically reflect your time zone.</p>
<p><strong>Survival of the Fittest: Investing in Today’s SaaS Market:</strong> The venture capital world is faster, and more competitive than ever. For investors hoping to get into the hottest SaaS deal, things are even crazier. With more non-traditional money pouring into the sector, remote dealmaking now the norm, and an increasingly global market for software startups, venture capitalists are being forced to shake up their own operations, and expectations. TechCrunch sits down with Casey Aylward (Costanoa Ventures), Kobie Fuller (Upfront Ventures) and Sarah Guo (Greylock) to discuss how they are fighting for allocation in hot deals, what they’ve changed in their own processes, and what today’s best founders are demanding.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Data, Data Everywhere:</strong> As companies struggle to manage and share increasingly large amounts of data, it’s no wonder that Databricks, whose primary product is a data lake house, was valued at a whopping $38 billion for its most recent funding round. We’re going to talk to CEO Ali Ghodsi about why his startup is so hot and what comes next.</p>
<p><strong>AI Ethics at Enterprise Scale:</strong> Keeping AI models fair and unbiased is a tough enough job in the lab or with a single product. How can it be accomplished at the scale of business being done by Amazon and Salesforce? Amazon AI Applied Science manager Nashlie Sephus and Principle Architect of AI Practice Kathy Baxter will discuss the responsibilities as opportunities of putting ethical practices to work in enterprise applications.</p>
<p><strong>Nine Security Tips for Startups:</strong> When startups are in the beginning stages of growth, it becomes harder to balance between taking necessary security measures and bringing the product to market. You don’t want to slow iteration speed, but you also know that there are security steps that need to happen in order to grow the business. How do you balance these competing objectives? Christina Cacioppo, co-founder and CEO of Vanta, shares nine practical tips for building your product with security in mind and how to engage in conversations around security expectations from the start. Presented by Vanta.</p>
<p><strong>Building a Hypergrowth SaaS Startup in a Remote World:</strong> It’s hard to stand out in today’s startup market, given the sheer number of companies building, launching, and fundraising. But despite all the busyness, Workboard has made waves. Competing in a crowded niche, Deidre Paknad’s upstart tech company has posted huge growth despite COVID-19’s disruptions. We’ll sit down with the CEO to dig into how she managed to scale her company in both revenue, and human terms, despite the global pandemic. Founders, expect to learn something!</p>
<p>That should get your SaaS motor running, and of course there’s so much more waiting for you at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=tomorrowpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=tomorrowpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: SaaS 2021</a>. Don’t have a pass yet? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=tomorrowpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=tomorrowpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy one now</a> and we’ll see you tomorrow!</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e"
			width="100%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/check-out-whats-happening-tomorrow-at-tc-sessions-saas-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222488</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiger and Falcon look to double down on Indian social commerce startup DealShare</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tiger-and-falcon-look-to-double-down-on-indian-social-commerce-startup-dealshare/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tiger-and-falcon-look-to-double-down-on-indian-social-commerce-startup-dealshare/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 15:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DealShare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[falcon edge capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meesho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tiger Global and Falcon Edge Capital are looking to double down on their bets on DealShare, becoming the latest high-profile investors to go all-in on India&#8217;s nascent but growing social commerce trend. The two firms, both of which are already an investor in Jaipur-headquartered startup (AWI, which is managed by Falcon, is an early investor [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tiger Global and Falcon Edge Capital are looking to double down on their bets on DealShare, becoming the latest high-profile investors to go all-in on India&#8217;s nascent but growing social commerce trend.</p>
<p>The two firms, both of which are already an investor in Jaipur-headquartered startup (AWI, which is managed by Falcon, is an early investor in DealShare), are in advanced stages of talks to co-lead a financing round of over $225 million in DealShare, three sources familiar with the matter told me.</p>
<p>The talks propose giving DealShare a valuation of over $1.7 billion, the sources said, requesting anonymity as the talks are private. The round will likely see some early investors and founders selling as much as $60 million worth of shares, the people said. DealShare, which has raised $183 million in its previous financing rounds, was valued at $455 million (post-money) in its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/indian-social-commerce-dealshare-raises-144-million-eyes-international-expansion/">Series D round three months ago</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224142" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>DealShare and one of its co-founders didn’t respond to a request for comment. Tiger Global declined to comment.</p>
<p>The startup had preliminary talks with a number of other investors including Coatue Management, according to a source familiar with the matter. Coatue Management declined to comment.</p>
<p>The investment talks come at a time when the trend of social commerce has taken off in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market. Indian social commerce startup Meesho <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/meesho-india-social-commerce-raises-570-million/">recently secured $570 million in a round</a>. (Meesho, which counts SoftBank, B Capital, and Prosus Ventures among its investors, is in talks to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/google-in-talks-to-invest-in-facebook-backed-indian-social-commerce-meesho/">raise over $50 million from Google</a>, TechCrunch reported last week.) Flipkart, India&#8217;s largest e-commerce firm, recently forayed into the social commerce category and said it is aiming to tap over 25 million merchants on its platform by next year.</p>
<p>Even as Amazon and Flipkart have been able to create a sizable market in the urban Indian cities, much of the nation remains still underserved. DealShare, which began as an e-commerce platform on WhatsApp, where it offered hundreds of products to consumers, is attempting to reach consumers in smaller Indian cities and towns. The startup says customers on its platform buy curated items in groups, which makes purchases “highly competitive” in affordability. The average cart size on DealShare is between $16 to $19, the startup said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup offers “high-quality, low-priced essentials coupled with a gamified, fun and virality-driven vernacular shopping experience that makes it easy for first-time internet users to experience online shopping,” its executives have said in past interviews. The community purchasing, they said, enables “ultra-low-cost delivery mechanism” and ensures “best-in-class unit economics.”</p>
<p>DealShare has recently aggressively expanded its private label brands, through which it sells a range of items including rice and pulse, according to a source familiar with the matter.</p>
<p><em>This is a developing story. More to follow&#8230;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tiger-and-falcon-look-to-double-down-on-indian-social-commerce-startup-dealshare/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224142</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Logicbroker taps into $135M to advance cloud-based drop ship software</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/logicbroker-taps-into-135m-to-advance-cloud-based-drop-ship-software/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/logicbroker-taps-into-135m-to-advance-cloud-based-drop-ship-software/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 15:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connecticut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[K1 Investment Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logicbroker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peyman Zamani]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Simon Yu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walgreens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company closed last year with $2 billion in GMV and is on target to do close to $6 billion this year. To maintain its status as a global leader, that meant going after some new capital.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.logicbroker.com/">Logicbroker</a>, a Connecticut-based e-commerce company focused on cloud fulfillment, secured a $135 million growth round from K1 Investment Management.</p>
<p>Its software provides drop ship and marketplace automation capabilities to brands, retailers, suppliers and third-party logistics providers. As CEO Peyman Zamani explained it, “drop ship” is a way that packages get from the seller to the buyer.</p>
<p>For example, Walgreens is one of the Logicbroker’s customers, and if you purchased a bottle of Walgreens brand vitamins from the website, it might get to you from a company warehouse, shipped directly from the provider or from a third-party, but the item you receive will be branded Walgreens. Drop ship can also happen in-store: say you see a dress you like, but the retailer only has the blue one available and you want it in red. The store can order it and send it to you or you can pick it up in the store.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223702" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Zamani, who was previously an executive at Office Depot, says this kind of technology started about 30 years ago when the concept of electronic data interchange — businesses communicating information, like purchase orders and invoices, electronically versus on paper — began to become mainstream.</p>
<p>“Electronic data interchange is now at the heart of e-commerce,” he added. “The concept today is the same, but what I envisioned was this taking place in the cloud, but no one was focusing on the connectivity and automation in a scalable way.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223705" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223705" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2223705" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Potal-1.png" alt="Logicbroker" width="1024" height="581" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Potal-1.png 1984w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Potal-1.png?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Potal-1.png?resize=300,170 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Potal-1.png?resize=768,435 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Potal-1.png?resize=680,386 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Potal-1.png?resize=1536,871 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Potal-1.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223705" class="wp-caption-text">Logicbroker portal</p></div></p>
<p>He founded Logicbroker in 2010, his third startup, and hadn’t raised much in the way of venture capital since 2013, just under $2 million, to get to profitability, Zamani said. Logicbroker hit that milestone about six years ago, and is growing about 80% year over year in revenue. It expanded into five global regions and works with over 4,000 companies, including Mars Wrigley and Samsung, to manage more than $5 billion in gross merchandise value annually.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Over the years, investors were knocking on the door, and Zamani was always “respectfully declining,” that is, until this year. The company closed out last year with approximately $2 billion in GMV and is on target to do close to $6 billion this year. In order to be a powerhouse and global leader in drop ship, Logicbroker wanted to accelerate product features, which meant going after some capital.</p>
<p>“We had eight offers, but picked K1 because they only invest in SaaS companies and look for category leader,” Zamani said. “We were already there in the U.S and want to repeat that globally. We could have gotten there ourselves, but it would have taken five to 10 years. Now we can get there in a couple of years.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1W30ky7K0Y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/6-tips-for-establishing-your-startups-global-supply-chain/">6 tips for establishing your startup&#8217;s global supply chain</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;6 tips for establishing your startup&#8217;s global supply chain&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/6-tips-for-establishing-your-startups-global-supply-chain/embed/#?secret=1W30ky7K0Y" data-secret="1W30ky7K0Y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The new funding will go toward adding to its 65-person employee base, the global expansion and continued product development. Logicbroker launched its curated marketplace this year with half a dozen customers and intends to make it one of the company’s leading offerings over the next four quarters.</p>
<p>Simon Yu, senior vice president at K1, said via email he reached out to Zamani a few years ago when the firm saw that Logicbroker “was building something unique in the e-commerce space.” In speaking with the company’s customers, Yu said they told K1 how much “they loved the products and thought the team was building an innovative platform that had a direct positive impact on revenue.”</p>
<p>He believes digitalization of global e-commerce is still in the early stages, and behavior, like drop shipping, will become more prevalent over time.</p>
<p>“COVID-19 definitely accelerated some of that,” he added. “Logicbroker is fueling this transformation and we’re excited to work with Peyman and the Logicbroker team on building a category leader.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Lp6k3f76Es"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/5-ways-ai-can-help-mitigate-the-global-shipping-crisis/">5 ways AI can help mitigate the global shipping crisis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 ways AI can help mitigate the global shipping crisis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/5-ways-ai-can-help-mitigate-the-global-shipping-crisis/embed/#?secret=Lp6k3f76Es" data-secret="Lp6k3f76Es" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/logicbroker-taps-into-135m-to-advance-cloud-based-drop-ship-software/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223702</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bridgit secures $24M CAD in funding to provide construction companies with &#8216;workforce intelligence&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/bridgit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/bridgit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 15:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bridgit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Camber Creek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storm ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bridgit, a “workforce intelligence” technology company that is focused on the construction industry, announced today that it has raised CAD$24 million, or about US$19.4 million, in Series B funding. Camber Creek and Storm Ventures co-led the financing, which brings the Toronto-based startup’s total raised to more than CAD$35 million. Nine Four Ventures also put money [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bridgit</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a “workforce intelligence”</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">technology company that is focused on the construction industry, announced today that it has</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">raised</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> CAD$24 million, or about US$19.4 million,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Series B funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Camber Creek and Storm Ventures co-led the financing, which brings the Toronto-based startup’s total raised to more than CAD$35 million. Nine Four Ventures also put money in the round, along with existing backers BDC Capital’s Women in Technology Venture Fund, StandUp Ventures, Sands Capital and Vanedge Capital.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Mallorie Brodie and</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">COO Lauren Lake founded </span><a href="http://gobridgit.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bridgit</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in late 2012 with the mission of helping construction companies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> maximize profits “by taking a people-first approach.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">” Over the years, the pair say they spoke with hundreds of contractors and construction executives to better understand how technology could make them successful. Strategic workforce planning was a recurring theme, in addition to the need to forecast future staffing demands and “collaborative” access to people and project data, according to Brodie.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223729" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup launched its first product, Bridgit Field, in March 2014. In 2019, it brought its second product, Bridgit Bench, to market. Built for construction workforce planning, cloud-based Bench has become Bridgit’s flagship offering. This is not shocking considering the widespread labor shortage the industry has been experiencing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bench aims to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> help general contractors plan and grow their workforce, leverage project data to improve bidding and staffing decisions and forecast project pipelines. The end result, Bridgit claims, is increased productivity and profitability. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“General contractors are in the business of managing risk — ensuring you have the right people on the right project in order to reduce risk is difficult at the best of times,” Brodie said. “Up until now, general contractors had no better option than to complete their people-planning</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">efforts in spreadsheets. That’s a manual lift, and often more of a reactive than proactive process. Given the added pressures of the labor shortage that the industry is facing, building a proactive ‘people strategy’ is top of mind for builders across North America.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bench is also a big reason why Bridgit has raised its latest round. In July of 2020, publicly traded construction design software giant Autodesk led a CAD$9 million round into Bridgit. Since then, the company has increased its headcount from 46 to 83 while</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> its revenue has surged by 140%, according to Lake. During that same time frame, Bridgit has onboarded 58 new customers, including Clayco, The Walsh Group and Hoffman Construction, with enterprise-wide agreements signed with Skanska, Ryan Companies and Alberici-Flintco. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No doubt the COVID-19 pandemic and its resulting shift to digital had an impact as well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Once the pandemic hit, construction companies were forced to bring any remaining paper-based processes online, which led to a surge in usage of our workforce planning platform,” Lake told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to use its new capital mostly toward building out its team, product development and doubling down on its go-to-market strategy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The construction tech market is exploding and for good reason,” said investor </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Arun Penmetsa of Storm Ventures, who took a seat on Bridgit’s board as part of the financing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bridgit, he said, acts as a unifying layer for an organization’s data and provides “unprecedented visibility” into its people and projects, along with the appropriate workflows to support analytics, compliance and prediction, Penmetsa said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There is really no one out there doing what they are doing, and most organizations rely on Excel,” he said. “Bridgit’s approach is fundamentally different compared to other companies in the space.”</span></p>
<p><em>This story was updated post-publication to reflect that the round was raised in Canadian dollars</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/bridgit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223729</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>From the American heartland, a startup boom</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/from-the-american-heartland-a-startup-boom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/from-the-american-heartland-a-startup-boom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 14:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beam Dental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[m25]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Midwest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oculii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Midwest could sustain its results at present levels. If that comes to pass, the region would no longer be a place to fly over, but a location to Zoom into.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It felt like something of a coming-of-age party for the Chicago startup scene, a city that has long held a leading position in the larger Midwest market, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/13/chicagos-sprout-social-prices-ipo-mid-range-at-17-per-share-raising-150m/">when Sprout Social went public</a>.</p>
<p>The company would go on to become a breakout IPO success, pricing at $17 per share in the closing days of 2019 to a value of more than $123 per share today.</p>
<p>Sprout has put together a $6.6 billion company, mostly outside of the normal Silicon Valley headline mill. But its success is not singular. Instead, Sprout’s IPO was more akin to the opening shot of a starter pistol.</p>
<p>Since 2019, according to <a href="https://blog.midweststartups.com/2021-best-of-the-midwest-startup-cities-rankings-95de17d13760">data compiled by a Midwest venture capital firm</a>, capital invested in the region has effectively doubled, from around $10 billion in the 12-month periods ending June 2019 and 2020 to $20 billion in the year concluding June 2021.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Other notable successes have cropped up more recently, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/5-lessons-from-duolingos-bellwether-edtech-ipo-of-the-year/">including Duolingo’s IPO this year</a>, taking the Pittsburgh-based edtech company public at a valuation that now just tips past the $7 billion mark.</p>
<p>This year has proved lucrative for Midwest startups. A few data points make the trends clear. Per <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research/report/venture-trends-q3-2021/">CB Insights venture data through Q3 of this year</a>, Denver-based startups have raised about $3.1 billion in total venture capital. In all of 2020, that figure was $2.7 billion, and we still have a full quarter of data missing from this year’s tally.</p>
<p>Chicago is a similar story, with $4.9 billion raised through Q3 2021, per CB Insights, compared to $3.1 billion raised in all of 2020. Midwest cities are crushing their 2020 venture capital tallies, results that were at times already at or near record highs.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2220366 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>The Exchange has checked in on the Midwest <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/when-vcs-turned-to-zoom-chicago-startups-were-ready-for-their-close-up/">here and there in 2021</a>, noting certain venture capital and startup results as they came in. Today, however, given how strong the year is shaping up in general terms, we wanted to advance our understanding not of what is merely driving the boom in funding activity for Midwest startups, but what impacts the rush of capital is having on startups in the region.</p>
<p>We put questions to a number of area startup CEOs (from Beam Dental, Azumo, NanoGraf, Total Expert and Oculii) and Midwest-focused venture capitalist <a href="https://twitter.com/dmikeasem">Mike Asem</a>, asking how the pandemic has shuffled the domestic startup talent market and more.</p>
<p>The resulting picture is one that could indicate that recent strength in the region in terms of attracting capital to fund local upstarts may have the momentum to continue.</p>
<p>For the Midwest, then, long a somewhat overlooked region of startup activity, the future could be one of sustained results at present levels. If that comes to pass, the Midwest would no longer be a place to fly over, but a location to Zoom into. But as we’ll see; not every blessing is without costs, and what’s allowing the Midwest to put up more points may at times be a double-edged sword.</p>
<p>Let’s explore.</p>
<h2>The talent wars</h2>
<p>Sticking to the double-edged concept, it’s a well-worn trope by now that investing over Zoom has changed where many venture capitalists put their dollars to work. That means good things <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/16/india-poised-for-record-vc-year-as-unicorns-head-for-decisive-ipos/">for India’s startups,</a> as well as those in the U.S. Midwest, as investors not traditionally located in those areas may now be more open to investing afield from their IRL HQ.</p>
<p>The talent market is undergoing similar changes. With Zoom and related technologies allowing for more remote hiring, the global war for talent is now just that: global.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/AlexFrommeyer">Alex Frommeyer</a>, co-founder and CEO of <a href="https://www.beam.dental/">Beam Dental</a> (more than $168 million raised, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/beam-technologies">per Crunchbase</a>, with its headquarters in Columbus, Ohio), said in an email that the national talent market has “changed a lot since COVID, as more coastal companies have started to compete for top Midwestern talent for the first time with remote positions.”</p>
<p>After noting that he moved his company to Columbus to secure “access to a specific profile of talent, namely the mix of insurance and tech talent,” Frommeyer added that the city has “gotten more competitive” from a talent perspective, as “arguably the startup scene is growing even faster than the city.”</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/from-the-american-heartland-a-startup-boom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224088</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon’s Clubhouse competitor may let you DJ your own radio show</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/amazons-clubhouse-competitor-may-let-you-dj-your-own-radio-show/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/amazons-clubhouse-competitor-may-let-you-dj-your-own-radio-show/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 14:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[turntable.fm]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon is said to be working on a live audio app that sounds like it will let anyone be the DJ of their own radio show — including music. It's called 'Project Mic,' and will be U.S-focused at first.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Kris Holt</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://www.twitter.com/krisholt">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Kris Holt is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/">Engadget</a>. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/15/you-can-preorder-the-xbox-series-x-mini-fridge-on-october-19th/">You can preorder the Xbox Series X Mini Fridge on October 19th</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/youtube-removes-r-kellys-official-channels/">YouTube removes R. Kelly&#8217;s official channels</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/amazon/" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="16" data-v9y="1"><ins>Amazon</ins></a> is said to be working on a live audio app that sounds like it will let anyone be the DJ of their own radio show — including music. Project Mic, as the app is currently known, will reportedly focus on the US market at first, though the launch timeline is not clear.</p>
<p>Creators will be able to play songs from the vast <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-music-spatial-audio-headphones-ios-android-dolby-atmos-sony-360-reality-audio-142301483.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1"><ins>Amazon Music</ins></a> library, according to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22744585/amazon-project-mic-launch-live-audio-app" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1"><em><ins>The Verge</ins></em></a>. Along with music, it seems programming will include pop culture, sports and comedy. Amazon is said to be looking at bringing in celebrities and influencers to host shows. You’ll be able to search for shows by name, topic or music, and it appears Amazon will highlight live content, including trending topics and certain creators.</p>
<p>The presentation showed that in addition to the app, creators will be able to broadcast shows on Amazon Music, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/twitch/" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1"><ins>Twitch</ins></a>, Audible and Alexa-enabled devices. With the latter, listeners will reportedly get to interact with the shows, even from their car.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224120" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The report doesn’t mention whether listeners will need to be Amazon Music subscribers, but given the breadth of platforms on which the shows will be available, that seems unlikely. Engadget has contacted Amazon for more details.</p>
<p>It’s not the first time we’ve heard about Amazon working on such an app. <em>Axios</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-clubhouse-clone-leaked-163829793.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1"><ins>reported on its existence</ins></a> this summer, but this latest report provides more details about what Project Mic entails.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-spaces-everyone-ios-android-223459655.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1"><ins>Twitter</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-launches-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-110028076.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1"><ins>Facebook</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-launches-its-clubhouse-live-audio-rival-greenroom-130034550.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1"><ins>Spotify</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/discord-stage-discovery-portal-170039853.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1"><ins>Discord</ins></a> have all joined the live audio space over the last year after Clubhouse exploded in popularity. Those apps tend to focus on live conversations, though, rather than songs.</p>
<p>Spotify does have a morning show called <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-is-launching-its-first-fm-radiolike-music-and-talk-morning-show-120032078.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1"><em><ins>The Get Up</ins></em></a> that blends chat and personalized music, and it seems the most likely contender to offer a similar feature to what Amazon has in mind. Elsewhere, Clubhouse recently started <a href="https://www.engadget.com/clubhouse-has-a-new-high-quality-audio-mode-for-musicians-082436512.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="26" data-v9y="1"><ins>offering musicians</ins></a> a high-quality audio option for better livestreamed concerts.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-clubhouse-competitor-project-mic-music-dj-142534929.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/amazons-clubhouse-competitor-may-let-you-dj-your-own-radio-show/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224120</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple launches Fitness+ group workouts powered by SharePlay</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/apple-launches-fitness-group-workouts-powered-by-shareplay/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/apple-launches-fitness-group-workouts-powered-by-shareplay/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 14:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple one]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SharePlay]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has launched a new way for Fitness+ users to work out or meditate with people in other locations through group workouts powered by SharePlay. The tech giant first teased the feature at its September 14 virtual event. Fitness+ subscribers can use SharePlay to start a group workout or meditation session with up to 32 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple has <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/fitness-plus-introduces-workouts-and-meditations-with-shareplay/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched</a> a new way for Fitness+ users to work out or meditate with people in other locations through group workouts powered by SharePlay. The tech giant first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-adds-fitness-updates-including-a-group-workout-feature/">teased</a> the feature at its September 14 virtual event.</p>
<p>Fitness+ subscribers can use SharePlay to start a group workout or meditation session with up to 32 other people while using FaceTime on an iPhone or iPad. The Fitness+ session will stream completely in sync for everyone on the call.</p>
<p>To begin a group session, users need to start a FaceTime call and navigate to the Fitness+ app. From there, you can select a workout and get started. SharePlay also works with Apple TV so users can follow the workout on a larger screen while staying connected with their friends on FaceTime through their iPhone or iPad.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224079" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Apple notes that when you work out in a group through SharePlay, you’ll see their metrics and progress toward closing their Activity rings. When someone closes their Activity rings during a workout, everyone in the session will be notified.</p>
<p>Additionally, Fitness+ will be available in 15 new countries on November 3, including Austria, Brazil, Colombia, France, Germany, Indonesia, Italy, Malaysia, Mexico, Portugal, Russia, Saudi Arabia, Spain, Switzerland, and the United Arab Emirates. Fitness+ will be available in English, with subtitles in Brazilian Portuguese, English, French, German, Italian, Russian and Spanish.</p>
<p>The service is currently available in the U.S., Canada, Ireland, New Zealand, Australia and the U.K. With this upcoming expansion, Fitness+ will be available in 21 countries in total.</p>
<p>Apple also says that ​​beginning November 1, 2021, around 3 million fully insured UnitedHealthcare members in the U.S. will be able to enroll with Apple Fitness+ for a year-long subscription, at no additional cost as part of their plan benefits.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Fitness+ is also introducing a new episode of its Time to Walk series, which is an immersive audio walking experience, with actor and disability advocate Marilee Talkington. In this episode, she talks about defying expectations and how she helps empower others to do the same.</p>
<p>Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/apple-fitness-launches-on-december-14/">launched</a> Fitness+ on December 14, 2021, and has since worked to compete with other subscription fitness offerings, including Peloton. Fitness+ is available as a <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-fitness-plus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">standalone subscription</a> for $9.99 per month, or as a part of the <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-one/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple One Premier</a> plan for $29.95 per month, which gives users access to Apple Music, Apple TV+, Apple Arcade, Apple News+ and iCloud+ with 2TB of storage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/apple-launches-fitness-group-workouts-powered-by-shareplay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224079</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crossbeam lands $76M Series C as network effect fuels partner cloud growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/crossbeam-lands-76m-series-c-as-network-effect-fuels-partner-cloud-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/crossbeam-lands-76m-series-c-as-network-effect-fuels-partner-cloud-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crossbeam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partnership tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Crossbeam founder and CEO Bob Moore founded his startup to help companies building sales partnerships understand their overlapping accounts, using a process called account mapping. He knew that eventually the company would benefit from a network effect as customers attracted other partners to the network. As that vision has come to fruition, it has caught [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://crossbeam.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crossbeam</a> founder and CEO Bob Moore founded his startup to help companies building sales partnerships understand their overlapping accounts, using a process called account mapping. He knew that eventually the company would benefit from a network effect as customers attracted other partners to the network. As that vision has come to fruition, it has caught the attention of investors and today the company announced a $76 million Series C.</p>
<p>Andreessen Horowitz led the round, with participation from prior round lead investors Redpoint Ventures, FirstMark Capital, First Round Capital and Uncork Capital, along with Salesforce Ventures, HubSpot Ventures and Okta Ventures. The company has now raised almost $117 million with today&#8217;s investment, according to Crunchbase <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/crossbeam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">data</a>.</p>
<p>Moore says that the network effect was what is attracting investors and it provides an easy way for the company and its investors to measure success by looking at the network graph. &#8220;So all the ways that we think about if the business is working and how we measure success tends to revolve around the growth in this network graph and how many new companies are coming on board,&#8221; he said.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224064" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>That&#8217;s because many of these companies joined because they were recruited by other companies. They also can look at how deeply engaged they are in terms of using the platform and how they are collaborating across company lines, he explained. When you look at the growth from inception today, you can see that.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2224065" style="width: 489px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224065" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2224065" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CrossbeamGrowth-Small.gif?w=479" alt="Crossbeam network growth since inception." width="479" height="281" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224065" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Crossbeam</p></div></p>
<p>Further, over the last year, they have been attracting much larger companies, which has grown the network even faster. &#8220;One of the biggest changes in the last year is that we started landing very large enterprise accounts that have these really amazing ecosystems that almost serve as their own centers of gravity [in the partnership graph],&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He says that early on they were selling to partner teams, but now they are also moving into sales and marketing and that&#8217;s helping feed valuable data into systems like Salesforce and HubSpot (which not coincidentally are also investors). &#8220;That wider interest is driven by these integrations into products like Salesforce and HubSpot and Slack where the data can flow into where people are doing their work and actually allow them to get the answers to these questions and measure where the impact is coming from in their partner ecosystems.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In fact, it&#8217;s only when companies start putting Crossbeam data to work that they start paying. &#8220;We have a freemium model, so you can join for free, you can have unlimited partners for free and you can connect all your data for free. The point at which you start paying is when you want to take the data that you&#8217;ve been able to acquire through Crossbeam and have it exit the Crossbeam system and go out into another platform [like Salesforce],&#8221; Moore said.</p>
<p>So far that network has grown to 5,000 companies. He says that about 20% of participants have become paying customers, which is a pretty standard ratio. Today, the company has around 65 employees, with plans to get to 80 by the end of the year.</p>
<p>When we spoke to Moore at the time of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/06/crossbeam-announces-25m-series-b-to-keep-growing-partnerships-platform/">the company&#8217;s $25 million Series B</a> in August 2020, he talked about diversity and inclusion as part of the entire recruiting process and the culture he and the executive team are trying to create at the company &#8212; and he says that has continued as the company has grown.</p>
<p>&#8220;We talk about it openly and regularly in our executive team meetings. We have a diversity, equity and inclusion committee internally that is responsible for internal cultural efforts and checks and balances on all of our own processes, which is made up of a diverse array of employees. I think the bottom line is that our diversity numbers and representation among all ranks of the company has held up or gotten even better since the time of the Series B,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He adds that even in a tight employment market, they have been able to attract talent because people want to work at a company that is growing quickly and attracting investors as Crossbeam is.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re a B2B company that feels almost like a consumer business in some ways because of all these network effects…and we have a great story to tell and the company is growing very rapidly. We have amazing investors and it shows in the data and we&#8217;re very transparent culturally about how things are going,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/crossbeam-lands-76m-series-c-as-network-effect-fuels-partner-cloud-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224064</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gusto buys Remote Team in bid to support more international hiring</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/gusto-buys-remoteteam-com-in-bid-to-support-more-international-hiring/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/gusto-buys-remoteteam-com-in-bid-to-support-more-international-hiring/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 14:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The labor market is changing. More workers expect to keep working in a remote manner, even if many large employers are reticent to support the movement. The longer the pandemic drags on, the more it appears that work will look quite different in the future. As TechCrunch has reported, startups have already cast their lots [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The labor market is changing. More workers expect to keep working in a remote manner, even if many large employers are <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578804/apple-employees-work-from-home-request-denied-hybrid-model">reticent to support the movement</a>. The longer the pandemic drags on, the more it appears that work will look quite different in the future. As TechCrunch has reported, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/28/the-remote-work-argument-has-already-been-won-by-startups/">startups have already cast their lots in with a remote future</a>, often building their early teams across time zones and geographies.</p>
<p>The trend is pronounced enough that we&#8217;re seeing private tech companies get acquisitive to better support it. This morning, for example, payroll and HR provider <a href="https://gusto.com/">Gusto</a> announced that it is buying <a href="https://www.remoteteam.com/">Remote Team</a>, a startup that focuses on supporting far-flung staff.</p>
<p>As part of its news item, Gusto also announced that it now supports paying contractors in 80 countries and quick tax registration in all 50 American states.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223817" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Remote Team, unlike Gusto, is an early-stage startup. Crunchbase has but a <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/remoteteam/company_financials">dusting of data</a> regarding its history and capital raises, for example. In the view of <a href="https://twitter.com/joshuareeves">Gusto CEO Josh Reeves</a>, Remote Team was at around the Series A stage of startup life. Putting current fundraising trends aside, that means that the smaller firm likely had customers and a go-to-market motion that was just hitting its stride.</p>
<p>In contrast, Gusto has raised nearly $700 million in capital, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/gusto/company_financials">again according to Crunchbase data</a>, most recently <a href="https://news.yahoo.com/hr-software-company-gusto-raises-144746285.html">adding $175 million to its accounts at a valuation of just under $9.5 billion</a>. Gusto is, therefore, in the current parlance, essentially a decacorn.</p>
<p>Or, as we like to think of it at TechCrunch, a company that should go public.</p>
<p>Regardless of our views of the current late-stage unicorn market, Gusto could offer Remote Team something that simply raising more capital could not, namely scale. Per Remote Team <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sahinboydas/">CEO and founder Sahin Boydas</a>, selling his company to Gusto made sense because it could offer more reach into the global corporate footprint than raising oodles more private funds would allow the startup on its own.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Boydas indicated that support for more countries is coming, implying that Gusto&#8217;s ability to support international hires will only grow in the coming quarters.</p>
<p>Terms of the transactions were not disclosed, but Gusto&#8217;s CEO did indicate that equity was a component of the transaction. Translating that a little, the deal was executed in both stock and cash. Regarding the latter element, Reeves told TechCrunch that his company&#8217;s Series E earlier this year was not put together to fund the company&#8217;s day-to-day operations; Gusto still had most of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/smb-payroll-startup-gusto-raises-200m-series-d-plans-rd-expansion-to-nyc/">its preceding round in the bank</a>. You raise extra capital when you can, and, we&#8217;d add, when you want to buy some smaller companies that have tech or staff that you want to tack on to your current business.</p>
<p>We&#8217;d not be utterly shocked if Gusto bought another company or two before it goes public. (The company has now purchased three smaller firms, counting Remote Team. The previous two were Ardius and Symmetry, for those curious.)</p>
<p>On that front, Gusto said that it is growing at around 50% per year, but didn&#8217;t share more than that. TechCrunch pressed Reeves on the lack of details regarding its financial performance, essentially curious why he won&#8217;t share more at this juncture given that we expect to be able to look back at this period when his company goes public. As with every CEO we put that question to, the answer was polite.</p>
<p>Summing: Gusto&#8217;s small and midsized business focus doesn&#8217;t preclude it from seeing demand for more international and interstate hiring, so it&#8217;s tooling its service to meet the need. It will prove interesting to see how the larger Gusto-versus-Rippling rivalry bears out. The two companies have a history of not getting along, and Rippling recently put together its own mega-round, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/parker-conrads-rippling-is-now-valued-at-6-5-billion-more-than-zenefits-at-its-peak/">adding $250 million to its coffers at a $6.5 billion valuation</a>.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, we&#8217;re curious if Gusto and related private technology companies get into the corporate spend game, another corner of the startup work that is awash in both venture capital and market demand. You can see the synergies somewhat easily; Gusto wants to help SMBs start and run their businesses regardless of where they or their workers are based. And if Gusto is going to help make payroll work for those firms, why not add in another category of spend to the mix?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/gusto-buys-remoteteam-com-in-bid-to-support-more-international-hiring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223817</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
